Hello.
Ya?...
What?
Sir kindly switch off your mobile phone.
Just one sec one sec please!!!
Excuse me!
Sir please sit down!!!!
Captain there is a medical emergency
A passenger has just fallen down on the aisle
Delhi Air India 11 returning to medical emergency
Sir excuse me, sir excuse me sir
One minute!!!
I'm alright now
Thank you!
You can all go now
I'll go now
Gentlemen wait!!
Get the vehicle
Are you Mr.Dullon
Why?
Should I tatoo my name here?
Take out the vehicle fast!!
Ok sir!! Come sir
Should go to hotel right sir??
Ya ya we'll go hotel
But through Vasant Vihar,  take me there
Put some load on accelerator kaake!!!!
Ya Farhan, tell me
You come out fast, I'm reaching your place in 5 min
What happened dude?
Chatur had called
Remember him?
Who, "Silencer"?
Ya ya
He says Rancho is coming
What are you saying?
If you wanna meet Rancho come to campus at 8, on the tank
Oh, shaks...
Hey you come out fast
Ya okay ok
Sruthi I'll be back in sometime
Ooh shoes...
Hey I got my friend back
what?
Hey I'll come back and speak to you!!!
At least wear pants and go!!!
Now can we go to hotel sir?
We'll go to hotel kaake
But only after going to the "Imperial College of Engineering"
Okay sir!!!
Forgot to take socks dude!!
You talking about socks??? Hey look down even pants you forgot!!!
Ooh...
Sir now you can go to hotel?!
Yes, but only after going to airport because my sir is coming there.
Take him to hotel! Same surname - "Dullon".
I'm Dullon! Where the hell did you sent taxi? Is it on the runway?
Oye Rancho
Hey Chatur. Where is Rancho?
Rancho
Where is Rancho?
Welcome idiots
Wanna drink madiera (rum)
This is that rum you all used to drink here?
Have a drink
Hey where is Rancho?
I'll tell you
First you watch this
Not my wife...
Look at the bungalow behind idiots: 3.5 million
Swiming pool. Heated!!!
Living room maple wood flooring
My new Lamborghini. 6496cc. Sss... very fast
Hey, why you showing all these to us?
Forgot?
What is this?
5 September... today's date... What year?
Let's bet... after 10 years we'll come back
Here, on this same day
And we'll see who is the more successful???
Do you dare?... Say, will you come?... Will you come?
Remember something now???
Here. I kept the bet with that idiot
I kept my promise
I'm back he he
Stupid
I left my flight and came
He left his pants and came just to meet Rancho
For 5 years we're searching for him. Don't know if he's dead or alive.
Do you think he'll come for this stupid bet?
He won't come. I know he won't come he he eh
What? Will you break his teeth or shall I do it...?
One min Farhan, one min
Idiot. Then why did you call us over here?
To meet Rancho
Come and see where he stayed back and where I reached!!!
Means that you know where is Rancho? aah?
Yes
Where is Rancho?
He is in Shimla!!!!
#.....he was like a fleeting wind.....#
#.....like a flutterting kite.....#
#.....where did he go? let's find him.....#
#.....he was like a fleeting wind.....#
#.....like a flutterting kite.....#
#.....where did he go? let's find him.....#
#.....while confined channel guided us.....#
#.....he would define his pathways.....#
#.....and loiter along them merrily.....#
#.....while our future haunted us.....#
#.....he would celebrate the present.....#
#.....and live every moment with reckless freedom .....#
#.....where did he come from? .....#
#....touching our hearts .....#
#.....where did he go? let's find him.....#
#.....he was like a shade in sweltering heat .....#
#.....like village in desert .....#
#.....he was like salve for our distress .....#
#.....while we cowered from challenges .....#
#.....he would dive in seas .....#
#.....and swim against the rip currents .....#
#.....he was a wandering cloud .....#
#.....he was our pal .....#
#.....where did he go? let's find him.....#
Rancho!
Ranchhodas Shamaldas Chanchad
How different his name was?
That same different thoughts
Since childhood we heard that life is like a race...
If you don't run fast others will overtake you...
Damn!!! To take birth... I had to race among 300 million sperms he he eh
1978. I was born at 5.15am
And at 5.16am my dad said:
My son will become engineer!!!
Farhan Qureshi! B-Tech engineer
And my fate was sealed!!!
What I wanted to become? Nobody asked me though?
Raju Rastogi
Ranchhoddas Chanchad
Tell me your room number!
D26
Follow me
I'm Manmohan
M.M.
All these enginneers call me Millimeter
Milk, egg, bread, wash clothes, iron clothes, filling journals, copying assignment
Let it be any work tell me! Fixed rate no bargain!!
One min, one min hold this...
This is kilobyte
This is megabyte and this is his mother, gigabyte
Take their pictures... this family doesn't byte [bite]
[Raju praying]
Tere comes one more big believer!!!
Hi Farhan Qureshi...I'm Raju Rastogi
Don't worry
After few days here... your belief in God will vanish eventually
Only naked girls posters sticked by your bed... and you'll say
Oh God
Give me one, at least once!
Hey get out of here! Out, out!
Give 4 rupees
2 rupees per bag
Here's 5 rupees... keep the change
Wow sir, you gave me tip
I'll also give you a tip
Tonight... wear underwear which doesn't have holes!!!
why?
Oh Emperor...
You are great...
Accept our gift
Aaahh
This is he-man, he-man take this...
Ohoo... white white white
We were humiliated,
Hands saluting,
Heads down like slaves,
When we saw Rancho for the first time!
New gift... gift gift gift gift!
Namaste sir!!!
Remove your pants and get sealed!!!
Whats your name? Tell...
Ranchhodas Shamaldas Chanchad!!
Huuii hhehehhee
Listen brothers learn by-heart!!! By final year you'll learn!!! hmmm
Remove your pants... remove pants
Ooh, so you won't listen like this huh?
Don't wear wet pants kid?
Come, remove it now!!
Aal iz well, aal iz well.......[Ranchod baba mantra lol]
What is he saying?
Someone make him understand!!!
Hey, James Bond, make him understand!! hmm
Take off your pants, or they're gonna piss on you
Oye English!!! Feeling shy to speak in Hindi huh?
Sorry sir I was born in Uganda, and studied in Pondicherry!!
So little slow in Hindi!!!
So slowly make him understand!! Who is in a hurry here?
Worn again huh?
[in pure Hindi!!!!laughing stock] take off your pants or they're gonna piss on you...
He is telling piss as Muthravisarjan??? hahahha
Ooh here come pandit learning engineering
Hey come out you idiot
Come out
Come out or else I'll piss on your door!!!
I'll count till 10
if you don't come out
I'll piss on your door for the whole semester
Salt water is a great conductor of electricity
8th standard physics
We all studied it!!
He applied it!!
ICE's director's name was Dr.Viru Shastrabhuddi
But every one calls him Virus
All called him Computer Virus!!!
Oye Virus is comin, carrying eggs with him
He has said first years to come down come fast
Virus was the most competetive man we had ever seen
If someone overtakes him even one step.
He couldn't accept it,
To save time he used velcro instead of buttons
And a hook in tie!
He has trained his mind
That he can write using both his hands at the same time
Everday at 2 he used to take a power nap of exactly 7.5 minutes
and used to listen opera
Govind had to do all unproductive works like shaving, cutting nails in this 7.5 mins
What is this?
Sir, a nest!!
whose??
cuckoo bird's nest
Cuckoo bird never builds a nest.
They lay their eggs on other birds nest
And when their babies come to the world, what do they do first?
They kick out other eggs from the nest...
Competition over
The life begins with murder
That's nature...
Compete
Or die!
You all so are like the cuckoo birds
And these are those eggs whom you kicked out and reached ICE
Don't forget
Because every year, 4 lakh applications comes to ICE
Among them only 200 will be selected
You
And these
Finished
Broken eggs!!
My own son applied for 3 years
Rejected
Everytime
Remember life is a race!!
If you don't run fast someone will beat you and move faster than you...
Let me tell you very interesting story
This is an astronauts pen
In space, fountain pen, ball pen cannot be used
So after spending millions of dollars
Scientists invented this pen!
With this you can write in any angle, any temperature, zero gravity
One day when I was a student, the director of our institute called me
He said "Viru Shastrabhuddi." I said "yes sir"
Come here!! I got scared
He showed me this pen
He said this is a symbol of excellence
I give it to you
And the day when you get a extraordinary student like you
Pass this pen to him
For 32 years Viru Shastrabhuddi is waiting for the next Viru Shastrabhuddi
Anyone here in this batch to honour this pen?
Good, hands down
Should I write on the notice board?
I said put down your hands
Sir I have a question sir...
If in space fountain pen, ball pen don't work
why astronauts didn't try pencil?
Could've saved millions of dollars
I will get back to you on this
That fellow kicks seniors
And irritates the director
I'm telling you if we stay with him...
He will put us in trouble
Buddy, your thought screwed Virus completely
Oh Emperor, you're great.
Accept our gift...
Get lost, don't you have school?
Who'll pay fees? Your father?
You're naming my father?
Hey stop! Stop Raju, what are you doing?
Eh listen!
No fees required for schooling!!! Uniform is required, uniform...
Whichever school you like go, get the uniform of that school.
Go sit in the class...
Who'll come to know when there is a huge population???
If I get caught?
If they catch you, then change uniform, school! ehhe
There was really something special about him,
He always used to challenge everything in the world, each and every move...
He was the only one free bird in VIRUS's nest...
We all were just robots operated by professors remote control...
But he was the only one.
Perhaps not a machine!!!!
What is a machine?
why are you smiling??
Um, actually sir
From my childhood I used to dream of studying in an engineering college
Today I'm sitting over here, feeling excited sir!!!
No need to be so overexcited...
Tell me the definition for machine
Um...
Sir
Machine is anything that reduces human effort sir
Will you please elaborate...?
Sir um...
All those things which makes the work for humans easier are machines sir
Feeling hot!!! Pressed button, wind blowing, FAN is a machine sir!!
You can talk to your friend  miles away. TELEPHONE is machine sir!!!
Calculate crores in less time... CALCULATOR is a machine sir
Sir, actually we are dependent in the world of machines sir
From PEN NIB to PANTS ZIB... all machines sir!!
One sec up one sec down, up down up down up
Tell me the definition??
Sir that's what I'm telling sir.
Will you write all these in exams huh?
"This is machine up down up down up"??
IDIOT!!!
Anybody else???
)*&#^*&#*&(%#(*&#
)*&%*&#%&*(#*&%#
$(^($*&%#*&%#
*(&^%%%$^&*&*&^%$%&*
he he eh bla bla bla bla
*(&#*&%(*&#%%#
!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!
Wow great !!!! Perfect !!
Great. Please sit down!
Thank you. Thank you
But sir even I said the same in simple language...
If you like simple language.
You can go join some other arts and commerce college
But sir, we should understand it at least
Mugging up from books like this, what's the use sir?
Oh you know more than books???
Book has the same definition...
And if you wanna pass, you'll write this.
But sir, ther are other books also
Get out!!!
Oh why?
In simple language... please go outside...
IDIOT!
So we were discussing about the machines
Hey, why do you come back?
I forgot something sir!
What?
Instruments to record, analyse, summarize, organize,
debate and explain information,
that are elastative and non-elastative, hard bound paper,
bag jacketed, non-jacketed
with forward introduction, table of cotents index, that are
intented for the enlightment, understanding
enhancement and education of human brains, of sense
in root of vision, sometimes touch!!
What are you saying?
My books sir,
I forgot my books sir,
can I take them?
Couldn't you say in simple way?
I tried simple before, but you didn't like that way sir...
Professors used to keep Rancho outside more often than in classroom
If he got kicked from one class, he'd go to another
Rancho used to say that knowledge is increasing everywhere
wherever you get... gain it!!!
He was entirely different from all of us
We used to fight for bathroom
But wherever Rancho found water, he had bath there itself!
He was very much attached to machines
Used to carry a screwdriver in his pocket wherever he went
He would open any machine that he found.... some got closed
Some did not!!
There was another guy just like him
Joy Lobo
Sir, excuse me sir
Mr.Joy Lobo
Sir, if you mind letting me know about the convocations dates...
Why?
Actually dad wanted to get a reservation
I'm the first engineer in my village sir.
All the relatives wanted to come on the convocation day
In that case call make a phone call to your dad
Son please, please don't waste my time, hurry
Hello
Dad, director sir will speak to you
Joy
Mr.Lobo, your son won't get graduated this year
What happened sir?
He has violated all the deadlines
With unrealistic... Mr.Lobo, Mr.Lobo...
unrealistic project, as I said already
He's making some non-sense helicopter
Wo I recommend you not to reserve his ticket, I'm so sorry
Sir I'm just close
Is your project ready?
Sir at least take a look at this once sir please
Submit it. I'll take into consideration
Sir give me some extension sir
Why should I give you an extension?
Sir after dads stroke I couldn't concentrate for 2 months sir please
Did you run out of food and water for 2 months?
No
You couldn't take a bath? No?
Then why did you left studies?
I'm very close sir pls take a look at this sir please..
Mr.Lobo, my son died falling from train on Sunday afternoon
Monday morning Viru Shastrabhuddi gave lecture in this college
so don't tell me that non-sense
I can only give you sympathy not extension
si...r
How cool design he made? Wireless camera over helicopter?
Traffic updates security... can be used for all
but VIRUS was telling this is an impractical design...
Won't fly it seems?
How it won't fly? I'll make it fly!! hm hm
Hey don't tell Joy will give him surprise
we'll make this fly out his window and record his reaction
If we do his project, who'll do ours?
Test, viva, quizzes included, there are 42 exams in each semester
Hey you worry a lot dude
Take this hand and keep it in your hand and say,
Aal iz well, aal iz well
Aal iz well
Now he has brought something new our BABA Ranchhodas!!
Hey in our village there was a watchman...
he used to yell in night saying aal iz well
And we used to sleep tight
One night there was a robbery in our village,
then we came to know that he's blind,
And he yells aal iz well, aal iz well
And we used to sleep like fools...
But that day we came to  know about the real fact
See our heart right, is a big coward...
Keep our heart as a fool
If you have any big problem in life
Tell our heart
No problem baby everything is ok
aal iz well, aal iz well
Hmm so that will solve problem? huh?
No but still it gains the dareness to survive
Remember this mantra... this is gonna become more  useful over here
Got it, got it yeah
Take it to Joy's window
Hey Joy, up up
Oye window... see Silencer naked naked heheh ehhe
Hey Joy come out Joy
Hey Joy look outside..
Joy....
#... give me some sunshine.. give me some rain...#
#... give me another chance I wanna  grow up once again.....#
You've a good news sir..
Neither police got to know
Nor Joy's dad....
Everyone will think it's a suicide, sir
Reason for death in postmortem report
Intense pressure in wind pipe resulting in choking
This fool believed that
He died because of the pressure here...
And from the last 4 years of pressure over here? What about that?
Even that's not in the report also sir,
These engineers are so back minded sir
Didn't even invent some machine, that could really behold the pressure over here...
If they had does, could've come to know this is not a suicide, it's a murder,
Are you blaming me for the suicide of Joy?
If one student can't tolerate pressure why I'm I the one responsible?
So much pressure will come in life...
Then everytime you'll blame others for that?
Sir I'm not blaming you sir
Actually I'm blaming the system
Sir I've got some statistics
Sir, in suicides India is no:1 sir
Every half-hour a student attempts suicide, sir
Students die less in sickness and more in suicide here sir
Something is going wrong right sir?
I can't tell about other colleges but this is one of the finest colleges in the country
I'm running this college for 32 years
I brought this college to no:1 from 28th position
Sir what no:1 sir ???
Here we don't have any talks related to new ideas,
no talks on inventions
Only great talk on marks, or else job in USA
We don't gain any knowledge here sir...
Here they only teach us how to bring good marks...
Now are you going to teach me how to take a class?
Please sit down
Today we have our great leader behind us
Who claims that he can teach better than our highly qualified teachers
So today our professor Ranchhodas Chanchad will teach us engineering
We don't have all day
You all have 30 secs
Should find the meaning of the word written on the board
If you want you can make use of your books too
The one who gets the answer can lift your hands up
We'll see who'll come first and who's last
Your time starts now
Time up
Time up sir, time up
What?
Nobody got the answer?
Now rewind 1 min of life a bit and think
When I asked this question.
Anybody thought that today we will learn something new?
Anyone, sir
No
Everyone sunk in race
Whats the use if you come first studying like this?
will you improve your knowledge? No.
Only pressure will increase
And this is a college not a PRESSURE COOKER
The lion in the circus also learns to sit on the chair fearing the whip held in his owner's hand
But we call such a lion as well trained, not well educated
Hello....
This is not a philosophy class!
Tell us the meaning of those 2 words,
Sir, actually no such words exists sir
These are my friend's names
Farhan and Raju
Quiet
Non-sense
Like this you teach engineering?
No sir I'm not teaching you engineering, you know better than me
I was teaching you that, how to teach,
And I believe that you learn someday for sure sir
Because I never leave my weaker students hand
Busted
Quiet
Quiet I said
I would regret to inform you that your son Farhan, Raju is going on wrong routes
If you don't take required action their future will be spoiled
VIRUS's letters fell down in our homes like an atom bomb
There was mourning in Hiroshima and Nagasaki!
And we were invited to both the home to get kicked
Come, come inside
See there
We could only afford one airconditioner
And we didn't keep in our bedroom, we kept it in Farhans bedroom
for him to study conveniently
I didn't buy a car, rode a scooter till now
Invested all money in Farhans studies
We sacrificed our future for Farhan's better future.. did you understand or not?
Then can you imagine what I must be going through!
Hey you took all these photos Farhan?
Quiet
He has the ghost of photography in his head
He used to take the images of animals and used to say he wanted to become
wild life photographer
Son what was your percentage that year?
91 percent
Did you hear that?
From 94 percent straight down to 91 pecent
You feel it funny?
No no uncle no
I was telling how great pictures he has taken
Why you making him an engineer you could've  made him a wild life photographer
I'm folding my hands and requesting you
Please don't spoil my son's future
Kids
Come let's eat somethin
When you come next time have food and go....
Dad though didn't give us food,
And at last to fill our hungry stomachs, and to fill the quota of advise
We reached Raju's home
Raju's home reminds us about the 1950's black and white films
One small bed where his paralysed father rest
One coughing mother
And one sister at her age of marriage
Sofa with all springs out
And 24 hours running water from terrace
Mother was retired from school and almost tired everytime...
His dad was a postmaster at his age
After paralysis he lost his half body and salary completely....
And sister!!!
Kammo (Raju's sister) is 28 now...
Asking Maruthi 800 as dowry...
If don't study and all how she'll get married?
Take lady's finger curry.. hand jee thank you
You know what? Lady's finger has now become 12 rupees per kg
And cauliflower 10 rupees
World is looting all over
These kind of letters come from college
What will we eat??
Want paneer?
Someday back you get little of paneer in Goldsmith's shop
No no enough
Mom just leave it keep quiet, what?
Ok ok, I'll keep quiet
Earn for kids, work like a servant, and after all these keep mouth shut?
Hey these all our news if I don't tell it to my son,
to whom will I say? to his friends?
Hey Raju
It was a big confusion whether we should control our friend or wipe his mother's tears
Then we thought to leave all these matter, and
let's concentrate on mattar paneer now,
Even his exhema's cream comes for 55 rupees now
Ewwww...
Want more roti son???
No no. Done. No. Stomach is filled aunty
Lady's finger 12 rupees and caulli flower 10 rupees hehheee
At least we offered you some food unlike your hungy father
Hitler Qureshi
Huh huh. Your mom is Mother Theresa right? She was serving us itchy roti
Don't make fun of my mother
Hey leave it, why you all fighting? Feeling damn hungry. Come let's go have some food outside
This is the end of month. Who'll give money? His mom, Mother Teresa?
To have food doesn't require money dude, uniform is required uniform
Watch there..
Come
Namaste jee, namaste
Ooh uncle
Hey, listen, get us 3 glasses of vodka
Half soda half water
What are the starters available?
What ever get us two plates each
And leave this here
And change the music yaar. Put some ghazal or something
Pia what the hell is this?
What have you worn?
Bloody 18th century watch?
What people will say?
Watch Suhas's fiance, she is gonna become doctor,
And she's wearing a watch just costing 200 bucks?
Please take it off. Thank you
Hi handsome
Hey aunty,
You're looking good
Don't miss my set darling
Rubies?
From Mendelaves..
Mendelave, wow!!!
Hey let's go meet David, come I'll show you, of course, of course
Excuse me
Yes
Um... flowers
Um... Can I take this glass?
Why?
What if you break my head with a glass?
Why should I throw this on you?
Because I'm gonna give you some free advice,
What?
Don't ever marry that fool,
Excuse me
He is not a human, he is just a price tag, price tag
He'll embarrass you telling all prices of different things all your life,
Your life will be spoiled and your future will be finished,
Should I give a demo?
Should I find out what's the price for his shoes?
I'm not gonna ask him, he himself will reveal, just a sec
Oh my God!
Hey hey
What have you done?
These are 300 $ shoes
You dropped mint chutney on my 300 $ shoes!
Run away, it's a free advise, take it or leave it
Genuine Italian leather hand stiched
Dad
Are these your guests?
These are my students
Why they're here?
One sec
This is really good dude, smelling very good,
Hey no space for puri dude, adjust it by side, ohh
Hi
Hey, hi,
You helped me opening up my eyes, thank you so much
Nothing like that... It was my duty!
can I ask you for a little  more help?
Ya ya
My dad won't allow me to break the engagement with Suhas
How great you explain!
It would be good if you give a demo for him also
Ya ya. Why not, why not? I'll give a demo
Raju get me chutney,
You're really sweet,
Where is he, where is your dad?
Totally behind you,
Ooh
Aal iz well, aal iz well
Run away, it's a free advise. Take it or leave it
What are you all doing here?
Um sir... we'll go on the stage, give this envelope and come sir
Give it to me
This is my sister's marriage
Umm. Sis, sister?
Sir, totally how many daughters do you have, sir?
It's empty!
As though we didn't invite you
You all might be from groom's side right?
No sir. Actually we're from science's side sir
How?
Can you explain?
Dad, he explains really good,
Now he'll give a demo
Um... sir in Delhi,
power goes out frequently sir
And this really affects the marriage too sir
so I thought to make an inverter
That can generate power from all cars that has come in the marriage,
Ohh
Wow
And did you make the inverter?
Sir, design is ready sir!
Um... Where is the design Farhan?
I've given you the design right?
Aah, I had given it to Raju,
Raju? The design?
Sir, actually, leave it sir, I'll make the inverter itself and show you directly,
You can only make us fool, not an inverter!!!
No sir, I'll surely make the inverter, I promise
And I'll give your name for the inverter
Because after all it had been invented in your daughter's marriage so it's an honour
Farhan, Raju... I wish to meet both of you in the office tomorrow
Sir what was your per plate cost sir,
We'll pay sir
In terms of installment sir
And afterward we won't intrude in any marriage sir
I won't even go into my marriage sir,
Infact I won't even marry sir. Even he won't marry sir
Huh huh, even I won't sir
Even your parents shouldn't have married
2 idiots wouldn't have taken birth in this world
Sit!!!!!!!!
Pay attention...
??????
This is Ranchhodas's father's monthly income
2.5 crores rupees,
Now from this,
One, or let it be two zeros if you remove out...
Doesn't make much difference to bother,
But if one more zero is less,
I would worry a little
This is your father's monthly income, Mr.Farhan!
Ye... yes sir,
And now if you make it one more zero less,
Now this is your family income Mr.Raju Rastogi,
Big reason to worry,
Follow Viru Shastrabhuddi's suggestion, change your rooms
And get shifted with Chatur Ramalingam
Exams are closer, and if you are with that Chanchad,
You'll never pass exams!
#..... opera started......#
Wanna get shaved?
No sir,
Then get lost!
Raju you try to understand,
VIRUS is playing games between us, divide and rule
Don't get scared,
Had to be scared!
For me to get a good job, I need good grades. And the grades are within his hands
I don't have a rich father like you... Using those money, I could spend the rest of my life
Hey Raju, what non-sense are you telling?
Should we do whatever he says huh? Aal iz well, aal iz well?
You'll be the only one who's gonna catch his tail not me,
Now you're crossing the line
No. I'm making line in between, because I have to support my family!
Mom's half salary has been spend on dad's medicines
Sister's marriage is not happening,
As the groom wants maruthi 800
from past 5 years
Mom didn't even buy one saree
yaar... Now in this argument... If you are getting mother's saree in between... What can I say?
yaar... so like that how many sarees are reserved for one year? heheh
Don't make fun of my mother,
Hey Raju we will study, with complete dedication we'll study,
But not only to pass exams,
Some great scholar has said,
"never study to be successful, study for self efficiency"
Don't run behind success,
Excellence
Follow behind excellence
Success will come all way behind you,
Who? The great scholar said this?
BABA Ranchhodas???
Hey hey. Don't take tension yaar
We'll top the exams yaar, nothing is impossible!
Nothing is impossible? Huh?
Take this
Now put this back, k!
Raju changed his train's bogey
Now he started the journey (saffar) with Chatur,
Not the "saffar" in Hindi,
English's SUFFER
S
SU
SUF
SUFF
SUFFE
SUFFER
SUFFER hehhehe
Everyone calls Chatur as "Silencer"
To make his mind even more sharper,
he used to eat some bengali BABA's PAN,
and he used to leave his HOT AIR!!!!
I didn't do it!
Raju....
and he always put the blame on others!
SILENCER used to mug up 18 hours a day
and during exam's night, he used to distract others from study
#.... ooh baby.... come on baby ye.....#
he believed in two ways of topping exams
one is to get marks by yourself,  or try reducing other's marks
Rancho has made the combined plan to teach Silencer a lesson and to help Raju,
Our director sir has done much miracle here,
Chamatkaar (miracle) means....
I don't want the meaning Dubey Jee, I'll memorize it....
Chatur has been chosen to present introductory speech on teacher's day
He wrote speech in pure Hindi from librarian Dubey Jee to impress VIRUS,
Hello,
yes, will call,
Chatur, you have a call
Dubey Jee, please keep this print out with you, I'll come back sometime,
ooh, even do that work also...
Hey Dubey Jee!
director sir has remembered you, ya now
ok, you give this to Chatur, I'll come back now
hello, hello
hello Mr.Ramalingam,
yes
ya I'm calling from Lajpat Nagar police station,
Are you from Uganda?
Yes sir,
Hmm. Your life is under risk,
what how?
Umm... Listen to my instructions carefullly
Else when you step out from the college gate
you'll face death in centre of road itself,
Why? What happened?
By the time Chatur recovers from this shock,
Before that Rancho changed a few words in the speech
like.....
Chamathkaar [=miracle] has become Balathkaar [=rape]
Did you call me sir?
who are you?
Dubey the librarian,
I'm permenant sir,
CONGRATULATIONS!!
Um... one min, one min
Commisioner sir's call, hold on,
Excuse me sir...
Take the phone. Take it.
What to say?
Ya ya, where was I?
You were telling, outside gate, my death
Huh! When you go out the gate, you a see a signal in front of you
Traffic signal! Huh okay, okay...
When that signal becomes red,
all vehicle will stop,
okay, okay then
then you cross the road carefully,
you know why son, nowadays' traffic is huge
so if any vehicle hits you or somethin, you might die
what non-sense I know that!
Oh you know that, very good son, then you are safe.
well done, well done.
#......became a fool.......#
Hey SILENCER!!! Dubey has given you this,
Hey you don't call me that CHANCHAD,
CHANCHAD
Director told me that he didn't call me,
He didn't call you, I said that he remembered you!
Idiots...
Respected teachers,
Chief guest minister Shri RD Tripati Ji,
Students and dear friends...
Today if ICE is touching sky high limits,
then the credit goes to only one man
Shri Viru Shastrabhuddi
Give him a hand,
Sir he's saying it...
but every word is mine
he is a great guy, really you are,
for the past 32 years he had continuosly
in this college,
has done rapes after rapes,,,
this means... miracles upon miracles
hope he continues to do so
We're all amazed...
how a person of his age can do these many rapes?
with his extreme self discipline...
he has made himself this capable
right usage of time
attention to details...
Everyone, learn from him,
learn from him, learn from him...
Sit down. Sit down
Today... We're all students here.
Tomorrow, we'll spread across so many countries
I promise you all
Whichever country we visit... we'll rape!!!
We'll enlighten the name of ICE!!!
We'll show everyone,
The capability to perform rape that students have here
No other student across the globe has it!!!
No other student, no other student!
Respected minister..
Namaskar
You have given that thing for this institution....
That we needed the most...
Money money!!!
Tits
Not that.... That means ****
What kind of offensive speach is this?
Everyone has tits...
But keep them for themselves...
Nobody shares...
eeaan eaan???
This guy is too vulgar
You have placed your tits in the hands of this rapist
Now let us see,
What he does with them...
Shastrabhuddi, don't you have so much of brains
Indecent guy...
On this golden occasion, I'd like to quote a shlok...
listen listen... now he'll explain the farting strength gradation in sanskrit
Utthamam dadhdadaath paadam
[ when I fart loudest is at its best (like motor vehicle)... ]
paadam?!? [ =fart ]
ooh Silencer!!!...
Madyam paadam..... tuchuka tuchuk.
[ without full pressure it comes like thuchuka thuchuk (the sound of train) ]
kanishtam thud thudiya paadam
[ with controlled pressure it sounds thud thudi (sound of a sirene)... ]
sur suriiee.... praana gatakam...
[ but the silent ones are breath of life (aka silent killers)... ]
see, without understanding if you cram things,
this will be the result, see see
By cramming, you can save 4 years of your college life..
but for the next 40 years of your life, you'll go on getting raped...
aare yaar, we're explaining him so much..
but still he doesn't seem to get it.
madyam paadam thuchuk thuchuk...
unbelievable yaar....
You done the right point.. Rancho
how fun it was...... hehe
poor fellow didn't had any idea......
hey you hey
you swines..
in what way have I harmed you??
eheh ehe
hey sorry dude don't take it personally,
I'll take it personally,
Chatur Ramalingam is not gonna forget this insult,
I'll think of it every minute,
every sec of my life
dude leave it, acttually we were giving demo for Raju...
that don't cram things and study.
understand and study..enjoy the beauty of science yaar
I'm not here to enjoy...
Then what?... Are you here to rape? Or have you come here to rape science!...tuchuk tuchuk!!
laugh...!!! laugh on my methods..
one day using this methods...
I'll become successful and show everyone
and then I'll laugh... and you'll cry!!
yaar, you're boarding the wrong train again
don't run behind success......
become such great engineer that success follows you...
these ideals don't work in the real world CHANCHAD
You board your train... and I'll board mine
and after 10 years from now... We'll come back to this same station
on this same date,
we'll see whose more successful!!!
you?
or me!
do you dare...?
do you dare...???
then let's bet....tell me
will you come..?
will you come..??
will you come..???
what are you doing yaar?
what has happened to him?!
what is he writing yaar??
don't forget this date...
I'm not used to such expensive gifts, Suhas!
Get used to it Pia.. You're gonna be Suhas tandon's wife!!
Where's the bill man?
I'll be back huh!
You had changed the speech right?... Don't lie!
Ooh... Umm... Yeah.
what problem do you have with my dad, huh?
I don't have any problem with him.
I'm making an inverter on his name... see this
ooh...
broke it!
why are you behind my dad, huh?
because he's not running a college, but a factory.
where donkeys are manufactured every year....
See... See over there... Your donkey
How dare you call him a donkey!!
Then what else should I call him?
First he did engineering... then MBA...
and after that he went to America to work for a bank... heeeh
If he had to work in a bank only, then why did he do engineering?
for such donkeys... life only means profit or loss statement...
he's seeing there's profit being with you, that's why he's with you
you, director's daughter whose gonna be a doctor, it's good for his image etc etc
He has no attachment with you...
what do you think of yourself?
what do you mean by saying Suhas is not interested in me?
aare... you bought new watch?... one minute... hold this
I have to show you demo everytime...
Hey Suhas!
where were you?... I've been looking for you!
she lost her watch yaar... she's searching for it...
what!?!?... You lost the watch???
aare leave it yaar... get a new one
aare it cost 4 lakhs.....
4 lakhs!?!... mine cost only 150 yaar but shows the same time
Oh shut up!
how could you be so careless Pia? This careless attitude is disgusting
It's disrespectful
that was a limited edition watch you just lost!
You got it 4 free... so that's it... Now you wear your 18th century watch at dinner.
what?... what are you staring at?
huh... Now you'll start crying. Real mature Pia
I can't handle this... Now stop crying and search!!
seach for some other hand for this watch... donkey!!!
hey.. You're solid yaar.. You said donkey to him on his face!
get lost!!
yaar it's too much noisy here right..?
she's saying thank you to me, but I hear it as get lost
I said get lost only!
aare yaar, why're you getting so angry?
do you know... actually you never had loved him at all!
what do you mean?
means... whenever he comes in front of you..
have you ever felt like wind is blowing..or dupatta/veil is flying in slow motion??
or the moon looks even bigger in the sky....?
such things only happens in a film, not in real life!
aare no-no..it happens in real life also....if you love a human, it'll happen...
it doesn't happen with donkeys
#.... phone ringing...#
hello!!..ya
what??..
Oh God!!..
ok ok..I'm coming..ya bye bye
hey.. You're a medical student right?
I need your help... It's an emergency. Please, please!
Come with me. Please
aare yaar.. You doctors take an oath that you'll never say no to a patient!
what do you call it: hippocratic oath?
yaar help me yaar... please... it's an emergency... please
You barged into my sister's engagement, you broke my engagement
Dad is taking BP pills because of you
and I'm helping you over here
unbelivable!!
this hippocratics... it has just ruined doctor's life!
aunty, where is Raju?
he's gone to get a taxi... we called for an ambulance two hours ago.
our country is so weird... there is a guarantee for pizza to arrive in 30 mins... but an ambulance!
He must be hospitalised... Urgently!
Hey stop man!
Move..move..move..move
move..move..move..move
Doctor..doctor..  emergency..emergency..
Patient
keep this with you.
Hey Raju
Idiot, you brought dad on a scooter?
Then should I have sent him through a speed-post?
Don't get into my dad's profession!
where?... where is dad?
ask the doctor!!!
this was a close call Pia...
If it would've been late by 2 or 2.5 hours, then we would have lost him
good that you did not wait for an ambulance and got him on a scooter,
I'll go now..if there is any problem..call me ok..bye
Rancho....
Thank you yaar!
Idiot, are you saying thank you to a friend...?
is that Silencer teaching you manners? huh?
Didn't he tell you?... Friendship is the biggest sthan of a human!
Go go.. Now go... You guys have exam tomorrow, right?
aare there are a lot of exams... but dad is mostly only one.
now we'll take the post master sir and go only then!!
Rancho..forgive me yaar..i was frightened!
Enough..enough.sshhh..quiet..quiet
Forgive me.
Enough. Quiet!
Go... meet dad... And don't go with such a gloomy face
Go
Thanks yaar
#..... he was our pal......#
Your Scooty saved a life today... It's nice.
How much is it?
Put chutney and see.
Might be, it'll say
aaaaaaeeeee....
Hey. Happy Independence Day....
But today is not August 15th
But it is so for you. Now you can wear your mom's watch whenever you want!
Nobody will say why have you worn a 18th century watch and all that!
bye
hey
how do you know that it was my mom's watch?
in a sister's wedding. if a girl is nicely dressed head to toe
except for an old watch in the hand, what does it mean?
on that day, you were missing your mom a lot, right?
yes
Your mom must have been very beautiful, right?
yes, how do you know?
have you seen your dad?
life is a race..... if you don't run fast....  you'll be like a broken egg of the cuckoo bird
today we'll teach you how to prepare chutney
this chutney is very useful,
this is not only to have,
but its really useful to understand people too.
now the bad time has gone for you...
now you can leave donkeys and start loving humans
time is perfect for starting love....
temperature is constant... and the climate is clear and clean....
and if you felt love for someone...
sure it's gonna rain on you...
hello... wake up!
what... Uncle passed away or what! what?
no stupid!
its already 8:30.. at 9:00,the exam starts.. You wanna go or not!
aare yaar... how can you leave him alone here and go!
I'm there, doctors are there.. And its only a matter of 3 hours
C'mon... take my scooter and go... Now come on go... it's getting late
hey!!
why have you worn an old watch!
Go!!
sorry sir... we were late... emergency!
settle down there!
sir, they are still writing!
Hello... time up!
Sir... 5 minutes sir. We were half-an hour late!
it was an emergency sir..please please
Examiner looked at us like we asked for both his kidneys!!
but we still continued to write
while he was busy arranging papers according to roll numbers
it's over sir
you're late!.. I can't take your papers
sir, please sir
sir, do you know, who we are?
even if you are prime minister's son, I won't accept your paper!
Sir, do you know our names and roll numbers??
No... who are you guys?
You don't know... then.. run run run run
hey... what's your roll number?
where is it?
where is his paper?
aaaahhh!
today the results were gonna come
scared and innocent!... all were busy striking a deal with God
God... please save me with electronics, I'll break coconuts!
Oh snake-god!... Save my physics... I shall send one litre of milk everyday!
Oh cow-god! Just... just get me passing marks
God. I'll treat Malati and Sangeeta like my sisters. Please save my results
God. God. I'll offer 100RS per month. Surely God! Promise!
Nowadays, traffic constables don't accept 100RS.
As if God would fall for it!
Check... check... check from below... check from below
It's yours yaar. In the last...
and yours?
second last!
and Rancho?
It's not there yaar!
My heart sank,
Not because we were last but because our friend had failed!
Not possible.
It's fine Chatur
There is a mistake!..it's not possible!
This is injustice..injustice..Oh God!!
Why is this idiot Silencer shouting so much?
He has come second...
Idiot... whose first then?
Rancho!
Rancho...idiot..
Move... move yaar
we learnt something about human behaviour that day
if your friend fails, you feel sad!..
but if your friend comes first.. You feel even more sad!
on that day..we were sad..
but there were two more people who were sadder than us
Ranchhoddas Chanchad..first row..right of the director!
Uday Sinha... second row... third seat!
Alok Mittal... second row... fifth seat!
hey!
Sir... is it compulsory to sit acccording to our ranks?
why, do you have any problem?
sir, I have problem with entire grading system itself!
It's like the caste-system sir! A grade students - kings, C grade students - slaves!
it's not nice sir!
do you have a better idea for this?
yes sir, I do have!
results should not be put up on a notice board....
why should we exhibit someone's weakness in front of all?
now sir... if in your blood test, the haemoglobin count is less.,.
will the doctor give you tonic... or put up your report on the TV?
You see sir!?
so basically what you're saying is I must go to each one's room one-by-one and say results in their ears!
You've come first. You've come second. I'm so sorry, you failed!
No sir, I didn't mean that way
but the thing is..grade creates divide..divide
now see..I've come first so I'm sitting with you..
Whereas my friends have come last.
So they are seated in the last row... In a corner
At least they are sitting in a corner now. If they continue being with you,
next year they won't even be in the photo!
neither will they pass, nor any company will give them jobs!
sir, they'll find a job some how sir....
there will be at least few companies..
which hire people and not machines for work!
it's not like that sir..they'll find a job.. I guarentee
Oh.. You guarentee it.. You guarantee it!
You want to bet?
Govind....
if even one among those two get a job in the campus interview..
then shave my moustache!
ok sir!!
happy?
happy sir!
woahhhh!!!!..
by using car's horn.. You wanna hide your horn..idiot!
Idiot... Septic tank... You had the churan again...?
I didn't do it.
Raaaaju!!! huh.....
we've been very used to this hot air from those days..
This idiot is only responsible for global warming!
I can't take it!
Give me..give me your wallet..I'll go and buy a pant!
Leave it yaar..wear this Chatur Ramalingam's suit's pant!
hey don't you touch my suit!
leave it yaar..Rancho will recognise you even without the pant!
hey Mr., where's this address?
brother, if I was so educated... would I be selling groundnuts?
he doesn't know to read
but at least he knows to speak!
brother..here in Shimla..is there any Ranchhodas Chanchad?
yes..yes..he stays over there!
#....he was like the fleeting wind.....#
let's go!
#....like a fluttering kite.....#
#..... where did he go? let find him!......#
oye Chatur..here's is your bottle of churan!
Oh thanks..where did you find it?
it was in the pocket!
hey..how dare you!? That's my pant.
hey, what's yours is mine ... it's written in Gita!
hey shut up... remove the pants
hey what are you doing yaar!..people will misinterpret!
Mad, idiot!
hey leave.
hey I want it now!
what happened?
Rancho's dad!
brother, where can I find Ranchhodas?
he's sitting over there...
thank you...
Rancho
yes
Oh sorry..  we wish to meet Ranchhodas
I'm only Ranchhodas..tel me?
no..Ranchhodas Shyamaldas Chanchad
I'm only Ranchhodas Shyamaldas Chanchad..tell me?
Rancho....take care of yourself!
Ranchhodas Chanchad!!!
Raju!!
yaar..i must be the first man in history who travelled from Delhi to Shimla in underwear that too ..to meet a wrong person!
yaar..the same name..the same degree.. And the same photo
but the person is different..what's the matter!..I'm unable to understand!
but from where did Silencer get Rancho's address?
yes!
oye Chatur!..come here
hey..hey..
how dare you open this..i got this from San Francisco
it's hand-made biscuit..
specially for Mr.Phunsuk Wangdu!
Phunsuk Bangdu... Now who is this?
Wangdu..Wangdu..'W'..'W'...Phunsuk Wangdu..
do you know who that is??
he's a great scientist...400 patents..the world wants him!
I have been chasing him from past one year.. And the meeting has been fixed now!
You know..once he signs a deal with my company..I'll be huge!..huge!
now stop praising this Wangdu and tell us from where did you get Rancho's address?
You should be thanking Phunsuk Wangdu..it's because of him, that I found a clue
see this..my secretary tracey was here last month to arrange a meeting with Phunsuk Wangdu
Tracey couldn't get an appointment with Phunsuk but I got Rancho
I checked Shimla's phone directory..in that the name was..Chanchad Ranchhodas
Then how did his appearance change?
He heard you are coming and got a plastic surgery done or what?
only one man can answer this!
I'm sorry dad.
I couldn't fulfill your last wish!
You kept on telling..take me to Haridwar..take me to Haridwar
but I was waiting for the highway's tender to be opened
the tender opened over there
and you closed your eyes over here!
I'm so sorry dad.
I could not be a good son!
what are you saying yaar?
You have become such a great engineer,
the degree's been put up on the wall
You are a very good son!
how dare you enter my property without my permission, huh?
I'll put you behind bars!
You'll go behind bars, idiot!
we have investigated everything.
on the basis of ICE degree, you're taking these highway contracts and hydro projects
this degree belongs to our friend..how did it come to you?
it's a 150 hectares property..I'll blow off your heads and bury you in a corner.. Nobody will get to know!..
Get the point!.. Now get lost!
I'm taking dad's ashes and going to Haridwar..if you say, I'll even take your bones along with that!
lift the dad!!!!
over there..there there
leave my dad!
aeeeeee..
tell who you are..or else I shall immerse your dad's ashes over here itself
handover dad to me!
dad's ashes won't go to Ganga... they'll go into the gutter!!
aeeee...remove dad from the pot...remove from the pot!
if you press the trigger then I'll press the flush!
see, I'll count till three..that's it!..
hey..whom are you scaring, huh?..shoot!
Raju, put it in!
one..
hey..we'll go to hell but along with that we'll even finish your dad!..got it
two..
then strain-strain and remove your dad using a strainer!
what?
we got the wrong one..this one is empty.
empty???
empty??
empty... I'll empty it!
no no
I'll empty it... I'll empty it... I'm telling you. I'll empty it
noooooooo...hands up!
come on tel..tel, who you are?
aare, I'm Ranchhodas yaa!
aeeeeeeeeeee
No. I swear on dad. I swear on dad. I'm telling the truth yaar!
I'm Ranchhodas... he was Chote!
Chote??????
he was the son of our gardener..
everyone used to call him Chote!
even after his mom-dad passed away...dad let him stay in the house!
he used to do odd house-hold works.. You know
changing bulbs..getting eggs and bread..ironing..like
he was very much interested in studies!
he used to wear my old uniform and get into the school
whichever class he liked. he would go and sit in that one!
I used to take advantage of that..
I used to make him do my homework also
and make him write my exam papers also
I was having a good time!
then one day..
Master Ji saw that a sixth standard child was solving a tenth standard problem
Which class you are in, son? What's your name?
we were caught
Dad was a big man so Master Ji thought it's better to tell him before telling the principal!
You've beginned this..then you only will end it!
the whole himachal salutes in front of me..
but as soon as I turn away....behind my back,
they call me an illiterate!
this won't happen with my son!
he wants education...and me..just..degree
let it continue as it is...make this boy an engineer
Ranchhodas Chanchad's degree..over there..on that wall I want
I went away to london for four years .. And he kept studying in ICE using my name
he had a deal with my dad that after getting a degree from ICE
he won't meet anyone from ICE in his whole lifetime!
he usually said..i won't go meet anyone..but one day two idiots will come searching for me
then what will you do?
he misses you both a lot!
I'll give you the address..
go meet him..
but don't tel my secret to anyone yaar..please!
which secret?
aeeeeeeeeee
sir ji.. You got the wrong glass... big sir is in this
hey what the hell is going on?..
who was that gun man?
aare it's a very complicated story and it is without subtitles
You can't understand...
ignore it..ignore it
where are we going?
ladakh
ladakh?..why??
to meet Rancho!
is he in ladakh?
what he doing over there?
don't know..but this is a school's address!
school teacher..he he he..master ji!
I'm vice-president of rockledge corporation!
and he..A for apple..B for Ball
D for donkey
next week, I'll be signing a multi-million dollar deal with phunshuk Wangdu!
and he..A for apple..B for ball
today, my respect grew even more for that Idiot Rancho!
we all went to college only to get a degree....
if we don't have a degree, we won't have a job!
if you don't have a job, no father will give his daughter's hand
bank won't give credit card, and world won't respect us...
but that idiot came to college, not for the degree but to study!
he wasn't afraid to come last or greedy to come first!
who was the first man to step on the moon?
Neil Armstrong sir!
obviously it's Neil Armstrong, we all know it..but who was the second man?
don't waste your time, it's not important!
nobody remembers the man who ever came second!
after two monthes..26 companies will come to this college to offer jobs to you all!
that means before your final exams,
you'll have jobs on your hands!
this is your last act my friends!
put the medal on the pedal..press the accelerator
go out there and make history
any questions?
yes..
sir, suppose any student gets a job and.....
he fails in the finals by 1-2 marks..
then will the job remain or....?
very good question
is there any other person, in whose mind, the same question is arising?
as expected
please come on stage, everyone give them a big hand..come on the stage..come
come...come..don't waste time!
from past four years, they have been the most consistent students of ICE!
because consistently, they've come last in every exam
come my geniuses..come
if we remove these two people's brains and sell in the market, we'll get a very gud price!
because they are unused brain.. Never have been used!
n to answer to their question
whether they paas or fail, it's not gonna affect their jobs
because they are not gonna get jobs at all!
I guarentee it
their names will be written in gold
FARHANITRATE and PRERAJULISATION!..
give them a big hand please..everybody!
Idiot, he raped completely...
collective rape you know..in front of..in front of everyone!
God...I'll stop eating non-veg..I'll light thousands of incense sticks!
do only one thing..
take away VIRUS from this world!
burn him in hell..
make hot pakkodas of him in hot oil....God..
aeee
are you giving God a contract to kill?
idiot you sit quietly, huh..
idiot every year you sit in the centre with VIRUS and take photo
while we'll be rotting in the side
this year I think we'll be finished out of the photo itself!
aee..
do you know why I come first?
why?
because I'm in love with machines
engineering is my passion..passion
do you know what's your passion?
hey that's my bag..
keep quiet man!
what are you doin, Rancho?
hey..
this is your passion..this..this
go and post this letter..
but what is it?
5 years ago, he had written this letter to his favorite wild life photographer!
Andre Isthawa
ya... Isthawa
he wanted to go to him..go to Hungary and learn work from him!
but fearing his dad, due to Hitler Qureshi, he never posted the letter at all!
aare..quit engineering.. And become a wild life photographer!
do that work which you are talented in!
if Lata Mangeshkar's dad would have told her to become a fast bowler
or Sachin Tendulkar's father would have told him to be a singer.
then think... where would they stand today?!
are you understanding, what I'm sayin?
Idiot..he loves animals but is marrying machines!
ae
baba Ranchhodas..
my girlfriend and wife..both are engineering
then why do I come last...say?
because you are a coward... coward
see this..see his hand..the fingers are less..and the rings are more
one for exam..one for sister's marriage and one for job
aare..if you fear so much from the future.. You think you can live?
and where will you focus on today?
I've got weird friends yaar
one fears and lives..and one idiot..dies and lives!
heyy
but you idiot..do both the things..
You fear also and die also...
ae..i don't fear!
hey..listen
he dies on Pia and fears to tell
aaaaahahaaa...
go go..get lost
it's easy to give free advise dude but difficult to follow it
if you dare..then go and tell Pia..tel
hey from where and all you guys are connecting things..
there's full connection baba
listen to me..listen to me
what I say is..if you go and tell Pia about what you feeling
then even I'll go and tel my dad that I wanna be a photographer..
and don't wanna be an engineer
yes
even I'll remove all my rings and go to give interview
now say
say..do you dare..
baba Ranchodas rolled his tongue back....what will he say?
come..
come...
where... where.?
mmm hmm.. come...
Veeru,
Jay has come Veeru!!!
see..see if there's any dog!
hey cowards...I'm not afraid of anythin....come!
hey you guys get in..if there's any danger outside..I'll give VIRUS alert!
idiot..VIRUS..old man!
hey
shall I give background music?
Pia?
sshhhhh... don't shout..
I'm Ranchhodas Chanchad
listen to me for 2mins then I'll go away
[Raju singing...... on background]
[don't say anythin, don't at all say anythin!..]
Pia,
the 22minutes that I spent with you on the scooter
those were the most beautiful 22minutes of my life!
i can spend the rest of my life on the scooter with you
wow!
#.......everything is still.......#
do you know.. You come on scooter everyday wearing a bride's costume in my dreams!
instead of the veil... takes off your helmet!
and you come near me to kiss me
but that kiss won't happen yaar...
why?
beacuse nose comes in between and then I wake up
nose doesn't come in between, stupid
I'm sorry... I thought you were Pia..
I wish I was
Sister, why did you interrupt in between?
he took 4 years to say this
Pia kiss him and tell him, nose doesn't come in between
you have my permission
kiss him yaar..he's so cute
who is this?
sister
who are you?
Do you know... when you were speaking... he kicked... first time!
He... how do you know it's a he or a she?
Dad had asked the astrologer..
He wanted to know, is an engineer coming home or a doctor?
Means?
Means if it's a boy, then it's an engineer and if it's a gal, then it's a doctor
oye champ.. You stay inside itself..outside there's a lot of circus!
and the circus's ringmaster, your granfather will spin the hunter and say run!
life is a race..run..be an engineer
but you become whatever your heart says
if he scares you too much
keep a hand on your heart and say: AAL IZ WELL!
Hah!... He kicked!
say again, ALL IZ WELL!
ALL IZ WELL!
yes..he kicked..he kicked..Pia
say AAL IZ WELL
ALL IZZ WELL!
goooo...!
you send letter to my dad!....  take this pee-mail freely from us
pigeon..go go go..
pigeon go go go...
pigeon go go go
Who's there?
your coming son-in-law..idiotic VIRUS..and marriage attenders!
Rastogi!!
security..that way..that way!!!
so you all have already learnt about the simple pendulum
now let's get down to the advanced study about compound pendulum
it's an irregular object oscillating about its own axis
let me demonstrate to you
what's this??
pencil
what's inside it?
lead!
good!  lead is the axis to this pencil
even you can be a compound pendulum if you osscilate about
where is Raju Rastogi?
present sir!
hi... everybody is here
good morning sir..
where were you last night?
sir, he was studying sir..he was studying whole night sir!
really?
he hasn't slept since two nights, that's why he's looking like this sir!
what are you sayin!
what were you studyin?
ummmm..
induction motors sir..induction motor..he studied fully sir..induction motor!
in that case, Mr.Raju Rastogi..
yes sir........
can you tel me how an induction motor starts?
brrrrm..
brrrrrrrrrrrrrrr..
brrrrrrrrrr.....
stop it!
brrrrrrrrrrmmm brmmmmm brmm brm
sir..rum!!
Mr.Rastogi, let's have a cup of tea in my office
sir
close the door
do you know how to type?
yes sir
can you type a letter for me?
definitely sir
come sit
sir I'm sorry sir
please type
dear sir,
it is my painful duty to inform you that your son is restigated..
no no sorry..delete it delete it..go back!
ur son Mr.Raju Rastogi
is restigated from the IMPERIAL COLLEGE OF ENGINEERING!
come on..type type..come on..go on
dad will die sir....
please type
sir, please sir
my decision is final and irrevokable!
he's living only in a hope that he could see me becoming an engineer sir!
you could've thought of this before you pissed in front of my doors...
sir give me one more chance sir, please... just one chance
sir please sir
ok..remove your name from the letter
and put Ranchodas Chanchad's name!
I know he was with you last night!
be my witness and I won't remove you from the college
you have 7.5 minutes with you..to think
#......we won't let you go .......#
#.......we shall not let you leave.......#
#.......even if God might summon you.......#
#.....but we are not the one who fear him.....#
#.....we are standing here in this ground with resolve.....#
#.....take out our eyes from our pal....#
#.... No matter how hard you try.....#
#....we're not gonna let you leave lik this.....#
#......we won't let you go .......#
#.......we shall not let you leave.......#
Rancho, look at that monitor
Raju!
the body is paralyzed due to the shock
but the mind is alert
he can see us and hear us!
please aunty, don't cry in front of him!
talk to him normally.. motivate him.. crack jokes.. keep him happy
oye Raju, we have a good news yaar
dad is become proper yaar.... that new medicine worked!
it's Rastogi family's tradition that..
if one man gets up... the other man will lie down!
C'mon, c'mon... get-up now
your dad is asking for Pia's scooter?
what do you say?... shall I give it?
won't he bang it?
hey Raju, Farhan wants to tell you something
on the webcam..live from the hostel!
see this..Virus has cancelled your suspension..problem solved
c'mon...wake up at least now!
everything is solved...
oye..are you listening....hey
Rastogi!
see this..mom bought a new saree.. New saree
brand new
it costs 2000 bucks son... see
at least get up now... idiot
not one..she bought ten sarees..ten!
see
oye Raju
Raju..tel me, how do I look?
hey..kammo
have you heard about kammo?
aare, kammo's marriage has been fixed
and that too..without any dowry!
hey..bridegroom..the bridegroom doesn't want maruti 800
doesn't want anything..wants kammo..only kammo..
huh...
And do you know who's the bridegroom?
yes
who's the bridegroom?
guess it
You know him very well
huh...
he loves animals a lot
huh?!
and ..and he's gonna be a wild life photographer!
hey keep quiet!..keep quiet!
didn't flash??
aare, it's our Farhan yaar!
as if our Farhan will take dowry from you ppl!
aare, our Farhan will marry your sister..Farhan!
and that too..free..free..free
hey..hey..
hey..hey Raju
Raju
if we would have given 1 kilo lady's finger and 1/2 kilo paneer freely to that idiot
even then he would get up
what was the need to sacrifice me?
well done yaar..well done well done
everything is fixed.. Your sister's marriage is fixed
Farhan will marry..ok done!!!
Rancho!!..
idiots..how much will you lie??
You are saved..idiot!!
did you call for a taxi?
I have called for it,... it's waiting
thank you...
why?
I have to go 4 a job interview
Oh..so you gonna go with me?
no..I'll drop you home and I'll go for the job interview!
Idiot...why will I go home?
did you forget?..
we had promised something to this idiot!
give..give me your tie!
why?
give it..i don't think after reading this, you'll be able to go for the interview!
what is this?
it's a letter
It came for you. From hungary!
it's some photographer..Andre Isthawan!
idiots.. You posted my letter?
he liked your photos very much..he's become crazy!
he wants to make you his assistant!
He has called you to work in the Brazilian rainforest for one year!
He's saying he'll even give you salary!
Dad won't oblige!
Go to him. And make him understand lovingly.
Don't fear today Farhan.
Otherwise after 50yrs when you'll be old and fallen in the hospital...
and be waiting to die
You'll think then. letter was in the hand. taxi was at the gate.
if I had dared a little bit. life would have been something else!
what do you think, will he like it?
what was the need to get such an expensive one!
today, son is getting a job
now the days to put our head up and roam wid pride are arriving and you are being stingy! huh?
aare Farhan?
Farhan, today was your interview, right?
I didn't go
i don't wanna be an engineer dad!
what happened? You had an an accident?
sir... Umm...
that building in front sir.
I had jumped from its third floor sir!
why?
because I was restigated!
sir I had pissed on director's door when I was in a drunken state...
that devil Rancho is still playing with your brain?
I can't understand engineering...even if I'll be...I'll be a very bad engineer dad!
Rancho tells a very simple thing.
whatever you enjoy doing, make that your profession!
then work won't seem work but a game!
aare..how much will you earn in that jungle?
dad, stipend isn't too much but I'll get to learn a lot!
after 5 years, when you'll see your friends buying a car
then you'll curse yourself!
I'll be frustrated being an engineer,
then I'll curse you throughout my life!
Dad, it's better I curse myself, right?
aare..people will laugh!!
they'll say that you came till final year and had quit!
That Kapoor sir told me that you're lucky that your son is studying in ICE!
what will he think?
Kapoor sir didn't get AC fixed in my room!
making me sleep comfortably...he himself didn't sleep in heat!
making me sit on the shoulders...Kapoor sir didn't take me around the zoo!
you did all that dad!
what you think, makes a difference!
what Kapoor sir thinks, it doesn't make a difference to me!
aare... I don't even know his first name!
have you watched a film and come...
are you performing drama?
stop it now. poor guy is tensed!
God forbid, if he commits something like Raju!
then the discussion is only over!
don't say anything to son or else he'll jump from the terrace!
no dad... I won't commit suicide.
I promise!
That Rancho,
whom you call a devil.
he forcibly made me put yours and mom's photo in this!
he started saying that....promise me....that whenever such stupid thoughts come to your mind!
see this photo and think what will happen to this smile when they see your dead body!
dad, I wanna convince you.
but not by hanging this suicide's sword on your head!
what will happen.... huh?
If I'd be a photographer... then I'll earn less, right? Home will be small, car will be small!
But dad, I'll be happy...
I will be really happy!
Whatever I do for you. I'll do it from my heart!
Till today... I have listened to whatever you said, today... just once... let me listen to my heart!
Please dad!
Dad... Don't go... Please!
Return this one..
Son, how much will your professional camera cost?
Will we get it against this laptop?
If it costs more money, then ask me son
Go... Go son... Live your life
Your marks are consistenly poor... any particular reason?
Due to fear... I was a bright student since childhood
parents thought that it will abolish our poverty!
I started to fear!
when I came here.. I saw that there's a race,.. if you don't come first, no one will recognize you
I started to fear even more!
fear is not good for grade, sir!
I started wearing more rings... praying more
not only praying... I started begging to God
Give me this, give me that!
16 bones broke, I got two months to think..then I understood!
sir, today I haven't told God... that get me this job
I just folded my hands. And said thank you for this life
If you guys. If you guys even reject me today, then I don't have any regrets
Because I believe..I'll somehow do something worthy with my life sir!
see..this very much frank behaviour of yours is not good for our company!
we need a diplomatic person to handle the clients
and you are way too straight forward!
but..if you assure us that you can control this attitude of yours..
then..something can happen!!!
sure
after breaking both the limbs, I learnt to stand on my feet sir,
with great difficulty, I got this attitude in me!..it can't happen sir!
you keep your job, I'll keep my attitude
I'm sorry..don't mind sir!
stop
I've been recruiting from the past 25years.. conducted a lot of interviews
to get the job.. people find yes in our yes itself!
from where have you come yaar?
Sir... I?
how much salary will you take brother? let's discuss
thank you sir.
thank you
Oh Emperor...
you're great
accept out gift...
Govind...!!!
sir you only said if they get a job,
remove your moustache...
huh, what have you done?
he eh ehehehheehheeeehhe
I'm feeling like someone undressed me
humiliated me....
I won't let you conquer, Rastogi
you gonna get a job only when you pass in final exams,,,,
but this time I'm gonna set the paper for exam...
dad
that's not fair
everything is fair in love and war...
and this is world war 3
Rastogi you're gone this time...
hehe heheheee
what are you doing here?
easy easy...
you're drunk?
ya yaar, had to take two,  four...
two... four?
two or four?
I was in need of dareness...
for what?
to steal this...
what is this?
a duplicate key of VIRUS's office
sshh ssshh sshhhs
questions papers are in the red sealed envelope...
dad has set by himself...
to fail Raju in exam.
take it out...
mad or what?
this is cheating yaar... no..
everything is fair in love and war
eeheh eheheh
ok... just tell me one thing,
do you really feel...
nose comes in between if wanted to kiss?
hmmm...
ey have this dhokla... hold this,
you Gujrati people are too cute yaar, but why does your food sound so dangerous?
Dhokla, phaphda, handhwa, thepla, kakkrah
It seems as though they are some missiles!
come... come on
Tonight Bush dropped two dhoklas... 400 killed, 200 injured!
come on..
aare
I can bear with khakrah, phaphda
but this name of yours
Ranchhodas Shyamaldas Chanchad!
yack!!
I won't change my surname after marriage, huh?
Pia, we can't get married
why?
do you love someone?
no
are you gay?
then why don't you propose me?
are you impotent?
then prove it..prove it
Pia..I'm not..
hey stop stop stop stop!
aare, what happened?
aare, we haven't informed Pia at all!
Oh stop now..my bladders are bursting!
Oh shut up yaar!
are you in touch with her?
no yaar
but I have her landline no.
then dial it, I'll stop..
ya..stop stop stop
hello!
no place to piss in this country?
hello..ya..is Pia there?
she's not there sir
ok..where will she be availiable?..in the hospital?
Sir, why would she go to hospital today? It's her marriage today!
she's gone to manali!
Pia marriage is over!
it's not yet over..see, it's a 6 hour's way..if we speed up, then we'll surely reach before the marriage vows!
what do you say?
now if you have already thought about it partner, then take a u-turn!
ae, no u-turn...straight to Ladakh...we'll meet Rancho and come back...
Friday, I have a meeting with Phunsukh Wangdu
come...come...sit in the car
If I miss it, you know what will happen!
The Japanese will get in.
They are offering him a first name in the company
Phunshuk and Fujiashi. Profit hearings are.
Pia weds Suhas!
and thanks for the suit, huh!
yaar... Virus will suffer a heart attack
hello, hello
whenever his daughters are getting married, we come off to ruin it!
ok listen. I'll handle Pia. you pull out the price-tag!
Farhan!
we found Rancho, Pia!
Is it for 107?
Yes sir!
Give it here.
How much time do you take yaar?
Sorry sir...
Come on... go
house-keeping sir!
come in!
more..more..amore
quick quick iron my sherwani!
aare, we found Rancho..still, will you marry this donkey?
you're mad, Farhan!
don't fool yourself Pia!
you love Rancho even today.. and eating these dhoklas remembering him!
more..more..amore
he's a dog's tail..put it inside a pipe for 12years.. when you remove it..it'll still remain bent!
Shut up Farhan. Suhas is the changed man!
now he never talks about brands and prices!
My 1.5lakh worth sherwani!!!
why do you people eat chutney???
sir I'll do something sir!
what...what will you do?
sir...sir...we get such shirts and sherwanis everyday in our laundry sir!
I'll clean it within 2minutes sir!
sir..one minute sir!
get it soon!
but it's too late now, Farhan!
Pia...Pia...come, it's getting late! Come on.
Pia. I'm Raju. Don't shout, people will kill me
where is Suhas?
aare, he had come from house-keeping. he took away the sherwani!!
Go inside. And send Suhas
The hymns are going on Pia. If I get up and go then all will be furious yaar!
yes Farhan, tell me
car is ready at the gate
I'm telling..take Pia and run!
aare don't move yaar
sir?
sherwani?
you are here?
yes
whose taking the vows over there?
vows?
if the vows get over..then our marriage will be over..I'm already married Pia..let's go!
there are so many people over here..all of them will laugh!!
aare, because people laugh... so will you suicide?
aare..Rastogi?
Pia.. people will gossip for two days and forget it!
but today if you do this marriage..you never forget that car was at the gate!
we had come to take you to Rancho..but only because you feared from people
you got married to this donkey!
house keeping?
yaar Pia..there is a small..minor tension.
what?
we don't know if Rancho's married or not?
what!
aare, I wouldn't have happened yaar. it wouldn't have happened!
and if it would've happened?
then we'll drop you back!
aare, don't take tension. have this biscuit
hand-made biscuit from San Francisco
Idiot,,,.
from where did he come?
ignore it..ignore it..
you eat the biscuits..eat..
it's very good
AAL IZ WELL... AAL IZ WELL!
Till yesterday I was a noble citizen of this country
but in the last 24hours. I had got an emergency landing of a plane
almost immersed Shyamalda's soul in the gutter
and kidnapped a bride from her wedding
all for that idiot Rancho
but even that idiot gave out his heart for his friends
he had entered Ravan's territory, to steal a question paper for Raju
search for a red sealed envelope
ok come...
he was very afraid..that if Raju failed, he'll again go and do a high-jump!
but even we were very principled robbers!
we had sweared that we'll steal the paper oly for Raju...we won't even see it ourselves!
aare yaar, where has he hidden it?
aare yaar, searching like this, it'll be good morning
Rancho, ask Pia
where are you, since then I'm calling you?
Pia, your phone
give it to me, one minute Pia...Pia
Jiju..when we say AAL IZ WELL..it kicks!
it kicked
you heard?
Pia, your phone
we got it..Rancho..
hello?
aare at least call me sometimes!
make its copy..make its xerox copy..quick!
take it
keep it wherever we got it from...
carefully!
oye where had you been???? huh?
huh??
take this...
what is it?
enjoy...
question paper...
VIRUS's had set by himself to make you fail in exam....
weird friends I've got...
teaching how to live straight forward first....
then making me do things that are odd...
no..today..
if I pass, it'll be on my own ability!
otherwise it's okay if I fail!
Idiot!
idiot won my heart! My heart said I'll make this idiot my brother-in-law
um.. um... then I controlled my emotion!
go..go..
no sir no sir please..
you had come to change the system!
You'll piss on my door
bloody rascals
sorry sir
you are restigated, if you aren't gone by morning. I'll call the police
I'll call the police
rascals..rascals all of you!
how did he get my office's key?
I gave him the keys dad
I wish I had given it to my brother
he would have been alive today..
stop it Pia
what do you think?..brother, fell off the train and died?
shut up Pia
you decided that he'll be an engineer.....
did you ever ask him, what he wanted to be?
how much you pressurised brother, dad..
he thought it's easier to die than to give an entrance exam!
what is she saying?
dad, you go into the room!
you get into your room!
Pia stop it..what are you doing Pia?..I'm telling you right..
brother wanted to study literature..he wanted to be a writer
but he couldn't write anything more than this suicide note!
Pia, hide that letter..please!
till when will I hide it sister?
once
only once if you would have told him
if you can do engineering then quit it!
do whatever you like!
then today brother would have been alive, dad!
he cannot suicide
you're right dad, it wasn't a suicide...
it was a murder!
in many areas..the roads are immersed in water..their is total traffic jam!
Dad..
dad!!..
Mona....
aare, I told you to go back right? then why are you coming behind us?
why..is this your mom's road?
please help..we are desperate here! is there only one ambulance in the city?
get an ambulance from some other hospital!
the whole city is immersed in water, sir
we can't do anythin!
no..Pia..that..
hey Mona..what happened?
Rancho..Pia!
Rancho, it's impossible to reach over here.... so do as I say!
you guys are not understanding!..get water bags..drive fast!!.. You're not underst.......
they disconnected!
Monaa!
be careful..be careful
turn on the light..turn on the light!
table..table..table-tennis table
Raju,  switch on the webcam!
yaa
ya Pia..
hello Raju..where is sister?...show me!!
ya..hold on hold on
don't worry.. hold on
see this Pia
sister, everything will be alright! I'm near you..ok?
Pia I'm dying.
Rancho, when there were no hospitals and doctors in this world even then babies were born...
you guys will carry on sister's delivery
aaaaa
aal iz well.. aal iz well..
how dare you...???
what are you guys doing?
dad, don't come in between..please stay out of this ok!!
Farhan, you go get towels and scissors....
Millimeter, get cloth drying clip and hot water....
Rancho you cover sister...
sister.... push
push..push..come on..
push....
keep quiet..I'm unable to push
Rancho, see if crowning is happening?
crowning means?
go get that diagram
Rancho, see if the head is coming out
come on Rancho..quickly
Gooooooo
Go go go..go Rancho..go..come on
No. No crowning. It's not coming. No
sister.. please push
Mona..
Mona
she's tired Pia..
wake her up
if she doesn't push, then it'll be a big problem
vacuum cup has to be put, Pia
from where will they get a vacuum cup over there...
what is a vacuum cup?..how does it look?..what do they do with it?
I'll show u
if the mother gets tired and is unable to push then this cup is put on the baby's head
suction pump creates vacuum and this cup sticks on the baby's head
then the baby is pulled out
i can make this..i can make it
how?
vacuum cleaner sir..
vacuum cleaner??..
yes sir..vacuum cleaner
but vacuum cleaner's pressure is too much Rancho
I'll control the pressure
is there a vacuum cleaner over there?
it's there in my office
Farhan go soon and get it from sir's office
take the key
Mona..push Mona..come on push
what happened?
ya Pia
hello Raju what happened?
the light is gone Pia
Oh God! Now how will the vacuum cleaner work
Farhan, you get the vacuum cleaner and I shall get the light..
how?
Millimeter..get Virus out..fast come on
come Virus..get out..get out
aare not this Virus yaar.. my Virus, the inverter that I had made
that?
go get that soon
Oh ok, that one... I understood!!!
Raju..wake everyone in the hostel
and tell them that we want car battery, wires, tool kit and vaccuum gauge.. come on
come out..there's an emergency in the common room
where is Rancho?
sir sir sir..here sir
everyone keep the batteries over here..comeon..quickly!
and the wires
Raju.. turn off all switches and connect this inverter to main...
take this
Rancho, vacuum cleaner...
Farhan.... that camera cleaning thing..what do you call it?
plower..plower..go and get it soon
Rancho, take this plower
pull the vaccuum and put it on the pipe..over here!
Rancho..it's done!
is every swiches off?
now turn on only TT table's and computer's light!
Raju, turn on the computer..fast!
help me..connect this..put it in this!
Pia..come soon..Pia..come soon
love you Rancho
Farhan..on it
yes
Pia, how much must the suction be?
not more than 0.5 Rancho
Farhan..0.5
cover up
yes
0.5
ok
delivery using vacuum cleaner..i haven't seen this in 20 yrs of my career!
Farhan..off it..
yeah
Raju, get on the table..see me
push the baby down like this..like this
Farhan, turn it on..
come on sister....push.. You can do it!
come on Mona..push..come on
think abt champ..for champ..come on
come on Mona..Mona push
it's coming..it's coming
come on sister....you can do it
Farhan..turn it off..
ya ya. I turned it off
put two clips..and cut the umbical chord
Farhan, get two clips..fast!
put it on the umbical chord and get scissors
careful careful
get the towel..towel
Pia..Pia,,,why isn't it cryin?
huh?..
hey
hey champ
Rancho rub is back
no.. Nothing is happening..
blow air into its mouth..
come on..
come on champ
nothing is happening
Quiet Mona, quiet
say all iz well..  say aal iz well
it kicked
what!!!
say aal iz well..  all iz well
all iz well
yeah!!!!
at that time if VIRUS would have said that his grandson would have been an engineer... I would have raped that idiot!
but when that idiot opened his mouth, then a miracle happened!
solid you kick.. will you become a footballer or what?
become..become whatever your heart says
stop....where are you going?..
I'm not finished with you,
on the first day of college, you had asked me a question....remember?
that why don't they use a pencil in the space.
if the tip of the pencil breaks in the space, then it will be revolving under the action of gravity
it can get into someone's eyes, it can get into someone's nose
it can get into the instrument panel.
you were wrong... you were wrong
you cannot be right all the time!
you understand?
yes sir
this was a very important invention... you understand?
my director had told me....
when any extraordinary student comes...
go go go... go study...
pass in the exams and go away from here...
and now student of the year.. Ranchhodas Shyamaldas Chanchad
sir..one photo sir!
i wanted to capture all these memories in my camera and take it with me!
on that day, everyone were hugging each other, getting emotional and making promises
that we'll stay in touch, we'll surely meet up once in a year!
who knew that we were seeing Rancho for the last time?
yaar, untie him!
I'll sue you all in american court!
Raju.
this kinda school... only can be made by that idiot Rancho!
but where is he?
see there..
go in creatures... go
don't piss over here...
you want a beating, huh?
aaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaa
ha ha ha..
we got him.... that idiot is some where around.. come on
brother, where will we find Ranchhodas?
is his name Ranchhodas!!!
Rancho
Chote..Chote..Chote
aare, whats his name ultimately?
aare, cool down.... cool down
come with me..
where.. where is Rancho?
Rancho..Rancho
Farhan, do you know.....he has read every book written by u!!..see this
Raju.... he reads your blogs everyday!
he tells the children about your research very proudly!
do you remember your helmet Pia sister?
it was stolen right?
who are you?.. and how do you remember all our names?
didn't you recognize me?
no
how will you recogzine.. now that millimeter has become centimeter!
oye oye oye..idiot..what centimeter? you have become kilometer!!!
but what are you doing over here?
for the first time, I got a letter on my name.. I found a train ticket from that
it was written inside that if you wanna study then board the train!
and I boarded it..
idiot Rancho..
where is that idiot?
Furjee.. take this and go!!!
you come in my dreams everyday on a scooter wearing a bride's costume !
instead of the veil..  you take off your helmet!
and you come near me to kiss me!
aaaaaaah..ouch!
couldn't you say and go?
ummmm.. No..
ummmm...sorry
did you get married?
what?..what?..
no... you?
almost, idiot!
then?
then what?
do you love someone?
hmm..
ya
who?
you..!
did you see, the nose doesn't come in between, stupid!
yes, that's right!
idiot Rancho!
hi, Farhan!
aare keep your hi to yourself!
aare listen to me!
no, you listen to me
aare..you listen to me..listen to me,
no,you listen to me, I'll explain everything
hey Raju
idiot!!
look here...
aeee.idiot
hit him..hit him two-three from my side as well
because of you, what all I had to become..you know?
this idiot got glasses!
come.. getup idiot.. getup
ha ha eh ehhe hehhhee
hey idiot!
having fun idiots?
hey.. hi Chatur
Ranchhodas Chanchad.....
Namaste masterji
where have you reached?..you have become a teacher in the village, eh?
A for apple..  B for ball
we boarded the bus together right
but your train went away in reverse
straight to primary teacher from engineering
ha ha ha ha
whats the salary Chanchad?..tell me..Rs 5000, huh?
for me, they are like 100 $
my son's pocket money is more than your salary
hey stop this non-sense
he used to do non-sense.. he wanted to change the education system
he wanted to change the world
now he changes children's diaper over here!
will you break his teeth or shall I do it?... Idiot
Hey, let it be!
Do you remember? I told you.
One day you'll cry and I'll laugh
Hehehe hahhaa
Sign over here. Accept it. That you lost and I won!
The declaration of defeat. Unbelivable yaar. Chatur, unbelivable
Hey, that is Virus's pen
How did you get it? You stole it?
Umm.. Now what shall I say yaar?
This is for winners, not losers
No problem. If you have any difficulty in school and need a donation
Do call my assistant, eh!
Ha ha ehe he e
A for apple. B for ball
He hasn't changed at all yaar
yaar..ignore it,..ignore it!
leave him yaar..he'll keep saying anything
leave it..the good news is your name is not Ranchhodas Chanchad
imagine.... after marriage I would be Pia Chanchad!
yack
by the way, whats your real name?
Phunshuk Wangdu
Wangdu?
Pia Wangdu?
no.. means you are a scientist?
that means you have 400 patents in your name?
i won't change my surname after marriage
means you are Chatur's Wangdu?
are the japanese looking for you?
i don't like Wangdu! I think so...
yaar tell me one thing.. are you a scientist or a teacher?
I'm a scientist but I also teach children
means you are the phunshuk Wangdu??
yes man..yes
oye Silencer.. hey Chatur comeback!
stop stop stop
take van, huh? ehhehe hehe
he won't stop that way!..   I'll stop him!
Mr.Wangdu.. I can't believe you called!
I'm sorry Mr.Chatur but I can't sign a deal with your company!
what sir, what happened sir?
aare how shall I sign yaar.. you took away my pen!
he heh ehehe
what pen sir?.. I did'nt get you
the one that's in your hand.. Virus's pen!!
Virus's pen??
Mr.Wangdu?
ya tell me Chatur!
A for Apple..B for Ball.... L for lucky!
ehhe ehhee
yaar, he has been raped!!
eh ehhehee
you got me..
you got me Rancho
I mean Mr.Wangdu. Totally flowd me. Good one
I hope our personal problems are not gonna affect our deal....
hey Chatur..over here..here
I was just joking yaar.. I knew it from within that you'll do something in life!
no.. you're lying?
no no no no.. I'm telling you.. I swear
Rancho 100..Chatur zero
you win, I lose.. you don't believe me
aare yaar
Oh Emperor, you are great.. accept the gift
I'll give you a free advice Mr.Wangdu... run!!
run run...
hey Rancho.. I'll lose my job yaar... I have small-small kids
baba Ranchhodas used to say rightly
kids.... be self-efficeient.. self-efficient
then success will come behind you
Original subtitles by roliekgeorge@yahoo.com
Corrections & sync by Radu108