What crime did you commit?
The accidental killing
of a person, sir.
He brutally murdered a woman
in furtherance of theft.
Fourteen years, sir.
Excellent.
He's enterprising...
...aggressive...
...outgoing...
...young...
...bold...
...vicious.
He'll do.
Fine.
We could still look at C-block.
No, no. That's enough.
He's perfect.
I want his records sent to me.
This vicious young hoodlum...
...will be transformed
out of all recognition.
Thank you very much
for this chance.
Let's hope you make
the most of it, my boy.
- Shall we go to my office?
- Thank you.
Come in.
Sir!
655321. Sir!
Very good, Chief.
Over to the line.
Toes behind it.
Full name and number
to the governor.
Alexander DeLarge, sir.
655321, sir.
I don't suppose you know who
that was this morning.
That was no less a personage
than the Minister of the Interior.
The new Minister of the Interior.
What they call a very new broom.
These new ridiculous ideas
have come at last.
And orders are orders...
...though I may say to you
in confidence, I do not approve.
An eye for an eye, I say.
If someone hits you,
you hit back, do you not?
Why should not the state,
severely hit by you hooligans...
...not hit back also?
The new view is to say "no."
The new view is that
we turn the bad into good.
All of which seems to me
to be grossly unjust.
Shut your filthy hole, you scum!
You are to be reformed.
Tomorrow you will go
to this man, Brodsky.
You will be leaving here.
You will be transferred to
the Ludovico medical facility.
It's believed you'll be able to
leave state custody in a fortnight.
I suppose that prospect
pleases you?
Answer the governor's question!
Yes, sir.
Thank you very much.
I've done my best here,
I really have, sir.
I'm very grateful
to all concerned, sir.
Sign this where it's marked.
Don't read it, sign it!
It says you're willing to have
your sentence commuted...
...to submission to
the Ludovico treatment.
And this.
And another copy.
The next morning I was taken to...
... the Ludovico medical facility...
... outside the town center.
I felt a malenky bit sad...
... having to say goodbye
to the old Staja...
... as you will, when you leave
a place you've gotten used to.
Right, halt the prisoner.
Good morning, sir.
I'm Chief Officer Barnes.
I've got 655321...
...on a transfer from Parkmoor
to the Ludovico Centre, sir.
Good morning.
Yes, we've been expecting you.
I'm Dr. Alcot.
Dr. Alcot.
Very good, sir.
- Are you prepared for the prisoner?
- Yes, of course.
I wonder if you'd mind signing
these documents, sir.
There, sir.
And there, sir.
And there.
There you are.
Prison escort, move forward!
Halt!
Excuse me, sir.
Is that the officer who will
take charge of the prisoner?
A word of advice, doc.
You'll have to watch this one.
A right brutal bastard he has been,
and will be again...
...in spite of all his sucking up
and reading the Bible.
We can manage things.
Show the young man to his room.
Right, sir. Come this way, please.
- Morning, Charlie.
- Good morning, Doctor.
Good morning, Alex.
My name is Dr. Branom.
I'm Dr. Brodsky's assistant.
Good morning, missus.
Lovely day.
Indeed, it is.
May I take that?
- How are you feeling?
- Fine, fine.
Good. In a few minutes
you'll meet Dr. Brodsky...
...and begin your treatment.
You're a very lucky boy
to have been chosen.
I realize that,
and I'm very grateful.
We're going to be friends,
aren't we?
I hope so, missus.
What's the hypo for?
Sending me to sleep?
Nothing of the sort.
- Vitamins will it be, then?
- Something like that.
You're undernourished, so after
each meal we'll give you a shot.
Roll over on your right side.
Loosen your pajama pants
and pull them halfway down.
What exactly is the treatment here
going to be, then?
It's quite simple, really.
We're going to show you some films.
You mean like
going to the pictures?
Something like that.
That's good.
I like to viddy
the old films now and again.
And viddy films I would.
Where I was taken to, brothers...
... was like no cine
I ever viddied before.
I was bound up
in a straitjacket...
... and my gulliver was strapped
to a headrest...
... with wires running away from it.
Then they clamped, like,
lid-locks on me eyes...
... so that I could not shut them,
no matter how hard I tried.
It seemed a bit crazy to me...
... but I let them get on with
what they wanted to get on with.
If I was to be a free malchick
again in a fortnight...
... I would put up with much
in the meantime, O my brothers.
The first film was a very good,
professional piece of cine...
... like it was done in Hollywood.
The sounds were real horrorshow.
You could slooshy the screams
and moans very realistic.
You could even get
the breathing and panting...
... of the tolchocking malchicks
at the same time.
And then what do you know?
Soon our dear old friend...
... the red, red vino on tap...
... the same in all places...
... like it's put out
by the same firm...
... began to flow.
It was beautiful.
It's funny how the colors
of the real world...
... only seem really real...
... when you viddy them
on a screen.
Now, all the time
I was watching this...
... I was beginning
to get very aware...
... of, like, not feeling
all that well.
And this I put down
to all the rich food and vitamins.
But I tried to forget this,
concentrating on the next film...
... which jumped right away
on a young devotchka...
... who was being given
the old in-out, in-out...
... first by one malchick...
... then another.
Then another.
When it came to
the 6th or 7th malchick...
... leering and smecking
and then going into it...
... I began to feel really sick.
But I could not shut me glazzies.
And even if I tried to move
my glazzballs about...
... I still could not get out of...
... the line of fire
of this picture.
Get me up.
I'm going to be sick.
Get something for me to be sick in!
Very soon now,
the drug will cause the subject...
...to experience
a deathlike paralysis...
...together with deep feelings
of terror and helplessness.
One of our early test subjects
described it as being like death.
A sense of stifling or drowning.
And it is during this period,
we have found...
...the subject will make
his most rewarding associations...
...between his catastrophic
experience, environment...
...and the violence he sees.
Dr. Brodsky is pleased with you.
You've made
a very positive response.
Tomorrow there will be two
sessions, morning and afternoon.
You mean I have to viddy
two sessions in one day?
I imagine you'll feel a bit
limp by the end of the day.
But we have to be hard on you.
You have to be cured.
It was horrible.
Of course it was horrible.
Violence is a very horrible thing.
That's what you're learning now.
Your body's learning it.
I just don't understand about
feeling sick the way I did.
I never used to feel sick.
I used to feel the very opposite.
Doing it or watching it,
I used to feel real horrorshow.
You felt ill this afternoon
because you're getting better.
When we're healthy,
we respond to the hateful...
...with fear and nausea.
You're becoming healthy,
that's all.
By this time tomorrow,
you'll be healthier still.
It was the next day, brothers...
... and I had truly done my best...
... morning and afternoon
to play it their way...
... and sit like a horrorshow
cooperative malchick...
... in the chair of torture...
... while they flashed nasty bits
of ultra-violence on the screen...
... though not on the soundtrack,
the only sound being music.
Then I noticed,
in all my pain and sickness...
... what music it was
that, like, cracked and boomed.
It was Ludwig van.
Ninth Symphony, fourth movement.
Stop it! Stop it!
Please, I beg you!
It's a sin!
Sin?
What's all this about sin?
That!
Using Ludwig van like that.
He did no harm to anyone.
Beethoven just wrote music.
Are you referring
to the background score?
You've heard Beethoven before?
So you're keen on music?
Can't be helped.
Here's the punishment
element perhaps.
The governor ought to be pleased.
I'm sorry, Alex.
This is for your own good.
You'll have to bear with us
for a while.
But it's not fair.
It's not fair I should feel ill...
...when I hear lovely,
lovely Ludwig van.
You must take your chance, boy.
The choice has been all yours.
You needn't take it
any further, sir.
You've proved to me all this
ultra-violence and killing...
...is wrong, wrong
and terribly wrong!
I've learned me lesson, sir.
I see now what I've
never seen before.
I'm cured. Praise God!
You're not cured yet, boy.
But, sirs.
Missus!
I see that it's wrong!
It's wrong because
it's, like, against society.
Because everybody has the
right to live and be happy...
...without being
tolchocked and knifed!
No, no, boy.
You really must leave it to us.
But be cheerful about it.
In less than a fortnight now,
you'll be a free man.
Ladies and gentlemen...
...at this stage, we introduce
the subject himself.
He is, as you will perceive,
fit and well-nourished.
He comes straight from a night's
sleep and a good breakfast...
...undrugged...
...unhypnotized.
Tomorrow we send him out with
confidence into the world again...
...as decent a lad as you
would meet on a May morning.
What a change is here,
ladies and gentlemen.
From the hoodlum
the state committed...
...to unprofitable punishment
two years ago.
Unchanged after two years.
Unchanged, do I say?
Not quite.
Prison taught him the false smile,
the rubbed hands of hypocrisy.
The fawning, greased,
obsequious leer.
Other vices it taught him...
...as well as confirming him in
those he had long practiced before.
Our party promised
to restore law and order...
...and to make the streets safe for
the ordinary peace-loving citizen.
This pledge is now
about to become a reality.
Ladies and gentlemen,
today is an historic moment.
The problem of criminal violence
is soon to be a thing of the past.
But enough of words.
Actions speak louder than.
Action now.
Observe all.
Our necks are out
a long way on this, Minister.
I have complete faith in Brodsky.
If the polls are right,
we have nothing to lose.
Hello, heap of dirt.
You don't wash much, do you,
judging by the horrible smell.
Why do you say that?
I had a shower this morning.
He had a shower this morning.
You trying to call me a liar?
No, brother.
You must think I'm awfully stupid.
Why did you do that, brother?
I've never done wrong to you.
You want to know why I did that?
Well, you see...
...I do this...
...and that...
...and this because I don't like
your horrible type, do I?
And if you want
to start something...
...you just go ahead.
Go on!
Please do!
I'm going to be sick.
You're going to be sick, are you?
Please let me get up.
You want to get up?
Well, now you listen to me.
If you want to get up...
...you've got to
do something for me.
Here.
You see that?
You see that shoe?
I want you to lick it.
Go on!
Lick it!
And, O my brothers,
would you believe...
... your faithful friend
and long-suffering narrator...
... pushed out his red yabzick
a mile and a half...
... to lick the grahzny,
vonny boots.
And again!
The horrible killing sickness
had whooshed up...
... and turned the joy of battle...
... into a feeling
I was going to snuff it.
And again.
Nice and clean.
Thank you very much.
That will do very well.
Thank you very much,
ladies and gentlemen.
She came towards me...
... with the light, like it was the
light light of heavenly grace.
And the thing that flashed
in me gulliver...
... was that I'd like to have her
there on the floor...
... with the old in-out,
real savage.
But quick as a shot
came the sickness.
Like a detective who 'd been
watching around the corner...
... and now followed
to make his arrest.
Enough!
Thank you very much.
Thank you, my dear.
Not feeling too bad now, are you?
No, sir.
I feel really great, sir.
- Good.
- Was it all right, sir?
Did I do well?
Fine, my boy.
Absolutely fine.
You see, ladies and gentlemen...
...our subject is impelled
towards the good...
...by paradoxically
being impelled towards evil.
The intention to act violently...
...is accompanied by strong
feelings of physical distress.
To counter these,
the subject has to switch...
...to a diametrically
opposed attitude.
Any questions?
Choice!
The boy has no real choice, has he?
Self-interest.
The fear of physical pain...
...drove him to that
grotesque act of self-abasement.
Its insincerity
was clearly to be seen.
He ceases to be a wrongdoer.
He ceases also to be
a creature capable of moral choice.
Padre, these are subtleties.
We're not concerned with motives,
with the higher ethics.
We are concerned only
with cutting down crime.
And with relieving the ghastly
congestion in our prisons.
He will be your true Christian...
...ready to turn the other cheek.
Ready to be crucified,
rather than crucify.
Sick to the very heart at the
thought even of killing a fly.
Reclamation.
Joy before the angels of God.
The point is that it works!
And the very next day,
your friend and humble narrator...
... was a free man.
Son!
Hi, hi, hi there, my Pee and Em.
Mum.
How are you, love?
Nice to see you.
- Dad.
- Lad. What a surprise.
- Good to see you.
- Keeping fit?
How are you, then?
I'm fine, fine.
Keeping out of trouble, you know.
I'm back!
Good to see you.
Why didn't you let us know
what was happening?
I wanted it to be, like,
a big surprise for you and Pee.
It's a surprise, all right.
A bit bewildering too.
We've only just read about it
in morning papers.
You should have let us know, lad.
Not that we're not very pleased
to see you again, and all...
...cured too, eh?
That's right.
They did a great job on me.
I'm completely reformed.
Still the same old place, then?
There's a strange fellow
sitting on the sofa...
...munchy-wunching
lomticks of toast.
That's Joe.
He lives here now.
The lodger.
That's what he is.
He rents your room.
How do you do, Joe?
Find the room comfortable, do you?
No complaints?
I've heard about you.
I know what you've done.
Breaking the hearts of your
poor, grieving parents.
So you're back, eh?
Back to make life a misery for
your lovely parents once more?
Over my dead corpse, you will.
Because, you see, they've let me
be more like a son to them...
...than like a lodger.
Don't go fighting here, boys.
Do put your hand
over your mouth, please.
It's bloody revolting.
Are you all right?
It's the treatment.
It's disgusting.
Enough to put you off your food.
Leave him be, Joe.
It's the treatment.
Do you think we ought
to do something?
Would you like me to make you
a nice cup of tea, son?
What have you done
with all me own personal things?
That was all...
...took away, son.
By the police.
New regulation, see...
...about compensation
for the victims.
What about Basil?
Where is my snake?
He met with...
...like, an accident.
He passed away.
What's going to happen to me, then?
I mean...
...that's my room he's in.
There's no denying that.
This is my home also.
What suggestions have you,
my Pee and Em, to make?
All this needs thinking about, son.
We can't very well
just kick Joe out.
Not just like that, can we?
I mean...
...Joe's here doing a job.
A contract it is.
Two years.
We made, like, an arrangement.
Didn't we, Joe?
You see, son...
...Joe's paid next month's
rent already...
...so whatever we may do in
the future, we can't just say...
...to Joe to get out, now can we?
No, but it's much more than that.
I mean, I've got you two
to think of...
...who've been like
a father and mother to me.
It wouldn't be right for me
to go off and leave you two...
...to the tender mercies
of this young monster...
...who's been like
no real son at all.
Look, he's weeping now.
But that's all his craft
and artfulness.
Let him go and find
a room somewhere else.
Let him learn the errors
of his way, and that a bad boy...
...doesn't deserve such a good
mum and dad as he's had.
All right.
I know how things are now.
I've suffered and I've suffered...
...and I've suffered.
And everybody wants me
to go on suffering.
You've made others suffer.
It's only right
that you should suffer proper.
I've been told
everything you've done...
...sitting around the family table.
And pretty shocking
it was to listen to.
It made me real sick,
a lot of it did.
Now look what you've gone
and done to your mother.
Come on. It's all right now.
Right!
I'm leaving now.
You won't ever viddy me no more.
I'll make me own way.
Thank you very much. Let it lie
heavy on your consciences.
Now don't take it like that, son.
Can you spare some cutter,
me brother?
Thanks, brother.
Jamey Mack!
May the hokey fly!
Mother of God and all the blessed
saints in heaven preserve us!
I never forget a face, me God!
I never forget any face.
Leave me alone, brother.
I've never seen you before!
This is the poisonous young swine
that near done me in.
Him and his friends.
They beat me and kicked me
and punched me.
Stop him! Stop him!
They laughed at me blood
and me moans, this murderous dog!
Then there was like
a sea of dirty, smelly old men...
... trying to get at
your humble narrator...
... with their feeble rookers
and horny old claws.
It was old age
having a go at youth.
And I daren 't do a single
solitary thing, O my brothers.
It being better
to be hit at like that...
... than want to sick
and feel that horrible pain.
All right, all right!
Stop it now!
Come on. Stop breaking the
state's peace, you naughty boys!
Back away! Go away with you!
What's your trouble, sir?
Well!
Well, well, well!
If it isn't little Alex.
Long time no viddy, droog.
How goes?
It's impossible.
I don't believe it.
Evidence of the old glazzies.
Nothing up our sleeves.
No magic, little Alex.
A job for two
who are now of job age.
The police.
Come on, Alex.
Come for walking.
Come, come, come,
my little droogies.
I just don't get this at all.
The old days are dead and gone.
For what I did in the past,
I've been punished.
I've been cured.
That was read out to us.
The inspector read it
all out to us.
He said it was a very good way.
But what is all this?
It was them
that went for me, brothers.
You're not on their side,
and can't be.
You can't be, Dim.
It was someone we fillied with
back in the old days...
...trying to get his own revenge
after all this time. Remember?
A long time is right.
I don't remember them days
too horrorshow.
And don't call me Dim
no more, either.
Officer, call me.
Enough is remembered, though,
little Alex.
And this is to make sure
you stay cured.
That's enough.
A bit more. He's still kicking.
Cured, are you?
Be viddying you some more
sometime, droogie.
Where was I to go,
who had no home and no money?
I cried for meself.
Home, home, home.
It was home I was wanting.
And it was home
I came to, brothers...
... not realizing,
in the state I was in...
... where I was
and had been before.
Who on earth could that be?
I'll see who it is.
Yes, what is it?
Please...
Frank, I think this young man
needs some help.
My God!
What's happened to you, my boy?
And would you believe it,
O my brothers and only friends...
... there was your
faithful narrator...
... being held helpless
like a babe in arms...
... and suddenly realizing
where he was...
... and why "home" on the gate
had looked so familiar.
But I knew I was safe.
I knew he would not remember me.
For in those carefree days...
... I and my so-called droogs...
... wore our maskies, which were
like real horrorshow disguises.
Police.
Ghastly, horrible police...
...they beat me up, sir.
The police beat me up.
I know you!
Isn't it your picture
in the newspapers?
Didn't I see you
on the video this morning?
Are you not the poor victim
of this horrible new technique?
Yes, sir.
That's exactly who I am and
what I am, sir. A victim.
Then, by God, you've been
sent here by providence!
Tortured in prison, then
tortured by the police.
My heart goes out to you.
You're not the first to come here.
The police like to bring
their victims to this village.
But it's providential that you...
...who are also another kind
of victim, should come here.
But you're cold and shivering.
Julian...
...draw a bath for this young man.
Certainly, Frank.
Thank you very much.
God bless you.
He can be the most potent
weapon imaginable...
...to ensure the government
is not returned in the election.
The government's big boast, sir...
...is the way they have
dealt with crime:
Recruiting young roughs
into the police...
...proposing will-sapping
techniques of conditioning.
We've seen it before
in other countries.
The thin end of the wedge.
Before we know it, we'll have the
full apparatus of totalitarianism.
This young boy is a living witness
to these diabolical proposals.
The people, the common people,
must know, must see.
There are traditions of liberty to
defend. That tradition is all.
The common people
will let it go, yes.
They'll sell liberty
for a quieter life.
That is why they must be led.
Driven. Pushed.
Fine.
Thank you very much, sir.
He'll be here.
I'm singing in the rain
Just singing in the rain
What a glorious feeling
I'm hap-hap-happy again
I'm laughing at clouds
So dark up above
The sun 's in my heart
I'm ready for love
Let the stormy clouds chase
Everyone from the place
Come on with the rain
I've a smile on my face
I'll walk down the lane
Good evening, sir.
Good evening.
It was very kind of you
to leave this out for me.
There was no one around,
so I started.
Hope that's all right, sir.
Of course.
Food all right?
Great, sir. Great.
Try the wine.
Thank you, sir.
Cheers.
Happy days.
Won't you join me?
My health doesn't allow it.
No, thank you.
"1960, Château...
...Saint-Estèphe.
Médoc."
Very good brand.
Very good...
...color, sir.
Smells nice too.
Very nice little number.
Here's to it.
Very refreshing, sir.
Very refreshing.
I'm pleased you
appreciate good wine.
Have another glass.
My wife...
...used to do everything for me
and leave me to my writing.
Your wife? Is she away?
She's dead!
I'm sorry to hear about that.
She was very badly raped, you see.
We were assaulted by
vicious young hoodlums...
...in this very room
you're sitting in now.
I was left a helpless cripple,
but for her the agony was too great.
The doctors said
it was pneumonia...
...because it happened later,
during a flu epidemic.
The doctors told me it was
pneumonia, but I knew what it was.
A victim of the modern age.
Poor, poor girl!
And now you.
Another victim of the modern age.
But you can be helped.
I phoned some friends while
you were having your bath.
Some...
...friends?
They want to help you.
- Help me?
- Help you.
- Who are they?
- Very, very important people.
And they're interested in you.
This'll be these people now.
I don't want to trouble you
any further. I should be leaving.
No trouble at all.
Here.
Let me fill your glass.
So this is the young man.
How do you do, sir?
Missus.
I'm very pleased to meet you.
I hope you forgive us for coming
at this hour...
...but we heard you
were in trouble...
...and so we came over to see
if we could help.
Very kind of you, sir.
Thank you very much.
I understand you had a rather...
...unfortunate...
...encounter...
...with the police tonight.
Yes, I suppose
you could call it that.
How are you feeling now?
Much better, thank you.
Feel like talking,
answering a few questions?
Fine, sir. Fine.
As I said, we've heard about you.
We are interested in your case.
- We want to help you.
- Thank you very much.
Shall we get down to it?
Fine. Fine, sir.
The newspapers mentioned...
...in addition to being conditioned
against acts of sex and violence...
...you've inadvertently been
conditioned against music.
I think that was something
that they didn't plan for.
You see, missus...
...I'm very fond of music.
Especially Beethoven.
Ludwig van Beethoven.
- B-E...
- It's all right, thank you.
And it just so happened that
while they were showing me...
...a particularly bad film
of, like, a concentration camp...
...the background music
was playing Beethoven.
So now you have
the same reaction to music...
...as you do to sex and violence?
No, missus. You see, it's not
all music. It's just the Ninth.
You mean Beethoven's Ninth Symphony?
That's right. I can't listen
to the Ninth anymore at all.
When I hear the Ninth, I get, like...
...this funny feeling.
And then all I can think about
is, like, trying to snuff it.
- I beg your pardon?
- Snuff it. Death, I mean.
I just want to die peacefully...
...like, with no pain.
Do you feel that way now?
No, sir, not exactly.
I still feel...
...very miserable.
Very much down in spirits.
Do you still feel...
...suicidal?
Put it this way:
I feel very low in myself.
I can't see much in the future.
I feel that any second, something
terrible is going to happen to me.
Well done, Frank.
Get the car, would you, please?
I woke up...
... the pain and sickness
all over me like an animal.
Then I realized what it was.
The music coming up
from the floor...
... was our old friend,
Ludwig van...
... and the dreaded Ninth Symphony.
Let me out!
Open the door!
Come on, open the door!
Turn it off!
Stop it!
Please!
Turn it off!
Suddenly, I viddied
what I had to do...
... and what I had wanted to do.
And that was to do myself in.
To snuff it.
To blast off forever,
out of this wicked, cruel world.
One moment of pain, perhaps...
... and then sleep.
Forever and ever...
... and ever.
I jumped, O my brothers...
... and I fell hard.
But I did not snuff it.
If I had snuffed it...
... I would not be here
to tell what I told have.
I came back to life
after a long, black, black gap...
... of what might have been
a million years.
He's recovered
consciousness, Doctor.
Hello, lad.
Hello, son.
How are you?
You feeling better?
What...
...gives...
...O my Pee and Em?
What makes...
...you think...
...you are welcome?
There, there, Mother.
It's all right.
He doesn't mean it.
You were in the papers again, son.
It said...
...they had done
great wrong to you.
It said...
...how the government...
...drove you to try...
...and do yourself in.
And when you think about it, son...
...maybe it was our fault too...
...in a way.
Your home's your home...
...when all's said and done, son.
- Good morning.
- Good morning, Doctor.
- How are you feeling today?
- Fine.
Good. May I?
- I'm Dr. Taylor.
- Haven't seen you before.
I'm your psychiatrist.
Psychiatrist!
Do I need one?
Just part of hospital routine.
Are we going to
talk about me sex life?
I'm going to show you
some slides...
...and you're going to tell me
what you think about them.
Jolly good.
You know anything about dreams?
Something, yes.
- You know what they mean?
- Perhaps.
You concerned about something?
No, not concerned, really...
...but I've been having
this nasty dream.
Very nasty.
It's like...
...when I was all smashed up,
you know...
...and half-awake
and unconscious-like...
...I kept having this dream.
All these doctors were
playing around with me gulliver.
You know, like the inside
of me brain.
I seem to have this dream
over and over again.
Do you think it means anything?
Patients with injuries like yours
often have dreams of this sort.
It's all part
of the recovery process.
Now then, each of these slides
needs a reply...
...from one of the people
in the picture.
You tell me what you think
the person would say...
...all right?
Righty-right.
"Isn't the plumage beautiful?"
I just say what the
other person would say?
Don't think about it too long.
Say the first thing
that pops into your mind.
Cabbages. Knickers.
It's not got a beak.
Good.
"The boy you always quarreled with
is seriously ill."
My mind is a blank...
...and I'll smash your face
for you, yarblockos.
Good.
"What do you want?"
No time for the old in-out, love.
I've just come to read the meter.
Good.
"You sold me a crummy watch.
I want my money back."
You know what you can do with
that watch? Stick it up your ass!
"You can do whatever
you like with these."
Eggiwegs.
I would like...
...to smash them.
And pick them all up...
...and throw...
Fucking hell!
There. That's all there is to it.
Are you all right?
Hope so.
Is that the end, then?
I was quite enjoying that.
Good. I'm glad.
How many did I get right?
It's not that kind of a test.
But you seem well on the way
to making a complete recovery.
When do I get out, then?
I'm sure it won't be long now.
So I waited...
... and, O my brothers...
... I got a lot better...
... munching away at eggiwegs
and lomticks of toast...
... and lovely steakie-wakes.
And then one day...
... they said I was going to have
a very special visitor.
Just wait outside for a moment,
would you, Officer?
I'm afraid my change of schedule
has thrown you.
The patient's in the middle
of supper.
That's quite all right, Minister.
No trouble at all.
- Good evening, my boy.
- Hi there, my little droogies.
How are you getting on, young man?
Great, sir. Just great.
Can I do anything more for you?
I don't think so, Sir Leslie.
Then I leave you to it.
Nurse!
You seem to have a whole ward
to yourself, my boy.
Yes, sir.
And a very lonely place
it is too...
...when I wake up in the night
with me pain.
Anyway, good to see you
on the mend.
I kept in touch
with the hospital, of course.
And now I've come down
personally...
...to see how you're getting along.
I've suffered the tortures
of the damned.
Tortures of the damned.
Yes, I can appreciate that
you've had an extremely...
Oh, look. Let me help you
with that, shall I?
I can tell you that I, and the
government of which I'm a member...
...are deeply sorry about this,
my boy. Deeply sorry.
We tried to help you.
We followed recommendations
that turned out to be wrong.
An inquiry will place the
responsibility where it belongs.
We want you to regard us
as friends.
We put you right.
You're getting
the best of treatment.
We never wished you harm.
But there are some who did, and do.
And I think you know who those are.
There are certain people who wanted
to use you for political ends.
They would have been
glad to have you dead...
...for they thought they could then
blame it on the government.
There is also a certain man...
...a writer of subversive
literature...
...who has been howling
for your blood.
He's been mad with desire
to stick a knife into you.
But you're safe from him now.
We put him away.
He found out that you
had done wrong to him.
At least he believed
you had done wrong.
He formed this idea in his head
that you had been responsible...
...for the death of someone
near and dear to him.
He was a menace.
We put him away
for his own protection.
And also for yours.
Where is he now?
We put him away
where he can do you no harm.
You see, we are looking
after your interests.
We are interested in you.
When you leave, you'll have no
worries. We'll see to everything.
A good job on a good salary.
What job and how much?
You'll have an interesting job at
a salary you regard as adequate.
Not only for the job
you're going to do...
...and in compensation for what
you believe you have suffered...
...but also because
you are helping us.
Helping you?
We always help our friends,
don't we?
It is no secret
that this government...
...has lost a lot of popularity
because of you, my boy.
There are some who think that at
the next election we shall be out.
The press has chosen to take
a very unfavorable view...
...of what we tried to do.
But public opinion
has a way of changing.
And you, Alex...
...if I may call you Alex...
Certainly.
What do they call you at home?
My name is Frederick.
As I was saying, Alex...
...you can be instrumental
in changing the public's verdict.
Do you understand, Alex?
Do I make myself clear?
As an unmuddied lake, Fred.
As clear as an azure sky
of deepest summer.
You can rely on me, Fred.
Good.
Good boy.
I understand you're fond of music.
I have arranged a little
surprise for you.
Surprise?
One that I hope
that you will like...
...as a...
...how shall we put it...
...as a symbol of
our new understanding.
An understanding
between two friends.
I was cured, all right!
English Subtitles by
Gelula/SDI