- You were saying something.
- Yes
- Yes?
- I was speaking from my heart...
Actually I...
- What is it?
- I...
From quite some time now...
Two minutes.
- Miss Raveena!
- Doctor!
- You were saying something.
- Yes, about my stomach...
...no!
About my heart.
- Are you okay, doctor?
- Should I call a doctor?
- He was speaking his heart.
- Heart?! Yes? What was that?
- I'll tell her later.
- Let me listen, too. Go on!
- Let me go!
- Please speak.
- You'll break her heart!
- Let it break!
- Speak up, will you?
Speak up now or it'll be too late.
- It's late, anyway!
- Go away...
- You're fine, I hope.
- Absolutely! What can happen to me?
Where did this road-block materialize from?
The name is Crime Master Gogo!
I play with eye-balls as if they were marbles.
Where's your boss, Teja?
He ran away with my money!
- We don't know!
- We don't know, I swear!
- Get down!
- Why?
I must steal something since
I've come. It's family business!
I'm Mogambo's nephew...
Gogo!
Gogo's stunts are incredible, aren't they?
This was your idea, wasn't it you rascal?
To please Karisma in order to
know more about Raveena?
Exactly! Did she tell you
something about Raveena?
What could she tell me?
Whenever I ask her about Raveena,
she gives me a cold stare.
Karisma has fallen in
love with you, sonny boy...
...and deep down in your
heart, you care for her, too.
Yes, that's true.
But how did you know?
You're crazy! Do I want to be
a Cook by marrying Karisma?!
- Want to return to Bhopal then?
- Oh no.
I will not concede defeat so soon.
This story will take a new
turn after the Intermission.
Only I will get married to Raveena!
- Where are you, Doctor Khurana?
- Hide! Quickly!
Here's a blanket!
- Who were you talking to?
- To myself.
- Who will listen to my woeful tale?
- I will...
- No!
- All day, all night...
...without batting an eyelid.
I will listen and listen...
I will... tell you the story some
other day. Now I must...
...prepare the patient's medicine.
- Why do you love him so much?
Love? If I could help it,
I would strangle him!
- What does that mean?
- I mean...
...I'd thrust the medicine down
his throat. So, he'd recover.
Where's the noise coming from?
What are you boiling?
It's my pain, actually!
There's pain there and here, too.
Everybody's under pressure.
What can one do?
Cure Tilu soon, so that we can
have some party and music.
Madam loves music a lot, anyway.
- Madam likes music, eh?
- Yes.
Raveena likes it?
Listen to it then!
EROS
This poison is extracted
from a scorpion, Robert.
Mix just two drops in somebody's drinks...
...the one who drinks it,
turns blue and then yellow.
What happens after that, sir?
After that he sleeps the
slumber of death forever.
- Economical and trusted.
- It must be effective, too?
It looks as if it's used on animals!
- Yes. On buffaloes.
- Buffaloes!
Hold him tight, Miss Raveena.
- I don't want it.
- But I must give it!
Remember, this poisoned drink is for Raveena.
I'll give it to her, sir.
I don't want it!
Leave me!
Let him give you the injection.
It's for your own good.
Do that again... run your
hands on my cheek, please!
It's coming back... my memory's returning!
- Your memory?!
- Do it again, please...
It's here! It's back!
Thank you, Miss Raveena!
I feel like...
I can't control my joy!
I don't know what I'm doing!
You understand, don't you?
You do?!
It's a miracle!
A miracle!
To celebrate this, give your
servants gifts on my behalf!
Give them a bonus and a day's holiday!
- We normally do this.
- You do?
I'm Amar Singh, son of the
landlord of Bhevnagar, Vikram Singh!
I have only two hobbies; hunting and soccer.
- I used to be a champion!
- Really?
I used to play for Mohan Bagan!
He's getting even crazier!
I must give him this injection!
Hey, doctor! Just take your fees and get lost!
He's really gone mad, Madam!
You're a servant, yet you climb
sofas and even call me mad, eh?
You are mad!
If you had recovered, the doctor
would have known. Right, doctor?
The patient first knows
whether he has recovered!
Try to understand, Madam...
You've changed colors ever
since the doctor has arrived!
Haven't you changed, too?
Is he the one being treated or is it you?
At this rate, you'll be a patient too!
It's Robert's birthday.
On this happy occasion, he
has prepared a special drink.
It's called the
"Drink of the Heavens"
You may present the drinks, Robert.
You didn't tell me it was my birthday.
Take this glass.
Please, sir...
Cheers for Robert's birthday
and to my regained memory!
You think we'd really believe
you've regained your memory?
- What proof do you have?
- Proof? Idiot!
I remember everything!
I was a champion at football!
I even remember that historic match of 1988...
...when I scored six consecutive
goals for Mohan Bagan!
Let me show you how.
I was positioned here...
...and here was the
wicket-keeper of the opposition.
The goal-keeper, idiot!
This is soccer!
- Give me your glasses. Quick!
- Our glasses? Why?
- Come on!
- Here you are.
Strange servants this house has!
Your glasses! Climbs the sofa, insolent girl!
May I have your glass, too, Miss Raveena?
Let her finish her drink!
- Okay, you have it.
- No, I don't want it.
- Go ahead. It's your birthday!
- It's okay... play your game.
As I had the ball with me,
I was surrounded...
...I was here and there, there and here...
...left and right, fooling everyone of them...
...they kept running helter-skelter.
Making them dance, I approached...
...maneuvering my way to the goal-keeper...
I made the goal-keeper dance, too...
And then... GOAL!
Do you have your proof now?
Do you believe me? Yes!
- Here are your glasses.
- 'Our' glasses?
- Here are yours.
- No, thank you.
Strange servants. They now
refuse to take it! Take the glasses!
Good... it's very good.
Why aren't you people drinking?
Go ahead. It's very good!
Don't show your teeth.
Drink it!
It's my birthday, Madam.
I'll drink last.
He's insulting you, Miss Raveena!
- What was that, Bhalla?
- I'll drink it, Madam.
Now... you drink.
There's something fishy here.
Go on, drink it!
Drink it!
Swallow it! Go on!
You'll get a blow! Swallow it!
I knew something of this sort would happen.
If we go on like this, we'll be
made the 'game' one day!
I've got great satisfaction!
Sorry, sir.
We made a mistake.
That younger boy...
Please don't worry, Mr. Teja.
Till when will the prey escape the lion?
According to my new plan...
What kind of people have you employed, Teja?
They wear suits worth Rs. 10,000 but
don't possess brains worth 10 paise!
You'll end up in a heap, if
you keep such company.
You'll have to do something on your own, Teja!
Stand on your own two feet.
Start now, Teja!
You both can't do a thing.
I think I'll have to deal with you now.
There's a fair being held
at Fort Mayavi tomorrow.
Both these girls will go to the fair, too.
They will be killed there.
Very good.
But I will come to the fair, too.
I'll deal the cards henceforth.
But those two jokers...
what's to be done with them?
They both are destined to die at my hands.
According to the plan...
Hurry up, Miss Raveena. There's
a time to get to the temple.
Only then are you granted your wish.
What are you looking back for?
Don't mention that inauspicious name now.
- Let's go, 'Uncle"...
- Well, my son...
...where are you taking your sister?
Sister? Are you blind?
Let's go!
Okay, sit down.
- Take my hand, dear.
- Yes, he's an old man.
What's the matter, dear?
Where's the glow of your face?
Maybe you had to accompany
someone else and are not!
O God! You and your ways!
Grapes for an ape!
You dare call her an ape?!
No, son...
I called her the grape...
Grape?! That's a nice fruit.
You can move a little, dear.
Don't touch her! Let's go!
Old ass!
Thinking of your father, son?
Let's go...
We'll go... from the presence of everybody else!
The rose fell off!
Get it back for her, son.
We're getting late.
I'll get you another.
What a shame!
Had the rose fallen off from my wife's hand...
...I would have leapt after it!
Shame on the youngsters of the day!
- I'll get it.,
- Sit down.
You'll take ages!
Let's go!
Hey, old man!
Where are you taking her?!
EROS
- You're very much 'that'.
- What?
- 'That'.
That!
'That', eh?
'That' I am.
The love-birds are here,
but where are my guys?
- Where were you?
- We fell asleep, sir.
- Where's the gun?
- I have it, sir.
Here it is.
- What's this?
- This is Vasco Da Gama's gun.
Which 'Mama' (Uncle)
It's Vasco Da Gama's gun.
You don't have to aim with this.
Just imagine the guy and fire... it finds its target!
Let me take a look, Sir.
What was that?
What do you think went wrong?
That's life, pal...
You win some, lose some.
It's all part of the game.
Hadn't I asked you to return?
That you couldn't win here?
Just think; there's such a difference
between you and Raveena.
You need looks and luck to
marry such a wealthy girl.
You lack both.
I know very well...
...the broken heart, affects the brains, too.
Look what I've got.
Rum to drive away sorrows...
Have this tonight, to lessen
your burden of sorrow.
But don't get hooked; it affects your liver.
I've got something to talk to you about.
Go upstairs. I've no time.
Talk to Prem.
You're misunderstanding me.
I don't talk to servants.
Good-bye.
I want to say something to you, Prem.
But that shouldn't affect our relationship.
Relationship? What relationship?
You're a strange girl!
I'm not what you think I am.
- Meaning?
- I'm not Karisma.
What difference does it make?
If not Karisma, you could be
Jamila, Shakila, Sunita or Papita...
...whatever you are, my boat has capsized!
You see, that
Raveena is not Raveena...
...she's me and I'm her.
You are not you, it's her...
...she's not her, she's you.
You are not you and she's not her.
Am 'I' what I am, or not what I am?
Who am 'I'?
Idiot! I'm Ramgopal Bajaj's
daughter, Raveena Bajaj.
She's our accountant
Harishankar's daughter, Karisma.
- What?!
- Yes.
We had swapped names.
I wanted a boy to love me, and not my wealth.
And that love...
I've found in your eyes, Prem.
Really?
I have never liked India.
Even my friends used to tell me this.
"Amar, you're not made for this country"
"You should be elsewhere"
It's good that you came from
abroad and like a jeweler...
...recognized a diamond.
Otherwise, the people here
are, well... like Indians.
They could never know my true worth.
I've been trying to tell you...
You're trying to say that after
marriage we'll stay in London.
That we will have to do.
To handle the huge business
empire of your father...
...I'll have to stay in London.
You want to share your joy.
I believe in that, too.
Excuse me...
The evening shall be spent in our name.
The champagne and dinner for the
evening, for all of you, is on us!
Applause!
- How's that possible?
- You see, I can understand you.
Poor chap.
I think he's drunk everything.
It happens...
...a broken heart affects the brains.
Now, what can be done?
I tried to make him understand.
To return to Bhopal.
That nothing was possible here.
But he wouldn't listen.
- Now listen Amar...
- It's too late.
The poor chap's youth will
be spent in an asylum.
- Why don't you understand, Amar!
- Please explain, Raveena.
I'm not Raveena, I'm Karishma.
She's Raveena Bajaj.
She's Ramgopal Bajaj's only heir.
I'm his accountant,
Harishankar's daughter.
I did all this at
Raveena's instructions.
Prem... is not crazy.
He's dancing in glee.
Raveena must have told him the truth.
Prem has won what you badly wanted.
I have no wealth, Amar.
I have nothing.
It's good that we took this route, isn't it?
Or Gogo would have held us!
How was the idea?
- Where's your boss, Teja?
- We don't know.
Why do you always harass us because of him?
I won't spare him.
I'll have his eye-balls for marbles!
- I want my money!
- You'll get your money!
Teja's brother is bringing
diamonds from London.
He'll sell the diamonds and pay you off!
- I don't want the money.
- Good.
I want the diamonds!
- Get down!
- Why?
I'll steal something, since
I'm here! It's family business!
Mogambo's nephew, Gogo!
He took our scooter the last
time and our bicycle now...
...and the next time...
Did you see that?
Gogo's gimmicks?!
He's not at the bus-stop
and not at the tea-shop...
- Where have you been?
- Why? What's wrong?
Nothing yet...
But she went away crying.
Who?
Which Raveena?
The one who was first
Raveena and is now Karisma?
Is it the one who pretended to be the servant?
Or is it the one who
pretended to be money-bags?
- 'Your' Raveena!
- What happened to her?
She went away crying.
She said she'd commit suicide.
- What are you saying?
- Read it.
- Where did she go?
- There.
What's wrong?
Why are you screaming?
What happened?
I almost died!
What does this mean?
What have you written?
What's wrong with that?
I really came here to die...
...but I found it a bit too high.
I'll jump from down below.
It'll hurt less.
- What nonsense is this?
- What's my life to you, anyway?
Your love for me wasn't real in any case.
Look Raveena... I mean, Karisma...
Look at me...
Look into my eyes.
Does my love seem fake to you?
I admit I had come to enact a farce.
But I've really fallen in love with you.
Whoever you are, however you are... I love you.
Your friend has hurt my friend's heart.
If something happens to her...
...I'll never forgive you!
- But Karisma...
- Not Karisma, Raveena!
My friend talks a lot, but he's a nice chap.
He'd never hurt your friend.
She's gone to end her life!
What about that?
- Nothing.
- What?
Amar could even con the
God of Death and bring Him here.
They'll be here any moment, arm in arm.
- Where were you?
- She went to end her life.
She wanted less height.
I brought her back.
- Didn't I say, Karisma...
- What did you say?
- It's very confusing!
- Oh yes, it is!
This is a great problem.
We're not concerned with
what your real names are...
...your names will be what
we have always called you!
At least meet Amar and Prem once, Dad.
We've known them well.
They're one in a million.
They're not only handsome,
but able and sensible too.
It's 8 'O Clock.
Where's my newspaper?
Everything should be done at its time.
- Prem is a very good man.
- Amar's good at heart.
- They're wonderful.
- Intelligent.
- Handsome, wise...
- Good-hearted...
Where's my tea?
There's a time for everything.
I've been hearing about them since I've arrived.
Nobody seems to be asking about me.
Call them at 7 tomorrow.
Is it time for the sugar, sir?
Listen carefully or you could ruin everything.
- Uncle speaks little.
- Hears little, too.
- Is he deaf?
- Don't talk nonsense with him.
- Don't be quiet out of fear, okay?
- What's there to fear?
It's a matter of love.
Of getting married...
...we marry at home with
consent; in the temple without it...
- Right?
- I thought so too.
Put your hands down.
You're three minutes late!
Do you know the value of three minutes?
One can finalize deals worth
crores in that much time!
I had reserved six minutes for you.
Three minutes for you to
speak and three for me.
You've lost your three minutes;
Now only listen...
Amar and Prem...
...full of purity and devotion.
Your names had suggested that you
were glamour-struck vagabonds.
But you're useless parasites, too.
While you do certainly
look like illiterate bums...
...you proved to be greater fools when you...
...thought I'd agree to this match.
My three minutes are not up.
I've brought up these girls with
a lot of love and affection.
But I think they need medical help...
...because they've chosen rascals like you.
Pull the finger out of the mouth and get lost!
- What happened?
- What else?
He tried to throw his weight
around and started bragging.
About his achievements and status.
I told him that we were not
concerned with whatever he was!
It's for you to see, as to how we are!
Quiet!
He was absolutely quiet!
He really felt that what
I had said made sense.
- Tell them what I said, too.
- Oh yes!
His spirits also rose, when he
saw me. What's that you said?
I shut him up! I gave 2 answers
for each of his question.
There was one question, and two answers...!
It was only questions and
answers and then... silence!
A long silence...
You should do something to win his respect.
For instance, suppose Ramgopal
Bajaj gets into some problem...
...and you rescue him!
He himself is the 'problem'!
What problem will be get into?
Bloody Hitler!
Just suppose the old man gets kidnapped...
...and the two of you risk your lives to save him!
Won't both of you be heroes then?
Is that a marriage-plan or a death-trap?
He's talking about risking lives!
We won't risk our lives!
Who'll kidnap him anyway?
We will kidnap him.
We'll ask for a ransom of 5 lakhs,
but you come and rescue him!
Isn't the problem solved?
Very simple!
The man's a real 'clock', sir!
He has things planned for every single second!
You should call him the HMT
instead of Ramgopal Bajaj!
- So you're Teja's goons, eh?
- Not I, sir, it's him!
- It's him...
- He brought me here!
You work for him and even lie about it!
We work for him? Oh no!
He's a first-rate rascal, sir!
Let's go the Police Station, sir...
...we'll have him reported
and thrown behind bars!
I'll finish of your game!
Dealing my cards in my absence, eh?
Mr. Teja!
I always knew!
You've really pulled off this gimmick, sir!
I imitate him well, don't I?
- We both were fooled.
- Everybody else will be, too!
What I have to decide is
how to get into his house now!
I'll make the plan for that, too.
- He gets up at 6 every morning.
- And goes jogging after that!
- He jogs near the Ladies Hostel.
- Voyeuristic chap, sir!
- He reads the papers at 7 a.m.
- And bathes at 7.30, sharp.
Sitting in the garden, he reads the
newspaper for exactly 9.30 minutes.
- He's at the Golf Club at 9 a.m.
- Knows nothing, but plays Golf too!
Then, for exactly 13 minutes, he
walks about the golf-course all alone.
That's it!
When he's alone!
Fresh lime juice.
He must be kidnapped by now!
There will be a phone call, too!
Don't you go on ranting in there.
You'll spoil the whole show.
Just stay by my side silently.
I only meant to help you, pal.
You want to get married?
Then please don't help me!
- You're looking very beautiful.
- Is Daddy at home?
Why are both of you so quiet?
- Has your Dad scolded you again?
- There's no trace of Dad.
He hasn't even returned home.
He hasn't been kidnapped, has he?
He talks nonsense.
Your Dad will be back.
I'm getting scared.
There isn't even a telephone call.
There will be a telephone call soon!
What?!
Uncle has been kidnapped!
The ransom is Rs.50 lakhs!
- 50 lakhs?!
- Give the phone to me...
Ask them why it is 50 lakhs...
It's disconnected?
Please don't worry...
Your father is our father!
We'll risk our
lives to save him!
We'll be back in a jiffy!
I mean, it'll be difficult!
Please don't cry... you too.
The plan's successful!
The girls and the old man will be happy!
Congratulations on the Wedding!
Hey listen!
Uncle hasn't been kidnapped.
It's all a stunt of Amar and Prem.
- How do you know?
- I heard them talking.
- They planned to please uncle.
- How's that?
They'll first have him kidnapped
and them have him released...
...they'll be heroes in his opinion, right?
Yes! But how much of trouble
they've put us through.
We'll teach them a lesson, too.
It's incredible!
Honestly tell us, for how long
have you been in this business?
What's up now?
Instead of asking for 5 lakhs,
why did you ask for 50?
- Oh no!
- It's okay if you asked...
...but who's going to pay up?
We haven't asked for Rs.50 lakhs...
He has.
- Who's 'he'?
- Yes, who's 'he'?
The one who kidnapped
Ramgopal Bajaj.
- What did you say?
- I'll explain...
Everything went off according to our plan...
...we even had him in our trap.
But then...
There was a sudden attack on our heads.
The earth split, the heavens fell and...
Cut out the details!
This has turned serious, Prem.
There seems to be an
organized gang behind all this.
You're looking very smart today.
Has Uncle returned?
- He will.
- He's been kidnapped by a big gang.
We know that.
They've asked for Rs.50 lakhs.
The money will be paid.
It's okay... he's their father.
They're not bothered. Why should we?
Sit down. There's food here.
Let's eat.
- You don't seem to understand...
- A big gang and a small amount...
...only Rs.50 lakhs?!
Rs.50 lakhs?!
That's too much!
We were asking only for Rs.5 lakhs.
And he felt that was too much, too!
He should be ashamed!
You've arranged for the money, haven't you?
We have your bosses here.
Talk to them.
My boss?!
Who's this boss of mine?!
- This is Amar speaking.
- Give the phone to Raveena, punk!
- He wants to talk to you.
- I don't want to talk.
Tell me, what is it?
Give the phone to
Raveena, will you?!
- He wants to talk to you.
- He's your man. You talk to him.
They're not willing to talk.
Tell me whatever it is.
You donkey, idiot, scoundrel... rascal, ape...
You're a donkey and your father, too!
Speak now or I'll disconnect!
Listen!
Ramgopal Bajaj is in our custody.
If you want him alive, come to
the old temple with Rs.50 lakhs.
If you act smart, we'll
knock him off. Understand?
Your father's kidnapped, and
you're not even talking to him!
Enough is enough!
There's a limit to these jokes.
Now go and bring my father home.
We have not kidnapped your father.
But I heard you talking about
your plans. What about that?
Prem will explain that to you.
Explain it to them, Prem.
Yes.
That is exactly how it happened.
It means, our men did really try to kidnap him...
...but he was kidnapped by these guys.
What?!
Has Daddy really been kidnapped?!
Now look; it's our mistake...
...we will even risk our lives to save him.
Your father is...
...well, not out father.
Our fathers are back home.
- Let's go.
- You can cry if you wish.
- Here's a napkin.
- Let's go.
So, you converted your
earnings into diamonds, eh?
- How did you know?
- How did I know, eh?!
I won't give you the diamonds, even if I die.
Who'll bother you if you're dead anyway?
Now listen Ramu... quietly
give me the locker-number...
...I'm being tolerant because
you're my brother...
...or I would have finished you off long ago!
I've asked for Rs.50 lakhs, for your safety.
Your daughters must be on
their way with the money.
With Rs.50 lakhs, the police will be silenced...
...and I'll lead a peaceful
life as Ramgopal Bajaj.
Neither will the locker be out
of reach, nor the number.
Certainly not the keys, and
not at all the diamonds!
I asked for Rs.50 lakhs...
they're carrying it in that bag!?
- Must be 50 checks of a lakh each!
- Shut up!
I'll go and find out.
Amar... let's return.
He hasn't turned up.
I don't think he will.
I want to urinate... we'll
return tomorrow morning.
Wait.
Getting scared, are you?
No, not scared... I'm a bit frightened of nights.
Why get frightened?
I'm with you! Don't be...
- Why are you screaming?!
- Don't scream!
- What is it?
- Where's the dough?
- Here it is...
- Wait!
- Where's uncle?
- Where's the money?
- Here it is!
- Look, we're not novices...
...we want to see uncle, before
we show you the money. Right?
- See this...
- What is it? What is...
Give it to him! Hurry up!
What are you waiting for?
- This is small change!
- Small change?
It nothing less than Rs. 8,535.39!
Do you think I'd rob a piggy-bank?
This isn't ransom, it's more
like a donation for funerals!
- We've brought all we had.
- Yes...
I had asked for Rs.50 lakhs.
Where is it?
Where will we get
Rs.50 lakhs from?
- Why?
- You have a faulty plan!
You kidnapped the father
and asked the daughter.
You should have kidnapped the
daughter and threatened the father!
You've got it all wrong!
He seems to be a novice!
- Shut up! Or I'll shoot you!
- Sorry!
Get Ramu ready.
They've brought only Rs.7,000.
Didn't I say they're smart?
The shorter one...
We'll manage with this.
Don't you dare touch the money.
Keep an eye on Ramgopal;
I'll keep coming.
I'm leaving now; don't spend a penny.
- Uncle's come!
- We risked our lives for you!
- Okay, let's go.
- Yes, let's go.
- You can sit behind.
- Come here, in the middle.
- Push up a little. Come here...
- Yes... but how will I drive?
Are you comfortable?
- Sit on the bar there.
- Yes, on the bar here.
But how will I drive?
Sit in his lap, uncle!
- Yes, in my lap!
- Get down!
Sit in his lap, they say!
Get down!
He's an idiot... he won't even
know we're sitting here!
Get this thing, clearly.
If you love us, you'll have to
forsake your father and his wealth.
We agree, Prem...
...but father has changed a lot.
For someone who used to hate
liquor, he simply gulps it down!
Do you know the kind of foul language he uses!
It happens...
...it's the gangsters' influence
on him. Forget him!
- He's spoilt!
- Hitler is a write-off, eh?!
This is no time to joke.
He searched the house the other day,
as he were a cop in a thief's house!
He overturned the entire house last night.
- Overturned?
- Overturned?!
What's this?
Uncle? In this condition?
My God!
The world changes in seconds!
It's good that Karisma and
Raveena didn't come, too.
They would have wept, had
they seen this side of him.
I'm thinking of his late wife.
- Her soul must be in turmoil now!
- Great turmoil!
But so quickly?
He was okay just now.
He's okay even now.
But since when has he picked up these vices?
- I think there's some suspense.
- Suspense?
- The film 'Seeta Aur Geeta'!
- No! It was 'Ram Aur Shyam'!
Not one, but two uncles!
There's only one uncle.
The other's a look-alike.
Just like him!
- Let's go to the police.
- No, not the police.
This is the opportunity to
turn heroes in his opinion.
- How?
- Somehow or the other...
...we have to lock up the fake
one and pull out the real uncle!
Do you think I'd tell your clowns
about the diamonds, too?
- What?
- I'll give you the diamonds.
I?
I'll own Rs.30 crores?
I'll lead a decent life now.
I'll fulfill a dream that I had in
the corner of my heart for years.
I'll start a poultry farm.
I'll have thousands of birds.
Which will lay lakhs of eggs.
That will lead to many crore
new birds and many more eggs!
And billions of omelets!
I'll supply the bread to eat those eggs too.
I'll even have a bakery.
The Ling of Bakeries... and
the Emperor of Omelets!
"Our own Bajaj..."
You'll make omelets with
my hard-earned money, eh?
You'll start a bakery for the bread, too, eh?
Oh God!
Thank you very much!
What are you animals doing here?
We were awaiting you, uncle!
He looks just like our Uncle!
All that free food has made him fat!
We'll cut him down to size!
Uncle, get up!
We're here, Uncle!
Hurry up, uncle!
Let's go home!
Raveena and Karisma are
awaiting you there. Let's go!
- We risked our lives to save you.
- Yes, that's true!
Bravo! Bravo!
Tie him up, properly.
Lest he escapes again.
Yes! Let's do it again!
- What's this, uncle?
- I'm not 'uncle'!
I'm Teja!
He cleverly locked me in...
...and you cleverly pulled
me out and put him in!
Amuse yourself with rummy.
I'm off to play my game! Bye!
You're all mixed up, Uncle!
You're the real uncle!
Forget him and take care of
this chap. He can get violent!
I'll kill both of you!
He's not uncle,
I am!
You should have at least asked me who I was!
I had got out with great difficulty!
I knew when I first saw you that
you're the greatest fools ever!
I still haven't cooled down.
Donkeys! Owls! Apes! Illiterate bums...
Don't you dare utter another word!
We were just beginning to understand
who's Karisma and who's Raveena...
...and here's another!
Who's uncle?!
Is this a family-disease?
Is it our mistake that you resemble each other?
Had we asked your parents
to give birth to twins?
That too, a crook like him?!
What is to be done now?
Don't you dare move!
Don't wipe that off!
Come now...
Let's think of something.
What I can't understand, sir...
...is why do Hindi films portray
gangsters and villains...
...as stupid and morons?
Because all of them are not smart as we are.
- Where the hell were you?!
- What is that to you?
I'm Teja...
Open the door!
- So, you're Teja, eh?
- I... speak up!
This man is Teja.
If this is Teja, who is that man outside?
He was Ramgopal Bajaj.
He tricked me and locked me inside!
Then why did he leave these clowns with you?
Why don't you speak?!
You don't understand; He doesn't
want us to marry his daughters!
That's why he's
locked us inside.
- Look at this mark!
- Mark?
What mark is that?
Look at this pack of cards...
Your game will be over!
These are Teja's cards...
We've made a mistake!
- Open them! Where are the keys!?
- I'll finish the game!
- Hurry up, Robert.
- I'll finish your game!
I hope you didn't have any difficulty in there, sir.
Don't touch us!
We'll handle everything now.
Explain everything, Teja.
- What's there to explain?
- They are very understanding...
...their faces tell us how smart they are.
Don't smile! Straighten your cap and follow me!
This is Prem here.
We're bringing Uncle...
...till then, keep an eye on Uncle.
- Aw, shut up!
- What's he saying?
That man at home is not uncle.
He's an impostor.
He's Teja. Keep an eye on
him till we reach there.
But he's just
left with the keys!
He must have gone to the bank.
Don't worry.
We'll send the real uncle home...
...and go to the bank to
nab the fake one. Let's go.
There he goes! Catch him!
Wait!
I was a champ at stone-throwing!
It's found the mark!
'Rabbit' throws well!
Robert, not Rabbit!
Hurry!
We've found the diamonds, sir.
Bravo!
We'll call Teja and tell him we've
found this. He'll reward you!
Till Teja recovers...
I mean, keep hitting him!
They'll call Teja and ask him
to kill this chap. And then...
My dear!
My name is Crime Master Gogo!
I'll have his eye-balls for marbles!
I won't spare anyone!
Not even Teja!
- He's my father, not Teja.
- Teja's gone to the bank.
What's this fuss about?
Take all of them with us!
They disappeared after
they went to make that call.
Where's your boss, Teja?
Where are my diamonds?
- He's gone to fetch the girls.
- Amar's giving the diamonds to Teja.
- Bajaj is lying there.
- Bajaj is in the car!
- No, this is Bajaj.
- Bajaj is in my car!
Hey! Where are you going?
- I was looking for you.
- Why?
He's disappeared with uncle and the two girls.
- Who?
- Crime Master Gogo.
He's asked you to reach here with
the diamonds if you want them alive.
And he's also said that if you inform the police...
- Then what?
- The obvious.
He seems to be a master at the game.
Get down quickly...
Careful.
I'll play marbles with your eye-balls!
- Put your hands up!
- They were always up there!
Come on... follow me!
Amar and Prem are here!
But why are they walking with their hands up?
The two clowns!
Careful!
- Your apron, my Gogo.
- I'll pick it up!
Hi! Hello! How are you?
Hello there! Hi...
Shut up! What are you greeting
them for? Are you at a party?
They have the diamonds, Gogo!
- Hello, uncle!
- I'm not uncle. I'm Teja!
But Teja has a mark on his face.
Right, Robert?
- Yes. You must have the mark.
- What mark?
- Which mark is this?
- I'm Teja, my name is Teja too!
I'm Teja, Ramu...
I am Teja!
You'd better listen, Ramu.
I'm Teja!
- I'm Teja!
- I am! I have the mark!
- To hell with it! I'm Teja!
- I am, because...
- Shut up!
- I'm Teja.
"What's this business of Teja, Teja?"
What I ask is where are the diamonds?
How can we have the diamonds?
We're like innocent little birds.
Birds... of the same flock...
flying high in the skies...
- Am I right, Prem?
- Why not.
- We're kids.
- And very naive, too.
- And clean-hearted, right?
- Why not?!
We only came here to free the girls.
- Let's open them. Okay, Prem?
- Why not?
Don't act smart.
I'll use your eyes for marbles!
Why do you want to play with our eyes?
They all have such big eyes.
Look at them!
Don't let them con you!
They have the diamonds!
Robert snatched them away
from me and gave it to them!
What silly logic!
Why will his goons give the diamonds to me?
Can you do something silly
like that, Robert and Bhalla?
Oh no, I'd never do that.
Never!
Actually, he's being misled by your face.
- What's wrong with my face?
- They think you're an idiot.
He only looks like a foolish
fellow. But he's actually not!
Was that praise for me or abuse?
Praise!
It was praise all the way, sir!
I've been hearing tales about
you since I was a little boy.
Do you know what my mother
used to say when I cried, Prem?
What did your mother say?
She used to say...
"go to sleep son..."
"or Gogo will be upon us"
Did you hear that about
Crime Master Gogo's reputation?
When a kid doesn't sleep his
mother says, "sleep, dear..."
"or it'll bring Gogo here"
- Go on with some more.
- What's more...
...I've even heard you're very
knowledgeable and all-knowing...
...a very accomplished person.
You're strong, intelligent...
I'd even say you're not a man...
...you're a great soul!
I think we should leave with
the girls now, Mr. Gogo.
You will certainly extract the
diamonds from them, right?
Go get a cab, Prem.
I'm knowledgeable and all-knowing...
- Give me a hand, sir.
- I'm strong...
...intelligent. In fact,
I'm not a man at all!
Do you know what my mother taught me?
- What did she say?
- She said...
...always first take your money
and then deliver the goods.
I'll take the diamonds, first.
And then give the girls!
Why are you pestering us, sir?
We're like innocent birds...
...we want to fly away.
Birds...
- Look at this rifle!
- It's a revolver! Move it away!
That's excellent, my boy!
Excellent!
Now is when we have the bull by its horn!
Don't move! Freeze!
Or I'll have you 'shaken' forever!
Drop your guns!
Not you, you idiot!
You'll have us killed!
I could eat all of you alive, do you know that?!
And you?!
You call yourself Crime Master, eh?
"I made a mistake by oversight!"
Shut up! I have a terrible temper!
I'm capable of doing anything!
- Bullet...
- Yes, bullets!
We'll put bullets in all of them!
It's bullets that we don't have!
We've had it!
Teja... Mr. Teja!
Please don't take offence, okay?
Mr. Gogo...
The Great Crime Master Gogo!
I was only kidding!
I've been hearing tales of your
heroics from my childhood!
"Listen, ye people of the world,
Gogo's the Greatest of them all"
We're only children... very
naive... very good at heart...
Pick up your guns, friends!
We're innocent like birds... who fly in the sky!
What should I do with this gun, Amar?
- There's no bullet, right?
- Haven't I said so?
Then throw it away!
I've had enough of your drama!
I'll kill everyone now!
Tell me, what's your
last wish before you die?
Gogo, my friend...
Please let me have that loaded gun!
What's your last wish, buddy?
Before I die,
I want to beat him up!
No! I don't want to get beaten up before I die!
- Please let me beat him up!
- No...
I give you both two minutes.
Bash him up if you can.
And you, save yourself if possible!
Why did you say there was no bullet?!
I made a mistake!
Forgive me!
- Mistake, eh?!
- No, not your knee!
No... Not the chair!
Well done, my boy!
Well done!
Crime Master Gogo... I'll make
Band Master Toto out of you!
Take their guns and throw them in the gutters!
Hand over your guns to the girls!
And do not act smart!
Else, I'll fill this
Gogo's head with lead!
And Gogo!
This revolver is not empty!
Hey!
What are you up to?
It had only one bullet!
Catch them!
Bash them up!
They're all getting bashed up...
Let's slip out of here!
Cut out the dramatics!
Come on, clowns!
Come to me with the diamonds...
...else, I'll have dealt with these girls!
Okay...
Give them to me.
Hurry up!
How much must these diamonds cost?
At least a crore, right?
A crore?! Each of these
diamonds is worth a crore!
Each of them, worth a crore?!
Yes!
It's the earning of his whole life!
Take one last look at them, uncle.
What are you showing it to him for?
Come here!
Do you mean that if each of
these guys gets a diamond...
...their lives will be made, right?
Their lives?!
Lives for generations to come!
Be quick, or I'll kill them!
Please don't...
Here we come.
You too must take a look, Gogo.
This will be an addition to your folklore.
Of passing by a terrific opportunity.
- Don't touch it!
- Just one diamond!
I've given Teja a loan!
Give me one in exchange!
Come right here, or I'll kill them!
- Careful!
- Yes, I'm taking care...
Careful!
Don't drop it!
Raveena's mother in Heaven...
...I'm coming to join you!
Give one to
Crime Master Gogo!
They've taken everything away!
There's one of them...
Catch him!
He hit me!
Everybody's hitting me!
What's happened to Daddy?
What's happened, father?
Uncle, wake up! We've
risked our lives to save you!
Saved me, my foot!
Those people have taken
away my life's savings!
How can they take it away,
with both of us around, uncle?
Get out the real diamonds, Prem!
- We threw away the real ones, Amar!
- What are you saying?
Give me the bag in which
we had kept the fake ones.
No, you idiot! The real
ones were in the red bag!
Oh no!
Yes, I remember now!
They were in this bag!
In the red bag, right?
Must be these, then!
I always knew my darling
daughters would choose real gems!
"Listen to this tale,
O people of the world..."
"...the name of Gogo!"
Whoever you are...
...will you win the game
in which I deal the cards?
Give me the diamonds!
There goes another opportunity!
Give me the diamonds, as per our plan.
Yes, I'm Bhalla!
Pass the diamonds, good fella!
Pass the diamonds here.
I won't make any mistake this time.
My life is made now!
Not a soul will move!
I made the mistake again!
Join the queue!
Take them to the prison in a queue!
They're already in a queue!
Let me see...
Teja, caught at last, eh?
And who are you?
Oh! Gogo!
At least get me back the
money I had loaned him!
You'll get it in prison.
Here are your diamonds, Mr. Ramgopal.
Don't thank me...
Thank Amar and Prem...
...It was they who rang me up.
- About our marriage?
- Why not?
For getting the diamonds back...
I'll get my daughters married to Amar and Prem.
Uncle you're great!
Magnanimous...
...wise...
In fact, you're not man at all!
You're a Great Soul!