See these? With arcs.
You make the water flow from here
and give out with a hoe...
...so the water can pass on the others.
He was a little boy,
he was running around. He grew up.
- He was at your age.
- At my age?
I wish I could see my father
when he was at my age.
How can it be possible?
Those were the old times.
I wish there was a time machine.
We would push its button and...
...go back to my dad's childhood and
see him, that would be nice, right?
Sure, that would be nice and we
would seem younger, then, right?
Don't be so sarcastic.
Do you want to be a young girl, now?
I am still young, look who is talking!
You are an old woman,
but you still wear the same clothes...
...you used to wear 10 years ago
to pretend to be younger.
You go, we will go to coffee house.
We'll meet you there.
- Let's buy the books Deniz wanted.
- We can buy on the way back home.
We buy newspaper, too.
We shouldn't forget his books...
...or he gets mad at me in the evening.
- Children are so likeable, right?
- Sure, they are.
- I like my kids and yours, too.
I am his uncle,
meaning almost his father, right?
Right, brother.
Have a nice day, Mustafa.
Look, Sadik is here.
Welcome Sadik. What brings you here?
Hello Mustafa.
I got it now. That's why
he kept telling "the other one".
Your dad bought some books to your son.
How should I know? When he said
"books", I couldn't imagine.
- Did my dad buy books?
- Yes, he did. You know, Texas, Tommix.
So many of them. For his grandson.
Dad bought books to your son,
did you hear it, Sadik?
Yeah. All right, then. Let's go.
Look Mustafa, he sounded like us.
I told you, Sadik doesn't deny
where he came from.
Bon app, tit, Huseyin Agha. I heard
that Sadik is here. I am happy for you.
- Where did you see them?
- Downtown.
They said they were
coming to coffee house.
Yes, right. He wants to see you all.
We talked about it in the morning.
Where are you going, Hüseyin? You
haven't finished smoking your water pipe.
I have some work to do.
Your water pipe wasn't good.
Do you buy cheap tobacco or what?
It feels like smoking straw.
- What?
- Wait, dad.
I heard that you have bought
some books for Deniz, today. Thank you.
- The kid wanted.
- That's very kind of you.
All right, get out of my way,
go, do your job.
- I have no job, dad. I quitted my job.
- That's why you came here, then.
Come on, let's go the coffee house.
Birgül.
This is my day of
getting beaten up, I guess.
Why did you say that?
Forget it, come on.
All right, we are dead.
Go, play some where else. Don't bother us.
That's great. You said
he wouldn't come at that time of the day.
I wish I wouldn't believe you
and stay for a tea.
How should I know, sister? It is so
unusual for him to come at this time.
Why do you get me involved
with this sulking man?
Are you leaving, just because
I am here, you crazy girl?
Tell your husband,
I am here because kids are here.
Otherwise, may the devil be
with "some people".
- All right, I'll tell him.
- Oh, God.
- Like a camel's grudge!
- Look, who is talking.
Look, who is talking.
Are you the most peaceful man on earth?
- Do you want tea, dad?
- No. Stop it. It is so hot.
- Where is our new boy?
- He is playing with Hüseyin.
What did you buy?
Some stuff.
Have you ever entered this room?
There is treasure in there, right?
Grandpa'll get angry.
Stop meddling with it.
What's going on?
If you ever get close to this door...
...I fall out with you, OK?
- You what?
- I mean, I will punish you.
- What is in there?
There are dogs like monsters.
They may eat you.
I got you a present. Look, here.
However, it is not going to be opened
till the evening. You are punished.
You are not going to meddle with this, OK?
- OK.
- Come on, come with me now.
Where are you, big boy? Come out.
Wow, what an appetite!
Sadik seems a bit quiet.
Does he have a problem or what?
I know his problem.
He had quitted his job.
When did you talk about it?
Seeking a friend.
We came across downtown.
The flowers in the courtyard withered,
although I water them regularly.
How should I know?
We get the garden disinfected.
Maybe it affected the flowers, too.
It is weird.
Seeking a friend.
Come over here, grandson.
I hope you'll like them.
Grandpa bought me books.
They can be yours, if you kiss me once.
Come on, let's read together.
You found your friend here, Deniz.
You lost your time for nothing.
The letters are so small.
- Shall I read you out loudly for you?
- Come on, read.
They look great! Well done.
You are a bit quiet.
You are right. A bit.
Is this a case of "urban- rural
confusion" or alienation?
Don't even try to say that, I won't
believe you. This is your hometown.
Hometown? Home? Fatherland?
Lately, I have been revising
the meanings of these words.
I always thought that
I was struggling for this country.
But this country wouldn't even care.
That's what lots of people
think these days.
We used to dream about
leaving here, remember?
You managed, I couldn't.
I want to ask you something.
At least, you tried.
For someone who was afraid to try.
Can you really say that I missed too much?
I am asking, because I am really
curious about it. No other reasons.
If you were given another chance,
after all you've lived through...
...should you stay or leave?
- I don't know.
I guess, I would take everything I have
here or bring the ones over here back.
Do you know what the hardest one is?
To be caught in the middle.
- I could neither leave nor stay.
- What are they chatting about?
It's an "intellectual talk",
it doesn't suit us.
Come on, intellectuals, cheers!
Bon appetite.
These are like Turkish Delight.
You are late.
Go to your bed, right away.
Shall I make you coffee?
Did Salim go home?
Mum.
Take Deniz to Salims'.
I shouldn't have let Salim go,
he could take you with him.
What are you talking about?
Mum, please take Deniz and go,
just for tonight.
I am going to talk to dad
and most probably we'll argue.
Dad, I know you heard us, you hear me.
We need to talk.
I didn't come here to apologize,
because there is no reason for that.
I won't go into a discussion like
"forgive each other".
I will be in the courtyard, dad.
Get dressed and come.
This is very important.
We need to talk.
- Something wrong?
- No. Can you help mum?
She is near the tractor.
You wait here.
Uncle Ibrahim, where are we going?
To uncle Salims'.
You will stay there tonight.
- Why? Where is my dad?
- He is there, too.
All of us will stay over there tonight.
Don't be afraid, Deniz. It is OK.
It is just a visit.
It doesn't make sense. Uncle Ibrahim,
I think I am dreaming right now.
Yes, you are dreaming.
Don't afraid, Deniz, don't afraid!
Deniz wasn't afraid of anything.
Nene Hatun and her grandson
passed through the enemy...
...front bravely with corporal Ibrahim.
They were the super heroes
of the Independence War.
Don't be afraid.
- Good evening, dad.
- What evening?
Don't you aware of the time?
- It is almost morning.
- I'm sorry. This is not an appropriate time
The things you do are
always inappropriate.
Dad, let's not argue. We did that
a lot in the past. It never worked.
Nothing changed, as you see.
There are things we need to talk.
Cigarette?
I don't smoke that one, it makes me cough.
Dad, you don't know why I am back.
Actually, there shouldn't have been any
reason, I should have just come back,
But it didn't happen that way.
My name is Sadik,
my brother's name is Salim.
So what? My name is Hüseyin.
Why did you give us these names, dad?
Were you that much scared of us,
right from the beginning?
Did you want to manage our lives that
much? When I wanted to find my own way.
That way of yours.
We sent you Istanbul to study
agriculture, not to become an anarchist.
That's what I was just about to say, dad.
You sent me to study agriculture.
No other choice.
Become an engineer, manage the farm...
...to stay here and get married to Birgül.
You chose my school,
my life, my everything, dad.
Do you know that I hate that, dad?
You are calling me selfish, right?
You mentioned Birgül.
After you left, have you ever thought
of that girl, how she suffered?
Her tears didn't stop for years and you
are calling me selfish, give me a break!
Dad, you said "you left", but I didn't.
I couldn't. I couldn't stay though.
I couldn't recognize where my home is.
Somewhere in my mind
you have always tried to lead me.
Our arguments and matters between us.
Do you have any idea what it means to
have no home to come back, dad?
However, everything got even worse.
My wife died.
My revolutionist friends, who used to
call me "petty bourgeois" at the time...
...gave me jobs in advertisement agencies,
capitalist papers, taking pity on me.
Like throwing a bone to a dog.
In order to clear themselves,
in order to clean their souls!
Wait, I am getting out of the subject.
I was talking about "home".
Do you know why I returned, dad?
Give a room to Deniz?
Let him grow up here,
let him have a home.
He has nowhere else to go.
Did you get now, what it means
to have a child? It is hard, isn't it?
You aren't able to look after him, right?
- You see what it means to have a child?
- Sure I see.
Do you have any idea about not
to be able to see a child's growing up?
Do you know that feeling?
The life will go on...
Some people will write new books,
you won't be able to read them.
New films will be shot,
you won't be able to see them.
You will want to listen again some song
you like, but you won't able to do it.
Maybe you'll get used to
these things, easily...
While he is growing up, not be beside him.
Not to be able to see his first
girlfriend.
Dad...
...my heart is in flames.
I guess, this is a feeling like leaving
something left undone.
Recently, I've been trying to
push him away when he hugs me.
I have been trying my best to
keep him away from me.
I hate myself for
being a pain in his life.
Give him a room, dad.
Let him have a home,
but he could leave time to time.
There are so many things that
I wanted to tell him. You tell him.
Tell him that.
My son. What happened?
Where are you?
Hold it! I am coming!
- Come over here, sister.
- What happened? Where is Sadik?
- They got him in a room.
- Dad is talking to the doctor.
He said "don't tire him". We'll be able
to see him after a few minutes.
He is getting oxygen.
- What is wrong with him? What did they
say? - We don't know. We'll find out soon.
Come on Salim, don't.
Let's go to the garden.
Stop it, it doesn't necessarily mean
something bad. Don't let yourself go.
- Where are the kids?
- They are at home with Sakine.
We didn't tell them. We said
we were going to downtown, shopping.
He figured that something is wrong,
but didn't ask anything.
Let's go down to the café,
we can't talk here.
I can't wait till there. Say it.
Don't confuse me. The doctor said
so many things, I have to clear my mind.
- I hope he'll get well soon, Hüseyin.
- Thank you.
Sadik took out his health report from
his pocket...
...and gave it to us.
He was carrying in his pocket.
He has spent some time in prison,
you know.
During the military coup,
after Deniz was born.
He became ill there.
The doctor said, because of the torture
and prison conditions.
There is liquid accumulation
in his lungs. An edema.
It got better for a while.
A few years ago it came back.
One of his lungs is already damaged.
The other one He was getting
his treatment there, in Istanbul.
He was getting medicines.
This is the case.
The doctor said
he would do his best, but...
...there is little hope.
He told me to get prepare for the worse.
Salim, pull yourself together.
If you'll be like this near the kid
Pull yourself together, what a shame!
How can I, dad?
My brother is dying, what are you saying?
It's very kind of you to come here, Fatma.
Both the kid and Sadik
have been asking about you.
I intended to come earlier,
but it took too much time to.
Take the kids to the village,
to my sisters'.
- Where were you born, Fatma?
- Kayseri.
Some of my relatives are still there.
But we are very much apart of each other.
Some of us are in Istanbul,
some of us are there.
That's the way it is.
Come on, dad. Take over them!
- Don't intervene.
- You are treading on my toes.
- Don't hit me!
- Stop it! It may be an accident.
That's enough. Stop the car, Salim.
Let's throw the kids out of the car.
Be quiet, kids.
I am going to cry that here is a fire.
I wish I would go with the others.
I am sweating.
Sakine, what a big hip you have.
- Move a side a bit.
- It's the kids, what I can do?
Stop the car, Salim.
Why did you stop? What is it,
is it the car again? Why did you stop?
I don't know.
All of you told me to stop and
Go on, move it. Why did you stop?
Hüseyin, Ay segül, what happened to you?
If they make any noise, I'll call the
doctors to give them an injection.
They are afraid of doctors.
Let's go outside.
Is this room hot for you, son?
No, it is OK. It is cool in the evenings.
It is slept well here.
- The wind blows from here.
- Do you stay here, too?
Sometimes me, sometimes his mother.
We manage it in some way.
- You wanted these from home.
- Thanks.
Please put them into that drawer.
Fatma will stay with us, right?
We won't let her go.
I can't stay long. The schools will be
opened soon, I have some work to do.
There is still time for the schools.
Dad, will I go to school here?
Yes, Deniz. Is it bad?
No, it is even better.
You'll get better until that time, right?
The schools will be opened
a month later, right?
Yes, but you'll get better, right?
Sure, I will.
Your wife was a beautiful woman.
May God bless her soul.
Look at this, Deniz is so small here.
Had you taken this picture with you
to Istanbul?
I was wondering where it was.
When you first came here,
you know we went to the vineyard.
Deniz said "I wish I could see
my father wandering around.
When he was a child,
I wish there was a time machine.
- We would push the button".
- Really? Look at that little rascal!
- Bring me water from downstairs.
- There is water here. Shall I give you?
- I want another one from downstairs.
- It is water, dad. They are all the same.
Brother, bring it from downstairs.
Once you said something to me.
About Deniz.
You told that you had some things
you couldn't say to Deniz.
I have some things
I couldn't say to you, as well.
I am not good at making a speech.
You are my son...
...my everything.
That's all I am saying.
I understood, dad.
I understood very well, thank you.
You said once, "I wish
he didn't see me in bed like this".
Don't worry.
Sons remember their dads
just the way they want...
...right, Sadik?
Good morning.
Good morning, uncle Hüseyin.
Is your husband at home?
No, he went to Izmir.
We'll get our garden disinfected.
- He won't return till the evening, right?
- Yes, I guess so.
I have a request.
Open your mouth, come on.
I can eat by myself, brother.
Give me that.
Why would I? You don't eat, then.
You are cheating me.
Look, that fat nurse
is complaining about you.
Open your mouth.
You have a visitor.
I hope you'll get well soon.
Come on, go outside, to the garden.
Not before he finishes his soup.
The fat nurse is very angry.
Do you remember the time
when I was in primary school and...
...you were junior high school?
One day I had made some raisin cookies.
I was taking them to the school.
You had tasted one of them
and liked so much.
- You hadn't even believe that I made it.
- So?
I brought you those cookies. Eat it,
I wonder if you'll remember the taste.
I never forgot.
Didn't you? I didn't, either.
- You don't seem to be changed at all.
- I have changed.
How wouldn't I change?
- You are married with Mehmet, right?
- Yes, sure, I had.
How wouldn't I get married?
We heard about your wife.
We felt very sorry.
Well done.
We appreciated you so much.
You raised your child on your own.
You didn't need anyone.
You have two, right?
Yes, indeed.
It is delicious. Did you make it
right before you came here?
No, I had some at home.
My sons like it.
I wanted to name to
one of the boys after you.
But I was afraid that Mehmet might
realize and get angry with me.
We named him Caner,
but I always call him Sadik in my mind.
I wanted you to know this.
Did you forgive me?
Sure, I did, Sadik.
How wouldn't I forgive you?
The cars are coming. What should we do?
They'll all cry now,
maybe you should take away the kid.
I am sure they will control themselves
while the child is here.
Come on,
let's go to the field all together.
And make you a wooden horse, OK?
If I stood like this...
...right here.
If I opened my arms like this...
If I stopped him.
If I told him not to go.
15 years ago...
...if I stood like this,
Nuran If I stopped Sadik.
Get your arms down.
For God's sake, pull yourself together.
If I hugged him like this...
...if I told my son not to go.
Don't. You are our father.
Look, we have a grandson,
pull yourself together.
He wouldn't leave, then.
He would stay.
I wish I had said nothing.
I wish I had kept my mouth shut.
I brought about his death!
- I couldn't stop him.
- Uncle Hüseyin, please stop it.
Stand right here!
Open your arms!
I said "open your arms".
Sister, are you mad?
Come with me.
Move!
Run towards your dad.
Run. Break through him.
If you don't, your dad will never get
well for all his life. Run!
Catch him. Stop him!
Dad.
I am coming, dad! Get out of my way!
You see? No one can stop the one
who wants to leave.
Oh, no! Salim!
It is all right. You ran and
it is over. Come back here!
He is running towards the river.
He may fall in and drown!
Look how his uniform suits him!
- Let me get your collar.
- Don't move!
- You tightened so much.
- But you are going to be so pretty.
Very well, they all look pretty.
Let's put your handkerchiefs...
...into your pockets so that
they don't call you snotty.
These are the presents from your aunt,
Gülbeyaz, for your primary school day.
I mean, for your first school day.
"Primary school day" sounded like
"primary school".
I meant "the first day of school".
What am I saying? You made me confused.
Aunt Gülbeyaz, grandpa gave us money,
but you gave us handkerchiefs.
I am not rich as much as your
grandpa, my child.
Sure, not as much as me.
She was going to say "as much as Croesus".
But she got confused, I guess.
Who is Croesus?
There is a scorpion in your aunt's
pocket. She is afraid to be stung by it.
Don't laugh Nuran. Otherwise
I will never come to your house again.
- I swear, I will never come here again.
- I didn't laugh, sister. You misunderstood
Come on, line up. We'll take photos.
Brahim, you do that.
I wish we tidied ourselves up a little,
we'll seem ugly.
- You are OK, mum, come here.
- Come on, Gülbeyaz.
- You do it, I don't want.
- Come here, girl! Don't act like a child.
Ready!
- Dad, who is Croesus?
- How should I know?
- I guess, he was one of the kings.
- How is the grandson?
He has to get used to it.
We are trying best to
make him feel better.
He has talked only a few words
last 4 weeks, though.
It should be better for him
if he cried, screamed, let it go.
He is like a small bird
fallen down from nest.
We are so afraid to say anything.
They said it's psychological, he has
just closed himself to the world outside.
I don't know for which one
I should be sorry. Him or my son?
Deniz, let's go.
- My son!
- My grandson!
What is it, my dear?
I missed my dad so much.
Don't be sorry. Look, we are here,
your siblings are here.
Hüseyin, Ay segül, your grand aunt.
We are all here.
You don't have to go to school today.
Teachers wouldn't give homework,
this is the first day of school.
Look, you'll have new friends there,
they'll like you so much.
Look, there are horses here.
We can drive tractor,
I can teach you how to it.
Actually, do you know that
people don't die?
God takes them to his side.
We call them "dead", but...
...they actually wait for us in the sky.
- Right, grandpa?
- Sure.
Then, one day we'll all meet up there.
Your dad'll be there, too.
All of us will be there.
We'll look down from the skies.
You are lying. No one will fly.
Of course, we won't fly with our wings.
I mean some other form.
Why would we lie to you?
Look, he doesn't believe us.
We read a book together, remember?
You call it comics.
The guy was flying, don't you believe
him, either? What was it?
Right. Your dad became Superman.
- He is flying in the skies.
- I want him to come down.
I don't want him to fly.
I want him here.
Come with me, then.
I'll show you your dad.
- Grandpa. We entered the secret room.
- Yes, we did. Wait here, it's dark.
Look, Deniz, one of our neighbor
has gone to Germany to work.
His name is Osman.
Look at this.
- A projection machine!
- Right, there is a film in it, actually.
Let's watch it.
Your grandpa asked Osman to bring a
projection machine.
Grandpa shot all of us.
Look, like this.
I used to be a director in the past.
Come on, the film is about to start.
Did you get your tickets?
- Do you have any money?
- Yes.
We have and we have a lot,
you just gave us. Two for me.
Don't pay, my child. He is fooling you.
Grandpa the director,
don't get any money from us.
All right, then.
Only for this time it is free.
- I'll get her money, though.
- Forget it, you nuts!
- Didn't you leave?
- No, we didn't.
They wanted to return on the way.
- There is a projection machine!
- Come on, don't stand by the door.
Let's all seat.
That's my dad!
It is a silent movie.
Dad!
Take it, it's yours.
Don't tell anyone, OK?
You can shoot movies with this.
- Dad.
- My son!
Did you come out of this?
- Are you going to school?
- Yes, did you see me?
- Grandma says that you can see us.
- Yes.
Your uniform suits you so much.
You were very handsome as usual.
- Were you here?
- Yes.
Dad, am I dreaming again?
I don't know, but even if you are,
it is nice, right?
Why aren't you Superman, then?
Because you have grown up.
When a person grows up,
do his dreams get smaller?
I won't be able to see you again, right?
You can see me, if you want.
Yes, maybe none of them
will be that real like it is now.
Because you'll know that
you create them in your mind.
Yet maybe they'll be even nicer, then.
You can direct them as you like.
You can try to make them real.
- This means growing up, right?
- Yes, handsome. This means growing up.
- I wish I'd never grow up.
- Why is that?
- I won't able to see you again, then.
- You'll grow up, you have to grow up.
When you grow up, you won't need
to see me, you won't need me.
Come on, get into the house.
It's going to rain.
Will you get wet?
No, I won't and I'll always be happy,
because you have a home, handsome.
Are you leaving?
Look, let's play a game with you.
Get the camera and shoot me walking.
There is no film in it.
Yes, there is. I put it.
Come on, shoot me.
Bye dad.
Deniz made a promise to his dad
while he was saying goodbye to him.
He would grow up and never cry.
Because he had a superhero dad
even if he doesn't fly in the skies.
Deniz let the superhero leave, because
new adventures were waiting for him.
These happy ending stories
should be told to others.