Corporal Barry, eight paces forward...
... march!
Corporal Barry.
You're a gallant soldier,
and evidently of good stock...
...but you're idle and unprincipled.
You're a bad influence on the men.
And for all your bravery,
I'm sure you'll come to no good.
I hope the Colonel is mistaken.
I have fallen into bad company,
but I've only done as other soldiers do.
I've never had a friend
or protector before...
...to show that I was worthy
of better things.
The Colonel may say I'm ruined,
and send me to the Devil.
But, I would go to the Devil
to serve the Regiment.
Corporal Barry, fall in.
The war ended and Barry's regiment
was garrisoned in the Capital.
He had, for some time, ingratiated himself
with Captain Potzdorf...
... whose confidence in him
was about to bring its reward.
Good morning, Redmond.
Good morning, Captain.
I should like you to meet my uncle,
the Minister of Police.
Good morning, Herr Minister.
Redmond...
...I've spoken to the Minister regarding
your services and your fortune is made.
We shall get you out of the Army...
...appoint you to the Police Bureau,
and, in time...
...we'll allow you to move
in a better sphere.
Thank you, Captain.
Your loyalty to me and service
to the Regiment has pleased me.
Now there is another occasion
on which you can assist us.
If you succeed...
...your reward will be secure.
I'll do my best, sir.
There is a gentleman in Berlin
in the service of the Empress of Austria.
He calls himself
the Chevalier de Balibari.
He appears to be a professional gambler.
He's a libertine:
Fond of women, of good food...
...polished, obliging.
He speaks French and German indifferently.
But we have reason to fancy
that Monsieur de Balibari...
...is a native of your country of Ireland.
And that he has come here as a spy.
Your knowledge of English...
...makes you an ideal choice
to go into his service...
...and find out whether or not
he is a spy.
Does this assignment interest you?
Minister, I'm interested in anything
that can be of service to you...
...and Captain Potzdorf.
You will not know a word of English.
If the Chevalier remarks on your accent,
say you are Hungarian.
You served in the war.
You left the Army for medical reasons...
...then served Monsieur de Quellenberg
for two years.
He's now with the Army in Silesia,
but you'll have a certificate from him.
Good morning, Your Honour.
So you are the young man
recommended by Seebach.
Yes, Your Honour,
here are my credentials.
Your name is Lazlo Zilagy?
Yes, Your Honour.
Monsieur de Quellenberg
recommends you highly.
Monsieur is a very good man.
It was imprudent of him...
... but when Barry saw
the Chevalier's splendour...
... and noble manner...
... he felt unable to keep disguise
with him.
Those who have never been exiled...
... know not what it is to hear
a friendly voice in captivity...
... and would not understand the cause...
... of the burst of feeling
now about to take place.
You seem the right one to me.
Thank you, Your Honour.
Are you ill?
Sir...
...I have a confession to make to you.
I'm an Irishman.
My name is Redmond Barry.
I was abducted into the Prussian Army.
Now I've been put into your service...
...by my Captain Potzdorf
and his uncle, the Minister of Police...
...to serve as a watch
upon your... actions...
...and to give information to them.
The Chevalier was much affected
at thus finding one of his countrymen.
For he too was an exile.
And a friendly voice, a look...
... brought the old country
back to his memory.
He is very religious
and attends church regularly.
After Mass he comes home for breakfast.
He then takes an airing in his carriage.
Barry presented his reports
regularly to the Minister.
The details were arranged
beforehand with the Chevalier.
He was instructed to tell the truth...
... as much as his story
would possibly bear.
The information he gave
was very minute and accurate...
... though not very important.
Wine or punch, Your Honour?
Wine.
It was agreed that Barry should keep
his character of valet.
That, before strangers,
he should not know a word of English.
And that he should keep a lookout
on the trumps when serving the wine.
Having excellent eyesight...
... and a natural aptitude...
... he was able to give his dear patron
much assistance...
... against his opponents
at the green table.
Lf, for instance, he wiped
the table with a napkin...
... the enemy was strong in Diamonds.
If he adjusted a chair it meant Ace King.
If he said, "Punch or wine, My Lord?"...
... Hearts were meant, and so forth.
The Prince of Tübingen...
... who had intimate connections
with the Great Frederick...
... was passionately fond of play
as were the gentlemen...
... of almost all the Courts of Europe.
You owe 15,500 frederick d'or.
Chevalier...
...though I cannot say how...
...I believe you have cheated me.
I deny Your Grace's accusation...
...and beg you to say
how you have been cheated.
I don't know.
But I believe I have been.
Your Grace owes me
15,500 frederick d'or...
...which I have honourably won.
Chevalier...
...if you will have your money now
you must fight for it.
If you will be patient...
...maybe I will pay you something
another time.
Your Grace, if I am to be so tame
as to take this...
...then I must give up an honourable
and lucrative occupation.
I have said all there is to be said.
I am at your disposal
for whatever purposes you wish.
Good night.
Was the Prince cheated?
In as far as I am able to tell,
Herr Minister, no.
I believe he won the money fairly.
What are the Chevalier's intentions?
I'm not sure.
The Prince told him that if he wanted
his money he'd have to fight for it.
A meeting with the Prince is impossible.
The Prince has left him no other choice.
Will you be able to return here tomorrow
without arousing suspicion?
I know they won't allow a meeting
with the Prince.
But if I say that, do you know any reason
why he'll pay me what he owes?
You must tell them I intend
to demand satisfaction.
Don't look so downcast, my boy.
They cannot harm me,
the Austrian Embassy will see to that.
The worst they can do is send me
out of this dreary country of theirs.
If they should, don't worry...
...you shall not be left behind.
Have no fear of that.
The King has determined to send
the Chevalier out of the country.
Has he already demanded satisfaction?
Not yet, but I believe he intends to...
...possibly today.
Then this must be done tomorrow.
All the arrangements are made.
You said he takes a drive
after breakfast every day.
Yes, sir.
Is there any reason he should do
any different tomorrow?
No, sir.
Good.
When the Chevalier comes out
to his carriage in the morning...
...two Officers will meet him
and escort him to the frontier.
His baggage will be sent after him.
Excellent.
At ten o'clock the next morning...
... the Chevalier de Balibari...
... went out for his regular morning drive.
Where's my servant, Lazlo?
I will let down the steps, Your Honour.
What is this about?
Please get inside.
Am I under arrest?
We're driving to the frontier.
Frontier? But I'm on my way
to the Austrian Ambassador's house.
My orders are to escort you
to the frontier...
...and see you safely across the border.
But, I'm not going to the frontier.
I have very important business
at the Austrian Ambassador's house.
My orders are to take Your Honour
to the frontier by any means necessary.
If you come willingly...
...I'm to give you this purse
on behalf of the Prince of Tübingen...
...containing 2,000 frederick d'or.
All Europe shall hear of this.
And so, without papers or passport...
... and under the eyes
of two Prussian Officers...
... Barry was escorted across the frontier
into Saxony and freedom.
The Chevalier himself had uneventfully
crossed the frontier the night before.
By these wonderful circumstances,
Barry was once more free...
... and began his professional work
as a gamester...
... resolving, thenceforward and forever,
to live the life of a gentleman.
The four wins.
Soon he and the Chevalier were received
in all the Courts of Europe...
... and were speedily...
... in the very best society
where play was patronized...
... and professors of that science
always welcome.
The seven.
Why not the seven?
All... all, yes.
No more bets.
Number seven...
... loses.
Place your bets.
Chevalier, will you give me credit
for 5,000 louis d'or, please?
Of course, Lord Ludd.
Five thousand.
Now, everything on the four.
Yes, I know, everything on the four.
No more bets.
The four loses.
It is not important.
Now, I'm weary.
I would like dinner. Shall we?
Excuse me, Lord Ludd.
If you don't mind.
Not at all.
They always played on credit with
any person of honour or noble lineage.
They never pressed for their winnings...
... or declined to receive
promissory notes.
But woe to the man who did not pay
when the note became due.
Barry was sure to wait upon him
with his bill.
There were few bad debts.
Saluez.
It was Barry's skill with the sword,
and readiness to use it...
... that maintained the reputation
of the firm, so to speak.
On guard!
I will pay you today, sir.
Thus, it will be seen, their life...
... for all its splendour,
was not without danger and difficulty...
... requiring talent and determination
for success.
And required them to live
a wandering and disconnected life.
And, though they were swimming
upon the high tide of fortune...
... and prospering with the cards,
they had little to show for their labour...
... but some fine clothes
and a few trinkets.
Five years in the Army,
and considerable experience of the world...
... had dispelled any romantic notions
regarding love...
... with which Barry commenced life.
And he had it in mind,
as many gentlemen had done before him...
... to marry a woman
of fortune and condition.
And, as such things so often happen...
... these thoughts coincided
with his setting sight upon a lady...
... who will play a considerable part
in the drama of his life.
The Countess of Lyndon...
... Viscountess Bullingdon of England...
... Baroness Castle Lyndon of Ireland.
A woman of vast wealth and great beauty.
She was the wife of Sir Charles Lyndon...
... Knight of the Bath...
... Minister to George III
at several of the Courts of Europe.
A cripple, wheeled about in a chair...
... worn out by gout
and a myriad of diseases.
Her Ladyship's Chaplain, Mr. Runt...
... acted as tutor to her son,
the little Viscount Bullingdon...
... a melancholy little boy,
much attached to his mother.
I'm going outside for a breath of air.
Yes, My Lady.
To make a long story short...
... six hours after they met...
Her Ladyship was in love.
And once Barry got into her company...
... he found innumerable occasions
to improve his intimacy...
... and was scarcely out
of Her Ladyship's sight.
Good evening, gentlemen.
Sir Charles.
Good evening, Mr. Barry.
Have you done with my Lady?
Pardon?
Come, sir. I'm a man who would rather
be known as a cuckold than a fool.
I think, Sir Charles,
that you've had too much to drink.
What?
As it happens, your Chaplain, Mr. Runt,
introduced me to your Lady...
...to advise me on a religious matter,
of which she is an expert.
He wants... to step into my shoes.
He wants to step into my shoes.
Is it not a pleasure for me,
as I am drawing near the goal...
...to find my home such a happy one...
...my wife so fond of me, that she is even
now thinking of appointing a successor?
Isn't it a comfort to see her
like a prudent housewife...
...getting everything ready
for my departure?
I hope you're not thinking of leaving us,
Sir Charles?
Not so soon as you may fancy, perhaps.
I've been given over many times
these four years.
And there was always
a candidate or two...
...waiting to apply for the situation.
I'm sorry for you, Mr. Barry.
It grieves me to keep you
or any gentleman waiting.
Had you not better arrange
with my doctor...
...or have the cook flavour my omelette
with arsenic, eh?
What are the odds, gentlemen,
that I live to see Mr. Barry hang yet?
Sir, let those laugh that win.
Gentlemen.
I'll get a surgeon.
Have some brandy, Sir Charles.
From a report in
The Saint James' Chronicle:
"Died at Spa in Belgium...
"...Sir Charles Reginald Lyndon...
"...Knight of the Bath,
Member of Parliament...
"...and for many years...
"...His Majesty's Representative
at various European Courts.
"He has left behind him a name
which is endeared to all his friends. "
''Dearly beloved...
''... we are gathered together
here in the sight of God...
''... and in the face of this congregation...
''... to join together this man
and this woman in holy matrimony.''
A year later,
on the fifteenth of June...
... in the year 1773...
... Redmond Barry had the honour to lead
to the altar the Countess of Lyndon.
The ceremony was performed by the
Reverend Runt, Her Ladyship's Chaplain.
''And therefore is not in any way
to be enterprised...
''... nor taken in hand unadvisedly...
''... lightly or wantonly...
''... to satisfy men's carnal lusts
and appetites...
''... like brute beasts
that have no understanding.
''But reverently...
''... discreetly...
''... advisedly...
''... soberly...
''... and in the fear of God.
''Duly considering the causes
for which matrimony was ordained.
''First...
''... it was ordained for the procreation
of children to be brought up...
''... in the fear and nurture of the Lord,
and to the praise of His holy name.
''Secondly...
''... it was ordained for a remedy
against sin, and to avoid fornication.''
Barry had now arrived
at the pitch of prosperity...
... and by his own energy had raised
himself to a higher sphere of society...
... having procured His Majesty's
gracious permission to add the name...
... of his lovely Lady to his own.
Thenceforth, Redmond Barry
assumed the style...
... and title of Barry Lyndon.
Redmond, would you mind not smoking
for a while?
Lady Lyndon was soon destined
to occupy a place in Barry's life...
... not very much more important
than the elegant carpets and pictures...
... which would form
the pleasant background of his existence.
My Lord Bullingdon,
you seem particularly glum today?
You should be happy
that your mother has remarried.
Not in this way.
And not in such haste.
And certainly not to this man.
I think you judge your mother too harshly.
Do you not like your new father?
Not very much.
He seems to me little more
than a common opportunist.
I don't think he loves my mother at all.
And it hurts me to see her
make such a fool of herself.
At the end of a year Her Ladyship
presented Barry with a son.
Bryan Patrick Lyndon, they called him.
Her Ladyship and Barry lived,
after a while, pretty separate.
She preferred quiet, or to say the truth,
he preferred it for her...
... being a great friend to a modest
and tranquil behaviour in woman.
Besides, she was a mother,
and would have great comfort...
... in the dressing, educating
and dandling of their little Bryan.
For whose sake it was fit,
Barry believed...
... that she should give up the pleasures
and frivolities of the world...
... leaving that part of the duty
of every family of distinction...
... to be performed by him.
Lady Lyndon tended to a melancholy
and maudlin temper...
... and, left alone by her husband,
was rarely happy or in good humour.
Now she must add jealousy
to her other complaints...
... and find rivals even among her maids.
Samuel, what would the time be?
Twenty-five minutes past eleven,
My Lady.
Shall we make this the last game, ladies?
Good morning, ladies.
Would you mind excusing us?
I'd like a word alone with Lady Lyndon.
I'm sorry.
This coat is made of the finest velvet...
...all cunningly worked
with silver thread.
No finer velvet has ever been woven,
and you will see none better anywhere.
Pardon me, gentlemen.
Good morning, dearest.
We're taking the children for a ride
to the village. We'll be back for tea.
Have a nice time. I'll see you then.
Goodbye, little Bryan.
Lord Bullingdon.
Take good care of your mother.
Come now, give your father a proper kiss.
Lord Bullingdon...
...is that the way to behave
to your father?
Lord Bullingdon,
have you lost your tongue?
My father was Sir Charles Lyndon.
I have not forgotten him, if others have.
Lord Bullingdon,
you have insulted your father!
Madam, you have insulted my father.
Dearest, would you excuse us?
We have something to discuss in private.
Gentlemen.
One.
Two.
Six.
Lord Bullingdon...
...I have always been willing
to live with you on friendly terms.
But be clear about one thing:
As men serve me, I serve them.
I never laid a cane on the back
of a Lord before...
...but, if you force me to, I shall
speedily become used to the practice.
Do you have anything to say for yourself?
No.
You may go.
Barry believed, and not without
some reason, that it had been...
... a declaration of war against him
by Bullingdon from the start...
... and that the evil consequences
that ensued...
... were entirely of Bullingdon's creating.
I shall make you into
a real magician now, Bryan.
I shall show you the knot that never was.
As Bullingdon grew up to be a man...
... his hatred for Barry
assumed an intensity...
... equalled only by his
increased devotion to his mother.
Very good, Bryan. A little bow.
Put it on the table for me.
Thank you.
For Bryan's eighth birthday the local
nobility, gentry and their children...
... came to pay their respects.
The inside and outside are quite empty.
Wave your hand over the top.
Is there anything there?
Wonderful! Wonderful, colourful
silk handkerchiefs!
Take a bow, Bryan,
you did that beautifully.
Very good.
Let's see if you have something
behind your ear.
Yes, you have.
A little ball. Let's make it vanish.
It's gone.
Here it is, behind my elbow.
Wave your hand
over my green silk handkerchief...
...and see if we can produce
a magic flower. I wonder if we can?
Here it comes.
The colours of the rainbow.
You know all the colours of the rainbow
produce but one colour, Bryan.
Nothing in my magic cabinet.
They produce the colour... white.
And there is my own...
...beautiful white rabbit.
Bryan, you have done very well.
A little bow.
We crept up on their fort,
and I jumped over the wall first.
My fellows jumped after me.
You should have seen the Frenchmen's
faces when 23 rampaging he-devils...
...sword and pistol, cut and thrust,
came tumbling into their fort.
In three minutes we left
as many Artillery men's heads...
...as there were cannon balls.
Later we were visited
by our noble Prince Henry.
''Who is the man who has done this? ''
I stepped forward.
''How many heads was it
that you cut off? '' He says.
''Nineteen,'' says I,
''besides wounding several.''
Well, I'll be blessed,
if he didn't burst into tears.
''Noble, noble fellow,'' he said.
''Here is nineteen golden guineas,
one for each head that you cut off.''
What do you think of that?
Were you allowed to keep the heads?
No, they always become
the property of the King.
Will you tell me another story?
I'll tell you one tomorrow.
Will you play cards with me tomorrow?
Of course I will. Now go to sleep.
Will you keep the candles lit?
Bryan, big boys don't sleep
with the candles lit.
I'm afraid of the dark.
My darling, there's nothing
to be afraid of.
But, I like it with the candles lit.
All right, you can sleep
with the candles lit.
Thank you, Papa.
Good night.
Ah, Redmond!
It's a blessing to see my darling boy
has attained a position I knew was his due.
And for which I pinched myself
to educate him.
Little Bryan is a darling boy...
...and you live in great splendour.
Your lady wife knows
she has a treasure...
...she couldn't have had,
had she married a Duke.
But, if she should tire
of my wild Redmond...
...and his old-fashioned Irish ways...
...or if she should die...
...what future would there be
for my son, and my grandson?
You have not a penny of your own...
...and cannot transact any business
without her signature.
Upon her death the entire estate
would go to young Bullingdon...
...who bears you little affection.
You could be penniless tomorrow...
...and darling Bryan at the mercy
of his stepbrother.
Shall I tell you something?
There is only one way for you
and your son to have real security.
You must obtain a title.
I shall not rest
until I see you Lord Lyndon.
You have important friends.
They can tell you
how these things are done.
For money, well-timed
and properly applied...
...can accomplish anything.
And Barry was acquainted with someone
who knew how these things were done.
This was the distinguished Barrister
and former Government Minister...
... Lord Hallam...
... whose acquaintance he had made,
like so many others, at the gaming table.
Do you happen to know
the Thirteenth Earl of Wendover?
I don't believe I do.
Well, this nobleman is one
of the Gentlemen of His Majesty's Closet...
...with whom our revered Monarch
is on terms of considerable intimacy.
In my opinion, you would be wise
to fix upon him...
...your chief reliance for the advancement
of your claim to the peerage.
When I take up a person, Mr. Lyndon,
he, or she, is safe.
There is no question about them anymore.
My friends are the best people.
I don't mean they're the most virtuous...
...or, indeed, the least virtuous,
or the cleverest...
...or the stupidest,
richest or best born.
But, the best.
In a word, people about whom
there is no question.
I cannot promise how long it will take.
You can appreciate
it is not an easy matter.
But, any gentleman with an estate,
and 30,000 a year...
...should have a peerage.
And there standing behind me
was a total stranger.
I looked at him, and he said to me:
''Excuse me, sir, could you tell me,
is Lord Wendover alive or dead? ''
I was so astonished,
I couldn't think of what to say.
Then I became angry,
and said to him, ''He's dead.''
The striving after this peerage was
one of Barry's most unlucky dealings.
He made great sacrifices
to bring it about.
He lavished money here,
and diamonds there.
He bought lands
at ten times their value...
... purchased pictures and articles
of virtue at ruinous prices.
He gave entertainments
to those friends to his claim...
... all, being about the Royal person,
were likely to advance it.
And, I can tell you, bribes were
administered. And in high places, too.
So near the person of His Majesty
that you would be astonished to know...
... what great noblemen condescended
to receive his loans.
This is by Ludovico Cordi...
...a disciple of Alessandro Allori.
It's dated 1605...
...and shows,
''The Adoration of The Magi.''
It's beautiful.
Yes.
I love the use of the colour blue
by the artist.
Yes, that is very beautiful.
What is the price of this one?
Well, this is one of my best pictures.
But, if you really like it, I'm sure
we can come to some arrangement.
Lord Wendover, Your Majesty.
I'm glad to see you here today,
Lord Wendover.
What news of Lady Wendover?
Thank you, Your Majesty.
Lady Wendover is much better.
Good! Present my compliments to her.
Say we miss her company here.
And what of those excellent boys
of yours?
They're well. Charles has gone to sea
under Captain Geary on the Ramillies.
John has gone to Oxford to learn
how to preach and pray.
Good, good!
Your Majesty, may I present
Mr. Barry Lyndon.
Mr. Lyndon. We were very fond
of Sir Charles Lyndon.
And how is Lady Lyndon?
She's very well, Your Majesty.
Mr. Lyndon raised a company of troops
to fight in America against the rebels.
Good, Mr. Lyndon. Raise another company
and go with them, too.
Barry was born clever enough
at gaining a fortune...
... but incapable of keeping one.
For the qualities and energies
which lead a man to achieve the first...
... are often the very cause of his ruin
in the latter case.
Now he was burdened with
the harassing cares and responsibilities...
... which are the dismal adjuncts
of great rank and property.
And his life now...
... seemed to consist mostly of drafts
of letters to lawyers and money-brokers...
... and endless correspondence...
... with decorators and cooks.
Gentlemen, I'm going to leave you for
a few minutes. Carry on with your work.
Yes, sir.
Bully.
What does...
...''strenuous'' mean?
Bryan, I'm trying to work.
But what does it mean?
It means ''an effort requiring strength.''
What does ''quadrangle'' mean?
A quadrangle is a four-sided figure
like a square or a rectangle.
Now, please be quiet,
and let me get on with my work.
Bryan, please be quiet!
Have you seen my pencil?
No, I haven't.
Bryan, please stop making so much noise.
That's my pencil.
No, it isn't.
It is. It's my pencil!
I've had this all morning.
It's my pencil!
Listen, will you be quiet!
I'll teach you a lesson.
What the devil's going on in here?
I told you never
to lay a hand on this child.
One.
Two.
Six.
Will that be all, Mr. Redmond Barry?
Yes, that will be all.
Well then, look you now.
From this moment, I will submit
to no further chastisement from you.
I will kill you, if you lay hands
on me ever again.
Is that clear to you, sir?
Get out of here!
Don't you think he fits my shoes
very well, Your Ladyship?
Dear child...
...what a pity it is I'm not dead,
for your sake.
The Lyndons would then have
a worthy representative...
...and enjoy all the benefits...
...of the illustrious blood
of the Barrys of Barryville.
Would they not...
...Mr. Redmond Barry?
From the way I love this child...
...you ought to know how
I would've loved his elder brother...
...had he proved worthy
of any mother's affection.
Madam!
I have borne as long
as mortal could endure...
...the ill-treatment of the insolent Irish
upstart whom you've taken to your bed.
It is not only his lowly birth and the
brutality of his manners which disgust me.
But the shameful nature of his conduct
toward Your Ladyship...
...his brutal and ungentlemanlike
behaviour...
...his open infidelity...
...his shameless robberies and swindling
of my property, and yours.
And as I cannot personally chastise
this low-bred ruffian, and cannot bear...
...to witness his treatment of you...
...and loathe his company
as if it were the plague...
...I have decided to leave my home
and never return.
At least, during his detested life...
...or during my own.
Will anyone be joining
Your Lordship?
No, I shall be alone.
The roast beef's very good, My Lord.
Hello, Neville. How are you?
Ah, Barry. Hello.
I see you're alone.
Why don't you join me?
Oh, thank you, Barry,
you're very kind, but...
...I'm expecting someone to join me.
What a shame! Lady Lyndon and I
have missed your company lately.
Please give my respects to Lady Lyndon...
...and say I've been very busy of late
and not been able to go about much.
I shall.
The eighth of next month we're
having some guests over for cards...
...we'd love to have you
and Lady Wendover join us.
I'll check my diary, but I think
I'm engaged on that evening.
I hope you're not engaged.
We'd love to see you again.
I'll write and say if I'm free or not.
I look forward to hearing from you.
It's nice to see you again.
If he had murdered Lord Bullingdon...
... Barry could scarcely have been received
with more coldness and resentment...
... that now followed him
in town and country.
His friends fell away from him.
A legend arose of his cruelty
to his stepson.
Now all the bills came down
on him together.
All the bills he had been contracting
for the years of his marriage...
... and which the creditors sent in
with a hasty unanimity.
Their amount was frightful.
Barry was now bound up in an
inextricable toil of bills and debts...
... of mortgages and insurances,
and all the evils attendant upon them.
Lady Lyndon's income was hampered
almost irretrievably...
... to satisfy these claims.
Do you think that's good?
Excellent.
Who's this?
It's a peacock on the wall.
What's it say?
I saw this bird yesterday.
Who's that?
Mama in her coach.
Is she going to London?
I don't know.
Barry had his faults...
... but no man could say of him
that he was not a good and tender father.
He loved his son with a blind partiality.
He denied him nothing.
It is impossible to convey
what high hopes he had for the boy...
... and how he indulged
in a thousand fond anticipations...
... as to his future success
and figure in the world.
But fate had determined that he should
leave none of his race behind him...
... that he should finish his life...
... poor, lonely...
... and childless.
Papa.
Yes, Bryan?
Will you buy me a horse?
Buy you a horse?
Yes, Papa.
But you already have little Julia.
She's only a pony, I want a real horse.
Then I can ride with you on the hunt.
You think you're big enough for the hunt?
Oh, yes!
Jonathan Plunkett is only a year older
than I am and he rides with his papa.
I'll have to think about it.
Please, say yes. There's nothing I want
in the whole world more than a horse.
I'll think about it.
Oh, thank you, Papa. Thank you!
How much are you asking for him?
One hundred guineas.
He's a nice little horse,
but I don't think he's worth that.
Seventy-five seems
more like the right price.
I'll accept eighty guineas,
and not a shilling less.
Five guineas should never keep two
gentlemen from their drink. Eighty then.
Done, sir.
Take the horse to Doolan's farm.
Tell him he needs a bit of breaking in.
Say it's for Master Bryan's birthday,
and I want it to be a surprise.
And remember that yourself.
Papa.
What is it, lad?
Did you buy that horse?
What horse is that?
The horse you were going
to buy me for my birthday.
I know nothing about any horse.
But one of the stable boys told Nelly
you'd already bought it...
...and it was at Doolan's farm
where Mick the groom was breaking it in.
Is that true?
When is your birthday?
Next Tuesday.
Well, you'll have to wait till then
to find out.
Then, it's true! Oh, thank you, Papa.
Yes, Mama?
Promise me you won't ride that horse
except with your father.
Yes, Mama, I promise.
And I promise you a good flogging...
...if you even go to Doolan's farm
to see him before your birthday.
Yes, Papa.
You understand?
You promise me?
Yes, Papa, I promise.
All right, eat your food.
I'm sorry to trouble you, Mr. Lyndon...
...but I believe Master Bryan
has disobeyed you...
...and stolen away to Doolan's farm.
On going to his room this morning,
I found his bed empty.
One of the cooks saw him
cross the yard at daybreak.
Didn't you see him go?
He must have passed through my room
while I was asleep.
Oh, my God! What has happened here?
I noticed the lad riding
across the field, sir...
... and having trouble with the horse,
which was playing up.
Suddenly the animal plunged and reared,
and the poor lad was thrown.
Oh, Bryan, why did you disobey me?
I'm sorry, Papa.
You won't whip me, will you?
No, my darling.
I won't whip you.
Take my horse and ride like the Devil
for Doctor Broughton.
Tell him whatever he's doing
he must come at once. Understand?
The doctors were called.
But what does a doctor avail in a contest
with the grim, invincible enemy?
Such as came could only confirm
the hopelessness of the poor child's case.
He remained with his parents
for two days.
And a sad comfort it was to know
that he was in no pain.
Papa.
Am I going to die?
No, my darling, you're not going to die.
You're going to get better.
But I can't feel anything,
except in my hands.
Does that mean I'm already dead
in part of my body?
No, my darling, that's where
you were hurt by the horse.
But you're going to be all right.
Papa, if I die, will I go to heaven?
Of course you will, my darling...
...but you're not going to die.
Mama, give me your hand.
Papa, give me your hand.
Will you both promise me something?
Yes.
Promise me never to quarrel so.
But to love each other.
So that we may meet again, in heaven...
...where Bullingdon said
quarrelsome people will never go.
We promise.
Will you tell me the story
about the fort?
Of course.
We crept up on the fort.
I jumped over the wall first,
and my fellows jumped after me.
And you should have seen the look...
...on the Frenchmen's faces when
23 he-devils, sword and pistol...
...cut and thrust,
came tumbling into the fort.
In three minutes...
...we left...
'''I am the resurrection and the life,'
saith the Lord.
'''He that believeth in me,
though he were dead...
'''... yet shall he live.
'''And whosoever liveth
and believeth in me...
'''... shall never die.'
''I know that my Redeemer liveth...
''... and that He shall stand
at the latter day upon the earth.
''And though after my skin
worms destroy this body...
''... yet in my flesh shall I see God.
''Whom I shall see for myself
and mine eyes shall behold...
''... and not another.
''We brought nothing into this world...
''... and it is certain
we can carry nothing out.
''The Lord gave,
and the Lord hath taken away.
''Blessed is the name of the Lord.''
Barry's grief was inconsolable.
Such solace as he could find,
came only from drink.
His mother was the only person who would
remain faithful to him in his misfortune.
And many a night, when he was
unconscious of her attention...
... saw him carried off to bed.
''O blessed Lord...
''... the Father of mercies
and God of all comforts.
''We beseech Thee, look down
in pity and compassion upon this...
''... Thy afflicted servant.
''Thou writest bitter things against her...
''... and makest her to possess
her former iniquities.''
Her Ladyship,
always vapourish and nervous...
... plunged into devotion...
... with so much fervour, that you would
have imagined her distracted at times.
In the doleful conditions
which now prevailed at Castle Hackton...
... management of the household,
and of the Lyndon estate...
... fell to Mrs. Barry,
whose spirit of order...
... attended to all the details
of a great establishment.
You wish to see me, madam?
Yes, Reverend. Please sit down.
I have some matters I would like
to discuss later, Graham...
...but just now would you go
to Her Ladyship...
...and have her sign these papers.
Yes, madam.
Reverend Runt...
...I need not tell you
that the recent tragedy to this family...
...has made the services of a tutor
no longer required here.
And as we are in considerable difficulty
about money...
...I'm afraid I must ask you,
with the greatest reluctance...
...to resign your post.
Madam, I'm sensible
to your predicament...
...and you need have no concern about
my wages, I can willingly forego them...
...but it is out of the question for me
to leave Her Ladyship in her present state.
I'm sorry to say this to you...
...but I believe you are largely responsible
for her present state of mind.
The sooner you leave,
the better she will be.
Madam, with the greatest respect...
...I take my instructions
only from Her Ladyship.
Reverend Runt...
...Her Ladyship is in no fit mind
to give instructions to anyone.
My son has charged me with managing
the affairs at Castle Hackton...
...until he recovers from his grief and
resumes his interest in worldly matters.
While I'm in charge...
...you'll take your instructions from me.
My only concern is for Lady Lyndon.
Madam...
...your only concern is
for Her Ladyship's signature.
You and your son have almost succeeded
in destroying a fine family fortune.
And what little remains for you...
...depends on keeping Her Ladyship
prisoner in her own home.
Reverend Runt...
...this matter bears
no further discussion.
You will pack your bags
and leave by tomorrow.
God, help. Help!
In the midst of these great perplexities...
... Her Ladyship made an attempt
to kill herself by taking poison.
Though she only made herself
dangerously ill...
... due to the very small amount
which she swallowed...
... this, nevertheless, caused
an intervention from a certain quarter...
... which was long overdue.
Oh, my God!
If my mother had died...
...it would've been as much
my responsibility...
...as if I had poured
the strychnine for her myself.
For to the everlasting disgrace
of my family name...
...I have, by my cowardice,
and by my weakness...
...allowed the Barrys
to establish a brutal...
...and ignorant tyranny over our lives...
...which has left my mother
a broken woman...
...and to squander and ruin
a fine family fortune.
My friends profess sympathy,
but behind my back...
...I know I am despised.
And quite justifiably so.
However...
...I know now what I must do.
And what I shall do.
Whatever be the cost.
Good morning, My Lord.
Good morning.
Is Mr. Barry Lyndon here?
Yes, My Lord, he's inside.
Mr. Redmond Barry.
The last occasion on which we met...
...you wantonly caused me injury
and dishonour.
In such a manner, and to such an extent
no gentleman can willingly suffer...
...without demanding satisfaction...
...however much time intervenes.
I have now come to claim
that satisfaction.
Mr. Lyndon...
...these are a matched pair of pistols,
and as you have seen...
...your second has loaded one,
and I have loaded the other.
As they belong to Lord Bullingdon,
you may have whichever one you wish.
Lord Bullingdon.
Now, gentlemen, to determine
who will have first fire...
...I will toss a coin in the air.
As the offended party, it is
Lord Bullingdon's choice to call the toss.
Is that agreeable to both of you?
Yes.
If Lord Bullingdon calls correctly
he will have the first fire.
If incorrectly, Mr. Lyndon
will have the first fire.
Is that clearly understood?
What is your call, Lord Bullingdon?
Heads.
It is heads.
Lord Bullingdon will have the first fire.
Lord Bullingdon...
...will you take your ground?
One... two... three...
...four... five... six...
...seven... eight... nine... ten.
Mr. Lyndon, will you take your ground?
Mr. Lyndon, are you ready to receive
Lord Bullingdon's fire?
Yes.
Lord Bullingdon...
...cock your pistol...
...and prepare to fire.
Sir Richard, this pistol must be faulty.
I must have another one.
I'm sorry, Lord Bullingdon,
but you must first stand your ground...
...and allow Mr. Lyndon his turn to fire.
That is correct, Lord Bullingdon.
Your pistol has fired,
and that counts as your shot.
Mr. Lyndon, are the rules of firing
clear to you?
Yes.
Lord Bullingdon...
...are you ready to receive
Mr. Lyndon's fire?
Yes.
Very well, then.
Mr. Lyndon...
...cock your pistol...
...and prepare to fire.
Are you ready, Lord Bullingdon?
Is your pistol cocked, Mr. Lyndon?
Yes.
Then prepare to fire.
One...
...two...
Lord Bullingdon, in view of Mr. Lyndon
having fired into the ground...
...do you now consider
that you have received satisfaction?
I have not received satisfaction.
Mr. Lyndon, are you ready?
Yes.
Lord Bullingdon...
...cock your pistol
and get ready to fire.
One...
...two...
Barry was carried to an inn nearby
and a surgeon was called.
I'm nearly finished.
I'm sorry to have to tell you this,
Mr. Lyndon.
I'm afraid you'll have to lose the leg...
...most likely below the knee.
Lose the leg?
What for?
The simple answer is to save your life.
The ball has shattered the bone
below the knee and severed the artery.
Unless I amputate, there's no way
that I can repair the artery...
...and stop the hemorrhage.
Graham.
Yes, My Lord?
When we arrive at Castle Hackton,
inform Mrs. Barry of what has happened.
Don't go into any unnecessary detail.
Just tell her where he is
and that he has been wounded in the leg.
She will want to go to him.
See that she is out of the house and
on her way to London as soon as possible.
And in no event...
...is she to be allowed to see my mother...
...or create any disturbance at the house
before she leaves.
Yes, My Lord.
Mrs. Barry, how do you do?
How nice to see you, Graham.
Come in.
Thank you.
You... received my note?
Yes, we were expecting you.
Oh, good, I didn't want
to call unannounced.
Mr. Lyndon, how are you feeling?
I'm feeling much better,
thank you, Graham.
Won't you sit down?
Thank you, Mrs. Barry.
Would you like some tea?
Oh, no! No, thank you, Mrs. Barry.
Not just now.
How's the world treating you, Graham?
Oh, not too bad.
Are you comfortable here?
Most comfortable.
Good, good!
Shall we get down to the matter at hand?
By all means.
Mr. Lyndon...
...Lord Bullingdon has instructed me...
...to offer you an annuity...
...of 500 guineas a year for life.
Specifically on the condition of your...
...leaving England...
...and to be stopped...
...the instant of your return.
Lord Bullingdon has also asked me
to point out to you...
...that should you decide to remain here...
...your stay would infallibly plunge you...
...into jail.
As in view of the present circumstances
there will soon be...
...innumerable writs taken out
against you for...
...debts long-outstanding...
...and your credit is so blown that...
...you could not hope...
...to raise a shilling.
Utterly baffled and beaten...
... what was the lonely
and broken-hearted man to do?
He took the annuity and returned
to Ireland with his mother...
... to complete his recovery.
Sometime later he travelled abroad.
His life there, we have not the means
of following accurately.
He appears to have resumed
his former profession of a gambler...
... without his former success.
He never saw Lady Lyndon again.
Subtitles conformed by
SOFTITLER