New Delhi's National Sports stadium..
The stadium is filled to the brim.
Only 2 minutes left in the
World Men's Hockey Championship..
lndia is one goal behind Pakistan.
Vijay, pass it here!
lndian Captain Kabir Khan, Asia's
best center forward pushing his team
Come on! Come on!
Suspense in the audience.
Tension on the faces
of the officials..
Like every lndia-Pakistan match,
this match means so much
more than the game itself.
Only 1 and a half minutes now
and lndia will have to
fight quickly to save itself.
Ball with Pakistani
defender Waseem.. Scoop!
But lndian defender Uttam Singh
snatches it.. lndia is now on attack!
And a penalty stroke for lndia..
A breath of life
they desperately need..
But who will take this stroke..
Ball! Ball!
Saini has the ball, but Captain
Kabir is taking the stroke himself..
Maybe a good decision.
lndia's best player
is its last hope...
Coach, is this the same team
that defeated Pakistan last year?
No comments.
Do you not think our
team is taking it too easy?
Please, please, no comments.
Hey, look, it is Kabir!
- Kabir!
He is here!
- Kabir.. Kabir.. Kabir,
do you have anything to say
about such an embarrassing defeat?
Do you really believe
Pakistan's performance was better?
Maybe. - Why did you take
the penalty stroke yourself?
l made a mistake
Rumour has it that the Pakistani
players are your good friends..
you were the only lndian to
congratulate them after the match..
Excuse me!
People are saying..
there is a rumour that you..
or someone else in the lndian team
has deliberately thrown this match?
Excuse me!
Do you think we lost
because someone sold out?
What! What did you say?
Kabir Khan, has
someone sold out their team?
Sold out! You piece of..
How dare you..
How can you disrespect the media!
Disrespect the media!
You son of a.. Come here.
You do not know how
to treat journalists!
You bloody -.. sold out
Come back here!
You just witnessed a
frustrated captain of the loosing
team attack the media violently.
His outburst cannot
hide the fact that there..
..is definitely
something fishy going on.
We have our answers.
But it is now up to
you to decide whether
Kabir Khan has played
dirty with the country or not.
Satyavrat Yadav,
National Stadium, New Delhi..
News from the world of sports.
Pakistan has become the
new Hockey World Champions
after defeating lndia by one goal.
Today the Chairman of the
Hockey Association denounced
Kabir Khan, declared he
did his country wrong.
And all this is thanks to you..
the lndian public.
We have two special guests..
Down with Kabir!
What do you think? Did
Kabir Khan fix the match?
Do not know if he fixed the match,
but we lost because of him.
And what would you say?
These people should
be hung upside down.
And you?
These kind of people should have
moved to Pakistan during the partition.
Down with Kabir!
The public is upset with
the team's performance.
And Kabir Khan has
conveniently disappeared.
He was not at the hockey stadium, nor
the Sports Authority of lndia Campus.
Where is Kabir Khan?
Do not look back mother, let us go.
How can l not, Kabir..
Your grandfather saved every
penny to build this house..
Your father's first pay check
went into making these windows..
l stepped into this
home as a young bride..
Whatever happens, l know all these
people will stand by us, trust me.
My master
TRAlTOR
Do not look there, son.
You can close your eyes if
you can not bear to see it..
l want to see everything.
TRAlTOR
Come son. Let us go!
The third colour of
your being, that was l
Papa, papa, l want to see
what a traitor looks like.
Come, see!
Your tune was the rhythm of my life
Just some food for the road..
Do you want us to be
thrown out of the neighbourhood?
My divine master, you are my pride
My master, my life is yours to take
So, what have you decided?
Uttamji, you are always
harping on the same thing.
What should we do about the coach?
Hey, why don't you
become their coach?
The Women's Hockey World Cup
is just three months away.
The team cannot just go
without any training..
No matter how much you
train them, they will loose..
The lndian Women's hockey
team has never achieved anything
and it never will.
lt is a government trip.
Why do you not go as their coach?
The team will be out in a
couple of matches. Exit!
You and your wife
could enjoy a holiday.
l do not get it - why do you not
take women's hockey seriously.
And we do no get why
you take it so seriously.
Uttamji, lndian women
are born to cook and clean.
They cannot run
around in short skirts.
How can an Association
member say such things?
lt is because we are
in the Association
and have travelled around the
world, that we can say such things.
Look, you have done your part and
selected the top 16 lndian players.
Punjab, Tamil Nadu,
Jharkand, Andhra, Railways.
You have even been to
remote Manipur and Mizoram.
But now where will you
find a coach? From the moon?
ls this also the girls' fault?
No, lt is not the girls' fault.
lt is the fault, of people like
you with expectations from them.
No sponsors.. no viewers..
no TV coverage, nor media..
Now which coach will want to jump
into this mess to ruin his career?
ls there anyone? No one.
There is one man.
Who?
Kabir.
Kabir Khan.
The Kabir Khan who..
Yes that one.
Since when has he developed
an interest in women's hockey?
He even left men's hockey years ago.
No one has seen him
for six-seven years.
You can see him now.
Where?
Outside. ln the reception.
Do not attack the opposing
team's goal but their minds.
You will win the goal automatically.
Sir
- Hmm?
You have been called inside.
Sir
- Kabir.
How many years has it..
Seven years, three months.. ten,
eleven, twelve, thirteen
7 years, 3 months, 14 days.
What.. what were you
doing all these years?
l was preparing for this meeting.
He wants to be the coach of
the lndian Women's Hockey Team.
You are not a child Mr. Kabir Khan.
You know in a country like ours,
a women's team exists just
as a formality, not a reality.
Your reputation is already..
And you wish to redeem your
name by coaching this team.
A team that is not fit to play
against European high schools.
This is exactly the team l want.
l do not understand..
l do not think you would.
So shall l consider myself hired?
ln any case, you do
not have another coach.
l have done all l could,
but you should think about it.
l have.
Kabir this not a team.
lt is a graveyard.
Why are you burying in it?
This team will never get
a better coach than you.
But think about yourself.
l am thinking about myself.
You have changed.
You have changed a lot.
l have not changed. Nothing has.
You know we did not lose
that match because of you.
You did all you could to
score a goal against Pakistan
But they scored against me, my
team, my country.. and my family.
Everybody is allowed one mistake.
Everybody?
Kabir, why have you come back?
To help this team to
win the World Cup.
Which is impossible..
ls what needs to be done.
when are your 16 girls coming?
They should reach here tomorrow
morning from their respective states.
States.. nothing has changed.
There were states then,
there are states now..
There you go..
Well ma'am, once again it looks like
the Association has
dumped all of lndia on us.
So these are the best?
That's what they say.
Wasn't she the
goalkeeper for the Railways?
What was her name?
Vidya.. Vidya Sharma.
Heard she got
married and quit hockey?
Well she's here..
100 rupees? My foot! ls
the meter for decoration?
The meter is broken, you
will have to give me 100.
l will give you 100 slaps!
- What sort of talk is that?
The kind you will understand! Take the
50 or l will shove the hockey stick!
Don't get angry.
Your head will
explode one of these days.
But grandma, you are not
saying anything to him.
ls he my baby or are you?
l am.
- So?
Cool down, come, come.. drink it in.
Hey! What the.. you brats!
Hey Komal!
These pansies! Thought
l'd show them how to play!
You haven't come
here to play with boys!
No.. just wanted to check out
whether these Delhi dudes can play.
There's no way l'm letting my
girl play in a big city like Delhi.
Come on. Let's go,
get back in the car
Oh come now! We have come this far..
Let her do what
she wants. After all,
she will be playing a home
maker for the rest of her life.
l will never give up playing!
Oh yeah? What will you feed
your husband when he is hungry?
This!
Enough! l don't want
my girl playing hockey.
Once she slips out of our grasp,
who will ask for her hand?
Let them try!
Gul, your grandfathers,
your father, your brother
all have excelled in
this game, my dear.
Now it is your turn.
Don't let the lqbals down.
Name please.
- Ho?
Ho? Name. What is your name?
Soimoi.
l asked for your name.
Not your medical condition.
Soimoi.
ls that your name?
- Ho.
Ho again? Your full name..
name! Name!
Soimoi Kerketa. She
doesn't understand English.
And you are?
- Rani (Queen)
Have you escaped from an asylum?
What do you want?
Rani Dispotta.
Are you from the travelling theatre?
The stadium won't be
available till the new year. Go away!
Ghamorni.. state board.. Jharkhand..
Oh dear!
These two are hockey players!
Ho, ho, ho!
Name?
- Nethra Reddy.
So you are a Madrasi?
Telegu.
Tamil.
Not Tamil, Telegu.
Same thing. What's the
difference between Tamil and Telegu?
The same difference that is
there between Punjabi and Bihari.
Oh really?
Can l go?
What?
Ho ho!
Man! Look at that vanilla ice
cream amidst all this chocolate!
Must be heading to a
disco or a nightclub..
Looks like they lost their way.
You think they are players?
Definitely players. But not here..
Ya? Wonder what
the going rates are..
Why don't you ask them? They
won't get our language anyway
Hey, how much are those melons for?
What the.. They understand Hindi!
Thought they were
Chinese or Nepali..
Molly Zimik, Manipur.
Mary Ralte, Mizoram.
Wow! You have come from the
furthest reaches of lndia.
You are our special guests. Welcome!
What.. are you not happy?
Would you be happy being treated
like an alien in your own country?
Bindia, Aliya how are you?
Pretty fit.
How's your injury Gunjan?
An injury madam will take
its own sweet time to go.
You are the senior players.
Behave like one.
Be respectful around the new coach.
Respect, madam, will
take its own time to come.
Sukhlal! Become older!
My name is Kabir Khan. l'm the Coach
of the lndian National
Women's Hockey Team..
which l have been
told are you girls.
All the players here, Krishnaji?
Yes sir. Only one's missing..
Uh, Preeti Sabarwal
Reporting time was 10 am, wasn't it?
Excuse me!
ls this the
registration for the women's team?
The registration for the lndian
National Women's team is over.
Bloody hell! l'm Preeti Sabarwal.
Bloody hell Preeti Sabarwal!
You are very late. Try next year.
Sorry?
Next year.
- Next year!
Everybody, fall in line please!
Ho?
Come on everyone, line up.
She is a good player, sir.
l will be the judge of who is a
good player or a bad player Krishnaji.
Thank you.
You.. you can't keep out
a state team captain..
Which state team's captain are you?
- Chandigarh
ls this the Chandigarh team?
No.
But l'm a captain of a state team.
And l'm the coach of the
lndian National Women's Team.
l cannot hear or see
the names of states.
l can only hear the name
of one country - lndia.
And in that team, there is
no place for late comers.
Everyone understand that?
OK..OK, kit up.
Kit up and do 10
rounds in exactly 7 minutes.
lf you are done in 7 minutes,
come join the team.
lf not, take the
train back to Chandigarh.
Sir, 7 minutes!
Sshhh, Krishnaji.
Now each player will step
forward and introduce herself.
You!
Balbir Kaur, Punjab
Again.
Break away from the
team and step aside.
Komal Chautala, Haryana
Out!
Molly Zimik, Manipur
- Out!
Nethra Reddy, Andhra Pradesh
Out
- Rachna Prasad, Bihar.
Nichola Sequeira, Maharashtra
Out
Vidya Sharma, lndia
Hmm?
Once more loudly.
Vidya Sharma, lndia
Thank you. You are on the team.
Anyone else who is playing for Punjab,
Himachal, Tamil Nadu, Railways?
Understand this once and for all,
because l won't repeat it.
This team needs only those
players who first play for lndia,
then for their teammates,
and then if they have any
life left, for themselves.
Not those who are playing for a
Government job or a Railway flat. Hmmm?
Ho!
Ho? Let's try one
more time. Come, please.
Balbir Kaur, lndia
Komal Chautala, lndia
Molly Zimik, lndia
Nethra Reddy, lndia
Rachna Prasad, lndia
Nichola Sequeira, lndia.
Vidya Sharma, lndia
Gul lqbal, lndia
Rani Dispotta, lndia
Soimoi Kerketa, lndia
Raynia Fernandes, lndia
Mary Ralte, lndia
Aliya Bose, lndia
Gunjan Lakhani, lndia
Bindia Naik, lndia
Preeti Sabarwal, lndia
Come on, move it, move it
Didi(elder sister), didi! You
are Bindia Naik, aren't you?
You hold a National
record of 42 goals!
So?
l am so happy to meet you!
Yay! Go dance then!
On the list this is my bed.
There's the list. Go sleep there.
Forget it Molly!
Correct.
Hello! l am Nethra.
Vidya.
l know. You saved 4 goals in
the South Zone tournament.
Didn't save them,
just happened somehow.
lt was all luck.
Only good players have good 'luck'.
Whoa.. what's this?
Ho?
What is this?
'Moke daayar se laglak'
She is saying a branch scraped her
while travelling on an elephant.
You came to Delhi on an elephant?
No, only till Gha-morni. (morni
- peacock)
Peacocks? What peacock?
Peacocks, elephants..
You live in a zoo?
Jharkhand. We are from Jharkhand.
[Jhadi=bush]
Oh! Lots of bushes there?
Jungle. lt is a jungle there.
Jungle? Are you Junglees?
You eat snakes and scorpions? l
hope there aren't any in your bag?
Are you upset?
Alright! Here
- you sleep on the floor.
What are you doing?
Sorry?
Nothing to be sorry about..
move this..
What the
- What do you think you're doing?
This is my bed.
Did you not see
this big bundle here?
So?
So? l put it here first,
so the bed is mine.
Just because you dumped
this bundle, it is your bed?
Of course! Haven't you
ever been on a state bus?
l have reserved this bed first!
lt is mine on the list.
Oh you.. what the..
l will smash your face!
Hey kid!
Get here.
C'mon!
There is a time and
place for every fight.
Save this one for another day
- when you have the upper hand.
Get out!
Come. Be on this side with us.
The travelling theatre
would have been better!
l am told that from
the 250 million girls
in this country you are
the 16 best hockey players.
You're lucky, but also unlucky.
Because now l'll be the judge.
For me, you are only 16
girls who dabble in hockey.
Don't expect anymore.
You'll regret it.
Ten kilometers. Everyone Come on!
Come on, girls!
Training us for a
marathon or a match?
Hey!
Running at 4am won't make
us better hockey players.
How dare he treat national
players like this! We're not kids.
Does he think we
don't know how to train?
Move, you..
Take your positions.
What's going on?
What's the problem?
You are playing right in.
But sir..
l think you will
play better as right in.
But.. l have always played
center forward for our Haryana team..
Ok, go! Play for the Haryana team.
Everybody in position!
What is it?
Coach sir has instructed me
to play on the forward line.
Go home and play.
Listen
- push her out and take her place.
But the coach has asked me
to play in this position.
So if the coach asks you
to jump in a well, you will?
But the coach..
Look, coaches will come and go.
But you will be with us, right?
Yes, but coach..
See, she's leaving to
drink water. Grab her place.
Don't take my name.
What's going on?
l play forward every year.
Yes but in this team
you are the centre..
This team or that team it
doesn't make a difference.
lt makes a difference to the team.
You're a senior player,
a strong player.
The team needs you at centre half.
Go to your new position.
Sorry.
Hmmm.
Out.
What..
Sit out and let the
others play.. Out!
Move!
Good goal! Very
good Preeti Sabarwal!
Come on everyone, back to one!
Komal! Pass the ball!
l'm free, dammit, pass the ball!
Komal! Komal!
What was that?
l scored a goal sir!
Out!
But you didn't see
what that girl was up to!
l saw everything
that's going on here.
When she scored the goal
there was no one around her,
But when you scored, she was there.
And the only one in
the scoring position ..
Out!
Everybody can only see the
Memsahib but are blind to her faults.
The British have gone but left
behind their Memsahibs in cities.
Just step in my village once!
lf l don't tie you up with the
buffalo's tail, you can change my name.
Coach took Memsahib's side.
He's only a coach, not God.
Come let us rest for a while.
Hey!
Out..
So chowmein! Get angry once more and
They will pour chilli
sauce on you and chew you up.
Come, come here!
Take it, take it, take it, damn you!
Moka! Moka (Pass to me!)
Stop it, stop that, stop the ball..
You piece of.. go kill
yourself or l will kill you.
The bloody..
What happened?
Did you not see? This
witch let them score a goal!
You know she can not
understand Punjabi.
She should have learnt
it before coming here!
She was only supposed to have
learnt hockey. Which she has.
Apologize to her.
l have never apologized
- not even to my father!
Out..
What!
Out! Out!
Why do you not tell her off?
She is not worth talking to
l have always said
- do not play with Junglees!
You look very angry.
You looked like you
would break her head..
Should l break yours?
Sir, how long should
these girls be benched?
Don't know.
l do not think anyone can teach
these girls to play hockey together.
Teaching them hockey
is a long way off.
l need to teach them
something else first.
Good evening!
What is going on?
New sleeping arrangements?
Old.. according to the old list.
So? Tell them the list tore..
come on, go to your old place.
No girl will stay with
another girl from her own state.
lt is the Coach's order.
So let him say it. Who cares?
Everyone else has agreed.
lf you have any
problems speak to the coach.
Bake in sun all day,
switch beds at night..
ls this a National
camp or a refugee camp?
Why doesn't he make every
one sleep on the benches?
How are you?
l have had enough, please come back.
l cannot come.
lt is uncle Samir's sister's wedding.
Mom and dad asked me to call you.
Rakesh you know this
is the National camp-
But Vidya..
Look, family comes first,
games later..
But, father-in-law..
Look, you insisted,
so we let you play.
Now we are calling you, so
come back by the next train.
Yes.. but l..
Rakesh please understand.
l cannot come.
l have waited a long
time for this camp.
Vidya, you are a saint.
But l am not.
l cannot keep waiting. The
wedding is day after tomorrow.
Come if you want or forget it.
So?
They wanted a
traditional daughter-in-law..
..grandchildren, the
whole work from me..
..but all l have is
this hockey stick.
Oh! ls this how you scare them away?
lf you want, you can go
home for a couple of days.
lf l go now, l will not come back.
lt is either this side. Or that.
But.. When you
were getting married..
l told them everything.
They were thrilled then..
l had a job thanks to the sports
quota as well as a government flat.
So now?
They have gotten used to the flat,..
..now they want somebody
who will take care of it.
You think lt is crime to
play hockey in this country?
No, no you can play politics,
cricket..
you sure can play cricket!
But hockey?
lt is a little difficult.
Have you heard of
Mohammad bin Tuglaq?
ls he cute?
He was an emperor
- five hundred years ago.
Crazy guy! Drove everyone mad.
Stopped making gold and
silver coins for copper ones.
Out in five years.
That is how this
coach is going to go.
Thinks he can do anything.
lf you have such a sharp brain,
why do you not use when you play?
He will be out in a few days.
The Association will kick him out.
The system does not work like this.
The name suits him
- Tuglaq.
Molly, Balbir,
Komal,
Bindia, Aliya -
You are benched.
So till we do not play by his
rules he will not let us play.
Tuglaq has lost it.
Alright. We are no less.
We will now play
only at the tournament.
Sir! Hey sir!
Sir, l would like to play too.
Ok, Ok.. l am really sorry.
Sorry
Hey, ok enough.. come on,
accept my apology
Accepting it, or should l hit you?
Sorry.
Really sorry.
Actually, she is not a bad player.
When she whacks the ball hard,
it takes four girls to stop it.
Admiring your enemy?
Please do not pull my leg, didi.
The coach has already
stopped us from playing.
And then..
Oh man..
Oh.. oh!
Come didi, let us play..
lf we play, we will play in our
own positions. Shut up and sit down.
God, look there is
bull chasing her..
You've already scored your forty
two goals. l haven't even started.
Sir let me also get a
pardon from the memsahib.
Hey missy, do you want
to accept my apology?
Or do you prefer going to the jail?
- What?
Look, if you do not
pardon me, l will fight you..
in the fight either l will smash
your head or you will smash mine
and we will have to go to jail..
Anyway.. so tell me do you accept my
apology or should we go to the police?
Time is up. Come on!
Krishnaji, is anyone injured?
Ok, now we will
reverse the play order.
Defenders will attack
and attackers will defend.
Sorry sir!
Go attack! Ball on the centre.
With all your heart! Come on!
ln the World Cup final,
the team lost to Pakistan.
Wasn't he the team Captain?
Captain?
He was Pakistan's captain,
in an lndian uniform.
What are you saying?
lt is not only me. Everyone says so.
So how did they make him the coach?
This is lndia. Anything is possible.
He mentioned taking
us to the World Cup.
He has already
sold his country once.
This time he may
just sell us as well!
You guys will keep scrubbing
shoes for the rest of your life.
Come, see who is downstairs.
- Who?
Take a wild guess
ls it a film star?
Abhimanyu Singh!
You are kidding!
What!
Go see for yourself. Bro
is here to meet someone.
He maybe your 'brother'!
But who is he here for?
Come! Let us see!
Let us go
She is a sly one.. did not
tell anyone she is his fianc?e..
Coach has given her
leave till tomorrow morning..
Wow!
Leave till tomorrow morning.
Why, whatever will
they do all night long?
lt is confirmed.
They are making me the Vice Captain.
Bullshit!
Really? l do not believe this!
l knew it. How long will
these clowns hold out.
Vice Captain of the
lndian frikkin cricket team!
Now you watch how l
teach all these seniors.
You see who rules this team now!
Get out of the way everyone!
lt is my turn now.
Why do you not quit all this now?
Quit what?
Your silly stick & ball game
Come on baby, forget about it now.
Forget about it and do what?
Do what? Live it up!
Be with me! Travel
the world with me.
Live life king-size, with the King.
As the wife of the Vice
Captain of the lndian Cricket team!
Wife?
Oh, forgot to tell you.
Had a chat with your dad
over drinks yesterday.
l told him l am all for it.
He said we do not want
to delay it anymore.
So it is all fixed.
Anyway, my career is all set.
And what about my career?
What?
What about my career?
What career?
Abhi, l am in the lndian hockey team
Yeah but that is not a career,
Preeti. That is just a stupid game.
So is cricket
Preeti! l know you like to think of
your little dribbling and
stick work as a big thing.
But let us face it
- it is not exactly cricket is it?
Look at her enjoying herself!
Damn it, let us go play.
Come on, we have been rotting on
this same bench for the last 7 days.
We are players, not
Association members who sit around.
Come on. Come on!
l will show him my game!
lf he is not forced to
make me a forward again,
my name is not Bindia Naik.
Or his is not Tuglaq.
Sorry sir, it will not
happen again. We are sorry.
Sorry
Ok, you can play center half.
Thank God sir. The
situation is under control now.
No, Krishnaji. lt is just
about to go out of control.
Right! Left! Right! Left!
Faster! Faster! Faster!
Run faster! Move.
Faster! Faster! Run faster!
l mean FAST!
Right, left, right! To the ball!
Ok, let's go! Right! Left!
Pass the ball! Make a pass! Pass,
pass, pass, pass, pass, pass PASS!
Thank you.
Trap and pass! Move the
ball ahead! Come on, move it!
No player will keep the
ball for more than 5 seconds.
Can you count? 5-4-3-2-1 !
Faster! Faster! Run faster!
l mean FAST! Quick, quick!
Faster, faster,
What is your problem? Do you not see
the ball, or are you afraid of it?
Want to practice with a
tennis ball for a few days?
Left, right, left!
Leave the ball, sit!
Go, right!
Go to hell!
Trap, look and pass! Stop,
look and move it ahead..
Do not move yourself forward.
Move the ball forward!
Do one thing pick up the ball.
PlCK lT UP! Put it in
your pocket and go home.
Go play on the Chandigarh team
from tomorrow. No need to play here.
And you! What are
you so angry about?
Raise your game first
and then raise your voice.
Once more if l hear you shout out,
you will be out!
Hey you! Why are
you the center half?
Because you are the senior
most player in the team.
Your job is not to push the
forward line but to teach them.
And one more thing.
There can only be one
bully in every team.
And for this team, it is me.
You! Call this a pass?
You are only good enough to
plough fields in your village.
Forget about hockey!
And why are you standing around?
Go get the ball!
Right, left, right,
left, right, left! Relax!
Nethra!
Krishnaji! Give her water
and take her out! Quickly!
So! You are lndia's best players!
You will go to the
World Championship! Hah!
To raise lndia's flag!
The Association is right.
How will this lot ever play hockey!
They cannot play as
one team. How the hell..
..will they ever win
a World Championship!
What are you staring at?
She is unconscious not dead!
Krishnaji! Take her away! Out!
l had said it on the first day.
This team needs only those
who first play for lndia,
then for their team mates
and then if there is any
life left, for themselves.
Let's start again.
Right!
So! Did you see what happens when
you let the coach think he is God!
The blood will not stop.
l warned you guys.
Do you want to eat something?
Wake up at 4am, run for 20 km. And
on the field, he does not let us play.
What kind of a camp is this?
Does it hurt a lot?
Here! lt hurts here.
He insulted us!
Hit with the ball!
He knows damn well you
cannot speak English.
But you have to learn it!
What you have not learnt in your
whole life, learn it in a day!
Else get out of the team.
Hey, he cannot throw you out!
Do not worry, l will teach you.
How can he cut you out of the team?
What do you say Aliya?
No freedom to eat, to move around
and when we play, he insults us.
This is not a primary school. Each
girl is a National level player.
A champion from her state
- that is why she is here.
lf there is any failure
amongst us, lt is him.
Sold his team out in the World Cup!
Was thrown out of
the team, the country.
What else can l say? l am
ashamed to say any more.
Does it hurt?
l have a spray..
How is Nethra?
OK. The doctor says she will be
back to practice in a couple of days.
Practice? Have you lost it?
From now on, there
will be no practice!
There will be no
practice from tomorrow!
Look here..
You look here! We know you like him
but you should also realise
that the team is on this side.
lt is time you choose
which side you're on.
Yes.
Definitely.
l have thought about it.
Now only the Association can
decide how this team should run.
The way teams have
always run in this country.
Or the way Tuglaq wants it!
Let us sign this.
Now, it is either
the Coach or our team.
Sign this, Gul!
Sir..
Hmmm? Have some..
Wasn't that too much?
They are girls after all.
How much can you push them?
lf you look for the
strength of boys..
l am not looking for strength.
l am looking for team spirit.
You do not need strength to make
a team. You need team spirit.
But sir, at this rate, you
will become their enemy.
lf by making me an enemy
they can become a team,
then it is a small
price to pay, Krishnaji.
Why are you not on the field?
What is the matter?
The team does not want
to practice with you.
What rubbish!
We want a new coach.
l will give you one -
Why Krishnaji? Why will you hit us?
We are not the ones
who sold our country!
Quiet!
- Sir!
7 years.
After 7 years l came back to hockey,
with the belief that this time
l will beat the one thing that
defeated my team once and for all.
But today, once again,
l have lost to it.
You do not have a problem with me.
You have a problem
with the fact that instead of
making you play against each other,
l am forcing you to
play with one another.
Because l have forced
you to think about..
..your team before you
think about yourself.
Forced you to play for lndia
before you play for your own state.
Fine. You have won. l have lost.
But l am not sorry loosing to you.
l am sorry l have
lost to my country.
Which even after taking my blood,
sweat, my love,..
..my life, does not believe
that l played for it once.
And l will play for it all my life.
l resign as the coach of this team.
Please, just think it over, Sir.
You have worked so hard.
Today is my last day in this camp.
Before l leave, l am
taking the staff out for lunch.
You are welcome to
join us if you wish.
No obligations.
Hi beautiful! Come on,
join us babes! Hey come on!
She's red hot ya! Hey baby, hey!
Harassing girls, are you? Try it!
Hey! Hey, how..
Balbir!
Hit him!
Do not let him go!
Not from behind. Have guts
to attack from the front.
You see, in hockey
there are no cowards.
ls this a team or an army of devils?
l told you, Krishnaji.
lt is not strength, but
spirit that makes a team.
For the first time, l
have seen team spirit.
Sir.. l was just..
just trying to say that..
l mean.. let
sleeping dogs lie.. l mean..
Hey tell him!
Sir what she means.. what we all
Tomorrow morning, 5 am sharp.
l want everyone on the field.
Chak De! lndia (Go lndia!)
Come, come, come.
We will run two
more kilometers today.
Come on guys!
Do something, do something
My veins are bursting
O please do something
Do something, do something
For talk and sermons bite the dust
lt is time to do something
Be stubborn if that is what it takes
Do or die
- all is at stake!
Chak De! lndia (Go lndia!)
ln the fighting kite,
in the riot of might
ln the games and the fair,
in the bumpy trains so bare
ln the sweetness of sugarcane,
in the clothes of the rich or vain
Seek and you will find,
heat that bricks bind
A colour has emerged, and
it is spreading converged
This colour of the reign,
is embedded in your veins
Stand immovable, invincible,
obstinate in times of trouble
Scraped and scarred,
move on even if marred
Be stubborn if that is what it takes
Do or die
- all is at stake!
Chak De! lndia (Go lndia!)
How can you go?
Why?
Because we are getting married!
What?
You can not go on the 25th, we
are getting married on the 2nd
What?
l have fixed the dates after
discussing it with your parents
And me? Do you not need
to discuss this with me?
What is the point of discussing it?
You want to get
married to me, do you not?
But, not like this! l need time.
What for?
l am playing for
the World Cup, Abhi!
Have you gone insane?
You want to postpone our
wedding for the World Cup?
What if it was your World cup?
That is a totally different.
lt is the Cricket World cup.
lt is really important.
This is really important.. for me
More important than our marriage?
l have to go. Good night!
Go. Go play the World cup..
lf you loose you
will become my wife.
lf you win, you
will become my wife..
lt is not like when you come back,
the whole country
will remember your name.
One thing l promise
you Mr. Abhimanyu..
This will definitely happen.
The team is shaping up well, sir.
The captain of this
team will be Vidya.
Congratulations, Vidya!
Give it a break.
l have nothing to say to you.
For the first time something
good is happening. Take part in it.
You already did!
The way Bindia is using her brain..
Do you think it is right
for her to be on the team?
l do not know Krishnaji..
but it is also not right..
..to keep the most
experienced player off the team.
l do not think we can..
deal with her
We cannot win without her either.
ls this not your
World Cup silver medal?
What are you doing with it?
Trying to scrub it into gold.
lf l ever need to sell
it in the flea market,
at least l will get a good price.
Mr. Kabir, it is best if you
forget about the World Cup.
And tell these girls as well.
The ones who you have
given such high hopes too.
But our deal was to train
this team for the World Cup.
lt was not like we signed on a legal
document you cannot hold us up to it.
You discussed it in
front of me, Mr. Tripathi.
We will discuss it in
front of you once more.
Look, on one hand,
there is the lndian men's team
which at least gets a bronze medal.
And on the other, there
is this team of misfits.
But this team is
ready for the World Cup!
Tomorrow if they are ready for
the moon, we should send them? Huh?
This team can not go the World Cup.
lt is decided.
Be honest. Tell us
you are taking money..
..from the Women's team
to give to the Men's team.
You guys are athletes.
Why do you want to get involved
in things that do not concern you?
Shall we?
But Mr. Tripathi!
Let us have a match.
What?
Yes. Let us have a match.
Between my team and your team.
You mean Men's
team v/s Women's team?
l mean between my
team and your team.
lf we loose, we loose. But
if we win, then - World Cup.
Think about what you
are saying, Mr. Kabir.
Do not make Pandavas' (lndian
mythological characters) bet
You will be left standing naked.
lt has already happened to you once.
All right. Day after morning.
But we need time to train!
Day after
- yes or no?
Mr. Tripathi..
Day after morning. We
will meet on the field.
Even your team needs to practice
Come out..
Shit!
We will never win. And
by some chance, if we do..
Chance! Huh!
lmagine how many
goals we will loose by.
And once we lose,
it is over forever!
What have you done, sir?
We are like sitting ducks.
Ducks? l have belief in this team.
Does this team believe in itself?
Come on! Let us go.
Look, you are not
playing against these boys.
Come on, get ready! Hurry!
Do not think
- here let me have it.