I shall tell you of William Wallace.
Historians from England
will say I am a liar,
but history is written by those
who have hanged heroes.
The king of Scotland
had died without a son,
and the king of England,
a cruel pagan known
as Edward the Longshanks,
claimed the throne of Scotland
for himself.
Scotland's nobles fought him
and fought each other over the crown.
So Longshanks invited them
to talks of truce,
no weapons, one page only.
Among the farmers of that shire
was Malcolm Wallace,
a commoner with his own lands.
He had two sons, John and William.
I told you to stay.
Well, I finished my work.
Where are we going?
MacAndrews'. He was supposed to visit
when the gathering was over.
-Can I come?
-No. Go home, boy.
But I want to go.
Go home, William,
or you'll feel the back of my hand.
Go you home, William.
MacAndrews!
Holy Jesus.
-It's all right!
-William! William!
William! William, it's all right.
It's all right. Easy, lad.
William.
And I say we hit back now!
-We cannot fight them! It's suicide!
-Something's got to be done.
Wallace is right! We fight them!
Every nobleman who had a will to fight
was at that meeting.
We cannot beat an army.
Not with 50 farmers.
We do not have to beat them,
just fight them.
Now, who's with me?
I am, Wallace.
All right, all right.
Ready.
Where do you think you're going?
I'm going with you.
You're going with me, are you?
-And what are you going to do?
-I'm gonna help.
And a good help you'd be, too,
but I need you to stay here
and look after the place for me
while I'm away.
I can fight.
I know. I know you can fight.
But it's our wits that make us men.
See you tomorrow.
-English.
-Get down.
With your father and brother gone,
they'll kill us and burn the farm.
It's up to us, Hamish.
Nah.
Da?
William.
Come here, lad.
Amen.
-Amen.
William.
I'm your uncle. Argyle.
You have the look of your mother.
We'll stay here tonight.
Tomorrow you'll come home with me.
I don't want to leave.
You didn't want your father to die either,
did you?
But it happened.
Did the priest give a poetic benediction?
''The Lord bless thee and keep thee''?
It was in Latin.
You don't speak Latin?
Well, that's something
we shall have to remedy, isn't it?
The Lord bless thee and keep thee.
The Lord cause his light
to shine on thee.
The Lord lift up
his countenance upon thee
and give thee peace.
Amen.
Your heart is free.
Have the courage to follow it.
What are they doing?
Saying goodbye in their own way.
Playing outlawed tunes
on outlawed pipes.
It was the same for me and your daddy
when our father was killed.
First, learn to use this.
Then I'll teach you to use this.
Many years later,
Edward the Longshanks,
King of England,
supervised the wedding
of his eldest son,
who would succeed him to the throne.
Amen.
As bride for his son,
Longshanks had chosen the daughter
of his rival,
the King of France.
It was widely whispered
that for the princess to conceive,
Longshanks would have to do
the honors himself.
That may have been
what he had in mind all along.
Scotland. My land.
The French will grovel
to anyone with strength,
but how will they believe our strength
when we cannot rule
the whole of our own island?
Where is my son?
Your pardon, milord.
He asked me to come in his stead.
I sent for him, and he sends you.
Shall I leave, milord?
If he wants his queen
to rule when I am gone,
then, by all means, stay and learn how.
Please.
Nobles.
Nobles are the key
to the door of Scotland.
Grant our nobles lands in the north,
give their nobles
estates here in England,
and make them too greedy
to oppose us.
But, sire,
our nobles will be reluctant to uproot.
New lands mean new taxes,
and they're already taxed
for the war in France.
Are they?
The trouble with Scotland
is that it's full of Scots.
Perhaps the time has come
to reinstitute an old custom.
Grant them prima nocte.
First night.
When any common girl inhabiting
their lands is married,
our nobles shall have sexual rights
to her on the night of her wedding.
If we can't get them out,
we'll breed them out.
That should fetch just the kind of lords
we want to Scotland,
taxes or no taxes.
-A most excellent idea, sire.
-Is it?
Now in Edinburgh were gathered
the council of Scottish nobles.
Among these was Robert,
the 17th Earl of Bruce,
a leading contender for the crown
of Scotland.
I hear that Longshanks
has granted prima nocte.
Clearly meant to draw more
of his supporters here.
My father believes that we must
lull Longshanks into our confidence
by neither supporting his decree
nor opposing it.
A wise plan.
And how is your father?
We missed him at the council.
His affairs in France
keep him long overdue.
But he sends his greetings,
and he says that I speak
for all of the Bruces and for Scotland.
It's all over now.
You've dropped your rock.
Test of manhood.
You win.
Call it a test of soldiery, then.
The English won't let us train
with weapons,
so we train with stones.
The test of a soldier is not in his arm.
It's here.
No. It's here.
Hamish?
Here you go, Son.
Show him how.
Come on, Hamish!
You'll never beat Hamish.
Come on there, boy!
My boy!
That's a good throw.
Aye. Aye, it was.
I was wondering if you could do that
when it matters.
As it matters in battle.
Could you crush a man with that throw?
I could crush you like a worm.
-You could?
-Aye.
Well, then, do it.
Would you like to see him crush me
like a worm?
Aye.
-Come do it.
-You'll move.
I will not.
Right.
He'll move.
Come on, Hamish.
Come on there, boy!
Well done!
Fine display, young Wallace.
Are you all right?
You look a wee bit shaky.
-I should have remembered the rocks.
-Aye, you should have.
Get up, you big heap.
It's good to see you again.
Aye. Welcome home.
-Got my head.
-Well, you should have moved.
William, will you dance with me?
Of course I will.
I've come to claim the right
of prima nocte.
As lord of these lands,
I will bless this marriage
by taking the bride into my bed
on the first night of her union.
By God, you will not!
It is my noble right.
Good evening, sir.
Young Wallace.
-Grand soft evening, huh?
-Aye, it's that.
I was wondering if I might have a word
with your daughter.
What do you want
to have a word with her about?
Well...
Murron, would you like to come
and ride with me on this fine evening?
In this? You're out of your mind.
It's good Scottish weather, madam.
The rain is falling straight down.
Slightly to the side, like.
-She can't go with you.
-No?
No the now, anyway.
-No the now.
-No the now?
We'll see you later.
The weather's just fine.
It's hardly raining.
Did you not hear what I said?
-Murron!
-Murron! Get...
It's you she takes after.
How did you know me after so long?
I didn't.
It's just... I saw you staring at me,
and I didn't know who you were.
I'm sorry. I suppose I was.
Are you in the habit of riding off
in the rain with strangers?
It was the best way to make you leave.
If I can ever work up the courage
to ask you again,
I'll send you a written warning first.
That wouldn't do you much good.
I can't read.
-Can you not?
-No.
Well, that's something
we shall have to remedy, isn't it?
-You're going to teach me to read, then?
-lf you like.
-Aye.
-In what language?
You're showing off now.
-That's right. Are you impressed yet?
-No. Why? Should I be?
Do that standing on your head,
and I'll be impressed.
My kilt will fly up, but I'll try it.
God, you certainly didn't learn
any manners on your travels.
The French and the Romans
have far worse manners than I.
-You've been to Rome?
-Aye, Argyle took me on a pilgrimage.
What was it like?
What does that mean?
Beautiful.
But I belong here.
Murron? Come in now.
Sir, I know it was strange of me
to invite Murron to ride last night,
but I assure you...
MacClannough's daughter
is another matter.
I've come to fetch you to our meeting.
-What kind of meeting?
-The secret kind.
Your meetings are a waste of time,
Campbell.
Your father was a fighter and a patriot.
I know who my father was.
I came back home to raise crops
and, God willing, a family.
-lf I can live in peace, I will.
-Go on.
You say you want to stay out
of the troubles?
Aye.
If you can prove it,
you may court my daughter.
Until you prove it, my answer's no.
No?
No, Wallace. No.
-Didn't I just prove it?
-No!
-No?
Of course,
running a farm's a lot of work,
but that will all change
when my sons arrive.
So you've got children?
Not yet, but I was hoping
that you could help me with that.
So you want me to marry you, then?
It's a bit sudden, but all right.
Is that what you call a proposal?
I love you. Always have.
I want to marry you.
Is that a yes?
-Aye, that's a yes.
-It is?
We best hurry. He'll be waiting.
-Wait.
-Where are you going?
-What's that?
-You'll see.
Father.
I will love you my whole life,
you and no other.
And I you,
you and no other, forever.
When am I going to see you again?
Tonight?
-I can't.
-Why not?
My dad's growing suspicious.
Growing suspicious, is he?
Wouldn't have anything to do with that,
would it?
When? When? When?
-When?
-Tonight.
Look lively, Sergeant.
Where are you going, lassie?
That looks heavy.
-Let me help you with it.
-No. It's fine.
I'm not going to steal it.
You remind me
of my daughter back home.
Hello, lassie.
No! No!
Keep it quiet, Smythe.
You bitch!
Are you all right?
All right? Come on.
-Are you all right?
-Aye.
Are you all right?
-Can you ride?
-Aye.
Come back here, you bastard!
Raise the alarm!
Help!
Meet me at the grove. Ride!
They're getting away!
Go round back!
Get her!
Come on!
You bitch!
Murron?
Murron!
All of you know full well
the great pains I've always taken
never to be too strict, too rigid
with the application of our laws.
And as a consequence,
have we not learned to live together
in relative peace and harmony?
And this day's lawlessness
is how you repay my leniency!
Well, you leave me with little choice.
An assault on the king's soldiers
is the same as an assault
on the king himself.
Now,
let this scrapper come to me.
Sir!
There.
Corporal.
Some archers on the tower. Now!
Hold still, Father.
You're an idiot, boy!
Father, you all right?
MacAulish.
MacAulish!
MacAulish! MacAulish!
-MacAulish! MacAulish!
-Wallace! Wallace!
Wallace! Wallace!
Wallace! Wallace! Wallace!
What you waiting for, boy?
Here. You can do it. I'll hold him down.
Here. You can do it.
I'll hold him down.
Pour it straight in the wound, boy.
I know it seems like a waste
of good whiskey.
Indulge me.
Hold him. Hold him.
Hold him. Now let him go.
I'm sorry. I'm sorry.
That'll wake you up in the morning, boy.
There's somebody coming!
Arm yourselves!
There's somebody coming.
MacGregors, from the next glen.
We heard about what was happening.
We don't want you amadans thinking
you can have your fun without us.
-That's right.
-Aye.
Go home.
Some of us are in this.
Can't help that now.
But you can help yourselves. Go home.
We'll have no homes left when
the English garrison from the castle
comes through and burns us out.
-And they will.
-Aye.
Welcome.
Patrol returning, milord!
So what news?
I have dispatched
100 soldiers to Lanark.
They will be returning now!
Were they dressed like this?
Actually, it was more like 50.
Make it quick.
You remember me?
I never did her any harm.
It was my right.
Your right?
Well, I'm here to claim the right
of a husband!
I am William Wallace,
and the rest of you will be spared.
Go back to England and tell them there
that Scotland's daughters
and her sons are yours no more.
Tell them Scotland is free.
Burn it.
Good job, milord.
Scottish rebels have routed
one of my garrisons
and murdered the noble lord.
I heard.
This Wallace is a brigand,
nothing more.
And how would you deal
with this brigand?
Like any common thief.
Have the local magistrate arrest him
and punish him accordingly.
Leave us.
Wallace has already killed
the magistrate
and taken control of the town.
Stand up.
In the morning,
I depart for France
to press our rights there,
and I leave you here
to quell this little rebellion.
Understood? Is it?
One day, you will be a king,
at least try to act like one.
Get away from me!
Convene my military council.
There!
After them.
No point resisting.
You're outnumbered and trapped.
Now, where are the rest of you?
Where's Wallace?
Father?
Come in. Come in.
A rebellion has begun.
Under whom?
A commoner named William Wallace.
You will embrace this rebellion.
Support it from our lands in the north.
I will gain English favor
by condemning it and ordering it
opposed from our lands in the south.
Sit down. Stay awhile.
This Wallace,
he doesn't even have a knighthood,
but he fights with passion,
and he inspires.
And you wish to charge off
and fight as he did?
So would I.
Well, maybe it's time.
It is time to survive.
You're the 17th Robert Bruce.
The 16 before you passed you land
and title because they didn't charge in.
-Call a meeting of the nobles.
-They do nothing but talk.
Rightly so.
They're as rich in English titles
and lands as they are in Scottish.
Just as we are.
You admire this man,
this William Wallace.
Uncompromising men
are easy to admire.
He has courage, so does a dog.
But it is exactly
the ability to compromise
that makes a man noble.
And understand this,
Edward Longshanks
is the most ruthless king
ever to sit on the throne of England,
and none of us and nothing of Scotland
will remain unless we are as ruthless.
Give ear to our nobles.
Knowing their minds
is the key to the throne.
Wait. Wait. Look.
-This is out, and this is left.
-Of course.
Carry on.
Carry on!
You know,
eventually, Longshanks will send
his whole northern army against us.
Heavy cavalry, armored horse.
Shake the very ground.
They'll ride right over us.
Uncle Argyle used to talk about it,
how no army had ever stood up
to a charge of heavy horse.
-So what do we do?
-Hit, run, hide, the Highland way.
We'll make spears.
Hundreds of them.
Long spears, twice as long as a man.
-That long?
-Aye.
Some men are longer than others.
Your mother been telling you stories
about me again.
Volunteers coming in!
William Wallace,
we've come to fight and to die for you.
Stand up, man. I'm not the Pope.
My name is Faudron. My sword is yours.
I brought you this.
We checked them for arms.
-My wife made it for you.
-Thank you.
Him? That can't be William Wallace.
I'm prettier than this man.
All right, Father. I'll ask him.
If I risk my neck for you,
will I get a chance to kill Englishmen?
Is your father a ghost,
or do you converse with the Almighty?
In order to find his equal,
an Irishman is forced to talk to God.
Yes, Father?
The Almighty says
don't change the subject,
just answer the fucking question.
Mind your tongue.
Insane Irish.
Smart enough to get a dagger
past your guards, old man.
That's my friend, Irishman,
and the answer to your question is yes.
You fight for me,
you get to kill the English.
Excellent!
Stephen is my name.
I'm the most wanted man on my island,
except I'm not on my island, of course.
More's the pity.
Your island? You mean Ireland?
Yeah. It's mine.
You're a madman.
I've come to the right place, then.
Sure didn't the Almighty
send me to watch your back?
I didn't like him anyway.
He wasn't right in the head.
William!
It's several runners!
The English are advancing
an army toward Stirling.
Do the nobles rally?
Robert the Bruce and most of the others
will not commit to battle,
but word has spread,
and the Highlanders
are coming down on their own.
Aye, in droves of hundreds
and thousands.
Are you ready for a war?
-Well, what news?
-We're outnumbered,
at least three to one.
-How many horse, then?
-Three hundred. Maybe more.
Three hundred heavy horse?
-We must try to negotiate.
-Well, who is in command?
-Did he have a scarlet chevron?
-Aye, he did.
We can still negotiate.
What are they talking about?
I can't hear, but it doesn't look good.
The nobles will negotiate.
They'll do a deal, then we go home.
If not, we charge.
Three hundred heavy horse,
we've no chance.
So many.
I didn't come here to fight
so they could own more lands.
Then I'll have to work for them.
Nor me.
All right, lads!
I'm not dying for these bastards.
Let's go home!
Stop, men! Do not flee!
Wait until we've negotiated!
William Wallace.
Can't be. Not tall enough.
The Almighty says
this must be a fashionable fight.
It's drawn the finest people.
Where is thy salute?
For presenting yourselves
on this battlefield, I give you thanks.
This is our army.
To join it, you give homage.
I give homage to Scotland,
and if this is your army
why does it go?
We didn't come here to fight for them!
Home! The English are too many.
Sons of Scotland,
I am William Wallace.
William Wallace is seven feet tall.
Yes, I've heard.
He kills men by the hundreds,
and if he were here,
he'd consume the English
with fireballs from his eyes
and bolts of lightning from his arse.
I am William Wallace,
and I see a whole army
of my countrymen
here in defiance of tyranny.
You've come to fight as free men.
And free men you are.
What will you do with that freedom?
Will you fight?
No! No! No!
Fight? Against that? No!
We will run, and we will live.
Aye.
Fight, and you may die.
Run, and you'll live.
At least awhile.
And dying in your beds
many years from now,
would you be willing to trade
all the days from this day to that
for one chance, just one chance,
to come back here and tell our enemies
that they may take our lives,
but they'll never take our freedom?
They seem quite optimistic to me.
Maybe they do want to fight.
Confrontation might be
a foregone conclusion, milord,
but, nonetheless, I think
we should deliver the king's terms.
The king's terms?
He'll never live up to them.
Milord, I think...
All right. Offer them the terms.
They're coming out.
Shall we go and meet them?
-Let me do the talking. Agreed?
-Agreed.
Fine speech.
Now what do we do?
Just be yourselves.
Where are you going?
I'm going to pick a fight.
Well, we didn't get dressed up
for nothing.
Mornay, Lochlan, Craig.
Here are the king's terms.
Lead this army off the field,
and he will give you each
estates in Yorkshire,
including hereditary title,
from which you will pay...
From which you will pay him
an annual duty...
I have an offer for you.
Cheltham, this is William Wallace.
From which you will pay the king
an annual duty...
I said I have an offer for you.
You disrespect a banner of truce?
From his king? Absolutely.
Here are Scotland's terms.
Lower your flags
and march straight back to England,
stopping at every home you pass by
to beg forgiveness
for 100 years of theft, rape and murder.
Do that and your men shall live.
Do it not
and every one of you will die today.
You are outmatched.
You have no heavy cavalry.
In two centuries, no army has won...
I'm not finished!
Before we let you leave,
your commander must cross that field,
present himself before this army,
put his head between his legs,
and kiss his own arse.
I'd say that was rather less cordial
than he was used to.
You be ready and do exactly as I say.
On my signal,
ride round behind our position
and flank them.
We must not divide our forces.
Do it and let the English see you do it.
They'll think we run away.
Take out their archers.
I'll meet you in the middle.
Right. Come on.
Insolent bastard.
I want this Wallace's heart on a plate.
Archers.
-Archers! Archers!
-Archers!
-Archers, forward!
You bastards!
Loose!
The Lord tells me he can get me
out of this mess,
but he's pretty sure you're fucked.
-Ready!
-Loose!
Ride!
See, every Scot with a horse is fleeing.
Our cavalry will ride them down
like grass.
Send the horse.
Full attack.
Steady!
Hold!