With the coming
of the Second World War...
... many eyes in imprisoned Europe
turned hopefully or desperately...
... toward the freedom of the Americas.
Lisbon became
the great embarkation point.
But not everybody could get
to Lisbon directly.
And so a torturous, roundabout
refugee trail sprang up.
Paris to Marseilles.
Across the Mediterranean to Oran.
Then by train or auto or foot
across the rim of Africa...
... to Casablanca in French Morocco.
Here, the fortunate ones,
through money or influence or luck...
... might obtain exit visas
and scurry to Lisbon.
And from Lisbon to the New World.
But the others wait in Casablanca.
And wait...
... and wait...
... and wait.
"To all officers:
Two German couriers carrying official
documents murdered on train from Oran.
Murderer and possible accomplices
headed for Casablanca.
Round up all suspicious characters
and search them for stolen document.
Important."
May we see your papers?
I don't have them on me.
In that case,
you'll have to come along.
It's possible that I...
Yes. Here they are.
These papers expired three weeks ago.
You'll have to come along.
Halt!
- What is going on?
- I don't know, my dear.
Pardon me. Have you not heard?
We hear very little
and we understand even less.
Two German couriers were found
murdered in the unoccupied desert.
This is the customary
roundup of refugees, liberals...
...and beautiful girls for Mr. Renault,
the prefect of police.
With these refugees, the scum
of Europe has gravitated to Casablanca.
Some have been waiting
years for a visa.
I beg of you, monsieur.
Watch yourself. Be on guard.
This place is full of vultures.
Vultures everywhere. Everywhere.
- Thank you. Thank you very much.
- Not at all.
Amusing little fellow.
Waiter.
- How silly of me.
- What, dear?
I've left my wallet in the hotel.
Perhaps tomorrow
we'll be on the plane.
It is good to see you,
Maj. Strasser.
Thank you, thank you.
May I present Capt. Renault,
the police prefect.
Unoccupied France welcomes you.
Thank you, it's good to be here.
Maj. Strasser, my aide,
Lt. Casselle.
- Capt. Tonelli, the Italian service...
- That is kind of you.
You may find the climate
of Casablanca a trifle warm.
We Germans must get used to all
climates, from Russia to the Sahara.
- But you're not referring to the weather.
- What else?
What's been done about the murders?
My men are rounding up twice
the usual number of suspects.
- But we know who the murderer is.
- Good. Is he in custody?
Tonight he'll be at Rick's.
Everybody comes to Rick's.
I've already heard about this café.
Also about Mr. Rick himself.
For nobody else
Gave me a thrill
Honey, with all your faults
I love you still
It had to Be You, wonderful you
It had to be you
'Cause my hair is curly
Waiting, waiting, waiting.
I'll never get out of here.
I'll die in Casablanca.
But can't you make it
just a little more, please?
Sorry, but diamonds are
a drag on the market.
There are diamonds everywhere.
Twenty-four hundred.
All right.
The trucks are waiting.
The men are waiting. Everything...
It's the fishing smack Santiago.
It leaves at one tomorrow night.
From the end of the marina.
Thank you.
And bring 15,000 francs in cash.
Remember, in cash.
Cheerio.
- Open up, Abdul.
- Yes, professor.
- Waiter?
- Yes, madame?
Will you ask Rick
if he'll have a drink with us?
Madame, he never drinks with customers.
Never. I've never seen it.
What makes saloonkeepers so snobbish?
Perhaps if you told him I ran
the second-largest bank in Amsterdam.
The second largest?
That wouldn't impress Rick.
The leading banker in Amsterdam
is now the pastry chef here.
We have something to look forward to.
And his father is the bellboy.
Good!
Excuse me.
I'm sorry, sir.
This is a private room.
Of all the nerve! Who do you think...
I know there is gambling in there!
You dare not keep me out!
What's the trouble?
I have been in every gambling room
from Honolulu to Berlin.
If you think I'll be kept out
of a saloon like this, you're mistaken.
Excuse me, please.
Hello, Rick.
Your cash is good at the bar.
What? Do you know who I am?
I do. You're lucky
the bar is open to you.
This is outrageous!
I shall report it to the angriff!
Watching you now, one would think
you've been doing this all your life.
- What makes you think I haven't?
- Nothing.
- But when you first came, I thought...
- You thought what?
What right do I have to think?
May I?
Too bad about those two
German couriers.
They got lucky.
Yesterday, they were just clerks.
Today, they're the honored dead.
You're a very cynical person.
Forgive me for saying so.
I forgive you.
Will you have a drink with me?
I forgot you never drink with...
I'll have another, please.
You despise me, don't you?
If I gave you any thought,
I would.
But why?
You object to the kind
of business I do, huh?
But think of all those poor refugees
who must rot here if I didn't help them.
That's not so bad. Through ways of
my own, I provide them with exit visas.
For a price, Ugarte. For a price.
Think of the poor devils
who can't meet Renault's price.
I get it for them for half.
Is that so parasitic?
I don't mind a parasite.
I object to a cut-rate one.
After tonight, I'll be through
with the whole business.
And I'm leaving, finally,
this Casablanca.
Who'd you bribe for your visa?
Renault or yourself?
Myself. I found myself
much more reasonable.
Look, Rick.
You know what this is?
Something that even you
have never seen.
Letters of transit
signed by General de Gaulle.
Cannot be rescinded.
Not even questioned.
One moment.
Tonight, I'll be selling those for
more money than even I ever dreamed of.
And then, addio, Casablanca.
I have many a friend in Casablanca,
but just because you despise me...
...you are the only one I trust.
Will you keep these for me?
- For how long?
- An hour. Perhaps a little longer.
I don't want them overnight.
Don't be afraid of that.
Please keep them for me.
Thank you.
I knew I could trust you.
Waiter,
I'll be expecting some people.
If anybody asks for me,
I'll be right here.
Rick...
...I hope you're more
impressed with me now.
I'll share my good luck
with your roulette wheel.
Just a moment.
I heard a rumor those German couriers
were carrying letters of transit.
I've heard that rumor too.
- Poor devils.
- You're right, Ugarte.
I am a little more impressed with you.
- Say, who 's got trouble?
- We got trouble
- How much trouble?
- Too much trouble
Well now, don 't you frown
Just knuckle down and knock on wood
- Who 's unhappy?
- We're unhappy
- How unhappy?
- Too unhappy
That won 't do
When you are blue, just knock on wood
- How unlucky?
- Too unlucky
But your luck'll change
If you'll arrange to knock on wood
- Who 's got nothing?
- We got nothing
- Now who 's lucky?
- We're all lucky
- Just how lucky?
- Very lucky
Well, smile up, then
And once again
Let's knock on wood
- Hello, Rick.
- Hello, Ferrari.
How's business at the Blue Parrot?
- Fine, but I'd like to buy your café.
- It's not for sale.
- You haven't heard my offer.
- It's not for sale at any price.
- What do you want for Sam?
- I don't buy or sell human beings.
That's Casablanca's leading commodity.
In refugees alone, we can make
a fortune together in the black market.
Suppose you run your business
and let me run mine.
Suppose we ask Sam.
Maybe he'd like to make a change.
Suppose we do.
When will you realize that in this world
isolationism is not a practical policy?
Ferrari wants you to work
for him at the Blue Parrot.
I like it fine here.
- He'll double what I pay you.
- But I ain't got time to spend money.
Sorry.
The boss's private stock.
Because, Yvonne, I love you.
Shut up.
All right. For you, I shut up.
Because, Yvonne, I love you.
Monsieur Rick.
Some Germans gave this check.
Is it all right?
Where were you last night?
That's so long ago,
I don't remember.
- Will I see you tonight?
- I never make plans that far ahead.
Give me another.
- She's had enough.
- Don't listen to him. Fill it up.
Yvonne, I love you,
but he pays me.
- I'm tired of having you...
- Sascha, call a cab.
- We'll get your coat.
- Take your hands off!
You're going home.
You've had too much to drink.
Hey, taxi!
Who do you think you are,
pushing me?
What a fool I was
to fall for you.
- Go with her. Be sure she gets home.
- Yes, boss.
Come right back.
Yes, boss.
- Hello, Rick.
- Hello, Louis.
How extravagant,
throwing away women like that.
Someday, they may be scarce.
I think I shall pay a call on Yvonne.
Maybe get her on the rebound.
When it comes to women,
you're a true democrat.
If he gets a word in,
it'll be a major Italian victory.
The plane to Lisbon.
You would like to be on it?
Why? What's in Lisbon?
The clipper to America.
I've speculated on why
you don't return to America.
Did you abscond with the church funds?
Run off with a senator's wife?
I like to think you killed a man.
It's the romantic in me.
It's a combination of all three.
What brought you to Casablanca?
My health. I came
to Casablanca for the waters.
The waters? What waters?
We're in the desert.
I was misinformed.
Excuse me, Rick.
A gentleman inside
has won 20,000 francs...
...and the cashier
would like some money.
- I'll get it from the safe.
- I'm so upset. You know...
Forget it, Emil.
Mistakes happen all the time.
I'm awfully sorry.
There'll be some excitement tonight.
An arrest in your café.
- Again?
- This is no ordinary arrest.
A murderer, no less.
If you're thinking of warning him,
don't. He cannot escape.
- I stick my neck out for nobody.
- A wise foreign policy.
We could've arrested him
at the Blue Parrot.
Out of my regard for you,
we're staging it here.
It will amuse your customers.
Our entertainment's enough.
We'll have an important guest tonight.
Maj. Strasser, of the Third Reich.
We want him to see the arrest as a
demonstration of our efficiency.
I see.
What's Strasser doing here?
He didn't come here to witness
a demonstration of your efficiency.
- Perhaps not.
- Here you are.
- It won't happen again.
- That's all right.
Louis, there's something on your mind.
Why don't you spill it?
How observant you are.
I wanted to give you
a word of advice.
Yeah?
- Have a brandy?
- Thank you.
There are exit visas sold in this café,
but we know you've never sold one.
That's why we let you remain open.
I thought it was because
I let you win at roulette.
That is another reason.
There's a man arrived here
on his way to America.
He'll offer a fortune to anyone
who'll get him a visa.
- What's his name?
- Victor Laszlo.
Victor Laszlo?
That's the first time
I've seen you impressed.
He's succeeded
in impressing half the world.
It's my duty to see
he doesn't impress the other half.
Rick, Laszlo must never reach America.
He stays in Casablanca.
It'll be interesting
to see how he manages.
Manages what?
His escape.
- But I just told you...
- Stop it.
He escaped the concentration camp.
Nazis have chased him through Europe.
This is the end of the chase.
- Twenty thousand francs says it isn't.
- Is that a serious offer?
I just paid 20.
I'd like to get it back.
Make it 10.
I'm only a poor, corrupt official.
- Okay.
- Done.
No matter how clever he is, he still
needs a visa. Or, I should say, two.
- Why two?
- He is traveling with a lady.
- He'll take one.
- I think not. I've seen her.
If he did not leave her
in Marseilles or in Oran...
...he won't leave her in Casablanca.
Maybe he's not quite
as romantic as you.
It doesn't matter.
There is no exit visa for him.
What ever gave you the impression
that I might help Laszlo escape?
Because I suspect
that under that cynical shell...
...you're at heart
a sentimentalist.
Laugh if you will.
I'm familiar with your record.
Let me point out just two items.
In 1935, you ran guns to Ethiopia.
In 1936, you fought in Spain
on the loyalist side.
And got well paid on both occasions.
The winning side
would've paid much better.
Maybe.
It seems you're determined
to keep Laszlo here.
I have my orders.
I see. Gestapo spank.
You overestimate
the influence of the Gestapo.
I don't interfere with them
and they don't interfere with me.
In Casablanca, I am master of my fate.
- I am...
- Maj. Strasser is here, sir.
- You were saying?
- Excuse me.
Carl, see that the major gets
a good table, close to the ladies.
I've already given him the best, knowing
he is German and would take it anyway.
Take him quietly.
Two guards at every door.
- Everything is ready, sir.
- Go ahead.
- Good evening, gentlemen.
- Good evening, captain.
- Won't you join us?
- Thank you.
It's a pleasure to have you here.
Champagne and a tin of caviar.
May I recommend Veuve Clicquot '26?
A good French wine.
Very well, sir.
- A very interesting club.
- Especially so tonight.
You'll see the arrest of the man
who murdered your couriers.
I expected no less, captain.
Monsieur Ugarte.
- Will you please come with us?
- Certainly.
May I first cash my chips?
Very lucky.
Two thousand, please.
Two thousand.
Thank you.
Rick, help me!
- Don't be a fool. You can't get away.
- Rick, hide me! You must help me!
Do something!
Rick!
Excellent, captain.
When they come to get me,
I hope you'll be more help.
I stick my neck out for nobody.
I'm sorry there was a disturbance,
folks, but it's all over now.
Sit down and have a good time.
Enjoy yourselves. All right, Sam.
This is Maj. Heinrich Strasser
of the Third Reich.
- How do you do?
You know Herr Heinz
of the Third Reich.
Please join us, Mr. Rick.
We are very honored tonight.
Maj. Strasser is one reason
the Third Reich enjoys its reputation.
You say "Third Reich" as though
you expect there to be others.
Personally, major,
I will take what comes.
Do you mind if I ask
a few questions?
- Unofficially, of course.
- Make it official if you like.
- What is your nationality?
- I'm a drunkard.
That makes Rick
a citizen of the world.
I was born in New York City,
if that'll help you.
I understand you came here from Paris
during the occupation.
There seems to be no secret about that.
Are you one of those who can't imagine
Germans in their beloved Paris?
It's not particularly
my beloved Paris.
Can you imagine us in London?
When you get there, ask me.
- Diplomatist!
- How about New York?
There are sections of New York that
I wouldn't advise you to try to invade.
- Who will win the war?
- I haven't the slightest idea.
Rick is neutral about everything.
And that takes in...
...the field of women too.
You weren't always
so carefully neutral.
We have a complete dossier on you.
"Richard Blaine, American. Age, 37.
Cannot return to his country."
The reason is vague.
We know what you did in Paris...
...and why you left Paris.
Don't worry, we won't broadcast it.
Are my eyes really brown?
You will forgive my curiosity.
The point is, an enemy of the Reich
has come to Casablanca...
...and we are checking up on anyone
who can be of any help.
My interest in whether Laszlo
stays or goes is purely a sporting one.
In this case, you have
no sympathy for the fox?
Not particularly. I understand
the hound's point of view too.
Laszlo published the foulest lies in the
Prague newspapers till we marched in.
And even after that, he continued
to print scandal sheets in a cellar.
Of course, one must admit
he has great courage.
He's clever. Three times
he slipped through our fingers.
In Paris, he continued his activities.
We intend not to let it happen again.
Excuse me. Your business is
politics, mine is running a saloon.
Good evening, Mr. Blaine.
You see, major? You have
nothing to worry about Rick.
Perhaps.
Yes, monsieur?
- I reserved a table. Victor Laszlo.
- Yes, monsieur. Right this way.
Two Cointreaux, please.
I saw no one of Ugarte's description.
Victor, I feel somehow
we shouldn't stay here.
If we'd walk out so soon
it'd only call attention to us.
Perhaps he's in some
other part of the café.
Excuse me, but you look like a couple
who are on their way to America.
You'll find a market for this ring.
I must sell it at a great sacrifice.
- Thank you, but I don't...
- Perhaps for the lady.
The ring is quite unique.
Yes, I'm very interested.
Good.
Your name?
Berger, Norwegian.
At your service.
I'll meet you at the bar later.
We don't want the ring,
but thank you for showing it to us.
- Such a bargain. That is your decision?
- It is.
- Monsieur Laszlo, is it not?
- Yes.
Captain Renault, prefect of police.
What do you want?
To welcome you to Casablanca
and to wish you a pleasant stay.
It isn't often we have
so distinguished a visitor.
Thank you.
I hope you'll forgive me, captain.
The present French administration
hasn't always been so cordial.
May I present Miss Ilsa Lund?
I was told you were the most
beautiful woman to visit Casablanca.
That was a gross understatement.
You're very kind.
- Won't you join us?
- Lf you'll permit me.
Emil, please. A bottle of your
best champagne. Put it on my bill.
It's a game we play. They put it on the
bill, I tear it up. Very convenient.
Captain, the boy
who's playing the piano...
Somewhere I've seen him.
- Sam?
- Yes.
He came from Paris with Rick.
Rick? Who's he?
- You are in Rick's. Rick is...
- Is what?
Mademoiselle, he's the kind of man...
If I were a woman...
...and I weren't around,
I'd be in love with Rick.
But what a fool I am talking to
a beautiful woman about another man.
Excuse me.
Major.
Mademoiselle and monsieur,
may I present Maj. Strasser?
How do you do?
This is a pleasure
I've looked forward to.
I'm sure you'll excuse me
if I'm not gracious.
But you see,
I am a Czechoslovakian.
You were a Czechoslovakian. Now
you're a subject of the German Reich.
I've never accepted that privilege.
And I'm now on French soil.
I'd like to discuss some matters arising
from your presence on French soil.
This is hardly the time or the place.
Then we'll state another time and place.
Tomorrow at 10 in the prefect's office.
With mademoiselle.
Capt. Renault,
I am under your authority.
Is it your order
we come to your office?
Let us say it is my request.
That is a much more pleasant word.
Very well.
A very clever tactical retreat, major.
- This time, they really mean to stop me.
- Victor, I'm afraid for you.
We've been in difficult
places before, haven't we?
I must find out what Berger knows.
- Be careful.
- I will. Don't worry.
Mr. Berger, the ring.
Could I see it again?
Champagne cocktail, please.
I recognize you
from the news photographs.
In a concentration camp,
one is apt to lose a little weight.
I read five times
that you were killed in five places.
As you see, it was true
every single time.
Thank heaven I found you.
I'm looking for a man named Ugarte.
He's supposed to help me.
Ugarte cannot even help himself.
He's under arrest for murder.
He was arrested here tonight.
I see.
But we, who are still free, will do
all we can. We are organized.
Underground, like everywhere else.
Tomorrow night, there is a meeting
at the Café du Roi.
If you'll come...
Will you ask the piano player
to come over here?
Very well, mademoiselle.
- How's the jewelry business?
- Not so good. Check, please.
Too bad you weren't here earlier.
We had quite a bit of excitement, right?
Yes. Excuse me, gentlemen.
- My bill.
- No. Two champagnes. Please.
Yes, sir.
- Hello, Sam.
- Hello, Miss Ilsa.
I never expected to see you again.
It's been a long time.
Yes, ma'am.
A lot of water under the bridge.
- Some of the old songs, Sam.
- Yes, ma'am.
Where is Rick?
I don't know.
I ain't seen him all night.
When will he be back?
Not tonight no more.
He ain't coming...
He went home.
Does he always leave so early?
Oh, he never...
He's got a girl up at the Blue Parrot.
Goes up there all the time.
You used to be
a much better liar, Sam.
Leave him alone, Miss Ilsa.
You're bad luck to him.
Play it once, Sam.
For old time's sake.
I don't know what you mean, Miss Ilsa.
Play it, Sam.
Play "As Time Goes By."
I can't remember it.
I'm a little rusty on it.
I'll hum it for you.
Sing it, Sam.
You must remember this
A kiss is just a kiss
A sigh is just a sigh
The fundamental things apply
As time goes by
And when two lovers woo
They still say, "I love you"
On that you can rely
No matter what the future brings
As time goes by
Sam, I thought I told you
never to play...
You were asking about Rick
and here he is. May I present...
- Hello, Ilsa.
- Hello, Rick.
You've already met Rick?
Then perhaps you also...
This is Mr. Laszlo.
- How do you do?
One hears a great deal
about Rick in Casablanca.
And about Victor Laszlo everywhere.
- Join us for a drink?
- Rick never...
Thanks, I will.
Well! A precedent
is being broken. Emil?
A very interesting café.
I congratulate you.
- I congratulate you.
- What for?
Your work.
Thank you. I try.
We all try. You succeed.
She was asking about you earlier...
...in a way that made me
extremely jealous.
I wasn't sure you were the same.
- The last time we met...
- Was La Belle Aurore.
How nice. You remembered.
That was the day
the Germans marched into Paris.
Not an easy day to forget.
I remember every detail.
The Germans wore gray, you wore blue.
Yes. I put that dress away.
When the Germans march out,
I'll wear it again.
You're becoming quite human.
I suppose we have to thank you for that.
Ilsa, I don't wish to be the one
to say it, but it's late.
So it is. We have a curfew
here in Casablanca.
It wouldn't do for the chief of police
to be drinking after hours.
I hope we didn't overstay our welcome.
- Your check, sir.
- My party.
Another precedent gone. This has been
a very interesting evening.
I'll call you a cab.
Gasoline rationing, time of night...
- We'll come again.
- Anytime.
- Say good night to Sam.
- I will.
There's still nobody in the world
who can play "As Time Goes By" like Sam.
He hasn't played it in a long time.
Good night.
A very puzzling fellow.
What sort is he?
I really can't say,
though I saw him quite often in Paris.
- Tomorrow at 10 at the prefect office.
- We'll be there.
Good night.
Boss?
- Boss?
- Yeah?
- Ain't you going to bed?
- Not right now.
Ain't you planning on going to bed
in the near future?
- You ever going to bed?
- No!
I ain't sleepy either.
Then have a drink.
- Not me.
- Well, don't have a drink.
Let's get out of here.
No, sir.
I'm waiting for a lady.
Let's go. Ain't nothing
but trouble for you here.
I know she's coming back.
We'll drive all night.
We'll get drunk
and stay away till she's gone.
Shut up and go home, will you?
No, sir. I'm staying right here.
They grab Ugarte, then she walks in.
That's the way it goes.
One in, one out.
- Sam.
- Yes, boss.
If it's December, 1941, in Casablanca,
what time is it in New York?
What...?
My watch stopped.
I bet they're asleep in New York.
I bet they're asleep all over America.
Of all the gin joints in all the towns
in all the world...
...she walks into mine.
- What are you playing?
- A little something of my own.
- Stop it. You know what I wanna hear.
- I don't.
You played it for her,
you can play it for me.
- I don't remember...
- lf she can stand it, I can.
Play it!
Yes, boss.
Who are you really?
And what were you before?
What did you do
and what did you think?
We said no questions.
Here's looking at you, kid.
A franc for your thoughts.
In America they'd bring only a penny.
I guess that's about
all they're worth.
I'm willing to be overcharged.
Tell me.
Well, I was wondering...
...why I'm so lucky, why I should
find you waiting for me to come along?
Why there is no other man in my life?
That's easy. There was.
He's dead.
I'm sorry for asking.
I forgot we said no questions.
Only one answer can take care
of all our questions.
Nothing can stop them now.
Wednesday they'll be in Paris.
They'll find out your record.
It won't be safe here.
I'm on their blacklist already.
Their "roll of honor."
Hearts full of passion
Jealousy and hate
Woman needs man
And man must have his mate
That no one can deny
It's still the same old story
A fight for love and glory
A case of do or die
The world will always welcome lovers
As time goes by
Henri wants us
to finish three more bottles.
He'll water his garden with champagne
before he lets the Germans drink it.
This ought to take the sting
out of being occupied.
You said it.
Here's looking at you, kid.
My German's a little rusty.
It's the Gestapo.
They say they expect
to be in Paris tomorrow.
They're telling us how to act
when they come marching in.
With the world crumbling,
we pick this time to fall in love.
Yeah, it's pretty bad timing.
Where were you 10 years ago?
Ten years ago?
Let's see...
Yes, I was having a brace
put on my teeth. Where were you?
Looking for a job.
Was that cannon fire?
Or my heart pounding?
It's the German 77th, and judging
by the sound, only about 35 miles away.
And getting closer every minute.
Here, here, drink up.
We'll never finish the other three.
Germans will be here pretty soon
and they'll come looking for you.
There's a price on your head.
I left a note in my apartment.
They'll know where to find me.
It's strange.
I know so very little about you.
I know little about you.
Except that you had
your teeth straightened.
Be serious. You're in danger.
You must leave Paris.
No, we must leave.
Yes, of course. We.
The train for Marseilles leaves at 5.
I'll pick you up at your hotel at 4:30.
Not at my hotel. I...
I have things to do in the city
before I leave.
I'll meet you at the station.
All right, at a quarter to 5.
Why don't we marry
in Marseilles?
That's too far ahead to plan.
I guess it is a little too far ahead.
What about the engineer?
Why can't he marry us on the train?
Why not? The captain on a ship can.
It doesn't seem fair that...
What's wrong, kid?
I love you so much.
And I hate this war so much.
It's a crazy world.
Anything can happen.
If you shouldn't get away...
If something should keep us apart...
...wherever they put you...
...and wherever I'll be,
I want you to know that l...
Kiss me.
Kiss me as if it were
the last time.
All aboard! The last train
leaving in three minutes.
Have you seen her?
I can't find her.
She checked out of the hotel.
But this note came
just after you left.
That's the last call,
Mr. Richard.
Do you hear me?
Come on, Mr. Richard.
Let's get out of here. Come on.
Rick, I have to talk to you.
I saved my first drink
to have with you. Here.
- No, Rick. Not tonight.
- Especially tonight.
Why did you have to come to Casablanca?
There are other places.
I wouldn't have come
if I'd known that you were here.
Believe me, it's true.
I didn't know.
It's funny how your voice hasn't
changed. I can still hear it.
"Richard, dear,
I'll go with you anyplace.
- We'll get on a train and never stop."
- Don't, Rick.
I can understand how you feel.
You understand how I feel?
How long was it we had, honey?
- I didn't count the days.
- Well, I did.
Every one of them.
Mostly, I remember the last one.
The "wow" finish. A guy standing
on a platform in the rain...
...with a comical look on his face
from his insides having been kicked out.
Can I tell you a story, Rick?
Has it got a "wow" finish?
I don't know the finish yet.
Go on, tell it. Maybe one will
come to you as you go along.
It's about a girl who'd just come
to Paris from her home in Oslo.
At the house of some friends...
...she met a man about whom
she'd heard her whole life.
A very great and courageous man.
He opened up for her a beautiful world
full of knowledge, thoughts and ideals.
Everything she knew or ever became
was because of him.
She looked up to him
and worshiped him...
...with a feeling she supposed was love.
Yes, that's very pretty.
I heard a story once.
I've heard a lot of stories in my time.
They went along with
the sound of a tinny piano...
...playing in the parlor downstairs.
"Mister, I met a man once when
I was a kid," they'd always begin.
I guess neither one of our stories
is very funny.
Tell me...
...who was it you left me for?
Was it Laszlo, or were there
others in between...
...or aren't you the kind that tells?
I suspect Ugarte left
the letters of transit with Mr. Blaine.
I suggest you search
the café immediately.
If Rick has them, he's too smart
to let you find them there.
You give him credit
for too much cleverness.
My impression was that he's just
another blundering American.
We mustn't underestimate
American blundering.
I was with them when they
blundered into Berlin in 1918.
As to Laszlo, we want him watched
24 hours a day.
It may interest you to know that
at this moment he's on his way here.
There's nothing we can do.
I'm delighted to see you both.
Did you rest well?
I slept well.
That's strange. Nobody's supposed
to sleep well in Casablanca.
- May we proceed with the business?
- With pleasure. Sit down.
We won't mince words. You're
an escaped prisoner of the Reich.
So far, you've been
fortunate enough in eluding us.
You have reached Casablanca.
It is my duty to see
that you stay here.
Whether or not you'll
succeed is problematic.
Not at all. Renault's signature
is necessary on every visa.
Is it possible Herr Laszlo
will receive a visa?
I'm afraid not.
My regrets, monsieur.
Well, perhaps
I shall like it in Casablanca.
And mademoiselle?
- You needn't be concerned about me.
- Is that all you wish to tell us?
Don't be in a hurry.
You have all the time in the world.
You may be in
Casablanca indefinitely.
Or you may leave for Lisbon tomorrow.
On one condition.
And that is?
You know the leader of the underground
movement in Paris, in Prague...
...in Brussels, in Amsterdam,
in Oslo, in Belgrade, in Athens...
- Even Berlin.
- Yes, even in Berlin.
If you'll furnish me with their names
and whereabouts, you'll have your visa.
And the honor of having
served the Third Reich.
I was in a German
concentration camp for a year.
That's honor enough for a lifetime.
You'll give us the names?
If I didn't give them to you
in a concentration camp...
...where you had more persuasive
methods at your disposal...
...I certainly won't
give them to you now.
What if you track them down
and kill them?
What if you murdered us all?
From every corner of Europe, hundreds,
thousands would rise to take our places.
Even Nazis can't kill that fast.
You have a reputation for eloquence,
which I can now understand.
But you're mistaken.
You said enemies of the Reich
could be replaced.
There is one exception.
No one could take your place
if anything unfortunate...
...should occur to you
while you're trying to escape.
You won't dare
to interfere with me here.
This is still unoccupied France.
Any violation of neutrality
would reflect on the captain.
- Insofar as it is in my power...
- Thank you.
By the way, last night you evinced
an interest in Señor Ugarte.
Yes.
You have a message for him.
Nothing important.
May I speak to him now?
You would find the conversation
a trifle one-sided.
Señor Ugarte is dead.
I'm making the report.
We haven't quite decided whether
he committed suicide...
...or died trying to escape.
- Are you finished with us?
- For the time being.
Good day.
Their next step
will be to the black market.
Excuse me, captain.
Another visa
problem has come up.
Show her in.
Sorry, we wouldn't be able
to handle the police.
- This is a job for Señor Ferrari.
- Ferrari?
It can be most helpful
to know Ferrari.
He has a monopoly
on the black market here.
You'll find him at the Blue Parrot.
Thanks.
Don't be too downhearted.
Perhaps you can come to terms
with Capt. Renault.
- Hello, Ferrari.
- Good morning, Rick.
I see the bus is in.
I'll take my shipment.
- No hurry. Have a drink.
- I never drink in the morning.
Every time you send my shipment,
it's always a bit short.
Carrying charges, my boy.
Here, sit down.
There's something
I want to talk over with you.
The news about Ugarte upsets me.
You're a fat hypocrite. You don't feel
any sorrier than I do.
Of course not.
What upsets me is that he's dead and
no one knows where those letters are.
Practically no one.
If I had those letters,
I could make a fortune.
So could I,
and I'm a poor businessman.
I've a proposition
for whoever has them.
I'll handle the transaction.
Get rid of the letters, take
all the risk, for a small fee.
And the carrying charges?
Naturally, there will be
a few incidental expenses.
That's my proposition
for whoever has the letters.
I'll tell him when he comes in.
I'll put my cards out.
I think you know where they are.
You're in good company. Renault
and Strasser probably think so too.
I came over here to give them
a chance to ransack my place.
Don't be a fool. Take me into
your confidence. You need a partner.
Excuse me,
I'll be getting back.
- Good morning.
- Ferrari is the fat gent at the table.
You won't find a treasure
like this in all Morocco.
Only 700 francs.
You're being cheated.
It doesn't matter, thank you.
For friends of Rick's
we have a small discount.
Did I say 700 francs?
You can have it for 200.
I'm sorry I was in no condition
to receive you last night.
It doesn't matter.
Special friends of Rick's
get a special discount.
One hundred francs.
Your story had me confused,
or maybe it was the bourbon.
I have some tablecloths...
- I'm really not interested.
- Please, one minute.
Did you come back to tell me
why you ran out on me at the station?
Yes.
You can tell me now.
I'm reasonably sober.
I don't think I will.
Why not? I got stuck with the
railway ticket. I'm entitled to know.
Last night I saw
what has happened to you.
The Rick I knew in Paris,
I could tell him. He'd understand.
But the one who looked at me
with such hatred...
I'll be leaving soon and
we'll never see each other again.
We knew very little about each other
when we were in love in Paris.
If we leave it that way, maybe we'll
remember those days, and not Casablanca.
Not last night.
Did you run out on me because
you knew what it'd be like?
Hiding from the police,
running away all the time?
Believe that if you want to.
I'm not running away anymore.
I'm settled now.
Above a saloon, it's true, but...
Walk up a flight.
I'll be expecting you.
All the same,
someday you'll lie to Laszlo.
You'll be there.
No, Rick.
No. You see,
Victor Laszlo is my husband.
And was, even when
I knew you in Paris.
I was just telling Laszlo that,
unfortunately, I'm not able to help him.
The word has gone around.
As leader of all illegal activities,
I'm an influential and respected man.
But it'd not be worth my life
to do anything for Laszlo.
You, however, are a different matter.
Señor Ferrari thinks it might just be
possible to get an exit visa for you.
- You mean for me to go on alone?
- And only alone.
I'll stay and keep trying.
I'm sure in a little while...
Might as well be frank.
It'd take a miracle to get you out.
The Germans have outlawed miracles.
We're only interested in two visas.
- Please, Ilsa, don't be hasty.
- No, Victor.
You two will want to discuss this.
Excuse me.
I'll be at the bar.
No, I won't let you stay here.
You must get to America.
Somehow I'll get out and join you.
If the situation were different...
...if I had to stay and there was
only one visa...
...would you take it?
Yes, I would.
Yes, I see.
When I had trouble
getting out of Lille...
...why didn't you leave me?
When I was sick in Marseilles
for two weeks and you were in danger...
...why didn't you leave me?
I meant to.
Something always held me up.
I love you very much.
Your secret will be safe with me.
Ferrari is waiting for our answer.
Not more than 50 francs.
We've decided, Señor Ferrari.
For the present we're looking
for two visas. Thank you very much.
Good luck, but be careful.
- You know you're being shadowed?
- It becomes instinct.
I observe that you, in one respect,
are very fortunate.
I'll make one suggestion.
Why, I do not know.
It cannot possibly profit me.
Have you heard
about the letters of transit?
Yes, something.
They were not found on Ugarte
when they arrested him.
- You know where they are?
- Not for sure.
But my guess is Ugarte left
those letters with Rick.
He's a difficult man.
One never knows what he'll do, or why.
But it is worth a chance.
Thank you very much.
Good day.
Bye. Thank you for your coffee.
I shall miss that when we leave.
It was gracious of you
to share it with me.
- Monsieur.
- Good day.
- Here's to you, sir.
- Good luck.
- I'd better be going.
- Check, please.
I have to warn you. This is
a dangerous place, full of vultures.
- Vultures everywhere. Thanks.
- Goodbye.
It has been a pleasure to meet you.
I'm sorry.
You are getting to be
your best customer.
Well, drinking!
I'm very pleased with you.
You're beginning
to live like a Frenchman.
That's some going-over
your men gave my place.
We barely got cleaned up
in time to open.
I told Strasser
he wouldn't find the letters.
But I told my men to be
especially destructive.
You know how that impresses Germans.
Rick, have you got
those letters of transit?
Louis, are you pro-Vichy
or Free French?
Serves me right for asking a direct
question. The subject is closed.
It looks like you're a little late.
So Yvonne's gone over to the enemy.
Who knows? In her own way, she may
constitute an entire second front.
It's time for me to flatter Strasser.
I'll see you later.
Sascha!
French '75.
Put up the whole row of those.
Starting here and ending here.
We will begin with two.
What did you say?
Would you repeat it?
What I said is
not your business.
I'll make it my business.
I don't like disturbances in my place.
Lay off politics or get out.
You see, captain?
The situation is not under control.
We're trying to cooperate
with your government.
We can't regulate
our people's feelings.
Are you certain which side you're on?
I have no conviction.
I blow with the wind...
...and the prevailing wind
is from Vichy.
And if it should change?
Surely the Reich doesn't admit
that possibility?
We're concerned about more
than Casablanca.
Every French province in Africa
is honeycombed with traitors...
...waiting for their chance,
waiting perhaps for a leader.
A leader? Like Laszlo?
I have been thinking.
It is too dangerous if you
let him go or let him stay.
I see what you mean.
Thank you, Carl.
Sit down. Have a brandy with us.
To celebrate our leaving
for America tomorrow.
Thank you very much.
I thought you'd ask me,
so I brought the good brandy...
...and the dress glass.
At last the day's came!
We are speaking nothing
but English now.
So we should feel at home
when we get to America.
A very nice idea.
To America.
What watch?
- Ten watch.
- Such much?
You'll get along
beautifully in America.
How is lady luck treating you?
Oh, too bad.
You'll find him over there.
Monsieur Rick?
- Could I speak to you?
- How'd you get in? You're underage.
- I came with Capt. Renault.
- I should've known.
My husband is with me too.
He is? Renault's getting
broad-minded. Sit down.
Have a drink?
Of course not.
You mind if I do?
Monsieur Rick, what kind of a man
is Capt. Renault?
Like any other man,
only more so.
No, I mean...
Is he trustworthy? Is his word...
Who told you to ask me that?
He did. Capt. Renault.
I thought so.
Where's your husband?
At the roulette table, trying
to win enough for our exit visas.
Of course he's losing.
How long have you been married?
Eight weeks.
We come from Bulgaria.
Things are very bad there.
The devil has the people
by the throat.
So Jan and I, we...
We don't want our children
to grow up there.
So you decided to go to America.
But we have not much money...
...and traveling is
so expensive and difficult.
It was more than
we thought to get here.
Then Capt. Renault sees us.
He's so kind.
He wants to help us.
Yes, I'll bet.
He tells me he can give us
an exit visa.
But we have no money.
- Does he know that?
- Yes.
And he's still willing
to give you a visa?
You want to know...
Will he keep his word?
He always has.
You are a man.
If someone loved you very much...
...so that your happiness was the only
thing she wanted in the world...
...and she did a bad thing
to make certain of it...
...could you forgive her?
Nobody ever loved me that much.
And he never knew, and the girl kept
this bad thing locked in her heart...
...that would be all right?
- You want my advice?
- Yes, please.
Go back to Bulgaria.
But if you knew what it means to us
to leave Europe, to get to America.
But if Jan should find out...
He is such a boy.
In many ways,
I am so much older than he is.
Yes, everybody in Casablanca
has problems.
Yours may work out.
You'll excuse me.
Good evening.
See? Here we are again.
I'll take that as a compliment to Sam.
I suppose he means to you
Paris of happier days.
He does. Could we have
a table close to him?
And as far away
from Strasser as possible.
The geography may be
difficult to arrange.
Paul, table 30.
Right this way, if you please.
I'll have Sam play "As Time Goes By."
I believe that's your favorite.
Thank you.
Two cognac, please.
Do you wish to place
another bet, sir?
No, I guess not.
Have you tried 22 tonight?
I said "22."
Leave it there.
Cash it in and don't come back.
Are you sure this place is honest?
Honest? As honest as the day is long.
How are we doing tonight?
A couple of thousand less
than I thought there would be.
He's just a lucky guy.
Monsieur Rick, may I get you
a cup of coffee?
No thanks, Carl.
- Capt. Renault, may l...
- Not here, please.
Come to my office.
We'll be businesslike.
- We'll be there at 6.
- I'll be there at 10.
I'm very happy for both of you.
Still, it's very strange
that you won.
Well, maybe not so strange.
- I'll see you in the morning.
- Thank you so much.
Boss, you've done a beautiful thing.
Go away, you crazy Russian.
As I suspected.
- You're a rank sentimentalist.
- Why?
Why interfere
with my little romances?
Put it down as a gesture to love.
I forgive you this time.
But I'll be in tomorrow
with a breathtaking blonde.
And it'll make me
very happy if she loses.
I wonder if I could talk to you?
Go ahead.
Isn't there some other place?
It's rather confidential,
what I have to say.
- In my office.
- Right.
You know it's very important
I get out of Casablanca.
I'm privileged to be one
of the leaders of a great movement.
You know what I've been doing.
You know what it means to the work,
to the lives of thousands of people...
...that I continue my work.
I'm not interested in politics.
The problems of the world are not
in my department. I'm a saloonkeeper.
My friends in the underground tell me
that you've quite a record.
You ran guns to Ethiopia.
- You fought the fascists in Spain.
- What of it?
Isn't it strange you always
seem to fight with the underdog?
I found that an expensive hobby.
But then I never was
much of a businessman.
Are you enough of a businessman
to appreciate 100,000 francs?
I appreciate it,
but I don't accept it.
I'll raise it to 200,000.
Make it a million francs or three.
My answer would still be the same.
There's a reason
you won't let me have them.
There is.
I suggest that you ask your wife.
- I beg your pardon?
- I said, ask your wife.
- My wife?
- Yes.
Play "La Marseillaise."
Play it!
See? If Laszlo's presence in a café
can inspire this demonstration...
...what more will his
presence here bring on?
I advise that this place
be shut up at once.
- Everybody's having a good time.
- Much too good a time.
The place is to be closed.
- But I've no excuse to close it.
- Find one.
Everyone is to leave immediately.
This café is closed
until further notice.
Clear the room at once!
On what grounds?
I'm shocked to find that
gambling is going on in here.
- Your winnings, sir.
- Thank you.
Everybody out at once!
After this disturbance, it's not safe
for Laszlo to stay in Casablanca.
This morning it wasn't safe
for him to leave.
That's also true,
except to return to occupied France.
- Occupied France?
- Under safe conduct from me.
Of what value is that?
Remember what German guarantees
have been worth in the past.
- There are only two other alternatives.
- What are they?
French authorities may find a reason to
put him in the concentration camp here.
The other alternative?
Perhaps you have already observed
that, in Casablanca, human life is cheap.
Good night, mademoiselle.
- What happened with Rick?
- We'll discuss it later.
Our faithful friend is still there.
Please don't go
to the underground meeting.
I must.
It isn't often that a man gets to
display heroics before his wife.
Don't joke. After Strasser's
warning tonight, I'm frightened.
I'm frightened too.
Shall I remain here
in a hotel room, hiding?
Or carry on the best I can?
Whatever I'd say,
you would carry on.
Why don't you tell me about Rick?
What did you find out?
- Apparently he has the letters.
- Yes?
But he won't sell them.
I'd think if sentiment won't
persuade him, money would.
Did he give you any reason?
He suggested I ask you.
Ask me?
Yes. He said, "Ask your wife."
I don't know why he said that.
Our friend outside will think
we've retired by now.
I'll be going in a few minutes.
- Ilsa, l...
- Yes?
When I was in the concentration camp...
...were you Ionely in Paris?
Yes, Victor. I was.
I know how it is to be Ionely.
Is there anything you wish to tell me?
No, Victor. There isn't.
I love you very much.
Yes.
Yes, I know.
Whatever I do,
will you believe that l...
You don't even have to say it.
I'll believe.
Good night, dear.
Good night.
Yes, dear?
Be careful.
Of course I'll be careful.
Well, you are in pretty good shape,
Herr Rick.
How long can I afford to stay closed?
Two weeks, maybe three.
Maybe I won't have to.
A bribe worked before.
In the meantime,
everybody stays on salary.
Thank you.
Sascha will be happy to hear it.
I owe him money.
- You finish locking up, will you?
- I will.
- Then I'm going to the meeting...
- Don't tell me.
I won't.
Good night.
Good night, Mr. Rick.
- How did you get in?
- The stairs from the street.
I told you you'd come around,
but this is ahead of schedule.
Won't you sit down?
- Richard, I had to see you.
- "Richard" again. We're back in Paris.
Your visit isn't connected by any chance
with the letters of transit?
As long as I have them,
I'll never be Ionely.
Ask any price,
but give me those letters.
I went through that with
your husband. It's no deal.
I know how you feel about me...
...but please put that aside
for something important.
Do I have to hear again
how great your husband is...
...what an important cause
he's fighting for?
It was your cause too.
In your way you were fighting
for the same thing.
I'm not fighting for anything anymore,
except myself.
I'm the only cause I'm interested in.
We loved each other once.
If those days meant anything at all...
I wouldn't bring up Paris.
It's poor salesmanship.
Listen. If you knew what really
happened, if you knew the truth...
I wouldn't believe you no matter what.
You'd say anything now
to get what you want.
You want to feel sorry for yourself?
With so much at stake, all you can
think of is your own feeling.
One woman has hurt you, and you
take revenge on the rest of the world.
You're a coward and a weakling!
No.
Richard, I'm sorry.
I'm sorry, but you...
You are our last hope.
If you don't help us,
Victor will die in Casablanca.
What of it?
I'm gonna die in Casablanca.
It's a good spot for it.
Now, if you'Il...
All right.
I tried to reason with you.
I tried everything.
I want those letters.
Get them for me.
I don't have to.
I got them right here.
Put them on the table.
No.
For the last time,
put them on the table.
If Laszlo and the cause mean so much
to you, you won't stop at anything.
All right,
I'll make it easier for you.
Go ahead and shoot.
You'll be doing me a favor.
I tried to stay away.
I thought I would never see you again.
That you were out of my life.
The day you left Paris...
...if you knew what I went through.
If you knew how much I loved you.
How much I still love you.
And then?
It wasn't long after we were married
that Victor went back to Czechoslovakia.
They needed him in Prague.
But the Gestapo were waiting for him.
Just two lines in the paper:
"Victor Laszlo apprehended.
Sent to concentration camp."
I was frantic.
For months I tried to get word.
Then it came.
He was dead.
Shot, trying to escape.
I was Ionely.
I had nothing, not even hope.
Then I met you.
Why weren't you honest?
Why keep your marriage a secret?
It wasn't my secret, Richard.
Victor wanted it that way.
Not even our closest friends
knew about it.
He was protecting me.
I knew about his work.
If the Gestapo found out I was his wife,
it'd be dangerous for me...
...and for those working with us.
When did you first find out
he was alive?
Just before you and I
were to leave Paris.
A friend came and told me
that Victor was alive.
They hid him in a freight car
in the outskirts of Paris.
He was sick. He needed me.
I wanted to tell you,
but I didn't dare.
I knew you wouldn't have left and the
Gestapo would have caught you, so I...
Well, you know the rest.
It's still a story without an ending.
What about now?
Now?
I don't know.
I know I'll never have
the strength to leave you again.
And Laszlo?
You'll help him now, won't you?
You'll see that he gets out.
Then he'll have his work.
All that he's been living for.
All except one.
He won't have you.
I can't fight it anymore.
I ran away from you once.
I can't do it again.
I don't know what's right any longer.
You have to think for both of us.
For all of us.
All right.
I will.
Here's looking at you, kid.
I wish I didn't love you so much.
- I think we lost them.
- Yes.
They caught some of the others.
Come inside.
Come, Mr. Laszlo.
I will help you immediately.
I'll give you some water.
Carl, what happened?
The police break up our meeting.
We escaped in the last moment.
- Come up here a minute.
- Yes, I come.
Turn out the light at the rear.
It may attract police.
Sascha always puts it out.
Tonight he forgot.
Yes, I come. I will do it.
Take Miss Lund home.
Yes, sir.
Just a little cut.
We had to get through a window.
This might come in handy.
Thank you.
Had a close one?
Yes, rather.
Don't you sometimes wonder
if it's worth all this?
I mean, what you're fighting for.
We might as well question
why we breathe.
We stop breathing, we'll die.
We stop fighting our enemies,
the world will die.
What of it?
Then it'll be out of its misery.
You know how you sound?
Like a man who's convincing himself
of something he doesn't believe.
Each of us has a destiny.
For good or for evil.
I get the point.
I wonder if you do.
I wonder if you know you're trying
to escape from yourself.
You'll never succeed.
You seem to know all about my destiny.
I know a good deal more
about you than you suspect.
I know that you're
in love with a woman.
It's perhaps a strange circumstance...
...that we're in love
with the same woman.
The first evening
I came into this café...
...I knew there was something
between you and Ilsa.
Since no one is to blame...
...I demand no explanation.
I ask only one thing.
You won't give me the letters...
...all right.
But I want my wife to be safe.
I ask you as a favor...
...to use the letters
to take her away from Casablanca.
You love her that much?
Apparently, you think of me only
as the leader of a cause.
I'm also a human being.
Yes, I love her that much.
- Mr. Laszlo?
- Yes?
Come with us.
We have a warrant for your arrest.
On what charge?
The captain will discuss
that with you later.
It seems that destiny
has taken a hand.
You haven't any proof.
This isn't Germany or occupied France.
You can fine him and give him 30 days.
You might as well let him go.
I advise you not to be interested
in what happens to Laszlo.
If you help him to escape...
Why do you think I'd stick
my neck out for him?
Because, one, you bet
10,000 francs he'd escape.
Two, you've got the letters.
Don't bother to deny it.
You might do it because
you don't like Strasser's looks.
I don't like them either.
They're all excellent reasons.
Don't count too much on my friendship.
In this matter, I'm powerless.
Besides, I might lose 10,000 francs.
You're not very subtle,
but you are effective. I get the point.
Yes, I have the letters.
I intend using them myself.
I'm leaving Casablanca
on tonight's plane. The last plane.
I'm taking a friend with me.
One you'll appreciate.
- What friend?
- Ilsa Lund.
That ought to put your mind to rest
about my helping Laszlo escape.
The last man I want to see in America.
You didn't come here to say this.
You have the letters.
Fill in your name and hers
and leave anytime you please.
Why do you still care
what happens to Laszlo?
I'm not. But I am interested
in what happens to Ilsa and me.
We have a legal right to go,
but people have been held here...
...in spite of their legal rights.
Why do you think
we want to hold you?
Ilsa is Laszlo's wife.
She probably knows things
Strasser would like to know.
I'll make a deal with you.
Instead of this petty charge,
you could get something really big...
...that would chuck him
in a camp for years.
That'd be a feather in your cap.
It certainly would. Germany...
Vichy would be grateful.
Then release him.
Be at my place a half-hour
before the plane leaves.
Laszlo will come there
to pick up the letters.
That'll give you the grounds
to make the arrest.
You get him, and we get away.
To the Germans, that last
will be just a minor annoyance.
There's still something
I don't understand.
Miss Lund,
she is very beautiful, yes...
...but you were never interested
in any woman.
She isn't just any woman.
I see.
How do I know you'll keep
your bargain?
I'll make the arrangements
with Laszlo in the visitor's pen.
I'm gonna miss you. You're the only one
here who has even less scruples than I.
Thanks.
Go ahead, Ricky.
Call off your watchdogs when you let
him go. I don't want them around today.
I'm taking no chances,
not even with you.
Should we draw it up,
or is a handshake good enough?
Certainly not good enough. But since
I'm in a hurry, it'll have to do.
Ah, to get out of Casablanca and
go to America! You're a lucky man.
My agreement with Sam is
that he gets 25% of the profits.
That still goes.
I happen to know he gets 10%.
But he's worth 25.
Abdul, Carl and Sascha stay
with the place or I don't sell.
Of course. Rick's
wouldn't be Rick's without them.
So long.
Remember you owe Rick's
100 cartons of cigarettes.
I shall remember
to pay it to myself.
- You're late.
- I was informed as he left the hotel.
So I'm on time.
- I said to tie up your watchdogs.
- He won't be followed.
This place won't
be the same without you.
I've already spoken to Ferrari.
You'll still win at roulette.
Is everything ready?
I have the letters here.
When we searched the place,
where were they?
Sam's piano.
Serves me right
for not being musical.
Here they are.
You better wait in my office.
Victor thinks I'm going with him.
Haven't you told him?
- Not yet.
- But it's all right, isn't it?
Everything's quite all right.
We'll tell him at the airport. The less
time to think, the easier. Trust me.
Yes, I will.
- I don't know how to thank you.
- Save it. We still have a lot to do.
- I brought the money.
- Keep it, you'll need it in America.
- We made a deal.
- Never mind that.
You won't have
trouble in Lisbon?
No. It's all arranged.
Good. The letters are
made out in blank.
All you have to do is
fill in the signatures.
Victor Laszlo...
...you're under arrest.
For accessory to the murder of the
couriers from whom these were stolen.
You're surprised about Ricky?
The explanation is simple.
Love, it seems, has triumphed
over virtue. Thank...
Not so fast, Louis. Nobody's gonna
be arrested. Not for a while yet.
- Have you taken leave of your senses?
- I have. Sit down.
I don't want to shoot you,
but I will if you take one more step.
Under the circumstances,
I will sit down.
Keep your hands down.
I wonder if you realize
what this means?
I do. We'll discuss that later.
Call off the watchdogs, you said.
Call the airport.
You tell them.
Remember, this gun is pointed
right at your heart.
That is my least vulnerable spot.
Hello? Is that the airport?
Capt. Renault speaking.
There'll be two
letters of transit for Lisbon.
There's to be no trouble about them.
Good.
My car, quickly.
This is Strasser.
Have police meet me
at the airport at once.
At once, do you hear?
Hello, radio tower?
Lisbon plane taking off in 10 minutes,
east runway.
Visibility one and one-half miles.
Light ground fog.
Depth of fog approximately 500.
Ceiling unlimited. Thank you.
Have him go with Laszlo
to take care of his luggage.
Certainly, Rick, anything you say.
Find Mr. Laszlo's luggage
and put it on the plane.
This way, please.
Fill in the names.
That'll make it even more official.
You think of everything, don't you?
The names are
Mr. And Mrs. Victor Laszlo.
But...
...why my name?
You're getting on that plane.
But what about you?
I'm staying here
till the plane gets away.
What's happened to you?
Last night...
Last night we said
a great many things.
You said I was to do the thinking
for us.
I've done a lot.
It all adds up to one thing:
You're getting on that plane with Victor
where you belong.
Now, you've got to listen to me.
Do you know what you'd have
to look forward to here?
We'd both wind up in a
concentration camp. Isn't that true?
Maj. Strasser would insist.
- You're saying this to make me go.
- I'm saying it because it's true.
Inside we both know
you belong with Victor.
You're part of his work,
the thing that keeps him going.
If that plane leaves and you're not
with him, you'll regret it.
Maybe not today, not tomorrow,
but soon. For the rest of your life.
But what about us?
We'll always have Paris.
We didn't have. We'd lost it
until you came to Casablanca.
We got it back last night.
- When I said I would never leave you.
- And you never will.
I've got a job to do too.
Where I go, you can't follow.
What I have to do, you can't be part of.
I'm no good at being noble.
But it doesn't take much to see
that the problems of three people...
...don't amount to a hill of beans
in this crazy world.
Someday you'll understand that.
Here's looking at you, kid.
- Everything is in order.
- All except one thing.
There's something you should know.
I don't ask you
to explain anything.
It may make a difference
to you later on.
You said you knew about Ilsa and me.
She was at my place
last night when you were.
She came there for the letters.
Isn't that true?
Yes.
She tried everything.
Nothing worked.
She did her best to convince me
that she was still in love with me.
But that was all over long ago.
For your sake, she pretended it wasn't.
I let her pretend.
I understand.
Here it is.
Thanks.
I appreciate it.
Welcome back to the fight.
This time I know our side will win.
Are you ready?
Yes, I'm ready.
Goodbye, Rick.
God bless you.
Better hurry.
You'll miss that plane.
I was right.
You are a sentimentalist.
Stay where you are.
- I don't know what you mean.
- What you did for Laszlo.
And that fairy tale
to send Ilsa away with him.
I know a little about women. She went,
but she knew you were lying.
Anyway, thanks for helping me out.
This isn't going to be
pleasant for either of us.
Especially for you.
I'll have to arrest you.
As soon as the plane goes.
What was the meaning
of that phone call?
Victor Laszlo is on that plane.
Why do you stand here?
Why not stop him?
Ask Monsieur Rick.
Get away from that phone.
Do not interfere.
I was willing to shoot Renault.
I'll shoot you.
Put that phone down.
- Get me the radio tower.
- Put it down!
Maj. Strasser has been shot.
Round up the usual suspects.
You're not only a sentimentalist,
but you've become a patriot.
Maybe. It seemed like
a good time to start.
I think perhaps you're right.
It might be good for you to disappear
from Casablanca for a while.
There's a Free French garrison
at Brazzaville.
I could arrange passage.
My letter of transit?
I could use a trip.
But it doesn't change our bet.
You still owe me 10,000 francs.
And that 10,000 francs
should pay our expenses.
"Our" expenses?
Louis...
...I think this is the beginning
of a beautiful friendship.
English Subtitles by
GELULA & CO., INC.