What are you doing there, fella?
I just cut these...
You better come along with us.
Taking it off here, Boss?
Yeah, take it off, Dragline.
- Wiping it off here, Boss?
- All right, Koko, wipe it off.
Drinking it up here, Boss?
All right, drink it up, Gambler.
Hey, Rabbitt, water him down.
- All right, break it up!
- Yes, sir!
You eyeballing there, Society?
Checking my yo-yo, Boss.
Drag, new-meat bus.
Bunch. Must be half a dozen new-meat.
- No more than five, for a cold drink.
- You're on.
Babalugats, got a bet here.
All right, you men get lined up here.
Dog Boy, shut them dogs up.
They just smell new-meat, that's all, Boss.
What did they bring us today?
Come on, Blue.
"Gibson, 507. Manslaughter."
Good for a two spot.
It was an accident.
I've never been in trouble before.
You call the Captain, "Captain."
"Edgar Potter, 302 and resisting arrest."
"One year."
I was trying to keep in out of the rain.
Get the wax out of your ears.
You call the Captain, "Captain."
Yes, sir.
And you call the rest of us "Boss,"
you hear?
Yes, Boss.
This man is going to make us
proud of him, Mr. Hunnicutt.
"Raymond Pratt."
Yes, Captain.
"Breaking, entering, and assault."
Five spot.
And a seaman.
Suspect that should come in real handy
around here, Captain.
Maybe.
"Lucas Jackson."
Here, Captain.
"Maliciously destroying municipal
property while under the influence."
What was that?
Cutting the heads off of parking meters,
Captain.
We ain't never had one of them before.
Where do you think
that's going to get you?
I guess you could say
I wasn't thinking, Captain.
It says here that you did real good
in the war.
A Silver Star, Bronze Star,
couple of Purple Hearts...
Sergeant. Then come out
the same way you went in.
Buck Private.
Like I was just passing time, Captain.
Well, you got yourself some time now.
"Two years."
Well, hell, that ain't much.
We got a couple of men here
doing 20 spot.
We got one that's got all of it.
We got all kinds,
and you're going to fit in real good.
Of course, in case you get rabbit
in your blood...
and you decide to take off for home,
you get a bonus of some time...
and a set of leg chains to keep you
slowed down just a little bit.
For your own good, you'll learn the rules.
It's all up to you.
Now, I can be a good guy
or I can be one real mean son of a bitch.
It's all up to you.
All right, let's move it.
One at a time. Move it!
Them clothes got laundry numbers
on them.
You remember your number and always
wear the ones that has your number.
Any man forgets his number
spends a night in the box.
These here spoons you keep with you.
Any man loses his spoon
spends a night in the box.
There's no playing grab-ass
or fighting in the building.
You got a grudge against another man,
you fight him Saturday afternoon.
Any man playing grab-ass or fighting
in the building spends a night in the box.
First bell's at five minutes of 8:00
when you will get in your bunk.
Last bell is at 8:00.
Any man not in his bunk at 8:00
spends the night in the box.
There is no smoking
in the prone position in bed.
To smoke you must have both legs
over the side of your bunk.
Any man caught smoking
in the prone position in bed...
spends a night in the box.
You get two sheets.
Every Saturday, you put the clean sheet
on the top...
the top sheet on the bottom...
the bottom sheet you turn in
to the laundry boy.
Any man turns in the wrong sheet
spends a night in the box.
No one'll sit on the bunks
with dirty pants on.
Any man with dirty pants on sitting on
the bunk spends a night in the box.
Any man don't bring back his empty
pop bottle spends a night in the box.
Any man loud talking
spends a night in the box.
You got questions, you come to me.
I'm Carr, the floor walker.
I'm responsible for order in here.
Any man don't keep order
spends a night in...
The box.
I hope you ain't going to be a hard case.
Ain't but four. What did I tell you?
You owe me a cold drink.
I owe you. I owe you.
Move it.
Hey, any of you guys from Connecticut?
Forget it.
Wash them up!
Move!
Well, what are you still doing here?
Get at them beans! Move!
- Twenty-seven.
Next time you stay out of my place.
You try that again and I'll bounce you
all over the floor.
Well, man, I didn't know
it was your special seat.
You don't take another man's seat, man.
It wasn't his fault. Nobody said anything...
You better mind you manners, boy.
You're acting like a hillbilly tramp.
"Tramp." There you go, beauty.
Hey, yeah, man,
you got your bull-gang name now.
Yeah, well, it ain't no worse
than some I been called.
When I was in the Navy...
All you new-meats...
you're going to have to shape up
fast and hard for this gang.
We got rules here.
In order to learn them...
you gotta do more work
with your ears than with your mouth.
Somebody say something?
No, I didn't say nothing, Boss.
What have we got there?
Got a Lucas Jackson.
You don't have a name here
until Dragline gives you one.
Maybe we ought to call it "No-Ears."
You don't listen much, do you, boy?
I ain't heard that much worth listening to.
Just a lot of guys laying down
a lot of rules and regulations.
New-meat looks like a poker player, Drag.
Yeah, come on. Bet that eight.
Yeah, that wouldn't surprise me none.
I know you got $5 pocket money.
That would buy you a whole fistful
of cards. You in or out?
Out.
All right, come on.
It's a nickel to you, Drag. Let's go.
- Come on, Drag.
- Dime.
First bell.
All right, break it up.
How'd you get that scar?
What scar?
Last bell.
Fifty, Boss.
Right, Carr. Fifty.
Getting up here, Carr?
Hey, now.
- Twenty-eight.
- Twenty-nine.
- Thirty.
- Thirty-one.
- Thirty-two.
- Thirty-three.
- Thirty-four.
- Thirty-five.
- Twenty-one.
- Twenty-two.
- Twenty-three.
- Twenty-four.
- Twenty-five.
- Twenty-six.
- Twenty-seven.
- Twenty-eight.
- Twenty-nine.
- Thirty.
- Thirty-one.
- Thirty-two.
- Thirty-three.
- Thirty-four.
- Thirty-five.
- Thirty-six.
Get out of my eyeballing seat,
you new-meat dummy.
I'm a salesman. I used to drive
these roads all the time.
Drag, it's going to be
one hot mother today.
Yeah, I reckon the bear's going
to be walking the road today.
Then I'm lucky I got me a broom.
I work on top, real cush job. I would
hate to be down in that ditch today.
We work in a ditch?
What's the matter with you?
All your big-time driving around,
you ain't never seen a chain gang before?
I ain't used to hard work, neither.
I always tried to avoid it.
I ain't exactly crazy about it, myself.
Well, man, it's going to be
one tough day to learn on.
Now, Koko, why don't you give
one of these new-meat a break...
and let him use your broom today?
Oh, hell, Society,
I ain't going down in that ditch.
Well, I sure would appreciate it.
I ain't in too good a shape right now.
Hey, Koko, you really
going to sell your job?
Well, Drag, I may have to.
Maybe that Lucas War Hero
would give you your price.
I'll give you 50 cents.
50 cents for a sweet job like that?
That's worth at least a buck.
I'll make it a dollar.
Dollar's a deal.
Where'd you get that about "war hero"?
A little birdie told me.
Tearing the heads off of... What was it?
Gumball machines?
What kind of thing is that
for a grown man?
You know how it is. Small town.
Not much to do in the evening.
Mostly, was just settling an old score.
Boss, I made this arrangement
with this man to take his broom.
Get to work.
- You don't understand, I made this deal.
- Get moving.
But I made this arrangement.
Get to work.
Better take it easy.
You won't last two hours.
Taking it off here, Boss?
Yeah, Dragline, take it off there.
- Taking it off here, Boss?
- Yeah, take it off there.
Drinking it up here, Boss?
Man bear-clawed here, Boss!
All right, men.
Let's eat them beans!
Cold drink he don't make it.
You on.
Hey, Babalugats, got a bet here.
- Boss, drinking it up here?
- All right.
Who's that?
That's Godfrey.
The walking boss.
Don't he ever talk?
Think he just said something.
You owe that fella a cold drink.
All right!
You, Gibson, step out.
Boss Paul says you wasn't
happy with your job.
That you was complaining.
Well, we're going to give you
a chance to think about it.
All right.
Let's go.
Get them clothes off.
First bell.
Plumb busted out. Look like the hard road
finally got to Mr. Lucas War Hero.
I'll be back at it in the morning.
Just need a little nap.
Man, I never thought they'd put him
in the box on his first day.
It was only supposed to be a joke.
There ain't no brooms.
Well, can't expect to learn everything
the first day.
May have taught him
a very valuable lesson.
You guys sure give him all night
to think about it.
We can't help it if he's square. Huh, Drag?
Of course not. He ain't in the box
because of the joke played on him.
He back-sassed a free man.
They got their rules and we ain't got
nothing to do with that.
Probably happen to him sooner
or later anyway, complainer like him.
He's gotta learn the rules,
same as anybody else.
Yeah, them poor old bosses need
all the help they can get.
You trying to say something?
Last bell!
One of these days I'm gonna have to
flap me up some dust with it.
Forty-nine and one in the box, Boss.
Right, Carr, 49 and one in the box.
Putting them on here, Boss?
You see that, you see that?
I got eyes, don't I?
How am I not going to see something
that look like that?
Man, oh, man, look at that. Look at that!
- Wiping it off here, Boss?
- Wipe it off.
- Taking them off here, Boss?
- All right, take it off.
Damn things is blocking the scenery.
Oh, man, I'm dying. I'm dying!
Nice broad.
Great set.
Lucille, baby.
Oh, man, I'm dying! I'm dying!
She ain't got nothing but one safety pin
holding that thing on!
Come on, safety pin, pop!
Come on, baby, pop!
Hey, Lord...
whatever I done, don't strike me blind
for another couple of minutes.
My Lucille.
Your Lucille, boy. Where did you get that?
That's Lucille, you mullet-head.
Anything so innocent, and built like that...
just gotta be named Lucille.
Rub it, baby. Clean that car.
Rub, rub...
She doesn't know what she's doing.
Oh, boy, she knows exactly
what she's doing.
She's driving us crazy,
and loving every minute of it!
Shut your mouth about my Lucille.
Old MacDonald had a farm
And on his farm he had a pig
Will you shut up, Babalugats?
Why don't you leave him alone?
He's happy.
Because he's a damn moron!
Why don't you shut your mouth?
- Getting up here, Carr?
- Okay, now.
- Getting up, Carr?
- Yeah.
Getting up here, Carr?
No. Go up.
Oh, man, that little Lucille.
She was really a big lot of little gal,
wasn't she?
Did you see how she was just about
popping out of the top of that dress?
Come on, Drag, cut it out.
And down below...
man, that thing didn't reach
no higher than...
She's liable to catch cold
running around like that.
It was stretched so tight
across her bottom...
I do believe I saw one of them seams
bust loose.
And the opening got wider...
and wider and wider.
Forget it, man.
What do you mean, "forget it"?
Stop beating it into the ground.
You ain't doing nobody no good.
Okay, new-meat. You get some sleep.
And save your strength,
'cause you're going to need it.
Tomorrow.
Hit him! Hit him!
Hey, go get him.
- Nice shot, Drag.
- Stay away from him.
He's still got a chance.
It's a big one.
Come on, Lucas!
Why don't you just stay down, Luke?
He's just going to knock you down again,
buddy.
It's not your fault. He's just too big.
Let him hit you in the nose
and get some blood flowing.
Maybe the bosses will stop it
before he kills you.
I don't want to frighten him.
Stay down, Luke.
Stay down, Luke. He's gonna kill you.
Stay down!
Somebody ought to stop this thing.
Stay down.
You're beat!
You're going to have to kill me.
All right, pot's right. Here we go.
King gets a three, queen, deuce,
seven, pair of savannahs right here.
Deuce gets a four. No help.
Three gets a big ace.
Bet to the savannahs.
Pewter.
I call.
Kick a buck.
A dollar?
One time.
All right, I call.
Hell, if I catch, I'm gonna burn you. I call.
King, three, you got a four,
queen, deuce, gets a five...
and a pair of sevens gets a john.
And the big ace gets... slop in the face.
Okay, you still do the talking.
Pewter again.
I call.
Kick a buck.
- What you got?
- Pair of sevens.
I can see that, mullet-head.
What have you got in the hole?
He ain't got nothing showing.
Raise his head off.
He's been betting...
All right, then you just call it.
I call.
You've got to see it, Gambler.
I can't. I can't catch a damn thing...
I'm snake-bit. I can't catch. I fold.
King, four, three. You got a nine.
Nothing visible.
Pair of sevens and a jack gets a six.
Savannas, you is still a better man.
Pewter.
Kick a buck.
Kick him back a buck!
I'll see your buck and back a buck.
Kick a buck.
Damn!
Don't look at me, mullet-head.
Come on.
What're you going to do,
play like a coconut? You got to call him.
I know he's got a pair of kings.
You don't have to stuff them up my nose.
Well, you still got to call him, anyway.
You gotta look at them.
The man's got kings. Get your tail out.
You want to see them? Right there.
One, two, three, four, five.
Nothing. A handful of nothing.
You stupid mullet-head,
he beat you with nothing.
Just like today when he kept
coming back at me... with nothing.
Sometimes nothing
can be a real cool hand.
Move over.
I'm going to sit in here, next to my boy.
Cool Hand Luke.
Deal.
I'm in this next one.
Hey, Loudmouth!
Come on, get out there.
Your mama's waiting for you.
She never leaves me alone!
Be glad you got somebody, kid.
Luke, visitor for you.
- Son.
- Come on, Ma.
Just a closer walk with Thee
Grant it, Jesus, is my plea
Daily walkin' close to Thee
- Coming out here, Boss?
- Come on out, Luke.
Let it be, dear Lord
Let it be
Through the days of toil that's near
If I fall, dear Lord, who cares?
Who but Thee my burden shares?
None but Thee, dear Lord
None but Thee
How did you find me?
That Helen...
she sent your things along with a note...
and then John here,
he wrote to the police.
Move around here, Boss?
Well, Arletta, I've got to stay here.
I always hoped to see you well-fixed...
have me a crop of grandkids
to fuss around with.
I'd like to oblige you, Arletta, but...
right off, I just don't know
where to put my hands on them.
You know, sometimes...
I wish people was like dogs, Luke.
Comes a time, a day like, when...
the bitch just don't recognize
the pups no more, so...
she don't have no hopes,
nor love, to give her pain.
She just don't give a damn.
They letting you smoke here?
Smoking up here, Boss?
You've done your best, Arletta.
What I've done with myself
is my own problem.
Oh, no, it ain't, Luke. You ain't alone.
Everywhere you go, I'm with you.
And John, too.
You never thought maybe
that's a heavy load?
Why, we always thought you
were strong enough to carry it.
Was we wrong?
I don't know.
Well, things are just never the way...
they seem, Arletta, you know that.
A man's gotta go his own way.
Guess, I've just got to...
got to love you and let go.
I guess.
I ain't asking what you're going to do
when you get out, because...
I'll be dead and it don't matter.
You never did want to live forever.
I mean, it wasn't such a hell of a life.
I had me some high old times.
Your old man, Luke...
he wasn't much good
for sticking around...
but, damn it, he made me laugh.
I would have liked to have known him,
the way you talk about him.
He'd have broke you up.
- Luke?
- Yeah, Mamma?
What went wrong?
- Nothing. Everything's cool as can be.
- No.
Arletta, I tried.
I mean, to...
live always free and above board
like you, but...
I don't know, I just can't seem
to find no elbow room.
You always had good jobs.
And that girl in Kentucky...
Oh. I'd taken a shine to her.
She sure took off
with that convertible fella.
Well, why not?
Idea of marrying got you all,
all bollixed up.
Trying to be respectable.
You was boring the hell out of all of us.
I'm leaving the place to John.
That's good. He earned it.
Ain't nothing to do with it.
I just never give John...
the kind of, you know,
feeling that I give you.
So, I'm going to pay him back now.
Don't feel you have to say anything.
The way it is, you see...
sometimes you just
have a feeling for a child...
or else you don't.
With John, I just didn't.
I gotta go, Arletta.
Laugh it up, kid. You, you'll make out.
Uncle Luke, why can't you have chains?
John-Boy, let me tell you something.
You know, them chains ain't medals.
You get them for making mistakes.
And you make a bad enough mistake,
then you've got to deal with the Man.
He is one rough old boy.
Okay?
So long, Arletta. Take care.
You know it, kid.
Now there ain't nothing to come back for.
Just a closer walk with Thee
Grant it, Jesus, is my plea
Daily walking close to Thee
Let it be, dear Lord
Let it be
Through the days of toil that's near
If I fall, dear Lord, who cares?
Who but Thee
My burden shares?
None but Thee, dear Lord
None but Thee
All right.
This gang's been doing so good...
the Captain decided
to give you something special.
You've got yourselves
a whole road of tarring to do.
And I want to see you roll it.
Pick up your shovels.
Get with it. Move!
The bear's sure going to be walking
the road today.
What's the deal?
Man, you think you been working hard?
This mother's going to break your back.
Let's roll! Let's see those shovels!
All right, roll it!
I'm gonna twist my arm off
if this heat don't kill me first. Right, Boss.
Hey, buddy, slow down.
That's a long road.
Well, the Man wants speed,
let's just give it to him.
Cram it in and break it off. Go hard.
What are we racing for?
Wants speed, let's give it to him.
Use that shovel like it was your spoon.
Shag it, man.
The Man, boy, get the Man!
Moving it up here, Boss?
Now you tell me, Rabbitt,
what's going on here?
I don't know, Boss.
I think they're all bear-clawed.
They don't know whether to smile,
spit, or swallow.
Well, they've never seen
a bull gang before.
Where'd the road go?
That's it. That's the end of it.
Man, there's still daylight.
About two hours left.
What do we do now?
Nothing.
Oh, Luke, you wild, beautiful thing!
You crazy handful of nothing!
"As Carol pressed her lips to him...
"his right hand started a slow
descent down her silken body.
"Desire and fear, temptation and terror...
"yearning and horror warred
within her beautiful young body."
They have to close those things,
or we'll drown...
but it sure is suffocating in here.
Talk about drowning.
When I was in the Navy...
I was on submarine duty once,
and when you get down there...
Will you tell your story walking?
It's too hot.
Did you see my skinny little boy
chow tonight?
He's matching you plate for plate.
I wasn't feeling good.
I think I got an ulcer or something.
He had a bigger spoon.
Made you look like yours had a hole in it.
Come on, Clarence.
What do you mean, "Clarence"?
You calling me a liar?
No, not a liar.
You just have a common and
likeable tendency toward exaggeration.
That there's the champion hog-gutter
of this camp.
Hell, I've seen him eat
ten chocolate bars...
and seven cold drinks in 15 minutes.
He can eat busted bottles and rusty nails,
any damn thing.
If you be so kind to let me cut off
your Yankee head, he'll even eat that.
I can eat 50 eggs.
Nobody can eat 50 eggs.
You just said he could eat anything.
You ever eat 50 eggs?
Nobody ever ate 50 eggs.
Hey, Babalugats! We got a bet here.
My boy says he can eat 50 eggs,
he can eat 50 eggs.
Yeah, but in how long?
In an hour.
Well, I believe I'll take part of that wager.
$2. Right here. I'm going to Koko.
Come on now, let's talk some money.
All right, $20. Anything.
The syndicate will cover any kind of bet
you want to make.
Koko, get some paper.
Drag, 50 eggs got to weigh
a good 6 pounds.
Man's gut can't hold that.
They'll swell up and bust him open.
You gonna kill him.
All right, get your money up. Now,
Gambler, Dynamite, come on, get it up.
Coconut-head's going to take all the
money. Come on, Loudmouth, get it up.
Wait just a minute, now.
How's he gonna eat them?
Boiled for 15 minutes.
Eat the whole thing in an hour.
One rule. No throwing up.
He throws up, you forfeit everything.
Now when was the last time
you ever saw my boy throw up?
Now shut your mouth
and give your money to Koko.
Come on, now. Right over here.
Luke, what did you have to say 50 for?
Why couldn't you say 35 or 39?
It seemed a nice round number.
That's money you're talking about.
What's the matter with you?
Yeah, well, it'll be something to do.
- Ten!
- Ten, right!
What did I do?
I stole and I told lies.
Keep your left up.
- But I love my neighbor.
- And his wife.
He'll never make it.
Wait a second.
What we've got to do is stretch
that little old belly of yours.
Do it, man.
Get all this stuff out of the way
of them eggs coming down.
What do you think?
We've got to get it all in fighting shape,
like a barrage balloon.
Ready?
And go!
Hey, Boss, man needs a brown bomber
and a dose of salts.
Nobody said nothing about that.
You can't do that!
- I want my money back.
- No money back.
Twenty of those pills still won't
make any difference. Go ahead.
What are you worried about?
He can't do it.
Do we get our money?
What's he doing?
Here comes his eggs.
All right, stand back, you pedestrians.
This ain't no automobile accident.
Is that all 50 of them?
Move over, losers.
I got money riding on it.
All right, I've got it figured out.
If he eats an egg a minute,
he's got 10 minutes left to swallow them.
Hey, I was just sent $5 from a rodeo outfit.
- What for? Well, you gonna bet it?
- Last bull I fell off of.
- Hey, you're peeling his eggs!
- That's right, Mr. Alibi.
He peels his eggs himself.
That's understood.
Now you may be just great
at hanging paper around the big city...
and passing bad checks...
but us country boys
ain't entirely brainless.
When it comes to the law,
nothing is understood.
Wait a minute! Wait a minute!
Who made what law
about peeling the eggs?
I'm his trainer.
I'm the syndicate covering all bets.
And I'm his official egg-peeler.
That's the law.
Just wait till the hour starts, that's all.
I was banking on the fact
that he had to peel them.
First it was the salt...
What's going on?
All right.
You ready, champ?
Ready?
Go!
One...
two...
three...
Man, he's going to lose a finger
eating eggs like that.
Twenty-four...
twenty-five...
Slow down a little.
Twenty-six...
Forget it, he's wasting time.
What's the exercise,
is that part of the rules?
You better forget about it.
Thirty-two.
Still got 18 more to go...
What's wrong?
- I think he's gonna throw up!
- Oh, no.
- That's it.
- He's finished.
- Come on, Luke!
- Eighteen to go.
Hey, you'll feel better.
He's finished.
Just like a ripe watermelon
that's about to bust itself open.
Your boy's done for, Drag.
I'm putting in my last penny.
- It don't look good, Drag.
- Man's gut can't hold more than that.
- He's all right, he's all right.
- He's going to make himself sick.
- He's all right.
- Attaboy.
I give you a dollar, he don't eat all 50 eggs,
I get $2 back.
Fixer, you is a sweet old boy.
You better take that dollar and buy
yourself a new spark plug or something.
But as long as you done took a stand...
why don't you put some money where
your mouth is and not no measly buck!
Well, all I got is $3.75, Drag.
That's a bet, Koko.
All right, now, the rest of you,
I want to hear from some big-money men.
Where's all the high rollers?
I believe you've got it all, Dragline.
Every cent in camp is riding.
Thirty-three.
- What's the time?
- Come on, baby.
Twenty-four minutes to go.
Just let that little old belly sag
and enjoy itself.
Thirty-nine.
Going down into the cage.
Twenty-four minutes. He'll never make it.
Forty-one.
Stay loose, buddy. Just nine more
between you and everlasting glory.
Is he eating them, Alibi?
He's chewing. Look at that.
They're pigeon eggs, that's all.
Fish eggs, practically.
How much more time, Carr?
Six minutes to go, Stevie.
Chew, chew, chew!
You're helping him chew now!
I'm not.
- Forty-two.
- He's not spitting them out.
Tiny, tiny egg.
Two minutes to time!
Forty-four.
All right, now,
get mad at them damned eggs.
Eat them down, boy.
Chew on it.
Gnaw on it.
Thirty seconds.
You got the last one.
Stuff it down in there. Get it in.
That's the last one in there now, baby.
Chew. Chew.
He's got to swallow it all
before the time's up.
Ten, nine, eight...
seven, six, five...
four, three, two...
one, zero!
Hold it! He didn't swallow the last.
You think so? Just take a look here.
Open that mouth.
Nobody can eat 50 eggs.
Snake in the grass here, Boss!
Get it.
Get it!
Pick it up here, Boss?
Hey, Boss?
Forgot your walking stick.
Man, you sure can shoot.
You've gone too far when
you mess with the Man With No Eyes.
You'll be out of here in a little bit.
Why don't you take it a little easy?
All right, everybody in the trucks.
Boy, look at him go! Bam! Bam!
Just knock it off, Luke!
You can't talk about him that way.
You still believe in
that big bearded boss up there?
You think he's watching us?
Get in here!
Aren't you scared?
Aren't you scared of dying?
Dying? Boy, he can have this
little life anytime he wants to.
You hear that? You hear it?
Come on! You're welcome to it, old timer.
Let me know you're up there. Come on.
Love me, hate me, kill me, anything.
Just let me know it.
Just standing in the rain...
talking to myself.
Blind Dick is paying back three
and borrowing five.
Next.
You borrowing or paying back?
Borrowing.
Well, Mr. Cool Hand here is the soft heart
in our loan department.
I just need five, Luke.
I knew you could really eat all them eggs.
Yeah, well, I didn't.
That's my darling Luke.
He grins like a baby...
but he bites like a gator. Next.
I believe I still owe the 30.
I don't suppose you'd care to take a check?
Luke.
Sorry.
His mother's dead.
I don't care if it rains or freezes
As long as I got my plastic Jesus
Sitting on the dashboard of my car
Comes in colors pink and pleasant
Glows in the dark 'cause it's iridescent
Take it with you
When you travel far
Get yourself a sweet Madonna
Dressed in rhinestone sitting on
A pedestal of abalone shell
Going 90, I ain't scary
'Cause I got the Virgin Mary
Assuring me
That I won't go to hell
Get yourself a sweet Madonna
Dressed in rhinestone sitting on
A pedestal of abalone shell
Going 90, I ain't scary
'Cause I got the Virgin Mary
Assuring me
That I won't go to hell
Luke, fall out.
When a man's mother dies...
and he gets to thinking about
her funeral and paying respects...
before he knows it, his mind ain't right.
He's got rabbit in his blood and he runs.
We're keeping you off the road for a while.
I'm going to say a prayer
for your ma, Luke.
Sorry, Luke, I'm just doing my job.
You've got to appreciate that.
Calling it your job
don't make it right, Boss.
Twenty-one.
- Twenty-two.
- Twenty-three.
- Twenty-four.
- Twenty-five.
- Twenty-six.
- Twenty-seven.
- Twenty-eight.
- Twenty-nine.
- Thirty.
- Thirty-one.
- Moving it up here, Boss?
- Move it up.
Four.
Five.
- Six.
- Seven.
- Eight.
- Nine.
- Ten.
- Eleven.
- Twelve.
- Thirteen.
Your ma's in the ground now,
God rest her soul.
You best forget about it, Luke.
Got a day and a half lay-in.
Tomorrow's a holiday.
- Happy Fourth of July!
- Same to you!
Break it up. Come on, you had your fun.
First bell! Move it, Stevie.
Hey, Carr. Come here.
What have you got,
another one of them dirty books, Drag?
Do yourself a favor. Read this part
that Koko underlined for me.
"She moved her head another inch
while he reached up...
"and put his left hand on Carol's...
"As Carol pressed her..."
Oh, I can't stand it!
You're just coming to
the interesting part now.
Yeah, go ahead.
- I can't hear you.
- "Her trembling body...
"shivered under his..."
All right!
Last bell. Last bell.
- Move it.
- Hey, Carr.
What's that noise outside?
Man on the fence, Boss!
Hit him!
Wait a minute! Damn it!
Blue, come back here! Damn it!
Forty-eight, Boss.
One in the box and one in the bush.
Forty-eight. One in the box
and one in the bush.
Oh, listen to Blue sing!
He's onto him, he says. He's got him.
Hell, that dog's running around in circles.
No, he's onto him.
Captain says for us to wait
till the patrol gets here.
Should've waited for me to get him out.
Loose like that he can run him crazy.
Didn't even have enough sense
to run from the road like everybody else.
Oh, I'm beat. This ain't my job nohow.
Your dogs are crazy.
He's crossed it.
He's smarter than I thought. Let's go!
He made it!
Look, Captain!
Look what he done to Blue.
He's dead.
He run himself plumb to death.
Mr. Hunnicutt.
Get in line facing the Captain.
You're going to get used to wearing
them chains after a while, Luke...
but you'll never stop listening
to them clinking.
'Cause they're going to remind you
of what I've been saying...
for your own good.
Wish you'd stop being so good
to me, Captain.
Don't you ever talk that way to me.
Never!
What we've got here is...
failure to communicate.
Some men you just can't reach.
So you get what we had here last week,
which is the way he wants it.
Well, he gets it.
I don't like it anymore than you men.
Well, lookie here.
I knew they'd get you.
Them chains and a bonus
of a couple of years...
Your running days are over forever, boy.
Hell, I'd like to see you try to run again.
You know, you getting so you smell
so bad, I can track you myself.
Yeah, well, that ought to be easy
for a genuine son of a bitch.
Tell us what happened.
How far did you get?
Shut up and let him eat.
About a mile and a half.
This supermarket parking lot.
Found a car with keys in the ignition.
Hit this red light and this police car
slides up alongside.
Then what did you do?
Waited for that light to change.
This cop kept looking over, wondering
what somebody that looks like me...
dressed in state issue,
was doing driving a shiny new buggy.
So what did he do?
He leaned over and said, "Hey!"
Topflight police work,
that's all there is to it.
Fella's probably a lieutenant by now.
Now, we're just gonna lay low
and build time.
Before you know it,
the heat's going to be off of you.
Everything will be right back where it was.
Right, sweet buddy?
I hear tell you don't believe
in no God, Luke.
I was wondering how come a nice,
clean-cut young fellow like you...
gets to be put on the hard road.
Now I reckon I knows.
I've been on the road gang
almost 22 years.
In all that time,
I ain't never killed no white man...
but I ain't afraid to because...
Excuse me, Boss, don't mean to interrupt.
Caught short here.
It's all right. It's okay.
You just go on out there
behind them trees.
A man's gotta have his privacy sometime.
You just keep shaking that bush
so we know you're there.
Just keep shaking that bush.
Yes, Boss.
Shaking it up here, Boss!
Still shaking it, Boss.
I'm shaking it, Boss.
Damn!
He's gone. Get the dogs.
What you got them on for?
How do you take your pants off?
Best way is to get rid of them leg irons...
but you ain't strong enough.
Strong enough for what?
Hell, you couldn't heft an axe.
Can, too.
- I bet you can't.
- Can, too.
- Bet you can't.
Well, then go get it, man.
What's your name, boy?
Ben.
Aren't you going to take
those stripes off your pants?
You know it, kid.
- You want to see something real funny?
- Yeah?
Well, you go on in there and you get me...
chili powder, pepper, curry and the like.
A lot of it, all right?
You'd better let me handle that, son.
Here they are.
Thank you, son.
What's the matter with him?
He'll be all right.
Hey, boy.
Now listen. You're going to have
some fun. You hear that?
Well, you remember how them dogs do
when they come through here...
so you can tell me
about it someday, okay?
My wife hasn't written me for a month.
She's probably sick again.
Drag...
magazine for you.
- Carr, you got anything?
- Magazines.
Hey, Koko, who's sending me magazines?
Don't know. It's from Atlanta.
My uncle!
Ain't heard from him in eight years
and now he's sending me magazines!
He must have gone crazy!
Look at that!
- That's Luke?
- Look at that, two of them.
What's the writing say?
What's that writing say?
"Dear boys: Playing it cool. Luke."
Let me take a look. Come here.
Hey, pass it around.
They must be 6 feet tall.
Give it back there.
Look at that!
My baby! We're in here
digging and dying...
he's out there living and flying.
Koko, will you stop that?
Why don't you try making me?
- Hey, Drag? Let me see the picture.
- What for?
Come on, Drag, let us see the picture.
No, you're just a kid.
What you know about it?
You don't want to see that dirty picture.
Luke and them broads and all that booze.
Come on, let me take a look.
It would go to your coconut head.
You're liable to get ideas...
and pass right out.
Come on, Drag, be a buddy.
Now, what you figure it's worth?
A peek at that there picture?
A quick look now.
I'm not talking about no memorizing job.
Cold drink.
A cold... One cold drink...
to feast your starving, fishy,
little eyes on the picture?
A true vision of paradise itself...
with two of the angels right there
frisking around with my boy?
Okay, it's a deal.
One cold drink, in advance.
One chilly bottle
right in my hot little hand.
That goes for the rest
of you mullet-heads, too.
Let me see.
Did you pay?
Coming in there, Wickerman.
You run one time,
you get yourself a set of chains.
You run twice, you get yourself two sets.
You ain't going to need no third set...
because you're going to get
your mind right.
And I mean "right."
Take a good look at Luke.
Cool Hand Luke.
- Easy, easy!
- Let him breathe!
Oh, my poor baby.
They done you real good.
I don't know if you're going
to have them girls chasing you.
I'll get some aspirin.
- He should have a doctor.
- Ain't you ever gonna learn?
They ain't gonna let no doctor see
what they've done.
Some ice should take that swelling down.
Get your razor. We'll clean up
some of these cuts on his head.
How you feeling, buddy? How you feeling?
Maybe he can't hear you.
Somebody ought to give him
something cold to drink.
- That's my baby.
- Now he's going to be all right.
Hey, Luke, look, we got the picture
you sent us. Look there.
You really can pick them, Luke.
Come on, tell us. What were they like?
Can't you wait until he stops bleeding?
- Why don't you go back to your knitting?
- Knock it off, you guys.
Picture's a phony. Cost me a week's pay.
What do you mean, a phony?
What you talking about, man?
We see them two women
right here in the picture.
Did you have them both at once?
I mean, together?
Picture's a phony.
I had it made up for you guys.
What do you mean? We saw it all!
You was having a big time, man.
You had it made!
Nothing. Made nothing, had nothing.
Couple of towns, couple of bosses.
I laughed out loud once, he turned me in.
But I got it here!
Oh, come on! Stop beating it!
Get out there yourselves!
Stop feeding off me! Get out of here!
Can't breathe. Give me some air!
Well, he ain't himself, can't you see that?
He's all beat up.
He don't know what he's saying.
All right, come on, break it up.
Now, straighten out that bench.
You was eyeballing.
Can't get your mind on them weeds
if you're eyeballing.
You don't need reasons to kick me, Boss.
First bell. Move it.
He'll never make it.
What are you talking about?
That old box will collapse and fall apart
before Luke calls it quits.
Your Luke's got more guts than brains.
Well, I don't see no sign of guts in you.
No. No chains, either.
Big deal paperhanger,
passing two-bit checks.
You haven't had much luck playing
follow-the-leader, have you?
All right! Last bell!
You want to spend the night
in the box, too?
Well, here's our champion hog-gut.
Ain't ate for four days.
You're going to need a little extra.
Got plenty for you.
Now you know the rules.
Got to clean your plate
or go back in the box. Right, Boss?
That's enough, Dog Boy.
Oh, man used to free-world food
has got a big appetite.
We're going to stretch that
hog-belly right out, huh?
One.
- Two.
- Three.
- Four.
- Five.
- Six.
- Seven.
Well, you made the week, boy.
Now you got a day-and-a-half
to rest up for old Monday.
Luke!
That ditch is Boss Keen's ditch.
I told him that dirt in it is your dirt.
What's your dirt doing in his ditch?
I don't know, Boss.
You better get in there and get it out, boy.
Well, you wake up in the morning
Hear the ding dong ring
You go a-marching to the table
See the same damn thing
Well, it's on the table
A knife, a fork and a pan
Say anything about it
You get in trouble with the man
Let the midnight special
Shine a light on me
Shine her ever-loving light on me
If you ever go to Houston
Boy, you better walk right
And you better not stagger
And you better not fight
'Cause the sheriff's gonna arrest you
Luke, what do you think you're doing?
Just getting my dirt
out of Boss Keen's ditch, Boss.
I'll be damned if you're going
to put your dirt in my yard.
You hear me?
Now let's get it out of there.
If you ever go to Houston
Boy, you better walk right
And you better not stagger
And you better not fight
'Cause the sheriff's gonna arrest you
They're gonna take you down
Say anything about it
You're penitentiary-bound
Let the midnight special
Shine a light on me
I told you to get your dirt out
of Boss Keen's ditch, didn't I?
Yeah, Boss.
Then how come it ain't out?
I don't know, Boss.
You don't know.
Ain't no grave
Gonna keep my body down
Gonna hold my body down
Keep your mind on me above
Keep your heart full of love
Ain't no grave
Gonna hold my body down
What's all this dirt doing in here?
I don't know.
When I was a little bitty baby
My mamma used to rock me in my cradle
In them old cotton fields back home
It was down in Louisiana
Don't, Boss.
Get to work.
Don't, Boss. Don't hit me anymore.
For God's sake, don't hit me anymore.
What was that you said?
What was that name you used, Luke?
Oh, God!
Oh, God, I pray to God
you don't hit me anymore.
I'll do anything you say,
but I can't take anymore.
- You got your mind right, Luke?
- Yeah...
I got it right.
Oh, I got it right, Boss.
Suppose you was to backslide on us?
Oh, no, I won't, Boss.
Suppose you was to back-sass?
Oh, no, I won't. I won't.
I got my mind right.
You try to run again,
we're going to kill you.
I won't, I won't, Boss.
Go get cleaned up and get yourself
some sleep. Suspect you need it.
Come on, son.
Come on up out of there.
Coming in, Boss.
I got my mind right.
Where are you?
Where are you now?
- All right. Smoke it up.
- Yes, sir.
Luke, water them down.
Yes, Boss.
Luke! Fetch the rifle.
You got him, Boss. You got him.
Go fetch it, Luke.
There he is, Boss.
Deader than hell, but won't let go.
You cut that up for our lunch, Luke.
Yes, sir, Boss Paul.
He took the keys off of Dog Boy's truck.
He got the keys here, too.
"I'm shaking it here, Boss. I'm shaking it."
That's my baby, Luke.
"Don't hit me, Boss. Don't hit me.
"I'll do whatever you say.
Only don't hit me."
You are an original, that's what you are.
Those mullet-heads didn't even know
you were fooling them.
Fooling them? You can't fool them
about something like that.
They broke me.
But they didn't get my mind right.
Not with no stick. No, sir.
All that time you were planning
on running again.
I've never planned anything in my life.
That's just a little old farm road.
Clean as a whistle.
I worked it a couple times.
We're home free. Come on.
We ain't going nowhere.
Now, what are you talking about, Luke?
We're going by my house
and we're going to have a big meal.
Then, I'm going to show you a couple of
farm girls that really knows what fun...
And then we're going to get Koko
out of there.
And then the terrible trio
going to be complete again.
Man, this old free world
ain't going to know which ear to stand on.
Yeah, well, you and Koko
can handle it without me.
What you mean, Luke?
I've done enough world-shaking
for a while.
You do the rest of it for me.
Send me a postcard about it.
- But, Luke...
- Take it easy, Drag.
Where are you going?
Just on my own.
But what am I going to do, all by myself?
Man, if I hadn't lost my head.
I only had a couple of years to do.
But when I saw you tearing down the road
in that truck...
Well, you're right, Luke.
We ought to split up.
And then, and then it will be safer
for the both of us.
Just the same,
you're a good old boy, Luke.
You take care!
You hear?
Anybody here?
Hey, old man. You home tonight?
Can you spare a minute?
It's about time we had a little talk.
I know I'm a pretty evil fellow...
killed people in the war and got drunk...
and chewed up municipal property
and the like.
I know I got no call to ask for much...
but even so, you've got to admit,
you ain't dealt me no cards in a long time.
It's beginning to look like you got
things fixed so I can't never win out.
Inside, outside, all of them...
rules and regulations and bosses.
You made me like I am.
Now just where am I supposed to fit in?
Old man, I gotta tell you.
I started out pretty strong and fast...
but it's beginning to get to me.
When does it end?
What do you got in mind for me?
What do I do now?
All right.
On my knees, asking.
Yeah, that's what I thought.
I guess I'm pretty tough to deal with, huh?
A hard case.
I guess I gotta find my own way.
Luke!
Is that your answer, old man?
I guess you're a hard case, too.
Luke, you all right?
They got us, boy. They're out there,
thicker than flies.
Bosses, dogs, sheriffs...
more guns than I've ever seen in my life.
You ain't got a chance.
They caught up with me
right after we split up.
And they was aiming to kill you.
But I fixed that.
I got them to promise
if you give up peaceful...
they ain't even going
to whip you this time.
They're even going to give us
our same bunks back?
Sure, why not?
We've only been gone a couple of hours.
They're reasonable men.
Yeah, well.
You've got to listen to me.
All you've got to do is give up...
nice and quiet.
Just play it cool.
Yeah, like I always do?
Yeah, just play it...
What're you doing?
"What we got here
is a failure to communicate."
Go get him.
You hang on in there, Luke. You hang on.
There's going to be
some world-shaking, Luke.
We're going to send you a postcard.
You follow me and I'll radio
the emergency clinic to open up.
I'm taking him to the prison hospital.
But that's an hour away. He won't make it.
Get out of the way. He's ours.
They took him right down that road.
- What'd he look like, Drag?
- Yeah, Drag, what did he look like?
Did he have his eyes open or closed?
- He was smiling.
- Smiling?
That's right. You know,
that Luke smile of his?
He had it on his face right to the very end.
Hell, if they didn't know it before...
they could tell right then
that they weren't ever going to beat him.
That old Luke smile.
Oh, Luke. He was some boy.
Cool Hand Luke, hell!
He's a natural born world-shaker!
English