Who's dealing, you or me?
Me.
One card for you...
...one card for me.
Three for you, one for me.
Four for me, one for you.
Five for me.
Rotten hand.
You're playing funny.
You don't want...? Don't get mad.
I was only asking.
How many cards do you want?
Three?
Are you going to give me a break?
I have a bad hand.
Wait till you see what I'm going to do.
Moron.
This will be my victory.
Daddy.
Did you see how brilliant...?
Show your hand...
Don't get mad.
You, don't interrupt me...
...or you'll be sorry.
When I get married,
buy me a truck like that.
I take two.
And you? None? Great.
Two for me.
Lovely hand. Three Aces.
-Swanker.
Promise, when I get married.
Four Sevens.
Look, how lovely.
Screw your "lovely".
Daddy, look.
I told you, don't interrupt
when I'm playing cards.
Daddy likes you,
but you're troubling him.
Cards are like whores.
Fickle.
Who do you think I am?
I can bluff.
Maxim Gorki is here. The Russians.
Look at this. Poker.
Maradona.
Hurry up, Zare.
-Give my eggs back.
How much for the horns, comrade?
Ten marks.
Come on, five marks.
No way. Ten.
What do you want with it?
-Silence. Simpleton.
It is secondhand raw material.
One for five marks.
One million horns, five million marks.
Sure.
How much for the washing machine?
-300 marks.
Fine machine. Very good.
I'll make you an excellent offer.
220 marks for the horns,
the washing machine and the computer.
No way. 280.
-250.
Sold.
-Shake hands.
Can I help?
-It's all right.
On that side.
Daddy.
We've been swindled.
Have a look.
The Russians trade water for Diesel.
What?
Water. Have a look.
100 percent Diesel.
Water.
-The barrel is full of water.
The whole barrel?
The cold rain falls at dawn.
I don't understand.
Why is she wearing spy-glasses
and a grater?
Some small change
for the baby she's expecting.
For the surgery.
Grandma expresses her gratitude.
-What?
It will be two, according to the echo.
Piss off, bloody gipsy.
The gate, the gate.
Halt, who goes there?
Hello.
-Who are you?
Matko Destanov.
-Hands up.
Hands up.
Goose, over.
I was planning to
go to Hungary tonight.
To the fair in Pecs.
Go to the fair wherever you like,
but don't return without a fiancée.
Understood?
Hello, mister Grga, boss.
Little bird, why have you returned?
I've never been here.
Yes you have, five years ago.
-Me? No.
Don't contradict me.
-We saw each other, but not here.
Someone important relocates often.
Eight years ago then.
-Eight? That's impossible.
O yes, yes.
My compliments, uncle Grga.
Look at me.
-I am looking at you.
Why are you here? And don't tell lies.
I would do anything for your father.
He saved my life twice.
In Genova, and in Marseille.
-I know.
He beat up half the city...
...to get me out of jail.
He is a gentlemen.
Was. May the Lord have mercy on his soul.
On whose soul?
-My father's. Last year.
One day I was doing all right, the
next day I was an orphan.
Without any help.
Lost and lonely.
No one can help me.
You were his downfall.
A swindler, a rotter, gambler, vagabond.
That was temporary.
Making mistakes is human. I have changed.
I've learned my lesson.
Uncle Grga, I've got a brilliant plan.
What kinda plan?
-A train.
A train with 20 wagon-loads of gasoline.
Gasoline?
What use is that going to be to me?
Since the death of my father...
...I don't get anybodies help.
That's business for the pros.
They'll screw you.
You're a freshman.
No, Uncle Grga. I've got it all
covered this time. It'll be all right.
I've got it on paper.
I'll show you the fax.
Don't come back without a wife.
Are you up to something again?
Laugh, dammit.
I received an urgent fax.
Everything's in there.
All the details.
Birdy.
Come here.
Goose, over... Reply.
Look, uncle Grga.
Everything's in the fax.
We invest 70.000 marks...
What, boss?
Goose, the laborers can go.
And you too.
All right, boss.
Let's have a break.
I want to loan 70.000 and within a
week I'll return you 100.000.
Did you see that?
I see it, uncle Grga.
You sure have a lot of money.
I'm only doing this for your father.
You won't have to pay me back...
...but I do want a full report
of your lucrative deal.
If not I'll send my grandsons
to skin you alive.
Am I making myself clear?
-Very clear.
Weirdo.
-Millions. Maradona.
You said your granddad died.
He's in a hospital,
that's practically the same.
He has a large cement factory
and never gave me a penny.
Zare, my son. With this money
your daddy will buy you a future...
...and your children's future.
Leave me be.
I'll never forgive you.
Zare.
Take a look at this miracle.
Now that's what I call an invention.
Only the Germans can
invent something like that.
Daddy makes a promise to you...
Boy, when I'm rich,
I'll make a ship-owner out of you.
Dadi.
There's our benefactor.
Pitbull.
Terrier.
Fortune favors the bold.
Ungrateful bastard. I give you something to
eat and that's your way of saying thank you?
It's all in the game.
Welcome, Dadi, my dear brother.
-Who is he?
What the fuck do you care?
-I was only asking.
So there's a God after all.
Is there anything to see?
Unlucky person. Read this.
You wanted to see me.
I don't wanna work with thieves anymore.
What are you waiting for?
Give the man something to drink.
I've got a cunning plan.
-You?
Honderd percent failsafe.
It's the plan of the century.
I've got a connection in Jordan.
He sells me a train full of gasoline.
Brilliant. A stroke of luck.
-Well just buy it.
I don't have the money.
That's why I need you.
You know the custom-house officers.
You don't need to know the
custom-house officers.
The Bulgarians always say: "Brother, if you
can't solve a problem with money...
...solve it with a lot of money."
Have a drink.
What is it?
Whisky in a gin-glass?
You don't like gypsies?
Get lost, bitch.
Get lost all of you.
Fuck you all. You too, out.
You choose her side.
No.
-He's lying.
Forget it.
-Piss off.
Suckers.
I'm not a racist.
Huh, Matko?
-You have always been tolerant.
I've known you since you were little.
-Sorry.
I'll drink from the bottle.
No way. Cheers.
On our deal.
Ain't he cute?
He's old enough to get married.
Zare? He's not of age, but he is mature.
Is he honest?
-One hunderd percent. That's what counts.
Lucky you. You live like a man.
Not like me, with that scum.
Motherfucking junkies.
Don't you dare that again.
Stop whining.
Apparently you're not short on anything.
What's that to me? Tell me.
I've got it made.
I have a big house, a castle.
2500 square meters.
Daddy's mausoleum.
No-one in this land has one like it.
Ain't it beautiful?
-Very much so.
Why are you crying, Dadi?
Don't cry.
-Why not?
Why shouldn't I cry?
-It's a wonderful house.
It's a shame. A shame.
-How come?
I've fulfilled all of daddy's wishes.
Except one:
Nobody wants to marry my sister.
It's a disgrace.
Don't you worry, my brother.
All will be well.
We'll make this deal
and drink on it.
Cheers.
Hello, Aksim?
I'm in trouble, help me.
I've heard you've got a singer.
She can work miracles.
Go serve the customer.
Wait till he comes in.
-Go water the pole.
What's her name? Medusa?
Damn, disconnected again.
The devil's playing with that phone.
The line got disconnected again.
I told you: it's the devil.
Damn it. Go water the telephone pole.
I can't do business this way.
She's getting on my nerves.
Hey you. Come here.
Who? Me?
Stop acting funny, you're not waiting for
anyone. You're following me all the time.
I only want a lemonade.
Of course.
Go water the pole.
Hurry up. Grab a bucket.
What a jerk.
Pour.
I don't hear you... I don't hear anything.
Now I can hear you.
Loud and clear.
Send that singer with the fast train.
She begins tomorrow.
And my lemonade?
You'll get that when
when the goose grow a beard.
Music.
My dear grandson.
I brought you some clothes.
What does the doc say?
That I'll live to become 100,
if they leave me alone.
And your liver?
-Completely gone to pot.
You shouldn't drink anymore.
What? I will drink.
I will drink if I feel like it.
This is a hospital.
Music isn't allowed here.
Doctor, you've got to make
an end to this.
Imagine what it would be like if
all patients brought an orchestra.
You don't have the right to be so cross.
It's a matter of respect.
What a wonderful life.
Excellent booze. I'm on fire.
Grandson, I've got to tell you something.
You don't have a mother,
your father is no good.
I sold the cement factory.
Up in smoke. I sold it to
that crook, Dadan.
I took the money.
For your future.
If you need money,
go to my friend...
...whom I haven't seen in 25 years.
His name is...
I know. Grga Pitic.
-You know him?
You've told me about your friendship
a thousand times.
A seven feet giant with
hands like shovels.
He's got two rows of teeth.
One gold, the other normal.
Elegant as a vampire.
Music... aggression.
Shoot me.
Here's a flowerpot.
Leave me alone, Apin.
I'll tell you something, old man.
I despise death.
"Louis, I think this is the beginning
of a beautiful friendship."
Boss, try to taste the difference.
Our whisky is better than the real thing.
Logical. Our technology is better.
Where are you, children?
-We're here, grandpa.
Sit down.
That's enough, children.
You, what have you've been up to?
-You know, I was looking for a wife.
He's been to 28 fairs.
-And did he find a wife?
Answer him, jackass.
There are enough women for fun and
making out, but not to marry.
Why? All your friends are married
and have children.
When I was your age I had
been married four times.
The sister?
Find a girl and get it over with.
Don't get excited. What was number five
like? The one that stole your heart?
Tell me.
My darling.
Only the memory of her was
enough to lighten my heart.
My darling...
That's family.
As soon as you saw her, you knew
she was the one. That's what I want too.
When will that be?
When I'm dead?
Why don't you be a good boy and
marry for him.
Yesterday I had another attack.
I can barely see.
Again?
-Again.
I beg you for the last time:
find yourself a wife.
Take me to the hospital
to recover.
I'll get out for your marriage.
Bring me a daughter in law.
Ok, grandad.
Kssss, cat.
Black cats are bad luck.
Mincha, brother.
Take care of the passenger train,
I'll take the goods train.
There's the train.
One...
...two, three...
...five...
...six...
...nineteen...
...and twenty.
All's well.
This calls for a celebration.
I was scared shitless to be screwed.
The train is here, as promised.
The money is here too, as promised.
You got what you asked for.
I was anxious when the train
crossed the border.
Is all going ahead of schedule?
-You made a promise.
Cheers.
Why are you hiding?
Dammit, I call the shots around here.
Stop, young man.
That suitcase is mine.
But I gave everybody their share.
Where's the rest?
It's all, I swear on the Bible.
There must be a misunderstanding.
You black soul!
I should finish you.
-No.
Shame on you.
Here's the little birdy.
He's sleeping.
My suitcase.
Give back my suitcase, thief.
I spit on your dead.
Get down, you pig.
I want my suitcase back.
I'll climb up there.
The moment has arrived
for you and me...
...to look each other in the eye.
Just you and me.
Bloody son of a bitch.
I'm here.
Man, this is way too high.
Dadan, brother.
Dadan, It's me. Matko.
The train is not here.
-What?
Did he cross the border?
Answer me. Where are my 17 tankers
I paid for?
It crossed the border 30 minutes ago.
It's here somewhere.
Here? Where?
You don't lose track of a train.
Somebody drugged me.
I was asleep for only 10 minutes.
-Who done it?
He did.
It was him.
-That pig?
My Bulgarian custom officers
didn't see no train.
They're lying. They're double crossing,
but they will have to pay.
A train rides on track,
not just through the woods.
It can't just have gone up in smoke,
or can it? Boss?
No way, dammit.
My dear public...
After a triumphant tour in
North-Africa, Asia and Australia...
...I'm proud to present to you:
Medusa.
An act, never seen before:
...to pull a nail from a beam
in the most spectacular fashion.
It wasn't an ordinary fight,
but more one man against King Kong.
Who was the man?
-Me.
It wasn't an ordinary Bulgarian.
That jerk could only pass the
doorway sideways.
Name?
-Rambo.
A warm welcome for this
young man named Rambo.
Please hold your breaths,
my honored guests...
The great, unforgettable,
breathtaking moment is near.
It will be burned into your memory.
I proposed an honest fight.
But he kicked me in the balls.
I grabbed him by the hair and whirled
his head around. He gets angry.
I had to save my skin after all,
didn't I?
You'll return my money tonight at
11 o'clock.
Otherwise I'll hang you by the balls
on the windmill.
So you can learn to be an astronaut.
Jerk.
Don't you have the money?
I'm in trouble.
Three tankers were mine.
I invested all I got.
I've got a cunning plan.
There's a different solution.
Yesterday I bought your father's factory
in the hospital.
The cement factory?
-I paid it.
You can always ask.
But it's not enough to cover your debt.
It's only two thirds.
I've got a better idea.
You have a marriageable son.
And I've got a marriageable sister.
We arrange a marriage
and forget your debt.
I'll give you anything you want, Dadi.
But that's impossible. -Why?
I'll bet the nail.
Name?
Don't lose your soul.
How can you propose something like that?
Your sister is 25, my son 17.
Younger men like ripe women.
And that's not all, Dadi.
What else?
-You know, you know.
She looks like a little Smurf.
Everyone calls her little Lady-bird.
So what? A diamond is small,
but valuable.
Wanna bet? Doesn't matter what.
Hands off.
Let's toast on the deal.
No. I've got it figured now.
I know who stole my train
and drugged me.
And who messed with my father
and stole my heritage.
Safet. Kazatchok.
I know who cheated my father.
Last chance.
The moment of truth.
Kiss my ass.
Attention.
One, two, three... freedom.
What are you doing?
Is this seat taken?
What do you want?
-Lemonade.
Hey you.
-Me?
Get an ice-cream.
I'm not an errand-boy.
You're always following me around,
might as well make yourself useful.
Don't you think so?
-Exactly.
Out of the way.
Strawberry or vanilla?
Strawberry and vanilla. Four servings.
Where are you going?
Are you in a hurry?
I've got to tell you something.
Where did you go to?
-Finish my lemonade.
Shame you're getting married.
I just thought: he's young, but handsome.
I'm falling in love.
And now you're getting married.
Married? Who's getting married?
I'm only thinking about you.
I'm always here for you.
It's over. Don't make a fuss.
That's a lie.
Someone's setting me up.
Don't lie to me. I'm too young,
I don't want to marry.
Prepare yourself to get engaged.
I overheard your father and Dadan
in my grandma's inn.
They agreed last night.
It's a shame. Here.
Dadan stole the factory.
That son of a bitch.
And now he wants me too.
You know how many people he cheated.
He got the train, the factory...
What else does he want?
What else?
His mother's pussy.
The Russians are here.
The water is nice.
He wants something else...
...that Dadan.
He wants to arrange a marriage
to pay of my debt.
A marriage? For whom?
For our child Zare and his sister.
The Lady-bird.
That bawler, the midget?
She's barely three feet tall.
Now I have to ask the help
of my friend Grga Pitic.
You're coming with me.
-It's too late.
Grga Pitic... is dead.
Dead?
God have mercy on his soul.
I haven't had a drink yet...
...but I'll have one now
for his salvation.
Grandfather.
There's my grandson.
Ain't he handsome?
I'll introduce you.
Hello, nurse.
Have you seen her?
-Who?
The girl.
No.
The nurse.
They call her Candy.
Those boobies, that body.
And that tiny butt. All so delicate.
I want love at first sight,
or nothing at all.
Love at first sight? Ridiculous.
The son of your deceased friend Zarija
dropped by.
He came for help.
All his money is being stolen.
I've got a score to settle with
those villains, with Little Grga.
We'll skin them like cats
and eat them alive.
I'm coming with you.
I want to see the grave of Zarija.
As you will, grandad.
It was only a proposition.
Nobody listens to me.
I'm talking to you.
I'm not getting married this way.
-Shame on you.
Miss, please.
You're my greatest enemy.
You're no brother to me.
You're a butcher.
Must our parents
curse me from their grave?
I don't want to marry.
I'm not getting married. Do you hear me?
If my true love appears,
I'll marry him.
Waist, 68.
-Who is it?
Tell me. Who is it?
I'll know when I see him.
I saw him a hundred times in my dreams.
I know what he looks like.
I know his eyes,
his face, his lips.
He's tall, very tall...
Which tall man would want you,
stupid goose?
You're barely over three feet.
One day he'll come.
Breast, 88.
-Silence. Leave me alone.
Safet.
Cool down.
When will you let me find peace
in my own home?
Let me go.
I'll marry the man I love.
Pull.
Little sister... what can I do?
Daddy's looking at you, little sister.
Are you convinced?
I'll turn you into a fountain.
Fuck you... Go on.
I'll marry the man I love.
What about your soul?
-Our parents are watching from above.
They can't see anything, it's clouded.
Hands up in the air.
Dadan. You're doing fine.
Move over, let the lady sit.
Congratulations.
Do you want something to drink?
-Coffee.
Only coffee?
-Only coffee.
Can I help you?
Ask Matko, that dumb ass.
Take care of the kitchen,
I fear the worst.
The one who looks like a vampire
and the fat one are married.
So only the little one is left.
They call her Little Lady-bird
or Smurf.
That midget?
Yes, in her bridal gown.
Good luck.
Never.
I'm here for business.
What business, Sujka?
You marry my Ida.
I see she pleases you.
My Ida.
You'll won't find a prettier girl
in the whole region.
I fed her from her birth.
We've been everywhere.
In spas
to make her beautiful.
To buy her Italian clothes...
...we went to Rome and Napels.
-Liar.
I showed her all countries.
In the end we went to Sweden.
I know. To beg.
At least we didn't scavenge the trash
like you did.
How much do you ask?
Give me 35.000 marks.
Grandma.
15.000 up front and 15.000 after.
For such a tip even I won't marry.
17.000 in three parts?
-At once.
And I don't want see you ever again.
Your Grandma's selling you like a cow.
Never.
Carry me.
Come on, carry me.
You're a weirdo.
And now...kiss me.
Damn tie.
Save me, grandpa. Don't let me be married.
I'll drink his blood.
Take it easy.
Give me that gun. Calm down.
The gun.
-I'll finish him.
You should be ashamed of yourself.
Give me that gun.
Relax. Keep cool.
I'll teach him.
I know what I have to do.
I don't want to.
-Listen.
I was nearly dead. Listen.
Her brother Dadan
is a war criminal.
He'll exterminate our family.
He'll drink our blood.
-But she's a midget.
O mirror, the dead with the dead...
....the living with the living,
the children with their father.
For two months.
Then you get a divorce.
...the dead with the dead...
I don't want to marry.
I won't.
I'll prevent the marriage in an
elegant manner.
Zare.
You'll get punished.
You'll fulfill your draft
in the zoo.
I'll fuck your ratface.
Where is he?
Who?
-Your grandson.
Go ahead, play. Great.
Where is he?
Should Dadan slaughter us all?
Where is my son?
-I don't know. Couldn't care less.
Where is he?
-I don't know.
Get out of there.
You shouldn't hide your shoe.
You should be ashamed of yourself.
It's a disgrace.
the dead with the dead,
the living with the living...
Granddad.
He doesn't breathe anymore.
Grandpa is dead.
Come.
He is dead.
Come, grandpa is dead.
His heart stopped beating.
Dead?
Do you die on the day your
grandson marries?
The day he marries...
Grandpa saved me. He saved me.
We'll flee together after the
period of mourning.
You'll need a costume, shoes,
a butterfly-tie...
Wreaths of flowers, candles...
Definitively dead.
Ah it's you, Matko, you womanizer.
You're early. Eight o'clock, you said.
Where's the son in law?
I've got something to tell you.
It's urgent.
I've got to talk to you in private.
Today I only want to hear good news.
I'm listening.
My father is dead.
Really?
-Yes.
My condolences.
-What can I do?
A marriage and a funeral don't
get along well.
He can die in three days.
But he died this morning.
Who says so? Who knows?
I know. Zare...
I told you straight away.
We'll have to mourn for forty days.
I'll mourn with you... in three days.
You're a wise man.
You didn't stop the preparations?
Sure I did.
Should my father turn in his grave?
Of course not.
Don't tell anyone about the old man.
It doesn't matter to him if he dies on
Wednesday or Friday.
Death's forever.
It doesn't matter when it begins.
You didn't hear anything.
-Nope.
We didn't hear anything.
-No.
Me neither.
Wait for the guests
and get the bride.
As you like, Dadi.
-Cheers.
He doesn't want to hear it.
-What?
Even if he kills us and places us dead at
the dinner table, the wedding will continue!
I don't want to.
Does he have to rip my head off?
Take this.
For your soul, daddy.
Take his legs. We are going to the attic.
Turn him aside.
Get ice downstairs.
Hurry up!
Quick!
Don't do this to me.
You don't need money anymore.
Put his legs on the chair.
Get the grandchildren of Grga Pitic here!
I left six messages.
They don't answer.
Who knows where they are?
Daddy, forgive me.
Hold it above the bride.
Hold it above her head.
-I don't want to.
Get away you.
Take the child, it will bring you luck.
This is the most beautiful day...
....of your whole life.
A unique day...
....to say so.
The day of your life.
Answer now in front of the witnesses...
....the following questions.
Be brief. And without hesitation.
Just yes or no.
Do you...
Zare Destanov do you...
....out of free will...
.... take Afrodita Karambolis to be your wife?
Karambolo.
Yes.
And you, Afrodita...
....lovely beauty and so sweet...
....do you take Zare Destanov to
be your husband out of free will?
She says she wants to.
Let her tell. Yes or no.
I want an answer.
-Yes.
So yes it is.
I don't see any legal objection.
I now declare you man and wife...
....in my presence...
....and in the presence of this crowd.
See if the food is ready.
I don't want to.
You know my hand can be very swift.
Thunder in one hand,
lightning in the other.
Please sign this.
I cannot serve on his wedding.
Why do you care about his wedding??
On behave of the people of Sarduk...
....I declare married:
Zare Destanov and Afrodita Karambolis.
Do you cry for him?
-Yes.
Then cry.
Cry, baby, cry.
I will buy you a convertible
and half the ocean!
and three houses
bigger than America
Little girl,
you have stolen my heart
and if you were mine,
you would live like a queen,
at daytime a queen
and at nighttime an empress.
Cheers, Dadi.
A real businessman and patriot.
Come and dance, little sister.
I can't.
Untie her.
Respect your brother in law, a sensible man.
Dance with your brother, it's tradition.
I don't want to.
Fine. It's your wedding.
Freedom.
Daddy, I hope you see this.
Let's see who has spent the most.
A portable record player...
....from Nada Adzovic.
Zudija Adzovic donates
a vacuum cleaner.
Spaho Ahmetovic, pots and pans.
It's ok, friend.
I am going to look how daddy is doing.
Stay here and please don't get us in trouble.
Nebojsa Palanovic
donates this ugly thing.
Don't show the people you are crying.
Don't get us in trouble.
I am a
pitbull-terrier.
I am going to give new ice to daddy.
You live poorly.
Repair your roof.
There is nothing wrong with the roof.
It's daddy who needs to be repaired.
Don't cry.
Do you want to marry someone you don't love?
No.
Neither do I.
Do you love her?
-Yes.
Help me run away.
What?
-Help me escape.
There is a big shutter near the table...
....two meter two the left.
It leads to the oil-barrels.
Can you be somewhere better?
For once be honest with me, daddy.
Where is your money from the factory sale?
Safet.
The grenades.
Grenades?
Where is the bride?
-Ask the businessman and patriot.
Everybody listen.
The bride has fled.
Chief, the bride has fled.
Chief, your sister is gone.
My sister.
Zare.
My sister...
Stop it.
Don't worry.
Your brother will not abandon you.
I will find the guilty one.
How could she remove her dress and escape?
You let your wife escape.
What have you done, stupid fool?
What have you done?
Has your sister escaped?
-No, yours.
Then why the fuck are crying? Get fucking lost.
Stupid junkies.
What are you doing here?
Searching for Smurfette.
How did you call her?
Smurfette.
Shame on you.
You don't call my sister Smurfette.
Eat shit.
Don't you know who I am?
Fuck you.
It's not her fault, she doesn't know anything.
She does know something.
Stop it. Everybody calls her
ladybird or Smurfette.
Grandfather.
Grandfather? You are unrealistic, boy.
Release him.
Don't bother your grandfather, he is dead.
Leave him, he doesn't know anything.
Where is she?
-My ear.
Let go of him, bastard.
Where is she? She hasn't vaporized.
Tell me , suckers. Or I will kill you.
Don't turn around. Look at me.
Shall I shoot?
-Later.
Dadi.
What are you doing here?
-Dadi, I am stuck.
I have important news.
My balls are stuck.
Shame on you. Repair that roof.
Forget that. I have seen the bride.
Where?
-She is going to the wood.
Safet.
Not there, friend. Further away.
The bride went that way.
I love her.
I am going to marry her.
Granddad, do you hear me?
Yes, what's the matter?
We can still turn back.
I will arrange it with Little Grga.
Visit his grave another time.
No, now.
Who knows how long I will stay alive.
Yes, but it's 39°c in the shadow.
It will last.
Zarija deserves to see me.
Ok then.
I said it for your own good.
Afrodita.
Sister.
I will not harm you.
There she is.
My sister.
All ends well.
She is not here.
Maybe she is in the woods.
What a shame the bride runs
away from her own wedding.
Everybody will talk about it for years.
Nonsense.
I will find her. The wedding will continue.
Chief, it's a shoe.
Sister.
I will kill you.
Wake up, we are free.
Wake up. An earthquake.
Little Grga, if I listen to you
I will get lost.
That map is a hundred years old.
Little Grga, do you hear me?
Where did you find that atlas?
Are you asleep?
I am in trouble.
That's destiny.
Why destiny?
All this. I will still marry you.
Yes.
Who could have thought Ladybird
would be so brave?
Nobody ever revolted against Dadan...
...except her.
I am afraid.
Why? We will manage fine.
Congratulations, son. brilliant idea.
I thought it was my imagination.
But it's destiny.
And my other shoe?
We will find it.
But this is one hundred percent destiny!
Exactly.
I was looking for my other half.
Me too.
I looked and looked, and will find
her when I least expect it.
Me too.
Let's introduce ourselves. I am Grga.
Me too. I mean, I am
Afrodita Karambolo. Ladybird.
We must celebrate,
if you agree.
My sister...
-Quiet.
It's a misunderstanding.
Why do you shoot like that?
And you, girl, you are in trouble.
You will pay.
If the girl has any debts
I will pay them.
What are you looking at? Do something.
Grga.
Give me back my sister.
Stop or I will shoot you.
Fuck off. Come here, sis.
What's wrong with you, idiot?
And your grandfather? And your brother?
You were losing us.
Look what I have got.
Don't come any closer
or I will pump you full of lead!
I swear to God. This is serious.
Sister in law...
Who are they?
-Put your guns down.
Stop.
She is my sister. Understand?
I don't know you.
But I do know her.
-And I know him.
Continue your path.
My path leads to her
If you are really her brother,
we can come to an agreement.
I want to marry her immediately.
She just ran away from her wedding.
You can run away from a fake marriage,
but you can't hide from destiny.
What a sniper.
Where did that asshole come from?
Put down your guns.
You call this driving, idiot?
You took the wrong road.
Ok, but look what I found.
Very good.
Take it easy.
This isn't necessary.
How's it going, Consignor Grga?
Is it you, worthless piece of shit?
What are you doing here?
We were just talking.
Talking about what?
Are you here to pay off your debt?
Do you know each other?
My last resort in Italy, in 1982.
He was a student in my brigade.
The worst kind.
Because of him I lost ground.
I live nearby.
Don't you want to marry her?
-No.
I want her.
We shall see.
Now.
-Be silent when you are speaking to me.
And you, do you want my grandson?
Yes.
And you do not object to your
sister marrying my grandson?
Of course not, if they love each other.
Why do you look so sad?
What's wrong?
Ah yes, he needs to go to the factory...
...and pay back the three
tankers of gasoline.
Do you know how much that is?
He will pay at once.
-Of course.
And the wedding must
start immediately.
The wedding can begin.
Music. It's my treat.
What counts, is that love conquers all.
Cheers.
Has he drank yet?
-Not yet.
My beautiful sisters.
-I hope there won't be any complications.
You will swim in your own shit.
Do you need anything, uncle Grga?
Have fun, I am going visit
the grave of my friend.
The grave?
Where is it? Tell me.
-Uncle Grga...
Don't you want to drink something first?
A refreshment. Eat something as well.
At this hour there are
vampires in the graveyard.
Once we are there,
it's already day again.
Whatever.
My servants will bring
you to the graveyard.
But to which graveyard?
Give me the money.
Traitor.
It was only ethical.
You must have fun. Eat and drink.
Your sister is happy, so is my son.
Like our benefactor, uncle...
Dammit.
What's the matter?
-Look.
What's the matter with him?
He is dead.
Really dead.
No. He will die the day after tomorrow,
like your father.
The wedding must continue. I can't
start over a hundred times.
Am I right?
-Completely.
Shall we put him in the attic?
We told his grandchildren,
we brought him to the graveyard.
What about the official?
-Which official?
He must cancel the first wedding
and perform the second wedding.
Don'worry,
I will get him.
Ok. We are doing well
Goddammit...
-Eat your shit.
Two sixes.
There you go.
How sweet.
The more natural , the sweeter.
Fifty marks.
Look, Dadan...
500 horns at 5 marks is 2500 marks.
In Düsseldorf it's wanted.
Are you crazy?
Do you want to stuff those horns?
Wait, Dadan.
Be a gentleman.
My stake is the factory.
You have lost that one already.
Look, you have signed this.
Ok, I still have a house.
You have lost that one too, idiot.
But you do have...
...a nice golden tooth.
That will be the stake. 500 marks, ok?
What's with the ice?
Get lost.
-What's the matter?
Damned black cat.
I am soaked. She has pissed on me.
Brother.
Where are we? Aren't we dead?
-We are.
I know I am not dead.
-They told me you were dead.
It's not true.
They have lied to you.
I am alive.
Daddy. I am glad you are alive.
Goddammit.
The cow is dead, the milk is finished.
Granddad.
Your father is alive.
I will notify you
of the agreements...
...of holy matrimony...
...and the responsibility of marriage.
I wish you a happy life.
May it last a life long...
...and enjoy each others company.
You should consider...
... fulfilling one of the most important
and beautiful tasks in life.
Be jealous, not with each other,
but on your marriage.
Honor it and protect it
against all evil.
Consider it...
When you died,
I decided to leave.
What has fallen?
Very wise. There is no sun here.
Forget your glasses. Hurry up.
Agreed?
I am having a difficult time.
I have been drinking
on the funeral, just now.
Don't forget the accordion.
In it you will find enough,
to become happy
Oh no. The death certificate
instead of the wedding certificate.
Are you crazy? Junkie.
My reputation...
Shall I call the police?
Here.
Everything is all right.
The signatures.
First the ladies, then the men.
The ladies don't marry each
other, stupid fool.
Don't make a fuss.
It must happen according to the law.
Do you, Afrodita Karambolo...
....take to be your husband...
....Grga Pitic junior?
Yes.
Do you, Grga Pitic junior...
....take to be your wife
Afrodita Karambolo?
Yes.
Sign the register.
According to the law you
are now husband and wife.
Wait, it's not finished yet.
Get me out of this mess. Come back.
I can't work in that manner.
There it is.
It's amazing.
Quickly!
We are not married yet.
-We will do it on the way.
Mr. Dadan, you're in trouble.
You always spoil everything.
We must continue the ceremony.
What a mess.
I can't work like that.
-Yes you can.
It must be according to the rules.
Don't shoot.
-Shut up.
We are missing the boat.
The boy has guts.
-He is right.
Zare, my grandson.
You are young, you don't understand.
What do you want from me?
-I want you to marry us.
Don't forget the accordion.
Finish the ceremony.
Sit down.
You don't have any witnesses.
-Yes we do.
Who?
-The cats.
You dirty pig.
You smell, boss.
-Fuck you.
Yes.
Do you, Zare Destanov, take her
to be your wife...
Of course.
Children...
Have a good journey.
Shall we drink to it
like it is tradition?
Grandmother.
You have fooled me, daddy.
You stupid asshole.
It's disgusting.
Nice stuff.
Thanks, daddy,
for everything you have done for me.
My soul is on fire.
Ah, children...
Dadan, brother.
"Louis, I think this is the beginning
of a beautiful friendship."