Has it come on?
No.
Now?
Turn the damn thing properly!
Welcome to the wrestling area
at the Seoul Olympics.
Looking forward to
an exciting match today.
It's come on.
Shall I come down?
No.
Stand there holding it.
The final match this Olympics...
in the 72-kilo category,
between wrestlers from
Russia and America.
It's really sad that,
despite wrestling being
such a popular sport in India
Indian wrestlers have
disappointed in the Olympics.
Even our boys
can bring home medals.
But where is the support?
Neither money,
nor facilities.
How will our boys win a medal?
If a medal could be won with words,
you would have won
it a long time ago.
Are you new here?
That's what I thought.
Try stepping into a
wrestling arena someday,
you'll run for your life
before the match begins.
Looks like you have
done it many times.
Run for your life.
If this were an arena,
then we'd see who would run.
Why do we need an arena?
Now, the moment
we were all waiting for.
The stage is all set for a big fight.
There's palpable excitement in the air.
Both the wrestlers are walking,
for the fight.
You are absolutely right, Tom.
Looks like it's going
to be an interesting bout.
The crowd seems excited.
The wrestlers come face to face.
Let's see how it plays out.
The customary handshake.
The referee's whistle...
and the match begins!
He's down!
An early thrashing
for the Russian wrestler.
Overconfidence can often
prove fatal.
Bro, you want to try once more?
Now, the wrestlers are gearing up
for the next round.
Yes, Tom, this match doesn't look
as easy as it had seemed.
Let's see what happens now.
Both wrestlers testing each other.
A great attack!
An equally superb defense.
And that was a magnificent move!
What an amazing move!
He didn't know what hit him.
Here's an attack.
And that's a counter-attack!
And it's over!
It's all over.
David has become Goliath,
and Goliath has become David here.
Well said, Tom.
No one expected such a quick defeat
for the Russian wrestler.
What a match!
This is top class wrestling.
You are good.
You've just defeated
a state level champion.
Don't be disheartened buddy,
you've just lost to
a national level champion.
Meet my uncle.
Mahavir Singh Phogat.
He quit wrestling many years ago,
but wrestling hasn't
quit on him.
# I'm here to stay. #
# Beat the best. #
# From the mother's womb to the
cemetery, your life is a wrestling bout. #
# So, wrestle, O Wrestler! #
# Wrestle, O Wrestler! #
# Your glory may rise and fall, #
# cause up in the sky
your stars are wrestling, too. #
# So, wrestle, O Wrestler! #
# Wrestle, O Wrestler! #
# When your heart
thumps with fear, #
# pat your back, #
# bring back courage, #
# and you'll be fine. #
# Every challenge is
like a crazed elephant, #
# standing in front of you, #
# staring fierce, #
# threatening you. #
# So, take it head on, #
# that's what you are born for! #
# So, wrestle, O Wrestler! #
# Wrestle, O Wrestler! #
# Your glory may rise and fall, #
# cause up in the sky
your stars are wrestling, too. #
# So, wrestle, O Wrestler! #
# Wrestle, O Wrestler! #
The smaller kid will win.
There you go!
Merely building a good body
does not make a wrestler.
Come here, kid.
Wrestling runs in the blood,
you have to be born with it.
Here. Buy yourself some milk.
Bless you.
When there's no food on your plate
what will you eat? Medals?
No one gives a damn
about wrestling.
Just take up the job
you are being offered.
Why did you quit wrestling?
I had no choice.
Wrestling gave me respect, fame,
but it couldn't give me money.
So, I took up this job.
Every wrestler dreams,
of bringing honor and
glory to the country.
But if the country offers no support,
how far can a wrestler go?
It's not your fault that you
couldn't win a medal for your country.
How long will you let these
memories depress you?
What I couldn't do,
our son will.
He will win gold
for our country.
Our flag will fly the highest.
Mark my words.
That day uncle was
as anxious as a student,
whose high school results
were due.
Don't worry, brother.
It's going to be alright.
It's a girl.
Uncle was hoping for a boy.
But a girl was born.
It's okay.
You have a sister now, Omkar.
I was genuinely happy.
But uncle was faking it.
And then it all started.
Suddenly everyone in the village
was an expert,
in the art of conceiving a boy.
Feed a black cow sweets made
with white sesame seeds,
wrapped in maize flatbreads,
with your left hand, before sunrise.
A son, for sure!
Mahavir, here's a special prayer...
for a son.
Recite it daily.
Here... eat this.
Eat this!
Stop, will you.
Mahavir,
make sure you try only on a Sunday.
On all other days,
reign in your urges.
Got it?
Neither did people stop
giving their advice,
Here you go, son.
nor did uncle and aunt
stop acting on them.
The day of the delivery arrived
and so did half the village.
To take credit for a son.
Geeta, you are going to
have a brother.
You can play with him.
It's a girl.
But neither did uncle get a son,
nor the villagers, credit.
But, in all these
"unfailing techniques",
where did the fault lie?
She must have fed a black buffalo
instead of a black cow.
Else, look at my cousin
from Rohtak.
She had three healthy boys
in three years.
If you say the prayer in reverse,
the results will also be reversed.
Self control is a virtue.
I told him to try only on Sundays.
He must have let
the reins free every day.
I couldn't give you a son...
It's not your fault.
And don't get me wrong.
Both, Geeta and Babita
are very dear to me.
But only a boy
can fulfil my dream.
Years went by.
Uncle remained adamant,
he wanted a boy.
But maybe God was adamant too.
The third child was a girl,
and so was the fourth.
This time I too was dejected.
Food is ready, papa.
Turn it over or it'll burn.
After that uncle gave up on his
desire for a son, and on his dream too.
Hey, Mahavir Singh-ji!
What's wrong with him?
Are you coming to watch
the wrestling match this evening?
No. You carry on.
Hey, Mahavir!
I've been blessed with a boy.
Here... have some sweets.
What happened?
Look how badly
they've been thrashed.
Say something!
Yes, look how badly
they've been thrashed.
They're all swollen and bruised.
Yes, they're all swollen and bruised.
Why did you beat them?
I didn't, uncle.
Geeta and Babita beat them up.
They started it.
He called me a loser
and Babita a witch.
So, we gave it to them.
They beat them so badly?
For such a trivial reason?
Yes, shouldn't have
beaten them so badly.
Please forgive them...
they're kids.
We are letting go because
they are your girls.
Move!
Got thrashed by girls!
Come here.
Come here!
We won't fight again, papa.
First tell me, how did you
manage to do it?
First, he called me a loser
but I remained quiet.
But then he called Babita a witch.
That was it.
I grabbed him and
punched him like this.
Then the other guy attacked.
I caught his hair
and shoved him down,
and dug my elbow in his back.
They say that a twig is enough
to give hope to a drowning man.
Here, uncle had found
not one, but two lifeguards!
All along, I was desperate for a son,
so he could win a gold
for the country.
But what didn't occur to me
is that gold is gold.
Whether a boy wins it, or a girl.
From now on, Geeta and Babita
will do no household chores.
Wrestling is in their blood.
From now on they will only wrestle.
Wrestling is for boys.
You think our girls are
any lesser than boys?
I've never ever seen girls wrestle.
What will the villagers say?
For how long will they talk?
What if the girls break
their hands and legs?
We'll fix them.
Where will the money come from?
I don't know.
Don't ruin the girls' lives
for your passion.
Let me try for a year.
For this one year,
you bury your feelings.
If I'm proven wrong,
I'll bury my dream forever.
Be ready at 5am tomorrow.
Why, papa?
I want to feed you
your favourite snack, 'gol gappas'.
5am. Okay?
What did you do now?
I thought you did something.
Eat.
How is it?
It's a little less spicy, papa.
Alright, make it spicier.
Eat as much as you want right now.
Because from today, you will both
lead the life of a wrestler.
And wrestlers are not allowed,
pickled, oily and spicy food,
in fact,
all the food that you most love.
Consider this your last treat.
# A messiah for the rest, #
# a terror for your own. #
Come on, faster Babita!
# O Papa, don't put us
through this torture! #
# A messiah for the rest,
a terror for your own. #
Papa, it's difficult to run
in these clothes.
# O Papa, don't put us
through this torture! #
# Don't torture us! #
# O Papa! #
Don't you dare stop!
# O Papa, you are
injurious to our health. #
# Have mercy on us, #
# we are little children. #
# So much discipline... #
# So much discipline
makes us want to die. #
# O Papa, you are
injurious to our health. #
# Have mercy on us, #
# we are little children. #
# So much discipline... #
# So much discipline
makes us want to die. #
# O Papa, you are
injurious to our health. #
Nobody would've ever been
punished so severely,
for beating up a couple of boys.
He abused me.
Why did you have to beat him?
Now you tell me!
# You stopped our
picnics and outings. #
# This is torture, #
# grave torture! #
# To tell children, not to
enjoy their childhood. #
# This is torture, #
# grave torture! #
# Toffees, games and toys, #
# scrumptious foods, #
# have bid us adieu, #
# since your scolding. #
# This is our time
for fun and games, #
# why is it being measured
by a stopwatch? #
# Our luck is like
a broken down car. #
# And our papa... #
# And our papa is the
driver of that car. #
# O Papa, you are
injurious to our health. #
# You have forbidden us
tasty and spicy food. #
# This is torture, #
# grave torture! #
# You ask delicate dolls
to toughen up. #
# This is torture, #
# grave torture! #
We'll obey your
every command, mummy.
Just save us
from this wrestling.
For one year forget
that you have a mother.
Hey! Forgot so quickly?
How utterly absurd, Mahavir!
Girls in the wrestling arena?
Will you have me sin at this age?
# Our childhood has been
thrown away, #
# the garden has lost its blossoms, #
# wonder what kind of
war we prepare for? #
# Day and night, we cry
cascades of tears, #
# you are still not happy, O dictator,
we are your sacrifice. #
# Do you think we are so hopeless? #
# Better than you, are... #
# Better than you,
are Bollywood movie villains. #
# O Papa, you are
injurious to our health. #
Babita...
Will you press my legs please?
I was going to ask you
the same thing.
Always respect Mother Earth.
The more you respect it,
the more respect
you will get in return.
Uncle had managed to bring
Geeta and Babita to the wrestling pit,
but there was something missing.
In order for Geeta and
Babita to train well,
they needed to practice
with good wrestlers.
Omkar?
Him?
Y es.
Isn't that too much, brother?
It was bad enough that
you were making the girls wrestle.
Now you want
them to fight boys?
Yes or no?
I don't have the heart to say yes.
And, I don't have the courage
to say no.
Okay, then send him over.
Because of you both
I'm caught in the crossfire.
Stop complaining!
You are just caught
in the crossfire.
We've been pushed into war.
Keep running!
Why has papa got him
to train with us?
This pint-sized boy is no challenge.
He looks like a 'TTSS' to me.
What does that mean?
Tall on Talk, Short on Strength.
'TTSS'... is it?
Go easy, I'm your little sister.
Yes... yes!
Don't mind me saying,
but your girls are a little weak.
Want to fight me?
I'll be right back.
I don't understand your ways.
At one time, I can either be
their coach or their father.
When the coach is at work,
the father has to take a backseat.
Sorry for calling you 'TTSS'.
Sorry, my foot!
You think this is a joke?
He is throwing you down
and you are letting him?
When he attacks from the left,
why don't you stabilize yourself
on the left and defend?
Sorry, papa.
Child, this is wrestling,
three sorrys and the game is over.
Come on.
Try again.
Where's the strength in you?
You are training the girls to wrestle,
I didn't say anything.
But I will not allow you to cook
chicken in my kitchen!
Try and understand.
Wrestlers require protein.
I don't care!
If meat is cooked in my kitchen,
I will stop eating.
You want your girls
to be weak wrestlers?
I don't know anything.
There's no way chicken will be
cooked in my kitchen!
Omkar!
- Yes.
Do you know how to cook?
No, uncle.
Then learn.
We don't have enough money
for their current diet.
How can we afford
chicken now?
What? Sell you chicken
worth 1 00 rupees for 20?
And I will benefit from this deal?
Why don't you explain the math?
Look, Geeta and Babita will eventually
become famous wrestlers.
And when people will find out that
they eat chicken from your shop,
where do you think
they'll buy chicken from?
That makes sense.
But just 20 rupees?
There are other shops too.
Wait... Iisten.
Let's make it 40.
I won't give a dime
more than 25.
I have browned the onions,
and now this pot
will not go back in my kitchen.
Now, put the chicken in the pot.
And let it cook on a slow flame.
It's to be eaten with rice.
But... it can also be
eaten with bread.
Uncle was fulfilling his duty,
and the villagers, theirs.
Girls are best suited
for the kitchen,
not for wrestling.
Mahavir Singh has gone mad.
Not mad,
he's become shameless.
He's getting the girls to
wear shorts and fight boys.
Since you all started wrestling,
your walk has become very manly.
Wonder what else will happen?
Next, it'll be my fist
and your face.
If only you had
given birth to a boy!
Their mother doesn't protest either.
The entire village is laughing at us.
Who will marry our girls?
I will make our girls so capable,
that boys will not choose them,
they will choose boys!
I'm going to tell papa today,
this wrestling isn't working out.
Me, too.
B-O-Y... boy.
C-A-T... cat.
Papa, this wrestling
isn't working out...
for Babita.
Yes, papa... and,
Geeta gets so tired
that she falls asleep in class.
She can't concentrate
on her studies at all.
Babita's body aches terribly.
She keeps tossing
and turning all night.
In school, girls tease
Geeta by calling her a man.
Sad, isn't it?
None of these
seem like a problem.
Tell me if there is
a real problem.
Read.
E-L-E-P-H-A-N-T
Papa, our hair is getting ruined
because of wrestling in the mud.
She even has lice.
I killed eight this evening.
Now, that's a real problem.
Okay, be ready tomorrow at 5am.
Papa, please.
We don't have any problem.
In fact, we are enjoying it.
Please don't cut our hair.
We will do as you say.
Ma, say something.
Look what papa is doing.
Please don't cut our hair, papa.
We'll do whatever you say.
We'll wake up in the morning!
Do everything...
won't ever complain.
Just don't cut our hair, please.
Please, papa.
Cut it.
Cut it?
Can you grow it?
Then cut it.
Getting them to wrestle
was still okay,
but it's cruel to chop their hair off!
They are girls, after all.
Whatever I'm doing
is for their best.
Anything that distracts them
from wrestling,
I will get rid of!
"ls that the full moon or the sun!"
I'm confused... today both
seem to have risen together.
Let it go, Babita.
Our stars are to blame.
Enough of wrestling,
now, it's time for a street-fight!
And then, in a small village
of Haryana called Balali,
a grand rebellion began.
Revolutionaries Geeta and Babita
versus dictator Mahavir Singh.
All of uncle's arsenal
were neutralized one by one.
The alarm clock was
cleverly misguided.
What happened, papa?
You are late today.
Age is catching up.
No problem.
We've finished today's training.
Come, Babita.
Countless light-bulbs were martyred.
How come the bulb fuses everyday?
Quality... papa,
quality!
Injury was made an ally.
In the battlefield, surrender
was given without a fight.
Should I give it to you?
And uncle, despite having both hands,
felt helpless like the armless character
from the film 'Sholay'.
Get out of here!
I couldn't understand how
I had suddenly become so strong.
But uncle understood very well
why Geeta and Babita,
had suddenly become so weak.
Geeta and Babita thought
that they had won the war.
Hey!
Are you going to Sunita's wedding?
M... mummy.
Are you trying to embarrass me?
Choose one.
This one.
Let me see.
Finally,
my girls are looking like girls.
Don't tell papa.
Come home before 8pm.
# I arrive, the blushing bride. #
# Shy... nervous. #
# I've seen many weird things
in my life, #
# but my groom is
the weirdest of the lot. #
# I've seen many weird things
in my life, #
# but my groom is
the weirdest of the lot. #
# Marrying me to him is like
casting pearls before swine. #
# My groom is such a loser. #
# My groom is a loser. #
# I told my groom,
help me freshen up, #
# get me a toothbrush
from the store. #
# But instead of a toothbrush, #
# he got me sugarcane
from the fields. #
# What a loser! #
# Such a loser! #
# My groom is such a loser. #
# My groom is a loser. #
- Let it go, brother.
- He is crazy.
We missed training
just for a day.
What was the need to create
such a big scene?
What kind of father forces
his daughters to become wrestlers?
Makes them wake up at 5am to run.
Works them like slaves.
Makes them fight boys.
And if they protest,
he cuts their hair.
May God never give
anyone such a father.
I wish God had given me
such a father.
At least your father
thinks about you.
Otherwise, our reality is,
the moment a girl is born,
teach her to cook and clean,
make her do
all the household chores.
And, once she turns 14,
marry her off.
Get rid of the "burden"!
And hand her over to a man,
whom she has never seen before.
Make her bear children
and raise them.
That's all she's good for.
At least your father
considers you his child.
He is fighting against
the whole world.
He is silently tolerating
their taunts.
Why?
So that the two of you
can have a future... a life.
What is he doing wrong?
# I'm here to stay. #
# Beat the best. #
# When fortune gives you
a chance to prove yourself, #
# You have barely
a handful of days to prepare. #
# It asks in exchange
every drop of your sweat. #
# Know for sure
you gain so much more. #
# Fortune bows before
your intense effort. #
# So, wrestle, O Wrestler! #
# Wrestle, O Wrestler! #
That day, one fact
became clear to me.
Don't know about Geeta and Babita,
but I sure didn't have
wrestling in my blood.
Look at him sulk.
Give him some butter, ma.
He's become so weak.
I lost intentionally to
make you happy.
Get lost... 'TTSS'!
"Lost intentionally..."
Don't worry.
It'll remain between us.
After all, you are family.
Your reputation is ours, too.
Don't get so cocky.
Watch me tomorrow.
You won't be able to tomorrow.
No, uncle. Tomorrow, I will
definitely put up a tough fight.
We are going
to Rohtak tomorrow.
For a wrestling competition.
But, I am not ready for
a wrestling competition yet.
Who is talking about you?
She will fight boys?
She won't last
two minutes, uncle.
Why?
Aren't you a boy?
She thrashed you.
I had seen a lot of wrestling
competitions in my life.
But today I was going to
witness a bout,
the likes of which, had never
been seen before in Haryana.
A riot was inevitable.
M r. Mahavir Singh Phogat...
welcome!
It's an honor that you have come
to watch the competition.
I've got a wrestler with me too.
Name, please.
Geeta Kumari Phogat.
What?
You'll make a girl wrestle?
Yes. So?
Write.
Sir, the day I organize
a cooking competition,
that day get Ms. Geeta along.
This is a wrestling competition!
We have come from very far.
We won't return without a fight.
Either Geeta will fight,
or you and l.
First, you utter nonsense,
and then you are being stubborn too!
What do you mean?
You want a girl
to wrestle with boys?
You may not be bothered
about your honor, but we are.
I will have your honor
laid out now!
Please... sir.
Please... we really respect you, sir.
But what you ask for,
can't happen.
We can't do this, brother.
Let's go.
How dare he...
You are getting a chance to
play the game,
and you are giving a walkover?
Meaning?
How many years have we been
holding wrestling competitions?
Five.
How many people come to see?
Just a handful.
So?
Dimwit, think about it.
In a town that has never
seen a girl wrestle,
when a girl wrestles a boy,
how many people
will come to watch?
Our competition will go
through the roof!
But what if the girl
breaks her arms or legs?
Let them break.
You bandage
your broken competition.
Even if you charge
two rupees per ticket,
your wrestlers will eat
for months.
Mahavir-ji!
Ladies and gentlemen,
boys and girls!
You must have seen a girl
walk on fire, eat a snake.
But today, for the first time
in the history of Rohtak,
see a girl wrestling a boy
in a competition,
in half-an-hour, at Lal Chowk.
Tickets - two rupees.
A wrestling girl for two rupees!
You have to win!
Even if you were to pit
your boys against a lion,
there still wouldn't have been
such a crowd.
What do you think?
How many seconds
will she last?
S... s... s...
Mate, by the time you finish
she'll be done and dusted.
Will she fight in trunks like these?
Get lost!
I was just hoping.
Where is she?
She looks hot.
Hope her t-shirt doesn't tear.
I hope it does!
Go, Geeta!
- Her father has lost it!
Do you know
the rules of mud-wrestling?
Then choose who you
want to lose to.
Who do you think she'll pick?
Our Scrawny Spider.
He will win for the first time.
Gosh, Jassi will beat her to pulp!
Three of you, out of here.
Your girl has lost it.
There is still time, stop her.
Or she'll go back on a stretcher.
Before you fight a bout
you have to fight fear.
At least, my girl has conquered fear.
Go easy, she's a girl.
Don't make that mistake.
Will you embarrass us?
Geeta, great going!
W... wow!
She's gone.
Wh... wh... what a save!
You fought well.
Excellent!
The committee awards
the winning wrestler, Jassi,
with a cash prize of 20 rupees.
And from our patron, Kartar Singh,
a special prize for
Geeta Kumari of 50 rupees!
Sorry, papa.
It's okay.
Come on.
You got lucky, or you'd have
gone home on a stretcher.
Papa,
when is the next fight?
# Dressed in shorts and a T-shirt
arrives a cyclone. #
# Make the calls, tell everyone, #
# watch out for the wild cat. #
# Whether you are from
Chandigarh or Delhi, #
# she will flatten you out. #
# She will relocate your limbs. #
# Your attack will be met
with a counter-attack. #
# She will flatten you,
flatten you out. #
# She's a force to reckon with. #
# A force! #
From tomorrow you'll have to
bless her as well.
# What a girl! #
# Hark, O Wrestler!
Your ego will go up in flames, #
# her grip has such fire. #
# She will measure your self-worth, #
# in tiny millimeters. #
# Your breath will run out, #
# she will slam you so hard. #
# She will flatten you out. #
# She will relocate your limbs. #
# Your attack will be met
with a counter-attack. #
# She will flatten you,
flatten you out. #
# She's a force to reckon with. #
# A force! #
Once again people had started
talking about Geeta and Babita.
These two girls come from Balali
and thrash boys.
This fellow lost to a girl.
Why don't you fight her?
But this time the heckles were
replaced with applause!
Some did not want to
wrestle with the girls.
And some didn't allow
them to wrestle.
Please leave!
Geeta and Babita were winning
not just wrestling competitions,
but hearts, too.
1 4, 900... 1 5, 000... 1 5, 1 50.
You've become a senior wrestler!
By getting selected to the
Haryana state team,
Geeta Kumari has brought fame
not only to our school,
but to the entire district of Bhiwani.
And we are sure that,
she will make our town proud
in the National Sub-Juniors, too.
Leave? For two months?
Is your daughter getting married?
I have to prepare
Geeta for the Nationals, sir.
Forget about it.
If she was getting married,
I might have considered.
I don't understand your decisions.
I didn't have a choice.
I couldn't let go of my dream,
so, I let go of the job.
What will you do now?
I'll start farming
on our own plot of land.
It's hard work,
but at least I will be able
to give the girls time.
Titu... put this in the car.
Wait... go...
Yes, Mahavir Singh-ji,
what were you saying?
If I could get some funds,
it would help a lot.
My girl has now reached
the state level.
So...
What is the big deal
in reaching state level?
That too in ladies wrestling?
Your daughter ran alone,
and came first.
What do you need the funds for?
Sir, I want to buy a mat
for her to train on.
She's playing well.
If you support her today,
then one day, she will
make the nation proud.
Look, Mahavir Singh-ji,
we get this much
funding for sports.
Wrestling gets this much.
Keep aside gents wrestling,
then remove coaching, dieting,
traveling, equipment, etc.
All that remains for ladies wrestling
is this much.
And for this much,
you bought me a box of sweets.
But you have our
complete support.
The reason lndia
doesn't win medals,
is because officers like you
are warming these seats.
Alright. I'll get up.
Titu, serve me lunch.
Mahavir Singh-ji,
care to join me for lunch?
The Federation is a breeding ground
for such termites.
They have ruined sports.
There is no support
for sports persons,
only abuses when you don't win.
Medalists don't grow on trees.
You have to nurture them.
With love, with hard work,
with passion.
And here, the scoundrels don't
give money for even a mat.
What is a mat, brother?
Synthetic mattresses
on which wrestlers fight.
A mattress is a mattress!
No?
Did I say something wrong?
Uncle had already ruined
our sleep, figuratively speaking.
Now he was hell bent
on doing it literally, too.
Wrestling on a mat is different
from mud-wrestling.
Now we have to wrestle
on the mat.
And in mat-wrestling
you have to score points.
You can score one, two,
three or five points.
Omkar...
If you hold the opponent
by the waist,
and drop him to his knees,
then you score one point.
And from the ground position
if you roll him on to his back,
then you score two points.
There are different ways
to do this.
Uncle!
Like this.
Or from the ground position,
like this!
If you flip your opponent on his back
from a standing position,
then you will score three points.
Please, uncle!
Like this... three points.
Like this... from standing position...
on to his back.
To score five points is difficult,
but it can be done.
If you flip your opponent
from a standing position,
above your head
in a rainbow-like arc,
and have him fall on his back,
then you score five points!
Watch.
No... no, please, uncle!
Come here.
- No, please.
A real wrestling mat is not like this.
It's like this.
We have to fight
in the yellow area.
The red zone is a danger area.
If you step out of it,
you lose a point.
There are three rounds
of two minutes each.
Three rounds
Whoever wins two out of
three rounds, wins the match.
Sir, your daughter is underweight.
So?
Take my advice.
Go back.
Feed her,
fatten her and
come back next year.
If she fights like this,
she will break her bones.
You just tell me whether
she is allowed to wrestle or not.
Yes... she is.
Sign up.
"Sub-Junior Nationals"
Good move!
Geeta had defeated beefy boys,
how long could these girls survive?
Is that a girl or a storm?
"Sub-Junior National Champion"
"Junior Nationals"
Is she underweight?
Yes... but how does it matter?
"Junior National Champion"
Time flew by.
Geeta went from junior to senior.
And uncle,
from senior to senior-citizen.
Go... Geeta!
Babita and I, went from
shorts to full length pants!
Push... push her down!
Side throw!
Victory to Haryana!
"National Champion"
Finally uncle's dream
has been achieved.
Now we can all relax.
No.
My dream remains to be fulfilled.
Every year sees
a National champion.
My dream will be fulfilled,
when you win gold,
not for yourself,
but for your country.
You can celebrate today.
From tomorrow we start
preparing further.
Papa...
Need to speak to you.
Tell me.
Papa,
now that I am a
National champion, so...
So?
No, I mean,
all National champions
need to go to Patiala,
for further training.
To the National Sports Academy.
What are you getting at?
Tell me clearly.
I will have to go too, papa.
From now, I'll have to train there,
under the national coach.
Geeta Kumari Phogat.
Wrestling.
The place looks good.
Let's hope the coach is good too.
Girls, come on.
You all must be rejoicing,
at the thought of
advanced training.
Well, forget about learning,
first you have to learn to forget!
Forget the wrong training
you've received.
Wrong diet, wrong exercise,
wrong technique.
And after forgetting all that,
your real training will begin,
with National Coach,
Pramod Kadam.
And you will only learn
what I teach you.
Is that clear?
- Yes, sir!
Good.
Warm up.
Get me tea!
Come on, girls.
Energy... more energy!
Yes, that's the way.
Keep it up!
Good.
Namaste, sir.
Sir, I'm Mahavir Singh Phogat.
Geeta's father.
Okay.
I'm the one who has trained her.
Yes... good.
She's good.
Very strong, with a lot of stamina.
Where's my tea?
Come on... move it!
Sir... one request.
If Geeta gets the right coaching,
she will definitely win
an international medal.
Geeta!
There should be a 90 degree
angle between your calf and thigh.
Who has taught you?
Is this how you will win
an international medal?
You came to drop her, right?
You've done that.
Now leave the rest to me.
Don't waste my time!
Is Geeta happy?
The institute must be
very big, isn't it?
Everyone there must be
a champion, isn't it?
And the facilities there
must be amazing, right?
Have you trained today?
Yes. And the coach
must be top notch?
You seem very eager
to go there.
Remember, I'm still your coach.
Your first time
away from home?
Just you wait...
we'll have a blast.
Girls, 'DDLJ' is showing on TV.
Wow!
Let's watch.
I'm going to sleep.
You can't say no
to Shah Rukh Khan.
It's a sin.
Come.
"Raj, if this girl loves you,
she will turn to look at you."
Please turn.
"Turn."
Turn.
She turned!
Just grow your hair.
You will kill it.
A rhino uses strength,
but the tiger uses both
strength and technique.
Be a tiger, not a rhino.
Clear?
# These new colours,
these sweet sounds, #
# why do my days
suddenly seem different? #
# I know not. #
# Why is my heart leaping, #
# like a squirrel? #
# I know not. #
# These new colours,
these sweet sounds, #
# why do my days
suddenly seem different? #
# I know not. #
# Why is my heart leaping, #
# like a squirrel? #
Shall we go out later tonight?
# Is the weather a little wild, #
# or is my spirit soaring? #
Just one won't make a difference.
# The taste of free will, #
# is so juicy. #
# I know not, #
# why the branches
of my desire, #
# are suddenly blooming
with flaming flowers? #
# I know not, #
# why is my heart leaping, #
# like a squirrel? #
# I know not. #
Y es, that's the way!
Remember one mistake
can cost you the medal.
# A new friendship is forming, #
# with the limitless open skies. #
# That's making the earth jealous, #
# she's complaining
I'm getting spoilt. #
# Life too, now-a-days, #
# seems bored of counting, #
# it's reciting couplets, #
# among math equations. #
Y es papa, training is going well.
I'm going.
Coach-sir is waiting.
Bye!
# I've left behind the arguments
of right and wrong, #
# I've moved on. #
# Why is my heart leaping, #
# like a squirrel? #
Geeta!
Come here.
Forget your papa's technique.
Learn only what I teach you.
Got that?
Hello!
Sorry, Geeta has gone out.
For years I have been losing
to both of you intentionally.
It is the truth!
That's it!
You see?
Wrestlers shine only when
the technique is right.
Win the Nationals soon.
You too will be sorted.
Yes... when are you coming home?
I'm coming next week.
Need something?
Nothing. You get here.
Okay.
Did you like it?
Really?
You grew out your hair.
It's looking good.
Your papa won't like it.
Now everything can't work
the way papa wants.
Coach-sir didn't say anything.
And he is such an accomplished coach.
You do as you please over there.
Just be a little careful here.
Mummy,
real training happens
with a lot of freedom.
Not with so many restrictions.
We watch movies,
television, eat out, too.
My performance hasn't suffered.
I am the topmost wrestler
at the NSA.
You home, wrestler?
How are you?
- I am fine, papa.
How's your training going?
She's going to Sydney for a fight.
It's going very well, papa.
You've seen...
I'm learning a lot of new things.
New strategy, moves,
technique...
very good.
I have thought that
I will teach her some things, too.
After all, she too has to
win the Nationals.
You've grown your hair.
Papa...
- No.
It's good.
Don't just attack,
you've to defend, too.
Hold me.
Now, how will you free yourself?
Hold this way, break and attack.
Got that?
That's an old technique.
Let me...
Hold me.
Tight.
Push your thumbs in this way,
and move it to the side.
Not in the front... but to the side.
Break and attack.
What's wrong with my technique?
What's wrong?
No, papa. It's not wrong.
This is more correct.
Coach-sir has taught it.
So now you are an expert?
International?
Papa, I was...
I'd like to know, what is it that
your coach-sir has taught you,
that your father couldn't.
Not her, show me.
Come on.
Push your thumbs in this way...
So, this is what your coach-sir
has taught you!
Is this how you'll win
an international medal?
I wasn't ready, papa.
So, get ready.
This is what I was saying, papa.
Isn't there a difference?
What happened today
wasn't right.
What wasn't right?
This was bound to happen.
Someone had to tell papa
that his techniques are weak.
His techniques aren't weak.
He's become a little weak.
And don't forget that
you've won the Nationals,
based on his "weak" techniques.
You can win the Nationals
with these techniques, Babita,
not international matches.
And the sooner
you realize this, the better.
Alright.
You keep faith in your techniques.
I still put my faith in papa.
I pray to God that you fight
well at the Nationals.
And I pray that you do well
in your international tournament.
# This world is a lie. #
# True is my pain. #
# Mirage-like, my beloved, #
# is our bond. #
# Those eyes, #
# that dreamt
beautiful dreams together, #
# they tear up in separation now. #
# Those eyes, #
# that stayed awake
nights together, #
# refuse to awaken
even in the mornings. #
# Separated are the paths, #
# of those who pledged, #
# to walk together always, #
# now they share only sorrow. #
# Those misty eyes, #
# that peered through
windows with hope, #
# are now suffocated
with despair. #
# The breath is unsettled, #
# with thoughts that torment. #
# Why is this soul in disarray? #
# Why this despair? #
# This disheartenment? #
# Why is the heart filled with
the storm of a million questions? #
# Those eyes, #
# that shone brightly like
stars in the sky, #
# have now disappeared
in the dark night. #
# Those eyes, #
# that used to feast
on the warmth of the sun, #
# tired, now seek the shade. #
# Separated are the paths, #
# of those who pledged, #
# to walk together always, #
# now they share only sorrow. #
# Those misty eyes, #
# that peered through
windows with hope, #
# are now suffocated
with despair. #
"World Championship, Sydney"
"National Games, New Delhi"
Go... Babita!
Throw her.
What are you doing, Geeta?
Defend!
Attack!
Good one!
Is this how you defend?
The next round, too,
play attacking.
You don't look happy, papa.
Didn't I fight properly?
No, my dear.
You fought exactly as I expected.
But, I never imagined Geeta
would fight like this.
And now, you too,
have won the Nationals.
You too, will go to NSA.
You'll have a new coach.
And your papa once again
will become old.
No, papa.
Never forget,
how you got till here.
Hey, champion.
Hello, sis.
Still upset?
Come.
What did you fill in the bag?
- Let me get it.
It's so heavy.
Hi, Jasmeet!
This is my younger sister, Babita.
Whoa! A family of wrestlers!
Here is the mess.
This is were we hog.
This is the lounge.
Here we chill and watch TV.
Where is the training center?
My, aren't you eager!
See it tomorrow.
Rest today.
Can I say something?
Don't feel offended.
Tell me.
You've changed a lot.
I remember the first time
you lost a match.
You couldn't sleep all night.
And now, in spite of losing an
international fight you are...
I mean, it doesn't show
at all on your face.
Has papa trained you
to say this?
I remember papa's training
very well.
It seems you've forgotten.
You focus on your training.
I will manage mine.
And why are you lecturing me?
I've only lost one match.
"Moscow"
Geeta Kumari is trailing
in the second round as well.
She's fought well,
but hasn't managed much.
Geeta tries,
but Kasha scores one point.
And that's it!
Geeta Kumari makes an early exit
from the world championship.
What a disappointment!
Yet another defeat for
India's Geeta Kumari Phogat.
In Jakarta too, Geeta exits
in the first round.
A humiliating defeat for Geeta
in the Istanbul World Championship!
Geeta, don't lose hope.
We've worked very hard.
And you played well.
You just couldn't win.
It doesn't mean you are
a bad wrestler.
It happens.
Some people are not made
for international victory.
Do you feel too,
that I'm not cut out
for an international medal?
I don't know about that.
All I know,
is that you are the girl,
who thrashed boys
in mud-wrestling.
You are the girl,
who in spite of being
underweight, won sub-juniors.
You beat everyone at the Nationals
for three straight years.
If you are not cut out
for international victory,
then I don't know
which girl in lndia is.
I have a lot of faith in you,
but it's nothing compared to
the faith that papa has in you.
Talk to him once.
How do I face him?
He's our papa.
At worst, what will happen?
He will give you an earful.
Take it.
His reprimands have
always helped us, haven't they?
Your medicine.
I spoke to Babita.
She said the training
was going well.
And?
Geeta is not okay.
Please talk to her once.
Hello.
Geeta?
Okay, wait.
Geeta...
Sorry, papa.
Only six months remain for
the 19th Commonwealth Games,
the biggest sporting event in lndia.
What remains to be seen is how
the lndian players hold up,
against the world's best.
This time in the Commonwealth games,
I want three medals.
Now, whether they come
from you three,
you three or you three!
I don't care.
There are six months left.
Give your best.
Got that?
Get cracking!
Geeta.
Come here.
You will get one medal.
Yes, sir.
Not in the category
that you are losing in,
but in the category
in which you can win.
Got me?
It's difficult for you to survive
in the 55-kilo category.
You too must have
realised that by now.
In the 51-kilo category,
you can hold your own,
and maybe win.
Monitor everyone's diet strictly.
No mess ups.
- Sir!
Sir, I want to fight in the
55-kilo category!
If you fight in the 55-kilo category
you'll get no where!
She has to lose four kilos.
Change her diet.
From tomorrow we'll start your
training for the 51-kilo category.
Come on, girls.
Why won't you win
in the 55-kilo category?
No need for you
to lose weight!
You will fight in the
55-kilo category, and win!
I'm coming to Patiala.
We don't know anyone in Patiala.
How will you stay for six months?
On rent.
And food?
I'll cook.
I'll cook, uncle!
I was thinking that
I too could come along.
What will you do there?
Well, in the past they did well
when they trained with me.
So, if they train with me
in the future too...
Honestly, I think I am
their good luck charm.
I mean... that's what I think.
And, I will buy vegetables for you,
chop them for you,
run errands for you,
press your feet.
I'll make sure you are stress-free.
You see...
it's the Commonwealth Games.
We can't take any chances.
Start preparing for gold!
"Patiala"
The room is on top.
Come.
Is there no other room,
in the same budget?
It's nice.
Yes!
It's nice, indeed.
I have to admit!
Yes?
Geeta and Babita Kumari's
father and close cousin.
Holy cow!
Uncle, doesn't this place
seem lovely?
How are you, champ?
And you?
I'm good, papa.
Why are you here?
Uncle insisted that I come.
He said it's the Commonwealth Games.
We can't take a chance.
Shut up, 'TTSS'!
Geeta's 51-kilo category
training has started,
and the diet too.
You continue their diet and training,
I'll supplement the rest.
What time does
your training start?
7am.
Okay.
Be ready at 5am tomorrow.
# I'm here to stay. #
# Beat the best. #
# Hold on firmly to your dreams. #
# Don't pay heed to what
naysayers and cynics say. #
# It's their turn today,
let them have their say. #
# Your turn will come too;
prove your point then! #
# One roar of the lion silences
the bleating of a thousand sheep. #
# So, wrestle, O Wrestler! #
# Wrestle, O Wrestler! #
# Your glory may rise and fall, #
# cause up in the sky
your stars are wrestling too. #
# So, wrestle, O Wrestler! #
# Wrestle, O Wrestler! #
Stop... stop.
Straight attacks won't do.
You have to play with
the opponent's mind.
Fake a move...
but make another.
Sir, I had put her on a diet,
but, I don't know why
it hasn't reduced.
What have you been up to, Geeta?
Will you say something
or just keep crying?
Sir, judging by their actions
I feel they don't need NSA.
The rest is up to you.
Do you all have anything to say?
So you admit you are at fault.
Sir, they have just one fault.
That their father is crazy.
He is so crazy about getting
a gold for the country,
that in their childhood itself
he snatched away their toys,
and made them wrestle.
When they resisted,
he cut their hair off.
In order to prepare them,
he made them wrestle boys.
Took the taunts and abuses
of the entire village,
just so that one day they would
make the country proud.
Look, sir.
Look.
These 50 rupees
she won at Rohtak.
This in Hisar.
This in Chandigarh.
This... this, all this... sir.
These girls have traveled
a long way to reach here, sir.
Now don't tell them to turn back.
It's all my fault.
I humbly apologise.
Coach-sir is just concerned
with getting three medals.
No matter if they are bronze.
But I want our country
to win gold.
And this girl can do it, sir.
All of you, please wait outside.
You've made a mistake
by wasting time.
In 55-kilos, Geeta won't even
get selected for lndia.
If she had fought in the 51-kilos
she could've won a medal.
She should've won a medal
much earlier, in 55-kilos itself.
You are responsible for that!
What did I do wrong?
Geeta's natural game is attacking.
By putting technique above instinct,
you've changed her game.
It's like telling a tiger
to fight like an elephant.
You'll be left with neither
a tiger nor an elephant.
So, why don't you tell me,
how to fight to win a medal!
With your permission, I would like to
demonstrate it here and now.
They're calling you inside.
What happened was wrong.
But the committee has decided
to give them another chance.
Thank you, sir.
But, from today,
neither are you allowed
to enter the NSA premises,
nor are they allowed
to step out.
Okay, sir.
Today, make one for me too, uncle.
Sorry.
Thank you.
We had come to play the lead role,
NSA made ours
a guest appearance.
Let's head back now.
No, Omkar.
They can stop me
from going inside,
but no one can stop me
from coaching Geeta.
Cheers, uncle.
Against three of them
I held my own.
But the one who
took me to the cleaners...
she was smaller than me
and not that strong either.
Do you have a recording
of this match?
Yes papa, in the library.
Courier me a copy of all.
Only three months remain
for the Delhi Commonwealth Games.
And the fervor can be sensed at the
National Sports Academy in Patiala.
Where are we going, uncle?
The one thing
I disliked about uncle,
was his constant
air of suspense.
It could kill you!
"CrazyCougar.com"
"The Lustful Aunt"
If you want to watch a movie,
let's go to Amar Mahal.
They don't show decent films here.
Get off.
"Wild Daughter"
Yes?
How much for all the tickets
of the next show?
Which film do you
want to watch?
We've brought it with us.
Pause.
Play.
Are you done?
Be happy.
Your next show is sold-out too.
What are you guys up to?
I mean, where is the movie from?
Atlanta... Indonesia.
Imported?
- Yes.
Listen, can I make a copy?
Give me 50 rupees less.
How will she win
if she fights like this?
Uncle!
Uncle, you've gathered
the knowledge,
but how will you pass it on?
NSA has issued a 'shoot-at-sight'
order against you.
Sit.
Again... suspense!
Is this how you fight?
Like a quivering kitten?
If this is how you want to fight,
then don't.
What happened, papa?
I saw all your matches.
You weren't wrestling,
that's for sure!
Do you have copies of
the DVDs that you gave me?
Yes, papa.
Can you arrange to watch
them alone?
I'll borrow a laptop.
Alright.
Be ready at 5am tomorrow.
It's been a while since
papa gave me an earful.
Felt good.
Play the Jakarta fight, round one.
I have, papa.
Go to three minutes 58 seconds.
You have a lead
of two points,
and you started
playing defensive.
Play. Look.
Threw away the lead, didn't you?
When the opponent is trailing,
go for the jugular!
How did you do that?
Alternately, when you should be defending,
you are attacking and giving away points.
You will gain nothing by
desperately chasing after points.
You'll have to apply your mind.
You've lost matches
that were yours to win!
Go... Geeta!
"National Trials, Patiala"
Each round consists of two minutes.
However, there are 120 seconds
in those two minutes.
Wait for that one second
when the opponent makes a mistake.
She's good. Isn't she?
Yes, sir.
Very good!
Now you look ready, sis.
Did you tell papa?
What did he say?
"There's no need to get too happy!"
A grand opening ceremony
to the 201 0 Commonwealth Games!
Host nation, India, displaying
her ancient culture.
A proud moment indeed!
And here comes
the Indian contingent!
A huge welcome for them.
Let us remind you that
the finest athletes,
from 72 countries are participating.
We'll be back tomorrow
to start off the events.
Until then... goodnight!
Geeta was quite nervous
before her first bout.
And that was expected.
So far her performance
in international events had been poor.
However little... the nation
still had hope on her.
And this was probably
Geeta's last opportunity,
to prove herself.
The first match in women's wrestling,
55-kilo category, is between,
India's Geeta Kumari and
Melissa Anderson from Wales.
Go, Geeta!
Geeta seems quite nervous.
Now, let's see if she can
break her jinx,
of losing in the first
couple of rounds.
We would like to remind
our spectators,
that there will be three rounds
of two minutes each.
Whoever wins two rounds,
wins the match.
With that the match begins.
Both the wrestlers are quite alert.
1 point to Melissa.
Melissa - 1 ; Geeta - 0.
Melissa seems stronger.
3 more points to Melissa!
What are you doing, Geeta?
Melissa - 4; Geeta - 0.
If Geeta gives away
2 more points,
Melissa will win this round
on technical superiority.
And Melissa gets 2 points!
Exactly as we feared.
Melissa has won the first round
on technical superiority; 6-0.
What are you doing, Geeta?
Don't lose so badly!
We now need to see that
after losing the first round badly,
is Geeta capable of making
a comeback in round two.
2 points to Melissa.
1 more point to Melissa.
The match seems to be
slipping out of Geeta's hands.
You are not to lose, Geeta!
Come on, Geeta.
Geeta, lagging by 3 points.
She'll have to score real quick.
2 points to Geeta!
Melissa - 3; Geeta - 2.
Geeta tries to score some more,
but the referee blows the whistle.
The round is nearing completion.
Geeta is still behind by a point.
Geeta in trouble!
Geeta gets 3 points!
Geeta - 5; Melissa - 3.
Just four seconds to go.
Y es, Geeta!
Geeta's back in the match!
It's one round each.
Geeta has shown that she is not
going to accept defeat so easily.
It's the last round.
Play defensive.
Got it?
Play attacking!
And the last round begins.
Geeta on the attack.
1 point for Geeta.
Geeta - 1 ; Melissa - 0.
2 more points in Geeta's kitty.
Geeta- 3; Melissa - 0.
Will she manage to keep her lead?
Very good. Defend now.
3 points for Melissa!
I told you to defend.
No problem.
Keep attacking!
The score is equal at 3-3.
Go for it, Geeta!
This match can tilt either way.
Geeta was poised to win
but lost her lead.
Geeta's in danger.
Wow! What a move!
3 points to Geeta!
Keep her down, Geeta.
Geeta has won this match!
India's Geeta Kumari Phogat,
has proven her critics wrong.
A proud moment for Geeta's father,
Mahavir Singh Phogat!
So far lndia has won,
five gold, 1 3 silver
and seven bronze medals.
In women's wrestling,
lndia's Geeta Kumari Phogat,
has entered the semi-finals
of the 55-kilo category.
Geeta will now face
Nigeria's Naomi Edwards,
two time world champion.
What do you think?
Naomi is a very strong wrestler.
Extremely aggressive and attacking.
She doesn't give any
opportunity to her opponent.
It's not going to be easy
for Geeta this time.
Today, you played as per your will.
Now, do as I say.
Or it's impossible to win.
It's a difficult one,
but not impossible.
You'll have to play offensive!
You have to play defensive.
Just go for the points!
Don't go for the points.
You'll get a lot of opportunities.
Don't give her any opportunities
because she won't give you any.
Force a lock-jam each time.
If she doesn't get to score,
she'll get frustrated,
and will give you an opportunity.
That's the moment
we should grab!
The first semi-final match in
the 55-kilo category.
India's Geeta Kumari
versus Nigeria's Naomi Edwards.
Naomi attacking from the start.
And against her nature,
Geeta playing defensive.
Naomi attacks!
Geeta in trouble.
Geeta putting up a strong defense.
Geeta holding her back.
Naomi made a strong attempt.
But Geeta held her own.
Go on the attack!
Go easy.
Naomi gets rough.
She seems frustrated.
Naomi twisting Geeta's wrist.
Naomi is being given a warning.
Hang in there, Geeta!
That's 3 points for Naomi!
Geeta had been
holding her off well.
A really good effort,
but Naomi's broken
through her defense.
Geeta has to act fast.
Geeta takes Naomi down.
1 point to Geeta!
She's still trying.
And time's up!
Geeta played well,
but she's lost this first round.
What are you doing, Geeta?
Why don't you attack?
The second round begins.
Naomi attacks.
Naomi tries to flip Geeta.
But Geeta defends well.
Naomi puts all her strength,
but Geeta isn't giving her a chance.
This is an exciting match.
Naomi trying hard,
but Geeta not giving her space.
Naomi attacks again.
Geeta defends.
A nice defense by Geeta.
The referee breaks the fight.
Second round is still 0-0.
Naomi must be wondering
how to break Geeta's defense.
"If she doesn't get to score,
she'll get frustrated,
and will give you an opportunity. "
Naomi attacks.
"That's the moment
we should grab! "
3 points!
And Geeta wins this round, 3-0.
Naomi, look at me.
That girl, she's smart.
But you are double smart.
Okay?
Don't allow her to turn you easily.
How are you fighting?
Sir, I am fighting as I have learnt.
The third and final round has started.
It's interesting to see,
that Naomi is now
playing cautiously.
Naomi trying real hard.
But Geeta holding her back.
It's a lock position again.
Naomi attacks again.
Geeta holds her back.
Will Naomi score?
Hold on, Geeta!
The score stands at 0-0.
Naomi tries harder.
Geeta is exposed here
but holds her back.
Geeta hanging on
by the skin of her teeth.
Only 1 2 seconds left.
The score still 0-0.
Geeta attacks!
With that this round is tied at 0-0.
She could have scored.
Now there'll be a toss.
Now there will be a toss.
This is known as a 'clinch'.
The wrestler who wins the toss
gets to choose a grip,
and gets 30 seconds to score.
If the red side falls up,
Naomi gets to attack,
if it's blue, Geeta gets to attack.
In 99 percent of the cases
the one who wins the toss,
wins the match.
Oh!
Maybe even destiny
doesn't want Geeta to win.
It's next to impossible to defend
against Naomi for 30 seconds.
Which leg do you choose?
- Right.
Naomi has chosen
Geeta's right leg.
Geeta takes a defensive position.
Naomi takes her grip of choice.
Now, Geeta has two options.
Not allow Naomi to score
for 30 seconds,
or score herself,
and win the match.
In this position against Naomi,
both are almost impossible.
She lifts Geeta!
And Geeta scores a point!
No one expected
Geeta to win this match.
She has beaten the number one
contender for gold,
in this very exciting clinch,
and entered the finals!
And let's hope that
Geeta Phogat,
maintains her wonderful form
in the finals too.
Shall we go, uncle?
Let's see the next match.
Let's find out whether Geeta's finals
is against the Australian,
or the Scottish wrestler.
I'm very proud of Geeta.
She followed my strategy to the T.
The result is in front of you.
Here she comes.
She looks good.
I mean... as a wrestler.
Uncle, isn't she the
same one from the DVD?
Angelina Watson.
She's defeated Geeta twice.
She's played well till now.
And she'll play well
in the finals too.
I've always had faith in Geeta.
Sooner or later she had to
win an international medal.
A silver is guaranteed now!
The final won't be so easy.
Geeta-ji,
your game has changed dramatically.
How did this happen?
The entire credit for this,
goes to my father.
He never stopped believing in me.
Mahavir-ji!
Hello, Mr. Shamim.
Congratulations, Mahavir-ji!
Geeta fought very well.
All of Balali is proud.
And these girls insisted,
on watching Geeta's match
in the stadium,
or they won't eat.
How did you like the match?
Loved it!
Give this to her.
What is this?
I prayed for her.
Tomorrow is the final.
Bless you!
How can we allow this, sir?
Mahavir Singh is shouting instructions
to Geeta from the audience.
The poor thing is getting confused
whether to listen to him or me.
From her game, it sure doesn't
seem like she's confused.
Besides, how can we ask
the audience to remain silent?
Aren't you the coach?
She should be listening to you.
No, sir... she is listening to me.
That's why she's winning.
- Then what's the problem?
You wanted a bronze, right?
It's quite possible that
tomorrow she may win gold.
No?
I'm surprised she's made it so far
but I am happy for her.
It should be an interesting
final tomorrow.
Playing an lndian
in front of an lndian crowd.
Beating her, of course!
Angelina, any pressure
before the finals?
Yeah, I'm sure she must be
under tremendous pressure.
I've beaten her twice.
First round?
- Yeah.
Yeah, first round.
So, thank you and,
Namaste!
What's the strategy
for tomorrow, papa?
There is only one strategy
for tomorrow, child.
You have to fight in a way
that people remember you.
If you win silver,
sooner or later
you'll be forgotten.
If you win gold,
you will become an example.
And examples are given, child...
not forgotten.
See those girls?
If you win tomorrow,
you will not win alone.
Millions of girls like them
will win along with you.
It'll be a victory for every girl who
is considered inferior to boys;
who is forced
into household chores,
who is married off
to just raise children.
Tomorrow's match is
the most important one.
Because tomorrow you won't be
fighting just that Australian
but all those people
who think less of girls.
The finals of the women's wrestling,
Commonwealth Games 201 0,
55-kilo category, is about to begin.
India's Geeta Kumari versus
Australia's Angelina Watson.
We'd like to remind you all,
that never before has
an Indian female wrestler,
ever won gold in the
Commonwealth Games.
In this crowd, we see,
a lot of hope, enthusiasm
and the Indian flag.
Hello, sir!
Aren't you Mahavir Singh-ji?
Geeta's father?
- Yes.
A moment please.
The chairman of the Wrestling
Federation wants to meet you.
Some important matter.
I'll meet him later.
It's my daughter's match.
He's a big man.
He might get offended.
Just two minutes.
You carry on. I'll be there.
"The entire credit for this
goes to my father."
Go... take the credit.
How much further is it?
We are almost there, sir.
Where have you got me?
Hey, brother!
What are you doing, brother?
A thunderous applause for Geeta
as she walks in.
Is anyone there?
Hello!
Anyone there?
This is the final.
Play carefully.
Angelina Watson enters the stadium.
And the final match begins.
Go for gold, Geeta!
Angelina, aggressive
from the start.
She attacks.
Geeta defends.
And 3 points for Geeta!
Geeta takes a big lead
right from the start.
Geeta - 3; Angelina - 0.
Good... good!
Another point for Geeta.
Geeta - 4; Angelina - 0.
Geeta playing very well.
Angelina will need to act fast.
1 point to Angelina.
Angelina looks for a takedown.
Geeta defends well.
Referee whistles.
Geeta leads, 4- 1.
1 point to Geeta.
Geeta- 5; Angelina - 1.
And with this, Geeta Kumari
wins the first round quite easily.
Perhaps Angelina is realizing,
that this is not the same Geeta,
whom she had defeated
easily in the past.
And the second round starts.
Will Geeta win this round
and create history?
An excellent takedown!
1 point to Geeta.
Geeta - 1 ; Angelina - 0.
Go... Geeta, go!
2 more points for Geeta!
Geeta - 3; Angelina - 0.
Geeta bearing down on Angelina.
Geeta attacks!
1 point for Geeta.
Two more points,
and she'll win this round
by technical superiority,
and the championship!
Geeta bearing down
with all her might.
Will Geeta win?
The referee's whistle saves Angelina!
No problem... Geeta!
Angelina seems furious.
1 point for Angelina.
Angelina - 1 ; Geeta - 4.
Geeta is still in danger.
2 more points for Angelina.
Geeta - 4; Angelina - 3.
No problem... come on!
Geeta still leads by 1 point.
She needs to hold on to it
a little longer.
Will Geeta retain this lead?
Time is running out.
Geeta defends well.
Angelina going all out.
3 points to Angelina!
Angelina - 6; Geeta - 4.
And this round comes to an end.
And Angelina has shown
what a true champion is made of!
What are you doing?
You could've won the match!
Angelina, with renewed enthusiasm.
It's not going to be
easy for Geeta.
Angelina aggressive
from the start.
3 points for Angelina!
A 3-point lead in the final round!
Angelina - 3; Geeta - 0.
1 point more to Angelina.
Angelina - 4; Geeta - 0.
And this match leaning
in favour of Angelina.
If Geeta has to get back,
she needs to score fast.
A clever move by Geeta.
1 point to Geeta!
Angelina - 4; Geeta - 1.
Time... running out.
Geeta needs to keep at it.
But carefully, because if
Angelina scores again,
it'll be impossible
to make a come back.
Geeta attacks,
but Angelina scores a point!
Angelina - 5; Geeta - 1.
It's almost impossible now
for Geeta to make a comeback!
"Remember!"
"Your papa won't be there
to save you every time. "
"l can only teach you to fight."
"But you have to fight yourself."
"Make the effort...
save yourself."
Only 22 seconds left.
And Geeta is trailing by 4 points.
At this level, it's almost impossible
to cover this lead in such short time.
"T o score five points is difficult,
but it can be done. "
Geeta trying.
But Angelina stalling for time.
Just a few seconds left.
And India might have to
settle for a silver.
"You have to play with
the opponent's mind. "
"Fake a move,
but make another."
And a fantastic move by Geeta.
Will time be on her side?
It's a gold for Geeta!
Geeta has achieved
the impossible!
She is the first ever
female Indian wrestler,
to win gold at the
Commonwealth Games!
Who would have thought that
a girl from a small village in India,
is capable of leaving her mark
on the whole world!
Well done, Geeta!
A proud moment for India indeed!
Champion!
Where's papa?
I don't know.
We came together though.
And now the gold medal,
for India's Geeta Kumari Phogat.
And now, as per tradition,
the national anthem of the
winning country will play.
Victory to lndia!
Hey! What are you doing here?
Geeta, come...
the media is waiting.
Come.
Come. Everyone is waiting.
Come... come.
And finally uncle uttered
those golden words,
that we had been pining to hear
for the past 1 0 years.
I'm proud of you!