Golshifteh Farahani
Taraneh Alidousti
Shahab Hosseini
Merila Zarei
Mani Haghighi
Peyman Moadi
Rana Azadivar
Ahmad Mehranar
ABOUT ELLY...
Script: Asghar Farhadi
Sound mixing:
M. Delpak
Editing:
H. Safiyari
Director of photography:
H. Jafarian
Producers:
A. Farhadi - S.M. Razavi
Written and directed by
Asghar FARHADI
That was fun, wasn't it?
Yes, but I need to pee.
Did you have to get so excited?
Stop, so I can take her to the loo.
This isn't preschool.
Stop bothering Elly.
It's fine.
I'm just taking her to the loo.
Shall I take this?
- You hadn't told them?
- What?
That she was coming.
I wasn't sure until last night.
She's no bother to anyone.
- You Ok?
- Yes. Thanks.
She looks sweet.
She is. Wait and see:
They'll all love her.
Let me do that.
No, please. I'm used to it.
Peyman!
You drive too fast.
- You're too slow!
- It's dangerous.
Amir, is something going on?
- What?
- As if you didn't know!
I have no clue.
Sepideh hasn't told you
why she brought the girl?
Not at all.
You must promise not to mention it
when she's around.
But seriously, Ahmad,
she's a nice girl.
You really mean it?
Yes. She'd sort you out.
You saw all that at a glance?
Of course.
It shows immediately.
Right, Nazy?
She's easygoing.
Already 3 votes.
I only said she was easygoing.
To know her is to love her.
Let him make up his own mind.
Can you find a good match
for me too?
Can you give him a slap for me?
Manuchehr!
Did you see that, Ahmad?
You deserved it!
That's what he's here for.
Oh, so that's how it is?
Sepideh, does the girl know
Ahmad was married once?
I don't know.
And forced to divorce?
I'll tell on you.
Peyman, don't!
What's her name again?
Elly.
Peyman...
Elly!
Stop it!
You'll embarrass her!
Here's the samovar.
I haven't had tea like this for ages!
Poor me!
How can you stand
living in Germany?
Stand it?
I'm going insane!
No wonder
your German wife left you.
She went to the judge and said:
"Achtung! The man is insane!"
Peyman!
Isn't it true?
Amir, would you help me?
I'm going.
What?
I didn't call you...
- Anything wrong?
- Not at all.
They joke all the time.
Don't take it personally.
Is that it?
Try to get on with them.
You'll spend a nice couple of days.
- Couple of days?
- Sure!
Madam...
See, it was right here!
Good thing I was wrong for once...
Hello. Can we have
the keys to the villa?
- The one in the woods?
- The same as last year.
Bahri?
So, you were all together?
Yes, at university.
My sister Nazy.
Here's Elly.
We've already been introduced!
Oh, have you...
- Is it here?
- Just the keys.
Take them to the villa.
We know the way.
Just give us the keys.
How are you?
Fine, thank you.
Don't forget, tomorrow.
- What?
- To leave early.
The owner comes
in the evening.
We'll have to clean up before.
We meant to stay 3 days.
I spoke to someone on the phone.
It was me.
- Can't we find an arrangement?
- I don't mind.
But the owner's coming.
Didn't you tell him we were staying?
We told you over the phone.
Didn't you say it was all set?
There was nothing left.
I thought once here, we'd manage.
Manage at the height of season?
I'm so sorry.
It's not your fault.
Why didn't you tell me?
We wouldn't have come at all!
Don't get so upset.
We'll find another place.
Over the phone you didn't sound
sure about the owner.
I was sure.
Can't you do anything?
Like what?
If it was just us,
we'd sleep in our cars or in tents.
But we have guests, newlyweds.
Congratulations.
The groom is here from Germany.
It's like their honeymoon.
What about the Mahmudi villa?
It's taken.
We can go anywhere.
- And the seafront villa?
- Sadeghian's?
With no proper doors and windows,
you'll catch cold.
It's dirty.
We can clean it.
Let's see it.
Get the keys at your uncle's.
Thank you.
What a beautiful sea!
"How happy we will be..."
Arash.
Are you sure this is the right key?
Mind your fingers.
There we go!
Never mind, Ahmad, it's open.
How did you get in there?
Be careful, sweetie.
It's dirty.
What's that?
Careful.
It's huge!
Watch your feet.
The fan works.
Where's the loo?
There's no lock.
Can you keep a look-out?
If you use the loo,
we'll have to keep the villa!
You idiot!
We'll spend the weekend cleaning.
Watch out!
Don't worry.
Hey, boy!
Are there any gas cylinders here?
- With a vacuum, it'd be fast.
- You go and sit down.
It'll get cold here at night.
All we need is to cover the windows.
Come on, you're not alone here.
I have a suggestion.
- Tonight...
- It's fine here. Let's stay...
Can I just finish my sentence?
Go on.
We go to the other villa tonight
and come back tomorrow.
Who wants to drag everything
back and forth?
There's no privacy in the loo
but it works!
Excellent point!
It's nice here.
It's beautiful.
Are we going to discuss this
for 3 days?
- What shall we do?
- Vote.
Elly, what do you say?
I'll clean up.
What about you, Shohreh?
We should try
and find something better.
One against.
And you, Nazy?
Whatever my man says.
So, her man?
Let's stay.
And you, Peyman?
My man said no, it's no...
You donkey!
Two against.
Two to five, we're staying!
I guess my vote doesn't count...
Oh yes, it does!
Come on!
- Where are you going?
- Getting a broom.
Shall we go for the luggage?
Let's tidy up first.
We won't feel like it later.
Sepideh...
Where are the car keys?
- What's your name, boy?
- Omid.
Omid, are there any shops around?
- What do you need?
- Cigarettes.
I'll do it.
Thank you.
Leave it. I'll take it.
Arash!
Come in, you'll get wet.
Peyman, call the little one.
I'm going to stress out all weekend.
Relax.
We all chose this place.
I can't keep everyone away
from the sea for our son's sake.
Come on, sweetie.
Peyman, see if you
can find the boiler.
Isn't it inside?
That's all we needed...
Sweetheart!
Yes? What is it?
Matches!
Got any?
Sorry!
- You scared me!
- I'm sorry!
I'll throw it away.
- Will it go through?
- Sure.
Hold it up.
- It won't fit. Wait.
- No, it won't open.
No way.
No! Watch out!
Tilt it a bit.
You see, it went through!
Shall I help you?
You'll cut yourself!
Be careful not to cut yourself.
I'm here, Morvarid.
Sepideh!
Who's sleeping where?
Anywhere. Who cares?
The women in the bedrooms.
The men in the living room.
I won't sleep away from my wife.
Then you two in the living room.
- Shohreh?
- Yes?
Coming.
We'll have a crazy night!
We'll have to dance to warm up.
What if I can't dance?
We'll teach you.
Go! Follow her!
- What should I do?
- Follow her.
Don't miss such an opportunity!
It's embarrassing!
Okay. I'll go!
Arash!
Get out of the water!
He's in the kitchen.
Here, your cigarettes.
Come on! Hurry up!
Go and get him.
Hurry UP!
You're soaked!
Look at yourself!
Elly!
- Looking for the lady?
- Yes.
She went to make a phone call.
There's no signal here.
Stop screaming. Run, now!
Can you go
and buy some light bulbs?
Ahmad, go and find her.
Elly's gone to make a phone call.
Take her for a ride.
Leave the poor girl alone.
The water's still cold.
I turned on the boiler.
We must wait.
You don't have much time.
Come on...
What are looking for?
Ahmad wants to go shopping.
He can fill the car up, too.
Here, the keys.
I'll leave tomorrow afternoon.
I'll be home by midnight.
Yes, by bus.
Don't worry.
My colleague will be with me.
She's fine.
Mom, if anyone calls,
don't say I'm out of town.
Just say you don't know where I am.
Has the pain come back?
Take care.
I'll be careful. I told you,
I'm with colleagues from school.
Okay.
I'll call you back later.
There's no signal here...
Talk to you soon.
Bye.
Did you speak to her?
Yes, thanks.
Was she worried?
Yes, as usual. She shouldn't,
as she's had a heart operation.
Recently?
A month ago.
Her doctor asked her to avoid stress.
If I'd called an hour later,
she'd have had a heart attack!
"Hello, Mom.
I'm fine. And you?"
"Are you eating?"
"Of course I am!"
She thought I was starving
over there!
Once, at Hamburg airport,
they opened my suitcase.
Ajar of pickles had broken,
it stank of vinegar!
I was so embarrassed!
She must be happy
that you're visiting.
She died 2 years ago.
I'm sorry.
It was in the middle
of the mess of my divorce.
She suffered a lot.
Do you mind if I ask you a question?
Nothing too personal?
No.
Go ahead.
Why'd you break up with her?
Which one do you mean?
You don't have to answer.
Why do you want to know?
Well, I'd rather know...
You'd rather know...
One day, we got up, we washed,
we had breakfast and she said:
"Achmed,"
"Besser eine Ende mit Schrecken..."
"als ein Schrecken ohne Ende."
What?
You say it.
- What?
- Besser...
eine Ende mit Schrecken...
I can't say it.
I'm sorry.
Shall I pull over?
No, I know who it is.
I'll call back later.
So, what does that mean?
A bitter ending is better
than an endless bitterness.
That's true.
What music do we have here?
- You took long.
- At least 10 minutes!
You had a good time, Ahmad?
Hello.
Arash, dear,
come and take the things in.
It gets cold at night.
This is the bedding
for the newlyweds.
We're all newlyweds!
I mean the just married ones,
the bride and groom...
Which ones are they?
Show them to me...
Congratulations.
I wish you happiness!
What's going on?
Are you staying for dinner?
No, thanks.
Lock the doors.
Also the cars.
The seafront is not safe.
Come on, guys.
I'll close the door.
Eat up, Ahmad!
You won't find this in Germany.
You mean, for free!
Come on, kids.
Why are you standing?
Sit down.
- Come here, Elly.
- Ahmad...
Make room for Elly.
I'm comfortable here.
Ahmad is not comfortable.
Manuchehr!
Make room for Ahmad, sweetie.
Does anyone need anything?
Coming.
- Shall I help you?
- I'll do it, thanks.
- You're too shy.
- No, I'll help myself.
Here.
What's this, you crazy?
Keep some for the loo!
- Amir!
- Sorry, bathroom.
- We're eating!
- No salt?
In the kitchen.
Manuchehr, go get the salt.
Did I forget the salt?
Did you wash your hands,
cow-boy?
It's getting cold.
Congratulations, man.
Long live the bride and groom
Eat, it's getting cold.
Elly, can't you find it?
Thanks a lot.
Salt, anyone?
Shut up!
Hey guys, come back in.
Why are you among men again?
Ahmad, what are you doing here?
Get up!
Why?
- How did it go?
- What?
Your trip together.
He's already fallen
head over heels in love.
I am a man in love
And I'll do anything...
I'm talking seriously.
At the end, we'll vote.
If the majority says yes,
I'll ask for her hand.
- If not, I won't.
- The majority means them?
We all agree!
What about you, Amir?
- What is it to me?
- I want your opinion.
- She's fine.
- Is that all?
What am I to say?
She's warm and calm.
I like her.
- Seriously?
- Sure.
You mean it?
She seems very healthy to me.
What about you,
Manuchehr?
She's nice and friendly.
You know what I think?
Don't laugh at me.
She's fine.
- Honest?
- I swear.
I'm off. You can talk.
We'd like 2 cups of tea.
Come and join your families!
Leave that here!
Fire! Fire!
What have you done?
Don't work my girl so hard.
She's working without a break.
No need to work,
we already like you.
- Go on, Elly!
- I want to make tea...
Fine. I leave this here.
We'll have time to tidy up tomorrow.
Come on. Let's go.
- How do you find her?
- She's nice.
Just a bit shy.
Poor thing is embarrassed.
Four words.
Second word.
- Bird?
- Flying?
A fly!
Insect?
Bee!
Third word.
Honey!
Good!
Honeybee.
Box?
Bee hive?
Television?
Cartoon?
The name of a cartoon?
Hutch, the Honeybee?
First word?
Baby?
Mother?
The Mother of Hutch the Honeybee!
Two words?
My love, is it two words?
- Mother?
- Child?
Baby?
Second word?
Moustache?
Your father has a moustache?
- Child?
- Father?
The child's father?
Well done, sweetheart!
Five words?
Second word.
Child?
- Bigger?
- Many?
Kids?
Third word.
Frame?
Television?
- Blackboard?
- School?
University?
University kids?
Students?
Fourth word.
- Scales?
- Justice?
Law!
Fifth word.
Summer? Heat?
Hot?
First word.
The first one.
Breathe?
Soul? God?
God, the kids from Law School
are hot shots!
I'm going in.
- Why?
- Something to do.
They were losing!
Let's go. Ready?
Elly!
We're going shopping.
Need anything?
I'm coming with you.
- I'll get what you need.
- I need a bus ticket.
No way!
Shohreh...
Sepideh...
Wait...
Arash.
No way, there's no way
- Shut the door.
- There's no one here, come.
I really have to go back today.
There's no way...
Are you having such a bad time?
No, Nazy.
I already explained.
I can't stay more than 1 night.
Weren't the men
going to tidy up?
Arash, don't go into the water.
He's so cute.
What kind of weekend is that?
You won't find a bus.
You'll have to walk back.
I may.
On foot?
Please, stay!
Sweetheart, my mom will tell me off.
You coming, Shohreh?
Sepideh...
I'd stay if I could.
- You'd better stay.
- My mother will worry.
- Nazy, you look after the kids?
- Yes.
- I'll call her.
- You promised.
Then I'll find a cab
and get tickets on my own.
I can't stay longer.
If she wants to leave,
you shouldn't insist, Sepideh.
I wish I could stay.
Sepideh knows I can't.
We came together.
We'll leave together.
- See you.
- I won't let her go.
Amir... the keys!
Where are the keys?
On the terrace, next to my cell.
Throw me the ball.
Be nice...
Arash, darling...
- Stay close by.
- Ok.
Just a bit more and then go inside!
Nazy, keep an eye on him, please.
Don't forget the onions.
What did she say?
We must buy onions.
Relax a little bit.
We'll have soup together later on.
Nice ring.
Thanks.
Can you keep an eye on them?
I'll tidy up a bit.
What's up, sweetie?
Can you fix it for me?
Yes, give it to me.
Come on, take it.
I have to go.
Daddy!
Yes, darling?
Daddy! Arash!
Come here.
Leave Arash alone.
Arash...
I'll take care of him!
Daddy! Daddy!
- Daddy, Arash!
- Morvarid?
Arash is in the water!
Arash!
Where's Arash?
Over there!
My God!
Was he in the water?
Who was with you?
Amir, check the house.
Arash!
Is he here?
He's in the sea!
Amir!
His shoes are here!
Manuchehr!
Ahmad! Ahmad!
Over there!
On the other side!
To your left!
He's there, Ahmad!
He's there!
Ahmad, check if he's breathing.
Is he breathing?
Put him down.
On the side,
so the water comes out of his lungs.
Lift his head.
Get up, my son!
Arash!
You just left them?
Where were the mothers?
Elly was with them.
Ahmad!
Elly!
- Was she in the sea?
- Morvarid didn't see her.
Morvarid, where was Elly?
- Isn't she inside?
- No.
What if she went after Arash?
Elly!
What's happened?
Nazy?
What's wrong?
Arash!
Was Elly in the sea with you?
Was she in the water?
- Look at me! Was she?
- We can't find her.
Hey, boy! Help!
Run! Go!
What a catastrophe!
Peyman?
Arash?
Don't worry.
It's Elly.
Oh no!
She wanted to rescue Arash...
Where's my son?
Inside.
Sepideh!
Help!
Who's in the sea?
Elly!
Elly?
Sepideh!
Don't go!
What's going on?
- We can't find her.
- Keep on searching!
The sea is heavy and muddy.
You can't just give up!
Wait a minute!
Take me along.
She might be stuck between rocks.
Let us go out there!
Take me!
You didn't try the other direction.
That's where we found the child.
We can't just leave her like this.
You have to wait
until the sea gets calmer.
Where are you going?
What if she's still alive?
We searched for over half an hour.
Please! What if she's alive...
She's not alive.
Was I talking to you?
Sepideh! Go inside!
Shohreh, take her in!
Peyman, don't let them go.
The body will be washed in.
If you check the shore this evening,
you'll find her.
Sepideh!
Sepideh...
They want her name and details.
She was flying her kite
and didn't see anything.
Did you see her go into the sea?
- No.
- What did you see?
Arash was shouting in the water.
Arash is my son.
I called my father to rescue him.
Ok. Are you sure
she was in the water?
I asked her to look after the kids.
What was her name?
- Elly.
- Elly?
You mean:
Elham, Elnaz, Elmira...?
Didn't you know her?
We called her Elly.
What was your relationship to her?
She was my daughter's teacher.
My wife had invited her.
You don't know the name
of your child's teacher?
I'll ask.
How strange!
You bring a guest from Tehran
without knowing anything about her
and we must ask a child about her?
What's her full name?
I don't know.
You don't know her surname?
Unfortunately, she doesn't know.
Look through her things.
There must be an ID or something.
I need the 3 of you
to give me your details.
And your documents, please.
Who's the owner of the villa?
Ahmad!
Her bag is gone!
Go and search for it.
I did. It's not here!
Nazy, give me Peyman's bag.
Shohreh, her bag is not there!
It must be in her room.
She can't have left!
Wasn't she with the kids?
She was about to go.
Sepideh stopped her.
She even wanted to walk back.
Right, Shohreh?
Without saying good-bye?
Her bag would be here...
My God...
Sepideh!
What's her number?
- Whose number?
- Elly's.
I want to call her cell.
What are you saying?
- Her bag...
- What?
It's not there.
She might have left.
No one has seen her in the sea.
I hid it to keep her.
If only I'd let her go...
My God...
Mom!
God damn you, Sepideh.
We should inform her family.
Let's wait and see
if the body's found.
Maybe she did leave.
Where to?
That's the end of it.
She's dead.
We should call them tomorrow.
Otherwise,
they'll drive up by night...
The road is one way.
Everyone's going back to Tehran.
It's just impossible.
Oh God!
Good grief!
Amir...
If she'd drowned,
the body would have been found.
Get up. Let's do something.
You did what you wanted.
Get up, come on.
What for?
Here. I'm up.
Let's go and ask at the bus station.
What can I say to you?
Give me a break...
You give me a break!
Maybe she did go away.
You were playing on the other side.
Listen, I'm talking to you.
I don't want you to talk to me!
You screw it up
and want to talk?
I'm also at the end of my rope.
Why did you invite her?
Right, it's my fault.
What now?
Nothing.
Did you ask me
before inviting her?
- I thought of Ahmad...
- Who are you to Ahmad?
Are you his mother?
His sister?
Who are you?
What's going on?
- What could she do about it?
- Nothing.
Nothing at all.
I asked her to invite her.
You shouldn't have!
Why always her?
You'll Wake the kids.
You should know
how crazy she is by now!
Who'd have thought
this would happen?
She's always involved in everything!
We want to go to the sea:
Sepideh!
We want to get together:
We need a villa:
Sepideh!
You need a plane ticket:
Now the man wants to get married:
Sepideh!
Let's go in.
We'll work this out.
What exactly?
We must call her parents.
We will.
But first, let's go in.
Whoever explains best what happened
will get a treat.
So, you start:
What were you doing?
I was fixing my kite.
And then?
Arash was in the water.
And where was Elly?
She was sitting there.
On the terrace.
What were you doing?
I asked her to fix my kite.
Then it flew off very high,
it fell in the water and I saw Arash.
When the kite was up in the sky,
was Elly with you?
Look at me. You were here.
Where was Elly?
Like Nazy is now?
Yes. She was there at first.
And then?
I ran after my kite on the other side
and there I saw Arash.
You saw Arash.
Stop it, Arash!
Anita. Did you see
Elly leave the villa?
- Look at me.
- I didn't see.
Morvarid, sweetie,
when your kite fell into the water
and you saw Arash about to drown
was Elly there
or was she leaving the villa?
- She was there.
- Ok.
And when you came over to us
as we were playing volleyball,
you know,
you were crying and calling us,
was Elly still there?
She was there before.
Long before?
A bit before.
How much is a bit?
Counting from 1...
1... 2... 3... 4...?
1... 2... 3...
I don't know.
What about you, Arash?
When you were in the water,
did Elly come get you out?
- Sit up and answer properly!
- I did a 100 times!
Sit up and answer.
- I'm hungry.
- Then go out!
Peyman!
Can't you just behave?
- He's hungry.
- I didn't see anything!
What's wrong with you?
He doesn't answer.
Since yesterday,
you've been mistreating him.
Ok, go away
and stop talking so much!
So he'll take all the blame?
You left him by the sea!
You should have thought of that
when you chose this villa.
Anita, come.
Any news?
Not since last night.
Why would she have left?
No idea.
She'd have taken her bag.
Didn't Sepideh hide it?
Sepideh,
was Elly the kind
to do such a thing?
Do what?
Leave without a word.
I don't know.
So, why did you hide her bag?
You must have supposed
this could happen.
Like the other evening,
she just vanished...
We had to look for her.
There was no signal.
She went to make a phone call.
Without a word.
- That was different.
- Why?
- Why would she've left?
- Out of pique.
What?
She might have been offended.
By what?
Did any of us say or do something
that might have offended her?
Dad, I'm hungry.
The other night,
when I was preparing the chicken,
you all came over.
The lady had brought the bedding
and she started clapping and singing.
And you ululated, Shohreh.
I had the impression
that Elly was offended.
Did I ululate?
That was in fun.
I just thought...
And during the dinner?
She went to get salt
and we all laughed.
No. It was just the two of us joking.
We all laughed.
But she did, too.
All this messing around
and dancing...
Maybe she disliked it.
She insisted on leaving yesterday,
as if she was upset.
I told you not to force her to stay.
She was standing right there.
You even joked
about her walking back
and she said she would.
Sepideh?
You know her.
Was she the kind to act on a whim?
Get offended and just leave?
Offended by what?
She doesn't even know her name.
Why are you asking her?
Amir, stop quibbling.
We're trying to move forward.
When we were washing up,
Sepideh, you said something,
and Shohreh said: "No need to work,
we already like you."
I think she took it badly.
I didn't mean anything nasty.
I know. I thought
she might have got it wrong.
Don't go blaming me for this, too.
Come on...
It'd be so childish
to leave for such a thing!
We're just talking.
Do you know how they've been
looking at my son since yesterday?
We're just hoping
she left because she was hurt.
Ahmad, that's not
what I'm talking about.
It doesn't make sense to leave
because you're hurt.
If she was a sensible person.
Really, if she's just left like this,
without a word, she's a...
Peyman...
The lady told us the place
wasn't safe. What if someone...
Why are you arguing?
Call Tehran
and you'll see if she's home.
Isn't it too early?
It's only 7:30.
I don't care.
This is driving me crazy.
Ahmad, let's go and call.
You stay here.
Ahmad, you go alone.
- Why?
- Stay here.
- Ahmad alone?
- You've done enough harm.
It's better if a woman calls.
Is Sepideh the only woman here?
I don't mind going.
But if ever she's not back...
I don't even dare think of it.
- Amir, let me...
- I said no!
Ahmad, let's go.
I'm going with you.
I'll take care of it.
Come on, Manuchehr.
Ahmad...
Sepideh, give me the number.
You want me to go with them?
No, Ahmad's gone.
Go and get breakfast for the kids.
They can go
one day without breakfast.
They won't starve.
The car keys.
Some weekend!
Keep on...
Don't accelerate!
The other tire is stuck, too.
Ahmad!
It's stuck deep.
Get out.
We won't make it.
If her mother answers,
don't say anything.
Why?
The other day, Elly told me
she'd had a heart operation.
We must be careful.
A stranger drowned
because of our son.
Do you realize that?
And all you care about
is talking back to me?
Don't talk to me like that.
I've told you a 100 times,
not to talk like that.
Like what?
Nothing else matters now?
How do I talk to you?
As you've always done.
I've been the same since we met,
and I'll still be the same fool
in 20 years!
I want to go back to Tehran.
- You can't.
- I want to go home.
Shohreh...
Don't Shohreh me.
I want to go back.
The sound of the sea
is driving me crazy.
My son wet the bed.
He's being mistreated.
I'm worse off than all of you.
I can't forget about this girl...
Sepideh, have you got painkillers?
There are some in my bag.
It was the mother again.
Don't hang up.
She's got heart problems...
Say you're one of her pupils' father
and you want to talk about the child.
So early in the morning?
With an out-of-town number?
Say you're her friend's husband.
Sepideh should be here.
You poor loves, what a honeymoon!
Thank you.
Honk at the dog.
Where are you going?
I was worried.
- Get in.
- Was she back home?
Get in.
What happened?
Did she have problems
with her family?
Why?
Her mother was quite cold.
So she wasn't there?
First, she said she'd gone out.
Thank God!
No, wait...
She didn't even acknowledge
that she'd been on a trip.
- What do you mean?
- She lied.
I said I'd call her on her cell
but she said she'd left it at home.
Didn't she have it with her?
She kept asking who I was.
Did her family know
she was here with us?
Didn't she call her mother
the other day?
Yes, but her mother...
Her mother...
seemed peculiar... wary.
Maybe because
we hung up a couple of times...
Why would she be suspicious
if she trusted her daughter?
How long have you known her?
Not long.
What happened?
No answer.
What a drag!
You should have tried again.
Ahmad...
We tried 10 times.
Sepideh...
Come here.
What is it?
Where's her cell?
Why?
We must inform someone she knows
and get this over with.
She must have taken it with her.
Where to?
I have no idea.
Why all the questions?
Come here!
- What's with you?
- What do you know about her?
What I know about her?
Whose is this?
It's hers, right?
- Where was that?
- In your bag.
Why was her cell in your bag?
I'd forgotten completely.
I found it by the window last night
and I put it away.
Don't lie to me!
What's wrong with you?
Leave me alone!
Leave me! You swine!
What the hell is wrong with you?
Why won't you speak?
You lying idiot!
Amir, shame on you!
Get away from her!
Don't interfere!
Don't you interfere, Shohreh.
Get in the car.
Shame on you!
Peyman, I'm going back to Tehran.
She drowned, she's dead.
Do you want to kill us, too?
I'm not staying here!
- What are you doing?
- She's lying.
I want to know
why this cell is in your bag!
What the hell?
You'd better not interfere!
Just shut your mouth!
Go away, Ahmad, go on.
Why does no one say anything here?
Stay if you want,
but I'm leaving!
Let's go, Sepideh.
Ahmad!
Go inside, please.
Morvarid, go in, darling...
Peyman...
She's driving me crazy!
The women and the kids
should go back to Tehran.
We'll stay and see what happens.
She got me to raise my hand to her.
I can't leave.
They all want to go home.
Let's go, Mom.
The poor kid's having a hard time.
You go ahead.
I have to stay.
Sepideh, it makes no difference
if you stay here.
I just can't, Peyman.
Nazy...
She hurt her leg.
Sepideh, look at me...
No, Ahmad.
Assuming this girl
did leave without a word,
is she worth the trouble
you're getting yourself in?
A girl you hardly know
anything about.
- Peyman...
- No, really?
Peyman.
If she went into the sea for Arash,
isn't she worth it?
How can you possibly know
if she went for my Arash?
Besides, I didn't ask her
to look after my child.
Leave her, if she wants to stay.
We're just talking, Peyman.
Why are you insisting?
Did I invite the woman?
Rent a villa by the sea?
Force her to stay?
That was all my doing.
So now, you can all go.
Get Elly's cell from Amir.
Amir...
Can I have Elly's cell?
Thanks.
How do you unlock it?
Call one of the numbers on the list.
What time did I go out with her
the other day?
Around eight, I think.
Her cell rang. She didn't answer
and said she'd call back.
Call that number
and tell whoever answers the story.
I think we should all stay.
Won't her family get suspicious
if they come and find 4 men here?
The mother was already suspicious.
But you said you didn't get through.
Wait a bit.
I'll try and call.
We'll see what happens.
So you did speak to her mother?
She didn't even know
her daughter was out of town.
Come on, Manuchehr.
- Where are the keys?
- On the ignition.
On the ignition.
What a weird girl!
How was her cell found?
It was in Sepideh's bag.
Nazy needed painkillers
and she found it there.
Wait, Ahmad.
Where are you going?
- Make a phone call.
- To whom?
A number on her call-list.
- I'll go with you.
- You know how Amir is...
I'm coming.
I'll call and come back.
Mom, I want to come, too.
Ahmad...
Drive on.
Shohreh entrusted the children to me.
Remember playing charades
the other night?
At some point, Elly said "Wreath".
It sounded like a premonition
of what was going to happen to her.
It was all written.
It was her fate, poor thing.
That's nobody's fault.
Manuchehr, I had a dream.
What dream?
A nightmare.
I can't stop thinking about it.
Shall we go back?
No. Let's drive on.
- She wasn't back home?
- No.
Who did you speak to?
- Her brother.
- Did you tell him?
I described her
and asked if he knew her.
I said I had his number from the cell
and asked if he'd heard from her.
He asked why I had her phone.
I asked him how well he knew her.
He said he was her brother.
But he wasn't home last night
and hadn't heard from her.
So I had to tell him.
- That she drowned?
- No, I couldn't say it.
I said we'd had a car accident
and she was in hospital.
He said she wasn't supposed to be
at the seaside.
She hadn't told her family.
That's why
she was so eager to go back.
What now?
Are they coming here?
Yes. He called me back.
He'll be at Chalus Square at 4.
How will we explain it to him?
We'll have to find a way.
One of the women must come along.
One woman must come with me.
What did he say?
One of the women
has to go with him.
Stop, Ahmad.
I feel sick.
You didn't eat anything.
Shall I get you something?
Shall I take Nazy along instead?
He's not her brother.
Who's not her brother?
The guy we're going to meet.
She was an only child.
I once asked about her siblings.
Who is he then?
I think he's her fiancé.
Whose fiancé?
Elly's.
What's that you're saying, Sepideh?
Was she engaged?
What on earth
have you done, Sepideh?
What have you done?
If you knew that,
why did you introduce her to me?
She's been trying to break off
the engagement for 6 months.
But he won't let her go.
Oh shit...
Oh shit!
I hid her cell
so that you wouldn't call him.
Isn't that him?
The guy with the bag.
I don't know.
Hello. How are you?
Have you arrived?
We're on the square.
Opposite a surgical clinic.
Imam Reza.
Imam Reza Clinic.
Where? A green Pride?
No, I can't see your car.
On the other side of the bridge?
On the ring road, right.
Yes, I see.
I'll be right there.
We're in a Patrol.
See you in a minute.
- Did he drive here?
- Yes.
- You'll go in his car.
- No.
There's no other way.
I have to go warn the others.
He mustn't find out
we know he's her fiancé.
I'll drive ahead.
You come with him.
- Amir mustn't find out.
- I know.
Hello.
Are you Alireza?
Ahmad. How are you?
Have you been here long?
Did your car hit her?
A friend of ours did.
Which hospital is she in?
- We'll take you there.
- How is she?
We shouldn't waste time.
Let's go.
Can you give me her cell?
It's not here.
- What happened exactly?
- I'll explain everything.
Ahmad, drive on!
I'll tell you.
Where are we going?
Just stay on the ring road.
If anything's happened, tell me.
They already told you.
Is she alive?
Yes, but her condition
isn't very good.
She's in a coma.
Oh, my God!
She wasn't supposed to come here.
When was the accident?
We'll talk while driving.
Stop tangling me up, please...
You saw her ID, didn't you?
What's her name?
Elly.
Is it the name written on her ID?
Elly is my daughter's teacher.
We didn't want to give you a shock.
She came up here with us and...
What are you doing?
And the story about the accident?
I'm sorry. We'll go in a second.
Can't you go bill and coo elsewhere?
I'm a total wreck now...
- I'm worse!
- Go ride a donkey!
- How about I ride you instead?
- Shut up!
Hello, Ahmad!
Hello!
Amir!
Peyman, Shohreh!
Where's Amir?
Come on, Nazy, quick.
Peyman, come here.
What's wrong, Ahmad?
Hurry up, Amir.
Come here.
Hurry up.
The guy is on his way.
Did you tell him?
He's not her brother at all.
He's her fiancé.
She has a fiancé?
My goodness!
What do you mean, fiancé?
I don't know. But he has to believe
we think he's her brother.
She comes here,
she goes out with you
and now she's got a fiancé?
Please, this is not the time.
How did you find out?
A friend of hers rang on the way.
I told her about the accident
and about her brother coming.
She said
Elly doesn't have a brother.
I asked who this man could be.
She said it had to be her fiancé.
If she's engaged,
why did she come here with us?
She didn't seem to be the kind...
Yes, she did. Only we...
are too naive.
Then maybe she didn't drown.
Maybe she just ran off.
If ever he finds out why we brought
his fiancee here,
he'll cause us trouble.
What do we do?
We'll pretend we don't have a clue.
He's the brother.
She's Morvarid's teacher.
The child insisted on
her coming along.
She agreed. That's it.
But please,
be careful not to goof up!
What if she really hasn't drowned?
I just don't know anymore...
Where's Sepideh?
She's with him.
Does she know everything?
Yes, I told her.
She's gently breaking it to him
that Elly drowned.
Look how a 20-year-old
gives us all the run-around!
The children have to be kept quiet.
Where are they?
Arash... Morvarid...
Children, sit down.
I have to tell you something.
Do you know why Elly
came with us?
To look after me
and keep me out of the sea.
- Bravo, that's it.
- No.
- Why then?
- Can I say it?
To fall in love with you.
With me?
Who told you that?
I saw it.
You're wrong.
All that was a joke.
You heard that, sweetie?
That's why she was sad
and went home.
No, she wasn't sad at all.
She wanted to save Arash
and she drowned.
Is she still in the water?
Now, listen. Both of you.
Elly's brother is coming now,
understand?
He's a very serious man
and he's very angry.
You have to make a promise.
Be very careful
not to tell him anything
about our kidding around...
- What kidding?
- What Arash just said.
We played and danced and laughed...
We played charades.
Right. You say nothing.
Even if he asks,
you say you don't know.
- We don't know.
- Very good.
Will you tell Anita, too?
Good.
Has she told him?
Don't go out.
Let's wait for Sepideh.
Please, come in.
No, thanks.
Where did she fall into the water?
Over there.
- Let's go inside.
- Leave me alone for 5 minutes.
What a quiet kid.
She must have paid
for the harm she did him.
Otherwise,
it wouldn't have happened.
Here he is.
Do you want a sedative?
No. Where's the bathroom?
That way.
- Thanks.
- You're welcome.
Has he told her parents?
Not yet.
Hadn't she told you about him?
Amir...
Shohreh, a towel, please.
No, thanks.
Is there a room where I can...
This room is cleaner.
Go ahead, please.
Can you bring a clean cloth?
There's no signal here.
But we were talking the other night
and we got cut off.
That must have been
when she went out.
Excuse me...
just a moment.
Didn't she tell you
anything about me?
Yes, she did.
About you, her parents...
What did she say?
That she missed you.
She praised you a lot.
She was worried about her mother.
I think her mother... your mother
has a heart problem, right?
Nazy...
- Excuse me.
- Come here.
He's not her brother.
Why did you say she missed him?
And she praised him?
I got nervous.
Didn't he get suspicious?
No... I don't know.
- You've not eaten...
- No, thanks.
I have to call Tehran.
I'll take you
somewhere you can call from.
Leave the bedding I brought
for the newlyweds, I'll pick it up.
Thanks.
Her poor husband was here earlier,
I didn't want to bother him.
- Whose husband?
- The drowned bride's.
Her husband was here earlier?
Madam, would you come here
for a second?
Peyman!
He found out!
The old woman came over.
She said the bedding
was for Elly and her husband.
Shit!
Where is he?
I left.
I guess he's coming.
Let's think of something.
Like what? It's over.
- Let's tell the truth.
- That we were hooking up his wife?
We didn't know
she was engaged.
It's true. We didn't know.
The best thing to do
is to tell the truth.
What can we say?
That we didn't know
she was engaged.
Otherwise, we wouldn't have
introduced her to Ahmad.
Don't mention Ahmad.
Why else would she be here?
We'll have to tell the police, anyway.
Does he know
she was here for Ahmad?
He's no child.
He'll have guessed it all.
He must have got suspicious
even before coming here.
Why else would he say
he's her brother?
- Let's tell him.
- No, please.
So what, Sepideh?
Shall we lie to him?
We can't.
He already knows it all.
We have no other choice, Sepideh.
- He'll find out.
- Elly will be disgraced.
Because of us?
She's dead now.
She came for a husband
while being engaged.
Which means:
1, she screwed all of us
2, she cheated on this poor guy.
Cheated?
What else?
Imagine you have a fiance
who finds someone better than you,
and they travel,
play volleyball...
What's wrong with that?
Don't you realize?
To you and me,
it seems perfectly right.
But from where he stands,
it seems all wrong.
From the alms she gave
to the cleaning she did here...
That was all a show to impress us.
Whatever.
What do we do now?
How could she dump
such a nice guy?
I felt so ashamed when I saw him.
The ululation the other night...
Hurry up now.
Ahmad, tell him we thought
she was single.
She had lied to us.
- We'll tell the truth.
- Please, don't.
Should we fool him
to save Elly's honor?
Does honor mean much
to the dead?
- I won't have it.
- Too late.
- Ahmad, don't let them...
- Peyman, come.
I knew.
She had told me.
I swear I'm not lying this time.
I swear on Morvarid's life.
I told Ahmad he wasn't her brother
but her fiance.
Ahmad, why don't you say anything?
We have no other choice.
I told her at the school
that a good friend of ours
visiting from Germany
had asked me to find him a wife.
She said she didn't want
to get married.
She'd been engaged for 2 years
and was trying to split up.
She didn't love him anymore
and he annoyed her.
Her family was also against him,
but he wouldn't let her be.
I suggested she meet my friend
who wasn't staying long.
She said she wouldn't
until the engagement was broken.
I sent her photo to Ahmad.
You liked her, didn't you?
I carried on calling Elly
and insisting.
And what did she say...?
That she was determined to split up.
I said, once Ahmad left,
he wouldn't be back for a while.
It would be a pity
not to meet him once.
She kept saying no.
Finally, she agreed
to come with us secretly
for a single night.
She told me.
You may have insisted.
But did she have to come?
I begged her.
I said I had already planned it all.
My God!
Let's at least save her honor.
If we say we forced her to come
although we knew she was engaged,
will he believe us?
No way!
What difference
does it make anyway?
What she did was wrong.
She shouldn't have come.
She couldn't say no to me.
That's no reason.
Tell him the truth.
Say you knew nothing.
I'll say I knew.
This mess is my fault.
Come what may.
Are you nuts?
They'll kill you!
Too bad.
He sees us as a whole.
In his eyes, we're all accomplices.
I don't need any more complications.
Sepideh, be reasonable, for once.
This isn't about just you or me.
We must stick together.
Ahmad,
what do you think?
We tell him.
Let's tell the truth.
Let's tell him.
And you, Manuchehr?
We really didn't know
she was engaged.
We found out too late.
And you, Shohreh?
I can't bring myself
to lie to this poor boy.
And you, Nazy?
Whatever the majority says.
The majority seems to choose
the truth.
We didn't know.
I did.
You're the only one
and you're telling us just now!
Here he is.
Let's go all together.
Peyman, watch out.
Where are the kids? Arash?
Stay here, Sepideh.
Come, Nazy.
Please, don't make it
worse than it is...
What will he think of Elly?
Arash, Anita,
Morvarid, come here.
Ahmad!
Let me see, Ahmad!
Bastard!
Raise your head.
You're bleeding.
Bring a Koran here,
so that I can swear
we didn't lie to you.
I swear on my children!
Come on,
why should we lie to you?
We came here
with our wives and kids.
Why would we bring an engaged girl
to introduce her to our friend?
Are we crazy?
If we'd had the slightest doubt,
we'd never...
What's this argument all about?
- Let's sit down.
- You shut up!
Shut your mouth!
- Stop it!
- Go inside, Ahmad!
What the hell?
We've been going through hell
for 2 days!
We haven't eaten a thing!
And you...
I'm not asking anything.
Just tell me the truth.
I offered to call the police
so you could see the report.
I don't care about the police.
We may lie to you
but we can't lie to the police.
Forget the police!
It has to be done legally!
- Was I talking to you?
- One moment.
Come here, Shohreh.
Who invited Elly here?
My wife.
- They see each other at school.
- Where is she?
Inside.
I want to speak to her.
Sepideh is feeling very bad.
Worse than me?
She's asleep.
We've told you everything.
There's a question
I want to ask her.
Let's go to the police.
We'll go.
- I want to ask her...
- She's just fallen asleep.
Don't worry. I won't feel any worse
than I already do.
Where is she?
Madam!
Wait here.
I'll get her.
Shohreh, call Sepideh.
I want to talk to her alone.
Shohreh!
He's not a guy
you can say everything to.
He bashed up Ahmad's nose.
I'm not against you.
I beg you, Sepideh,
get up.
Go and wash your face
so I can bring him in.
Get up, dear.
Did you ask her to come along?
Yes, I did.
May I sit down?
When you asked her
to meet your friend,
didn't she say anything?
Can I first say something?
- Elly...
- Listen...
I just want to know one thing...
Sit down.
Yes or no?
- When you told her...
- But...
...didn't she say no?
Didn't she say she had someone,
a fiance?
Did she or didn't she?
She really...
Listen, this is very important to me.
I dedicated
3 years of my life to her.
Could you please sit down, too?
Didn't she refuse?
Did she or didn't she?
No, she didn't.
Alireza,
the police called.
It seems that earlier today
they found the body of a woman
in the sea.
We must go and identify her.
They've called on the landline.
Amir!
Take Elly's bag.
Please...
Wait. We'll go with you.
Don't be afraid.
Is this her?
My condolences.
Give me my car keys.
Can you call the family
and inform them?
You call them.
Wouldn't it be better if you did?
Music: "Song for Eli"
Composed & performed
by Andrea Bauer
Adaptation: Massoumeh Lahidji
Subtitling TITRA FILM Paris