[Laughs to himself]
♪ ECHO & THE BUNNYMEN: The Killing Moon
♪ Under blue moon I saw you
♪ So soon you'll take me
♪ Up in your arms too late to beg you
♪ Or cancel it though I know it must be
♪ The killing time
♪ Unwillingly mine
♪ Fate
♪ Up against your will
♪ Through the thick and thin
♪ He will wait until
♪ You give yourself to him
♪ In starlit nights I saw you
♪ So cruelly you kissed me
♪ Your lips a magic world
♪ Your sky all hung with jewels
♪ The killing moon
♪ Will come too soon
♪ Fate
♪ Up against your will
♪ Through the thick and thin
♪ He will wait until...
I'm voting for Dukakis.
Hmm.
Well.
Maybe when you have children
of your own who need braces,
and you can't afford them
because half your husband's pay
goes to the federal government,
- you'll regret that.
- My husband's pay?
[Laughs]
I'm not gonna squeeze one out till I'm, like, 30.
Will you still be working at the Yarn
Barn? Great place to raise kids!
That's really funny.
A year of partying's enough.
She's going to Harvard next fall.
Mom, I haven't gotten in yet.
You think Dukakis will provide for
this country till you squeeze one out?
Yeah. I do.
- Can I squeeze one out?
- Not till eighth grade.
Excuse me.
Donnie, you're such a click.
Whoa, Elizabeth.
A little hostile there.
Mom and Dad should pay a therapist
$200 an hour to listen to you
so we don't have to.
OK. Wanna tell Mom and Dad
why you stopped your medication?
- You're such a fuck-ass.
- What?!
- Please.
- Did he call me a fuck-ass?
- Hey.
- That's enough.
- Go suck a fuck.
- How does one do that?
- Want to know?
- Yes.
We will not have this at the table.
[Mom] Stop!
[Elizabeth stifles a laugh]
- What's a fuck-ass?
- [Dad laughs]
[knock at door]
[softly] Hi.
I'm reading. Get out.
Where do you go at night?
Will you get out of my room?
Did you toilet-paper the Johnsons'?
- You came to ask me that?
- No.
I stopped rolling houses in sixth grade.
What happened to my son?
I don't recognise this person.
You start taking the goddamn pills!
[Door slams]
Bitch.
Our son just called me a bitch.
You're not a bitch.
You're bitching, but you're not a bitch.
[Sighs]
I want to be a president who makes sure
we never again do business
with a Panamanian dictator.
- That we never again funnel aid...
- Dukakis.
- Son of a bitch.
- Panama is friendly.
- I talked to Panama's president...
- Tell him, George!
...about cleaning up their money-laundering.
Mr. Noriega was there, but there was no evidence...
[clock chimes]
[ghostly voice] Wake up.
I've been watching you.
Come closer.
Closer.
28 days,
six hours,
42 minutes,
12 seconds.
That is when the world will end.
Why?
[Buzzing]
[car drives off]
[sighs]
[rumbling and crashing]
[glass shatters]
[alarm]
[panting]
Son?
Son? Donnie Darko?
Donnie Darko?
- What's going on?
- Who is it?
It's Eddie Darko's kid.
I'm sorry about this. He's a local kid.
- Guess he was sleep-golfing.
- [Both laugh]
Watch out for that drool spot.
Are you all right, son?
Let's stay off the links at night, OK?
I'm sorry, Dr. Fisher. It won't happen again.
- I hate kids.
- Let's golf.
[Sirens]
[girl] Donnie! Donnie! Donnie!
What happened to your house?
- No-one's allowed through...
- This is my house!
He's OK.
[Girl] Donnie, we know you're OK!
[Reporter] Channel 6 News.
We have just arrived on the scene...
Wait a minute. Here's your brother.
- Oh!
- It fell in your room.
Watch yourself down there!
Mrs. Darko? I'm Bob Garland. I'm with the FAA.
- You're what?
- I'm with the FAA.
We'd like to speak
to you and Mr. Darko privately.
- In private?
- Please.
All right.
And... here.
- You got it.
- OK.
We have arranged for you
to stay at a hotel, get some sleep.
- We will take care of things here.
- Thank you.
[Dad] Kids, we're going to a hotel.
They don't know where it came from.
[TV announcer] Transportation
authorities have begun a search...
Frankie Feeder.
...no airline will claim...
You remember him?
From high school.
Hmm.
He died.
- On his way to the prom.
- Mm.
- Remember?
- Mm-hm.
They said he was doomed.
Mm.
Jesus.
They could have said the same thing about Donnie.
[TV news continues]
If it fell from a plane,
then what happened to the plane?
They don't know, Samantha.
Mrs. Farmer will bring you home after practice.
Bye, honey.
Donnie. Good luck.
Oh, my God. Tell me everything.
- I'm not allowed to.
- Oh, my God.
- Hi, Cherita.
- Shut up.
Darko cheats death, uh?
You're like a celebrity, man.
I kept calling you. Where you been?
We stayed at a hotel.
My dad saw you at the golf course.
You sleepwalking again?
- I don't wanna talk about it.
- Now you're famous, have a smoke.
What happens if you tell Mom and Dad?
You'll put Ariel in the garbage disposal.
- Goddamn right I will.
- So grotty.
Hey, Cherita. You want a cigarette?
- Shut up!
Go back to China, bitch.
Just leave her alone.
Some good shit, huh?
It's a fucking cigarette.
♪ TEARS FOR FEARS: Head Over Heels
♪ I wanted to be with you alone
♪ And talk about the weather
♪ But traditions I can trace against the child in your face
♪ Won't escape my attention
♪ You keep your distance with a system of touch
♪ And gentle persuasion
♪ With one foot in the past now just how long will it last?
♪ No, no, no, have you no ambition?
♪ You keep your distance with a system of touch
♪ And gentle persuasion
♪ I'm lost in admiration, could I need you this much?
♪ Oh, you're wasting my time
♪ You're just just just wasting time
♪ Something happens and I'm head over heels
♪ I never find out till I'm head over heels
♪ Ah, don't take my heart don't break my heart
♪ Don't don't don't throw it away
♪ In my mind's eye
♪ One little boy, one little man
♪ Funny how
♪ Time
♪ Flies...
"There would be headlines in the papers."
"Even the guys who ran the betting at the wrestling
and the barrow boys would hear with respect
how Old Misery's house had been destroyed."
"It was as though this plan
had been with him all his life,
pondered through the seasons,
now in his 15th year crystallised
with the pain of puberty."
What is Graham Greene trying
to communicate with this passage?
Why did the children break into Old Misery's house?
- Joanie?
- They wanted to rob him.
Joanie, if you had actually read the story,
which at 13 pages would have taken you all night,
you would know the children find a
great deal of money in the mattress.
But they burn it.
Donnie Darko,
perhaps with your recent brush with mass destruction
you can give us your opinion.
Well, they say when they flood
the house and tear it to shreds
that destruction is a form of creation,
so the fact that they burn the money is ironic.
They just want to see what happens
when they tear the world apart.
They wanna change things.
[Door opens]
May we help you?
I just registered. They put me
in the wrong English class.
You look like you belong here.
Um, where do I sit?
Next to the boy you think is the cutest.
- [Excited voices]
- Quiet. Let her choose.
Joanie, get up.
The construction guys
say it'll take a week to fix the roof.
That airline better not fuck us
on the shingle match.
- They still don't know?
- Know what?
Where it came from.
No. Apparently they can't tell us what happened yet.
Something about a matching
serial number that got burned.
I had to sign a form saying
I wouldn't talk to anyone about it.
We're not supposed to tell anyone
what nobody knows?
Yeah.
But you tell...
What's your doctor's name?
- Dr. Thurman, Dad.
- Yes.
You tell Dr. Thurman whatever you want.
- Dad.
- What?
Dad!
[Dog barking]
No mail today. Maybe tomorrow.
[Whispers]
Well, what did she say to you?
- I made a new friend.
- Real or imaginary?
Imaginary...
Would you like to talk about him?
- Frank.
- What did Frank say?
- To follow him.
- Where?
- Into the future.
And then what happens?
And then he said...
Then he said the world was coming to an end.
Do you think it is?
No.
That's stupid.
[TV] For my entire life I was a victim of fear.
Love.
I was feeding fear through food.
Fear.
Finally I looked in the mirror.
Not just in the mirror. I looked through the mirror.
In that image I saw my ego reflection.
I thought ten-year-olds normally wet the bed.
- [Snorts]
- Shh!
The solution was there all the time.
I'm not afraid any more!
All over America, people have
come together to join hands.
People who believe that human life
is absolutely too important,
too valuable and too precious
to be controlled by fear.
Hello.
My name is Jim Cunningham.
Welcome to Controlling Fear.
[Frank] Wake up, Donnie.
"And the prince was led into a world
of strange and beautiful magic."
Hey, guess what!
I can't believe it!
The school is closed today because it's flooded.
- No way.
- Yes.
Holy shit! That's the best news I've ever heard.
My God. Is this ever gonna stop?
Eventually, yes. But I've got
12 classrooms full of water,
all coming from a busted water main.
- What else?
- What else?!
Principal Cole, I'll show you what else.
- Unbelievable.
- That's solid bronze, isn't it?
How did this happen?
The boys' locker room was flooded.
They found faeces everywhere.
- What are faeces?
- Baby mice.
Hey.
Has anyone ever told you that you're sexy?
- I like your boobs.
- [Boys laugh]
Hey.
School's cancelled.
Do you want to walk me home?
Sure.
- Don't look so freaked.
- I'm not.
Check your backpack.
Those guys love to steal shit.
- Why did you move here?
- My parents got a divorce.
My mom got a restraining order against my stepdad.
- He has emotional problems.
- Me too. What kind does he have?
He stabbed my mom four times in the chest.
Oh. Did he go to jail?
No, he fled. They still can't find him.
Mom and I had to change our names.
I thought Gretchen Ross was cool.
I was in jail once.
I accidentally burned down this house.
It was abandoned, but still...
I got held back in school,
I can't drive till I'm 21.
But I'm over all of that. I...
I'm painting and stuff. Writing.
I want to be a writer. Maybe a painter.
Maybe both.
I'll write a book and draw the pictures.
Then maybe people will
understand me. Change things.
Donnie Darko?
What the hell kind of name is that?
It's like some sort of superhero.
What makes you think I'm not?
Look, I should go.
Monnitoff wants me to write this physics essay.
Greatest invention ever to benefit mankind.
If it's Monnitoff, that's easy. Antiseptics.
The whole sanitation thing.
Joseph Lister, 1895.
Before antiseptics there was no sanitation.
- Especially in medicine.
- You mean soap?
I'm really glad school was flooded today.
Why's that?
You and I would never have had this conversation.
You're weird.
Sorry.
No, that was a compliment.
Well, look, um...
You wanna go with me?
[Laughs nervously]
Where do you wanna go?
I mean, like, go with me. You know...
That's what we call it here.
- Going together...
- Sure.
OK. Where are you going?
I'm going home.
So stupid!
I'd like to try something new this time.
Have you ever been hypnotised?
No.
When I clap my hands twice, you
will wake up. Do you understand?
Yes.
So, tell me about your week.
I met a girl.
- What is her name?
- Gretchen.
We're going together now.
Do you still think about girls a lot?
Yeah.
How are things going at school?
I think about girls a lot.
I asked you about school, Donnie.
I think about fucking a lot during school.
What else do you think about during school?
- Married With Children.
- Do you think about your family?
I turn down the volume and think
about fucking Christina Applegate.
I asked you about your family, Donnie.
No. [Laughs]
I don't think about fucking my family.
That's gross.
I'd like to hear about your friend Frank.
Sam Bylen.
[Clears throat]
Donald Darko.
Daye Dennis.
Hey, you fuck.
Did you tell them I flooded the school?
- I didn't say shit.
- They think I did it.
If you're innocent, you have nothing to worry about.
Fuck you! Know what I think?
I think you did it.
[Coughs]
Beer and pussy. That's all I need.
We gotta find ourselves a Smurfette.
- Smurfette?
- Mm-hm.
Not some tight-assed Middlesex chick.
A cute little blonde that'll get
down and dirty with the guys.
- Like Smurfette does.
- Smurfette doesn't fuck.
Smurfette fucks the other smurfs.
Why did Papa Smurf make her?
Because all the other smurfs were getting too horny.
Not Vanity. I heard he was a homosexual.
OK, she fucks them while Vanity watches. OK?
What about Papa Smurf?
He must get in on the action.
He does. He films the gangbang.
Later on he beats off to the tape.
First of all, Papa Smurf didn't create
Smurfette. Gargamel did.
She was sent in as Gargamel's spy,
to destroy the smurf village.
But the overwhelming goodness
of smurf life transformed her.
And as for the whole gangbang scenario,
it just couldn't happen.
Smurfs are asexual.
They don't even have...
reproductive organs under those little white pants.
That's what's so illogical about being a smurf.
What's the point of living
if you don't have a click?
Dammit, Donnie, why you gotta get
so smart on us?
- [Car horn]
- Grandma Death.
Excuse me! Excuse me!
Stay off the road, Miss Sparrow.
I'll have to call social services.
I hate that Miss Farmer.
She's such a fucking bitch.
Yeah.
- How old is Grandma Death?
- 101.
She does the same thing every day.
Just walks back and forth,
back and forth to the mailbox.
And nothing ever in there.
Oh, wait, wait, wait.
She's going back to the box.
We may still have mail.
- Mail, mail.
- Here it is.
This could be it. Oh!
No dice, Grandma. Sorry.
Someone ought to write that bitch.
[TV announcer] Authorities continued their search
for a suspect in the school vandalism.
The school has asked for donations
to help restore its mascot,
known only as the Mongrel.
In cooperation with the county police,
we have begun investigating
the cause of the flooding
and our suspects include
several of our own students.
I want to know why this filth
is being taught to our children.
[Breathing heavily]
Kitty, I would appreciate
if you would wait...
Dr. Cole, not only am I a teacher,
but I am also a parent of a Middlesex child.
I am the only person here who
transcends the parent-teacher bridge.
[Frank] Don't worry.
You got away with it.
I have in my hand Graham Greene's The Destructors.
This short story is part of
my daughter's English assignment.
In this story, several children
destroy an elderly man's house
from inside out.
How can you do that?
[Laughs nervously]
And how do they do this?
They flood the house
by breaking through a water main.
[Frank] I can do anything I want.
And so can you.
We pay good money for this school.
It's our children.
I think this garbage should be removed.
Excuse me.
What's the real issue?
The PTA doesn't ban books.
The PTA is here to acknowledge
that pornography is being taught.
- It's meant to be ironic.
- You need to go back to grad school.
Why did you make me flood the school?
They are in great danger.
Kitty, do you even know who Graham Greene is?
I think we have all seen Bonanza.
Well, uh... while we are on other topics...
Where did you come from?
Do you believe in time travel?
[Samantha] Who are you talking to?
I was just taking my pills, Sam.
[TV] It is time to breathe.
Thank you, Jim Cunningham.
Now let us begin lifeline exercise NO.1.
Please press stop now.
As you can see, the lifeline is divided
into two polar extremes.
Fear and love.
Fear is in the negative energy spectrum
and love is in the positive energy spectrum.
- Duh!
- Excuse me?
"Duh" is a product of fear.
Now, on each card is a character dilemma
which applies to the lifeline.
Please... Take this.
Thank you.
Please read each character dilemma aloud
and place an X on the lifeline
in the appropriate place.
Cherita?
"Juanita has an important math test today."
"She has known about the test for
several weeks but has not studied."
"In order to keep from failing her test,
Juanita decides that she will cheat
on the math test."
Good. Good. Very good.
Um, Mr. Darko.
"Ling Ling finds a wallet filled with money."
"She takes the wallet to the address
inside but keeps the money."
[Sighs] I'm sorry, Miss Farmer.
I don't get this.
Place an X in the appropriate place.
No, I know what to do. I don't get this.
You can't lump things into two categories.
The lifeline is divided that way.
Life isn't that simple.
Who cares if Ling Ling returns
the wallet and keeps the money?
It has nothing to do with fear or love.
Fear and love are the deepest human emotions.
OK. But you're not listening to me.
Other things need to be taken into account.
Like the whole spectrum of human emotion.
You can't lump everything into two
categories and deny everything else.
If you don't complete the assignment,
you'll get a zero for the day.
Donald.
Let me preface this by saying that your Iowa Test scores
are... intimidating.
So... let's go over this again.
What exactly did you say to Mrs. Farmer?
I'll tell you what he said.
He asked me to forcibly insert
the exercise card into my anus.
[Laughs then coughs]
[woman] These are modern times.
My political attitudes are forthright.
If there's a vice presidential candidate
worthy of my vote, it's Dan Quayle.
Nobody cares about responsibility,
morality, family values...
Kitty...
Excuse us, please.
He's suspended from after-school
activities for six months.
Ever since this jet engine fiasco
I don't know what's gotten into him.
Rose, our daughters have been on
the dance team together for two years
and I respect you as a woman.
But after witnessing your son's
behaviour, I have doubts about your...
Our paths through life must be righteous.
I urge you to go home and look in the mirror,
and pray that your son
doesn't succumb to the path of fear.
[Elizabeth] Do you remember
that weird gym teacher Mrs. Farmer?
Yeah.
My brother told her to shove a book
up her ass today.
And then my parents just bought him
all this new shit.
I know. I wish a jet engine would fall in my room.
[Frank] I can show you the way.
[Bells chime]
Yeah.
[Boys laugh]
- Dr. Monnitoff?
- Donnie.
Um, I know this is gonna sound kinda weird, but uh...
do you know anything about time travel?
Ah! A wormhole with an Einstein-Rosen bridge,
which is theoretically a wormhole
in space controlled by man.
So, according to Hawking,
a wormhole may be able to provide a short cut
for jumping between
two distant regions of space time.
So to travel back in time,
you have to have a spaceship
that can travel faster than light.
- Theoretically.
- And be able to find a wormhole.
The principles of time travel are there.
You've got a vessel, a portal.
The vessel can be anything.
Probably a spacecraft.
- Like a DeLorean.
- Any metal craft.
I love that movie, the way they shot it.
It's so futuristic, you know.
Listen... don't tell anybody I gave you this.
The woman who wrote this used to teach here.
She was a nun many years before that.
Then overnight she became
this entirely different person.
She up and left the church, she wrote this book.
She started teaching science.
Right here in Middlesex.
The Philosophy Of Time Travel.
Roberta Sparrow?
That's right.
[Laughs] Come on.
Roberta Sparrow.
Roberta Sparrow...
Grandma Death.
It's called The Philosophy Of Time Travel.
What does philosophy have to do with time travel?
- Let me see.
- Guess who wrote it.
Roberta Sparrow?
Huh! She wrote a book!
Grandma Death wrote a book.
That's a terrible nickname.
We almost hit her with the car.
She lives in that piece of crap house
and you know she's loaded.
- She's...
- You're right.
She used to be known for her gem collection.
Kids... used to go up there
and try to steal stuff from her.
She became a total recluse.
I didn't know she was alive
till we damn near knocked her down.
[Donny] She was standing in the road, frozen,
so I got out of the car and
walked over to see if she was OK.
She leaned over and whispered in my ear.
- What did she say?
- Frank wants me to talk to her.
He asked me if I knew about time travel.
She wrote a book about it,
so it can't be a coincidence.
What did Roberta Sparrow say to you?
She said every creature on earth dies alone.
How did that make you feel?
It reminded me of my dog Callie.
She died when I was eight.
She crawled underneath the porch.
To die?
To be alone.
Do you feel alone right now?
I...
I'd like to believe I'm not, but I just...
I've just never seen any proof, so I...
I just don't debate it any more.
I could spend my whole life debating it over and over
and I still wouldn't have any proof,
so I just... I just don't debate it any more.
[Laughs] It's absurd.
The search for God is absurd?
It is if everyone dies alone.
Does that scare you?
I don't want to be alone.
His tapes have made me realise
that for the last 39 years I have been
a prisoner of my own fear.
- Fear?
- [Sighs]
Rose, you have got to meet this Jim Cunningham.
I can't believe he's single.
[TV] It has been a disappointing night
for these Super Bowl champions.
Coach Joe Gibbs is on the sidelines,
water dripping off his glasses.
He'll be thinking, "What went wrong tonight?"
- Here's the kick.
- [Men groan]
And it's no good.
We need a quarterback. And a miracle.
We need to go for a safety.
Mark Rypien has some big shoes to fill.
He sure does.
You guys want anything?
I'm gonna get a beer.
[TV commentary continues]
[TV announcer] Good evening, ladies and ghouls.
Join us at the Middlesex pavilion hall
for the Middlesex Halloween Haunt.
[Ghoulish laughter]
[laughs]
[aeroplane]
What if you could go back in time
and take all the pain and darkness
and replace it with something better?
- Images?
- Yeah. Like a Hawaiian sunset
or the Grand Canyon. Things
that remind you how beautiful...
You know, we've been going together for two weeks.
Yeah.
Well, I uh...
Do you wanna kiss me?
Uh...
- I... Sorry...
- Donnie, wait. I just...
I just want it to be at a time when it...
- When what?
- When it reminds me of...
When it reminds you how beautiful the world can be?
Yeah.
And right now there's some fat guy staring at us.
Thank you for seeing us at such late notice.
We both felt it was time to come in and discuss...
What I think is going on with your son?
Yes.
Um... Well, he's uh...
You know about his past,
and he was suspended from school
for insulting his gym teacher.
I'm not sure that's a good example.
He had just cause to insult...
Rose, let me just lay out
what I believe is happening here.
Donnie's aggressive behaviour...
his increased detachment from reality...
seem to stem from his inability to cope
with the forces in the world
that he perceives to be threatening.
Has he ever told you about his friend Frank?
Frank?
The giant bunny rabbit.
What?
I don't recall him ever having mentioned a rabbit.
Donnie is experiencing what is called
a daylight hallucination.
This is a common occurrence
among paranoid schizophrenics.
What can we do?
I would like to do more hypnotherapy.
And increase his medication.
[Thunderclap]
Whatever will help him, really,
because that's why we're here.
We just would like him to experience some... relief.
So if you think that more medication will do that,
then I think we should give it a try.
[Bells chime]
Donnie Darko.
I know.
[Both laugh]
[music and applause]
- Good morning, you Mongrels.
- Good morning.
Is that all the gusto you can muster?
Good morning!
Good morning.
Now, that's a tiny bit better.
But I can sense some students
who are afraid to say good morning.
[Students] Good morning!
That's what I like to hear!
Entirely too many
young men and women today
are completely paralysed by their fears.
They surrender their bodies
to the temptation and destruction
of drugs, alcohol and premarital sex.
Now, I'm gonna tell you a little story today.
It's a heartbreakingly sad story
about a young man
whose life was completely destroyed
by these instruments of fear.
A young man searching for love
in all the wrong places.
His name was Frank.
Um, my stepsister...
I sometimes worry that she eats too much.
- Shut up, Kim.
- Sweetheart, please.
- What can I do when I grow up?
- That's a hard one.
How do I learn how to fight?
"How do I learn how to fight?"
Son, violence is a product of fear.
- Learn to truly love yourself.
- OK.
- Get up here.
All right.
- Good morning.
- [Jim] Good morning.
Um, how much are they paying you
to be here?
Excuse me?
What is your name, son?
Gerald.
Gerald, I think you're afraid.
Are you telling us this so we buy your
book? It's the worst advice I heard.
You see how sad this is?
Want your sister to lose weight? Tell
her to get off the couch and exercise.
No-one knows what to do when they grow up.
It takes a while to find that out. Right, Jim?
And you.
Yeah, you.
You sick of some jerk picking on you?
Maybe you should lift weights or do karate.
Next time he tries, kick him in the balls.
[Gasps]
[Jim laughs] Son.
Do you see this?
This is an anger prisoner.
A textbook example.
See the fear, people?
This boy is scared of the truth.
Son, it breaks my heart to say this,
but I believe you are a very troubled
and confused young man.
You were searching for the answers
in the wrong places.
You're right, actually. I am pretty
troubled and pretty confused.
And I'm afraid. Really afraid. Really afraid.
But I think you're the fucking Antichrist.
[Shocked gasps]
Get him out of here!
Who do you think you are?
[Whistling and cheering]
It's amazing.
The man thinks he's telling the truth.
Everything he says is a fucking lie.
Everything he says.
Everyone thinks he's so rad.
He's such a chud.
- Everything...
- Are you OK?
- Yeah...
- Sit down. Calm down.
You ever hear of Grandma Death?
Who?
The Philosophy Of Time Travel.
What is this?
She wrote it.
I'm...
I've been seeing stuff.
Like a lot of really messed-up stuff.
Chapters in there describe what
I've seen. It can't be a coincidence.
[Monnitoft] Each vessel travels
along a vector through space time,
along its centre of gravity.
Like a spear?
- Pardon?
- A spear coming out of your chest.
Um... sure, yeah.
For the vessel to travel through time,
it's got to find a portal, in this case a wormhole...
Could these portals just appear
anywhere, any time?
I think that's highly unlikely.
What you're talking about is an act of God.
If God controls time, time's pre-decided.
- I don't follow.
- Every living thing has a set path.
And if you could see your path or channel,
you could see into the future.
Like... a form of time travel.
You're contradicting yourself, Donnie.
If we were able to see our destinies
manifest themselves visually,
then we would be given a choice
to betray our chosen destinies.
The fact that this choice exists
would make all pre-formed destiny come to an end.
Not if you travel in God's channel.
Um... I'm not going to be able
to continue this conversation.
- Why?
- I could lose my job.
OK.
[Birdsong]
[laughs]
Now you know where he lives.
And they grow out of our chest...
solar plexus?
Like she described in the book.
The way they moved and smelled...
Like they're workers.
Assigned to each one of us.
They just... They're like liquid.
I followed it... into my parents' bedroom.
What did you find?
Nothing.
So we call them IMGs.
Infant Memory Generators.
So you buy the glasses for an infant
and they wear them when they sleep.
But inside the glasses are these slide photographs,
and each one is of something peaceful or beautiful,
whatever the parents want to put inside.
What effect would this have on an infant?
Well, nobody remembers their infancy.
Anyone who says they do is lying.
We think this'll develop memory earlier in life.
Yeah.
Did you consider that darkness is part
of infants' natural development?
No.
Yeah.
What if the parents put in pictures of Satan?
Dead people, crap like that.
Is that what you'd show your kids?
Uh, well, I mean... didn't your dad stab your mom?
Ha ha ha ha!
Get out.
Gretchen!
Gretchen. Gretchen.
I'm sorry about those guys.
- Two for Evil Dead, please.
- Two dollars.
[Slow, heavy banging]
Why do you wear that stupid bunny suit?
Why are you wearing that stupid man's suit?
Take it off.
What happened to your eye?
I'm so sorry.
Why do they call you Frank?
It's the name of my father...
and his father before me.
Frank?
When's this gonna stop?
You should already know that.
[Laughs nervously]
Watch the movie screen.
There's something I want to show you.
Have you ever seen a portal?
[Clock chimes]
Burn it to the ground.
♪ Woman singing wordless aria
OK. Now, girls, I want you to concentrate.
Failure is not an option.
Bethany, if you feel the need to vomit up there,
- just swallow it.
- OK.
Hey, you guys. Be lucky out there.
[Whistle]
Get off the stage, Cherita!
[Cheering and whistling]
[boy] You suck!
Hold on.
That was really something.
Thank you, Cherita Chen, with Autumn Angel.
Now the moment we've all been waiting for.
It is my distinct pleasure to introduce to you
Emily Bates, Suzy Bailey,
Samantha Darko, Beth Farmer and Joanie James.
They are... Sparkle Motion.
♪ DURAN DURAN: Notorious
♪ Notorious, notorious
♪ No, no, notorious
♪ I can't read about it
♪ Burns the skin from your eyes
♪ I'll do fine without it
♪ Here's one you don't compromise
♪ Lies come hardly disguised
♪ Betting me to fight it out, not wild about it
♪ Spare your seedy judgments
♪ Who says they're part of our lives?
♪ You own the money
♪ You control the witness
♪ I'll leave you lonely
♪ Don't monkey with my business
♪ You've paid the profits
♪ To justify your reasons
♪ I heard you promise but I don't believe it
♪ That's why I done it again...
[cheering]
[girl] All right! Sparkle Motion!
[Camera shutter clicks]
[cheering]
[scream]
[jaunty music]
How long was I asleep for?
Whole movie.
[Police radio]
Captain, looks like we got another room back here.
[TV announcer] The blaze was
extinguished sometime after 8 p.m.
Firefighters discovered what has
been called a "kiddie porn dungeon."
Cunningham, who has become
a celebrity for his books and tapes,
was arrested this morning...
Oh, my God!
Arson has not been ruled out
as the cause of the fire.
A group of Cunning Vision employees...
Dad played golf with that guy.
...denied alleged links to a child
pornography publishing circuit.
In a vicious statement, Cunningham
attacked fire department officials,
claiming a vast conspiracy.
[Dr. Cole] Karen, we don't think the
methods you've used are appropriate.
What exactly about my methods
do you find inappropriate?
I don't have time for a debate.
I believe I've made myself clear.
You call this clarity?
You don't have a clue what it's like
to communicate with kids.
And we are losing them to apathy.
To this prescribed nonsense.
They're slipping away.
I am sorry that you have failed.
If you'll excuse me, I have another appointment.
You can finish out the week.
[Screams]
Good afternoon.
It gives me great pleasure to
announce that the school dance team
has been invited to perform
on Ed McMahon's Star Search '88
in Los Angeles, California.
No, it was ridiculous...
I'll call you back.
- Rose.
- Kitty.
I'm sure you're aware of the horrible
allegations against Jim Cunningham.
I saw it on TV.
Something about a kiddie porn...
Oh, please! Don't use those words!
It's obviously a conspiracy
to destroy an innocent man.
I am going to spearhead the
Jim Cunningham defence campaign.
Rose, I have to appear
at his arraignment tomorrow morning.
The girls are scheduled to leave
for Los Angeles in the morning.
As their coach, I was the
obvious choice to chaperone them...
But now you can't go.
- Yes.
- Hm.
Now, believe me, of all the other mothers,
I wouldn't dream of asking you.
But none of the other mothers are available to go.
I don't know, Kitty.
It's a bad weekend. Eddie's in New York.
Rose, I don't know if you realise
what an opportunity this is for our daughters.
This has been a dream of Samantha's
and all of ours for a long time.
I made her lead dancer.
Sometimes I doubt your commitment
to Sparkle Motion.
Elizabeth will be in charge.
She'll drive you to therapy.
And if you need anything, promise me
you will call Dr. Thurman.
OK.
How does it feel to have a wacko for a son?
It feels wonderful.
What do I tell the others when they ask about you?
Tell them everything is gonna be just fine.
What's "cellar door"?
[Sighs] This famous linguist once said
that of all the phrases in the English language,
of all the endless combinations
of words in all of history,
that "cellar door" is the most beautiful.
"Cellar door"?
I promise that one clay
everything's gonna be better for you.
Shut up!
- I want to talk about your past today.
- No.
I want to talk about you and your parents.
They didn't buy me what I wanted for Christmas.
What did you want for Christmas
that year?
Hungry Hungry Hippos.
How did you feel, being denied
these Hungry Hungry Hippos?
Regret.
What else makes you feel regret?
That I did it again.
You did it again?
I flooded my school and I
burned down that pervert's house.
[Laughs]
I only have a few clays before they catch me.
Did Frank tell you to do these things?
I have to obey him. He saved my life.
I have to obey him or I'll be left all alone,
and then...
and then I won't be able to figure out
what this is all about.
I won't be able to know his master plan.
Do you mean God's master plan?
Do you now believe in God?
I have the power to build a time machine.
How is that possible?
How is time travel possible, Donnie?
Time's up, Frank said.
When is this going to happen?
Soon.
[Sobs] Soon.
What is going to happen?
[Sobs] Frank is gonna kill.
Who is he going to kill?
[Breathes heavily]
- Who is he going to kill?
- I can see him!
The sky is going to open up.
If the sky were to suddenly open up,
there would be no law.
There would be no rule.
There would only be you and your memories.
The choices you've made
and the people you've touched.
If this world were to end,
there would only be you and him.
And no-one else.
[Sobs]
Hey.
[Elizabeth] I got in.
[Laughs] I am going to Harvard.
We should throw a party.
Mom and Dad are gone. It's
Halloween. We could get away with it.
OK, but it has to be small, all right?
Happy Halloween!
[Cheering and whooping]
♪ THE DEAD GREEN MUMMIES: Proud To Be Loud
Beelzebub!
We got eggs, water, balloons
and 12 rolls of toilet paper.
I stole four beers from my clad.
- We got a keg.
- Keg beer is for pussies.
[Phone rings]
[beep]
Rose, this is Lilian Thurman.
It is extremely important that you
call me as soon as you hear this.
Thank you.
- Hi.
- Hey.
Are you OK?
Yeah. My mom's gone.
You wanna come in?
Yeah.
♪ JOY DIVISION: Love Will Tear Us Apart
♪ But emotions are low
♪ And we're changing our ways
♪ Taking different roads
♪ And love
♪ Love will tear us apart...
I don't know. She...
She didn't leave a note and...
the house was all messed up.
But you're OK?
Did you call the cops?
Yeah. They said I should leave
the house and go to a safe place.
I'm just so scared. I keep thinking
something awful is happening and...
It's my fucking stepdad. I know it.
I guess some people are just
born with tragedy in their blood.
- Have you guys seen Frank?
- No, I think they went on a beer run.
[Rose] If you're there, pick up.
Hello. Good news.
The girls got three and a half stars
and get to come back for the quarterfinals.
Samantha was amazing. Anyway...
We'll take the red-eye back tonight,
and we...
Mom, the plane's about to leave.
We'll take the red-eye and should arrive around 8.30.
Um... I hope everything's all right.
I love you. Bye.
♪ THE CHURCH: Under The Milky Way
♪ Under the Milky Way tonight
♪ Wish I knew what you were looking for
♪ Might have known what you would find
♪ And it's something quite peculiar
♪ Something shimmering and white
♪ It leads you here
♪ Despite your destination
♪ Under the Milky Way tonight
♪ Wish I knew what you were looking for
♪ Might have known what you would find
♪ Might have known what you would find...
[Karen] Cellar door.
♪ And it's something quite peculiar...
- Come with me.
- Where are we going?
- Just tell me.
- Look, we gotta go.
- You ever see Grandma Death?
- Is this about the book?
No, it's Frank. Time is running out.
We gotta go.
[Donnie] Roberta Sparrow.
Grandma Death.
[Sean] Donnie, nobody's here.
Let's forget about it.
Cellar door.
What?
[Screams]
Donnie!
Why the fuck are you here?
Oh, my God.
- You're dead!
- What do we do with him?
Leave him alone!
Don't fucking move.
Oh, fuck! Aargh!
- There's a car!
- [Gretchen coughs]
Get the hell out of here! Now!
Seth, there's a car coming! Let's go!
- I have a bigger knife now.
- God!
Let's go! Here come the cops!
[Gretchen struggles and coughs]
Did you call the fucking cops?
- Deus ex machina.
- What did you say?
- What the fuck did you say?
- Our saviour.
Donnie!
[Groans]
Gretchen?
Gretchen.
Wake up, Gretchen.
Frank.
- Wake up.
- What did you do?
Gretchen, wake up. Wake up.
Wake up.
Gretchen?
Gretchen.
What the fuck did you do, man?
You killed her, Frank!
Is she dead?
What were you guys doing in the road?
What were you thinking?
Go home!
Go home and tell your parents everything'll be OK.
Go!
[Distant rumbling]
[Sirens]
[Frank] 28 days,
six hours...
42 minutes,
12 seconds.
I'm going home.
[Laughs]
[Donnie] To travel back in time,
you have to have a spaceship
that can travel faster than light.
- [Monnitoff] Theoretically.
- And be able to find a wormhole.
The principles of time travel are
there. You've got a vessel, a portal.
The vessel can be anything.
Probably a spacecraft.
A metal craft of any kind.
[Violent rumbling]
[screaming]
[Gretchen]
What if you could go back in time
and take all those hours of pain and darkness
and replace them with something better?
[Donnie] Dear Roberta Sparrow,
I've reached you in your book
and there's so many things I need to ask you.
Sometimes I'm afraid of what you might tell me.
Sometimes I'm afraid you'll tell me
this is not a work of fiction.
I can only hope the answers
will come to me in my sleep.
I hope that when the world comes to an end,
I can breathe a sigh of relief
because there will be so much to look forward to.
[Laughs]
[sighs]
[gasps]
♪ GARY JULES AND MICHAEL ANDREWS: Mad World
♪ All around me are familiar faces
♪ Worn-out places
♪ Worn-out faces
♪ Bright and early for the daily races
♪ Going nowhere
♪ And their tears are filling up their glasses
♪ No expression
♪ Hide my head, I want to drown my sorrow
♪ No tomorrow
♪ And I find it kind of funny
♪ I find it kind of sad
♪ The dreams in which I'm dying
♪ Are the best I've ever had
♪ I find it hard to tell you
♪ I find it hard to take
♪ When people run in circles
♪ It's a very, very
♪ Mad world
♪ Children waiting for the day they feel good
♪ Happy birthday
♪ Made to feel the way that every child should
♪ Sit and listen
♪ Went to school and I was very nervous
♪ No-one knew me
♪ Hello, teacher, tell me what's my lesson
♪ Look right through me
♪ And I find it kind of funny
♪ I find it kind of sad
♪ The dreams in which I'm dying
♪ Are the best I've ever had
♪ I find it hard to tell you
♪ I find it hard to take
♪ When people run in circles
♪ It's a very, very
♪ Mad world
♪ Enlarging your world
Hey.
What's going on?
Horrible accident.
My neighbour... got killed.
What happened?
Got smooshed by a jet engine.
What was his name?
Donnie. Donnie Darko.
Hmm.
I feel bad for his family.
Yeah.
Did you know him?
No.
[Police radio]