Yes, Marlin.
No, I see it. It's beautiful.
So, Coral, when you said
you wanted an ocean view...
you didn't think you'd get
the whole ocean, did you?
Oh, yeah.
A fish can breathe out here.
Did your man deliver,
or did he deliver?
- My man delivered.
- And it wasn't so easy.
Because a lot of other clownfish
had their eyes on this place.
You better believe they did...
every single one of them.
You did good.
And the neighborhood
is awesome.
So, you do like it, don't you?
No, no. I do, I do.
I really do like it.
But, Marlin, I know that
the drop off is desirable...
with the great schools
and the amazing view...
but do we really need
so much space?
Coral, honey, these are our kids
we're talking about.
They deserve the best.
Look, look, look.
They'll wake up,
poke their little heads out...
and they see a whale!
Right by their bedroom window.
You'll wake the kids.
Oh, right, right.
Aw, look. They're dreaming.
We still have to name them.
You want to name
all of them right now?
All right, we'll name
this half Marlin Junior...
and this half Coral Junior.
- OK, we're done.
- I like Nemo.
Nemo. We'll name one Nemo...
but I'd like most of them
to be Marlin Junior.
Just think,
in a couple of days...
- we're going to be parents.
- Yeah.
What if they don't like me?
- Marlin.
- No, really.
There's over 400 eggs.
Odds are, one will like you.
What?
- You remember how we met?
- I try not to.
Well, I remember.
"Excuse me, miss..."
"can you check and see
if I have a hook in my lip?"
You got a little closer
because it was wiggling.
- Get away, get away!
- Here he is. Cutie's here.
Where did everybody go?
Coral, get inside the house.
No, Coral, don't.
They'll be fine.
Just get inside...
You, right now.
No!
Coral!
Coral?
There, there, there.
It's OK. Daddy's here.
Daddy's got you.
I promise, I will never
let anything happen to you...
Nemo.
First day of school!
Wake up, wake up!
First day of school.
I don't want to go to school...
five more minutes.
Not you, Dad, me.
- OK?
- Get up, get up.
It's time for school,
time for school.
All right, I'm up.
- Nemo!
- First day of school!
Nemo, don't move.
You'll never get out
of there yourself.
I'll do it.
- You feel a break?
- No.
Sometimes you can't tell
'cause fluid rushes to the area.
- Are you woozy?
- No.
- How many stripes do I have?
- I'm fine.
- Answer the stripe question.
- Three.
No! See?
Something's wrong with you.
I have one, two, three...
That's all I have?
You're OK. How's the lucky fin?
- Lucky.
- Let's see.
Are you sure you want to go
to school this year?
There's no problem if you don't.
You can wait 5 or 6 years.
Come on, Dad,
it's time for school.
Forgot to brush.
Do you want this anemone
to sting you?
- Yes.
- Brush.
- OK, I'm done.
- You missed a spot.
- Where?
- There.
Right there. And here and here.
All right, we're excited.
The first day of school.
Here we go.
We're ready to learn
to get some knowledge.
What's the one thing we have
to remember about the ocean?
- It's not safe.
- That's my boy.
First, we check to see
that the coast is clear.
We go out... and back in.
And then we go out...
and back in.
And then one more time...
out and back in.
And sometimes, if you want
to do it four times...
- Dad...
- All right, come on, boy.
Maybe while I'm at school,
I'll see a shark.
- I highly doubt that.
- Have you ever met a shark?
No, and I don't plan to.
- How old are sea turtles?
- I don't know.
Sandy Plankton
from next door...
he says that sea turtles live
to be about 100 years old.
He says that sea turtles live
If I ever meet a sea turtle,
I'll ask him.
After I'm done
talking to the shark, OK?
Hold on. Wait to cross.
Hold my fin.
Dad, you're not
going to freak out...
like you did at
the petting zoo, are you?
That snail was about to charge.
I wonder where
we're supposed to go.
Bye, Mom!
I'll pick you up after school.
Come on, you guys, stop it!
Give it back!
Come on, we'll try over there.
Excuse me, is this where
we meet his teacher?
Well, look who's out
of the anemone.
Yes. Shocking, I know.
- Marty, right?
- Marlin.
- Bob.
- Ted.
Bill. Hey, you're a clownfish.
You're funny, right?
Tell us a joke.
- Yeah.
Well, actually,
that's a common misconception.
Clownfish are no funnier
than any other fish.
- Come on, clownie.
- Do something funny.
All right, I know one joke.
There's a mollusk, see?
And he walks up to a sea...
He doesn't walk up,
he swims up.
Actually,
the mollusk isn't moving.
He's in one place,
and then the sea cucumber...
Well, they... I'm mixed up.
There was a mollusk
and a sea cucumber.
None of them were walking,
so forget that I...
Sheldon! Get out of
Mr. Johannsen's yard now!
All right, you kids!
Where'd you go?
Dad, can I go play, too? Can I?
I would feel better if
you'd play on the sponge beds.
That's where I would play.
- What's wrong with his fin?
- He looks funny.
Hey, what'd I do?
Be nice.
It's his first time at school.
He was born with it.
We call it his lucky fin.
- Dad...
- See this tentacle?
It's actually shorter
than all my other tentacles...
but you can't really tell.
Especially when
I twirl them like this.
I'm H-2-O intolerant.
I'm obnoxious.
Let's name the zones,
the zones, the zones
Let's name
the zones of the open sea
Mr. Ray!
- Come on, Nemo.
- You better stay with me.
Mesopelagic, bathyal,
abyssalpelagic
All the rest are too deep
for you and me to see
I wonder where
my class has gone?
We're under here!
Oh, there you are.
Climb aboard, explorers.
Oh, knowledge exploring
is, oh, so lyrical
When you think thoughts
that are empirical
Dad, you can go now.
- Hello. Who is this?
- I'm Nemo.
Nemo, all new explorers
must answer a science question.
- OK.
- You live in what kind of home?
An anemon-none.
A nemenem-menome.
OK, don't hurt yourself.
Welcome aboard, explorers.
Just so you know,
he's got a little fin.
I find if he's having
trouble swimming...
I let him take a break,
10, 15 minutes.
Dad, it's time
for you to go now.
Don't worry. We're gonna
stay together as a group.
OK, class,
optical orbits up front.
And remember, we keep
our supraesophogeal ganglion...
to ourselves.
That means you, Jimmy.
Aw, man!
Bye, Nemo!
Bye, Dad!
Bye, son!
Be safe.
You're doing pretty well
for a first-timer.
You can't hold on to them
forever, can you?
I had a tough time with
my oldest out at the drop off.
They got to grow up...
The drop off?
They're going to the drop off?
What are you, insane?
Why don't we fry them up now
and serve them with chips?
Hey, Marty, calm down.
Don't tell me
to be calm, pony boy.
Pony boy?
For a clownfish,
he really isn't that funny.
Pity.
Let's name the species,
the species, the species
Let's name the species
that live in the sea
There's
Porifera, coelenterata,
hydrozoa, scyphozoa
Anthozoa, ctenophora,
bryozoas, three
Gastropoda, arthropoda,
echinoderma
And some fish like you and me
Come on, sing with me.
Just the girls this time.
Oh, seaweed is cool
Seaweed is fun
it makes its food
OK, the drop off.
All right, kids,
feel free to explore...
but stay close.
Stromalitic cyanobacteria! Gather.
An entire ecosystem contained
in one infinitesimal speck.
There are as many protein pairs
contained in this...
Come on, let's go.
Come on, sing with me!
There's porifera, coelenterata
Hydrozoa, scyphozoa
Anthozoa, ctenophora,
bryozoas, three
Hey, guys, wait up!
Cool.
Saved your life!
Aw, you guys made me ink.
What's that?
I know what that is.
Sandy Plankton saw one.
He said it was called a butt.
That's a pretty big butt.
Oh, look at me.
I'm going to touch the butt.
Oh, yeah?
Let's see you get closer.
OK.
Beat that.
Come on, Nemo.
How far can you go?
My dad says it's not safe.
- Nemo! No!
- Dad?
You were about
to swim into open water.
No, I wasn't...
Good thing I was here.
If I hadn't shown up...
- He wasn't going to go.
- He was too afraid.
No, I wasn't.
This does not
concern you, kids...
and you're lucky
I don't tell your parents.
You know you can't swim well.
I can swim fine, Dad, OK?
No, it's not OK.
You shouldn't be near here.
OK, I was right. You'll start
school in a year or two.
No, Dad! Just because
you're scared of the ocean...
Clearly, you're not ready...
and you're not coming back
until you are.
You think
you can do these things...
but you just can't, Nemo!
I hate you.
There's
Nothing to see.
Gather. Over there.
Excuse me.
Is there anything I can do?
I am a scientist, sir.
Is there any problem?
I'm sorry. I didn't mean
to interrupt things.
He isn't a good swimmer,
and it's a little too soon...
for him to be out here
unsupervised.
I can assure you,
he's quite safe with me.
I'm sure he is,
but you have a large class...
and he can get lost from sight
if you're not looking.
I'm not saying
you're not looking.
Oh, my gosh!
Nemo's swimming out to sea!
Nemo!
What do you think you're doing?
You'll get stuck out there...
and I'll have to get you
before another fish does.
Get back here!
I said get back here now!
Stop! You take
one more move, mister...
Don't you dare!
If you put one fin
on that boat...
Are you listening to me?
Don't touch the bo... Nemo!
He touched the butt.
You paddle your little tail
right back here, Nemo.
That's right.
You are in big trouble,
young man.
Do you hear me? Big...
Big...
Daddy! Help me!
I'm coming, Nemo!
Get under me, kids!
Oh! No!
Dad!
Daddy!
Oh! Nemo!
Nemo!
Nemo, no! Nemo!
Nemo! Nemo! No!
No!
Nemo! Nemo!
Hold on.
Oh, no.
No. No, it's gone. It's gone.
No, no, it can't be gone.
No, no! Nemo!
Nemo! Nemo!
No!
No! No, please, no!
No, no!
Has anybody seen a boat?
Please! A white boat!
They took my son!
My son! Help me, please.
- Look out!
- What?
Oh, oh. Sorry.
I didn't see you.
- Sir? Are you OK?
- He's gone, he's gone.
There, there. It's all right.
- He's gone.
- It'll be OK.
No, no. They took him away.
I have to find the boat.
A boat? Hey, I've seen a boat.
- You have?
- It passed by not too long ago.
- A white one?
- Hi. I'm Dory.
Where? Which way?
It went this way.
It went this way. Follow me.
Thank you. Thank you,
thank you so much.
No problem.
Hey...
Wait!
- Will you quit it?
- What?
I'm trying to swim here.
Ocean isn't big enough for you?
You got a problem, buddy?
Do you? Do you?
You want a piece of me?
I'm scared now. What?
- Wait a minute.
- Stop following me, OK?
What? You're showing me
where the boat went.
A boat? Hey, I've seen a boat.
It passed by not too long ago.
It went this way.
It went this way. Follow me.
Wait a minute.
What is going on?
You already told me
which way the boat was going.
I did? Oh, no.
If this is some kind of
practical joke, it's not funny.
And I know funny.
I'm a clownfish.
No, it's not. I know it's not.
I'm so sorry.
See, I suffer from
short-term memory loss.
Short-term memory loss.
I don't believe this.
No, it's true. I forget things
almost instantly.
It runs in my family.
At least, I think it does.
Where are they?
Can I help you?
Something's wrong
with you... really.
You're wasting my time.
I have to find my son.
Hello.
Well, hi!
Name's Bruce.
It's all right. I understand.
Why trust a shark, right?
So, what's a couple
of bites like you...
doing out so late, eh?
We're not doing anything.
We're not even out.
Great!
Then how'd you morsels...
like to come to a little
get-together I'm having?
You mean, like a party?
Yeah, right. A party.
What do you say?
I love parties.
That sounds like fun.
Parties are fun,
and it's tempting, but...
Oh, come on, I insist.
OK. That's all that matters.
Hey, look, balloons.
It is a party.
Mind your distance, though.
Those balloons
can be a bit dodgy.
You wouldn't want
one of them to pop.
Anchor! Chum!
There you are, Bruce. Finally.
- We got company.
- It's about time, mate.
We've already gone
through the snacks...
and I'm still starving.
We almost had a feeding frenzy.
Come on,
let's get this over with.
Right, then.
The meeting has officially
come to order.
Let us all say the pledge.
I am a nice shark,
not a mindless eating machine.
If I am to change this image...
I must first change myself.
Fish are friends, not food.
Except stinkin' dolphins.
Dolphins. Yeah.
They think they're so cute.
"Look at me.
I'm a flippin' little dolphin."
"Let me flip for you.
Ain't I something?"
Right, then.
Today's meeting is Step 5...
Bring a Fish Friend.
Do you all have your friends?
Got mine.
- Hey, there.
- How about you, Chum?
Oh, I... seem to have
misplaced my friend.
That's all right, Chum.
I had a feeling
this would be a difficult step.
You can help yourself
to one of my friends.
Thanks, mate.
A little chum for Chum?
I'll start the testimonies.
Hello. My name is Bruce.
Hello, Bruce.
It has been three weeks
since my last fish.
On my honor, or may I be
chopped up and made into soup.
- You're an inspiration!
- Amen.
Right, then. Who's next?
Pick me, pick me.
Yes. The little
Sheila down the front.
Come on up here.
Hi. I'm Dory.
- Hello, Dory.
- And well...
I don't think
I've ever eaten a fish.
- That's incredible.
- Good on you, mate.
I'm glad
I got that off my chest.
All right, anyone else?
How about you, mate?
What's your problem?
Me? I don't have a problem.
Oh, OK.
Denial.
Just start with your name.
OK. Hello.
My name is Marlin.
I'm a clownfish.
- A clownfish? Really?
- Tell us a joke.
I love jokes.
I actually do know one
that's pretty good.
There was this mollusk...
and he walks up
to a sea cucumber.
Normally, they don't talk,
sea cucumbers...
but in a joke,
everyone talks...
so the sea mollusk
says to the cucumber...
Daddy!
Nemo!
Nemo! Nemo! I don't get it.
For a clownfish,
he's not that funny.
No, no, no, no. He's my son.
He was taken by these divers.
Oh, my. You poor fish.
Humans... think they own
everything.
Probably American.
Now, there is a father...
Looking for his little boy.
What do these markings mean?
I never knew my father!
- Group hug.
- We're all mates here, mate.
I can't read human.
We got to find a fish
that can read this.
- Hey, look, sharks.
- No, no, no, Dory!
- Guys, guys.
- No, Dory.
That's mine. Give it to me.
Gimme!
Oh, I'm sorry. Are you OK?
I'm so sorry.
You really clocked me there.
Am I bleeding?
Dory, are you OK...
That's good.
Intervention!
- Just a bite.
- Hold it together, mate!
Remember, Bruce,
fish are friends, not food!
- Food!
- Dory, look out!
I'm having fish tonight!
Remember the steps, mate!
Just one bite!
G'day. Grr!
There's no way out!
There's got to be a way
to escape!
Who is it?
Dory, help me find a way out!
Sorry. Come back later.
We're trying to escape.
- There's got to be a way out!
- Here's something.
"Es-cap-e."
I wonder what that means.
Funny. It's spelled
just like "escape."
Let's go.
Here's Brucey!
Wait a minute. You can read?
I can read?
That's right. I can read!
Well, then, here.
Read this now.
He really doesn't mean it.
He never even knew his father.
Don't fall off the wagon!
Oh, no, it's blocked!
No, Bruce, focus.
Sorry about Bruce, mate.
He's really a nice guy.
I need to get that mask.
You want that mask? OK.
No, no, no, no, no, no!
Quick, grab the mask!
Oh, no. Bruce?
What?
Swim away! Swim away!
Aw, is the party over?
Nice.
Dad?
Daddy?
Barbara.
Prep for his anterior crown,
would you, please?
And I'm going to need
a few more cotton rolls.
OK.
Hello, little fella.
Beauty, isn't he?
I found that guy
struggling for life...
out on the reef,
and I saved him.
So, has that Novocaine
kicked in yet?
I think so.
We're ready to roll.
Bubbles!
My bubbles.
He likes bubbles.
No!
Bonjour.
Slow down, little fella.
There's nothing to worry about.
- He's scared to death.
- I want to go home.
Do you know where my dad is?
Honey, your dad's probably
back at the pet store.
Pet store?
Yeah, you know, like,
I'm from Bob's Fish Mart.
- Pet Palace.
- Fish-O-Rama.
- Mail order.
- Ebay.
- So, which one is it?
- I'm from the ocean.
The ocean. The ocean?
He hasn't been decontaminated.
Jacques!
- Oui.
- Clean him!
Oui.
- Ocean.
- La mer. Bon.
Voila. He is clean.
The big blue. What's it like?
- Big and blue?
- I knew it.
If there's anything you need,
just ask your Auntie Deb.
Or if I'm not around,
you can talk to my sister Flo.
Hi. How are you?
Don't listen to anything
my sister says.
She's nuts.
We got a live one.
- Can't hear you, Peach.
- I said we got a live one.
- Boy, oh, boy.
- What do we got?
Root canal... and by the looks
of those x-rays...
it's not going to be pretty.
- Dam and clamp installed?
- Yep.
- What did he use to open?
- Gator-Glidden drill.
He seems to favor
that one lately.
I can't see, Flo.
You're getting a little too...
Now he's doing
the Schilder technique.
He's using a Hedstrom file.
That's not a Hedstrom file.
That's a K-Flex.
It has a teardrop cross-section.
Clearly a Hedstrom.
- No, no, K-Flex.
- Hedstrom.
- K-Flex!
- Hedstrom!
There I go.
A little help, over here.
I'll go deflate him.
All right. Go ahead and rinse.
Oh, the human mouth
is a disgusting place.
- Hey, Nigel.
- What did I miss?
Root canal... a doozy.
Root canal?
What did he use to open?
- Gator-Glidden drill.
- He's favoring that one.
Hope he doesn't get surplus
sealer at the portal terminus.
- Hello. Who's this?
- New guy.
The dentist
took him off the reef.
An outie. From my neck
of the woods, eh?
Sorry if I ever took
a snap at you.
Fish gotta swim,
birds gotta eat.
Hey! No, no, no, no!
They're not your fish.
They're my fish.
Come on, go. Go on, shoo!
Aw, the picture broke.
This here's Darla.
She's my niece.
She's going to be
eight this week.
Hey, little fella.
Say hello to your new mummy.
She'll be here Friday
to pick you up.
You're her present.
It's our little secret.
Well, Mr. Tucker,
while that sets up...
I'm going to see a man
about a wallaby.
Oh, Darla.
What? What's wrong with her?
She wouldn't stop
shaking the bag.
- Poor Chuckles.
- He was her present last year.
Hitched a ride
on the porcelain express.
She's a fish killer.
I can't go with that girl.
I have to get back to my dad.
Daddy! Help me!
Oh, he's stuck.
Nobody touch him.
Can you help me?
No. You got yourself in there.
You can get yourself out.
- Gill...
- I want to see him do it.
Calm down. Alternate wiggling
your fins and your tail.
I can't. I have a bad fin.
Never stopped me.
Just think about
what you need to do.
Come on.
Perfect.
- Yay!
- You did it!
Good squirming.
From the ocean...
just like you, Gill.
Yeah.
I've seen that look before.
What are you thinking about?
I'm thinking...
tonight, we give the kid
a proper reception.
So, kid,
you got a name or what?
Nemo. I'm Nemo.
Nemo. Nemo.
Are you gonna eat that?
Careful with that hammer.
No, no.
What does it say? Dory!
A sea monkey has my money.
Wake up. Get up. Come on.
Come on!
- Yes, I'm a natural blue.
- Get up!
Look out! Sharks eat fish!
Dusty.
The mask. Where's the mask?
No! No, not the mask!
Get it! Get the mask!
Get the mask! Get it!
Hoo doot doo doot doot doo doot
La la la la la la
it just keeps going on,
doesn't it?
Echo! Echo!
Hey, what you doing?
It's gone. I've lost the mask.
- Did you drop it?
- You dropped it!
That was my only chance
of finding my son.
Now it's gone.
Hey, Mr. Grumpy Gills...
when life gets you down,
know what you got to do?
- I don't want to know.
- Just keep swimming.
Just keep swimming,
swimming, swimming
What do we do? We swim, swim
Dory, no singing.
Ho ho ho ho ho ho
I love to swim
When you want to swim
See, I'm going to get
stuck now with that song.
- Now it's in my head.
- Sorry.
Dory, do you see anything?
- Something's got me.
- That was me. I'm sorry.
- Who's that?
- Who could it be? It's me.
Are you my conscience?
Yeah, yeah.
I'm your conscience.
We haven't spoken for a while.
How are you?
- Can't complain.
- Yeah? Good.
Now, Dory,
I want you to tell me...
Do you see anything?
I see a... I see a light.
- A light?
- Yeah. Over there.
- Hey, conscience, am I dead?
- No. I see it, too.
What is it?
It's so pretty.
I'm feeling... happy...
which is a big deal for me.
I want to touch it.
Hey, come back.
Come on back here.
I'm gonna get you
I'm gonna get you.
I'm gonna swim with you
I'm gonna be your best friend
Good feeling's gone.
I can't see!
I don't know where I'm going!
- The mask!
- What mask?
OK, I can't see a thing.
- Oh, gee.
- Hey, look, a mask.
Read it!
I'm sorry,
but if you could just...
bring it a little closer,
I kind of need the light.
That's great.
Keep it right there.
- Just read it!
- OK, OK.
Mr. Bossy. "P."
OK. "P. Sher..."
"Sher... P. Sher..."
P. Shirley? P..."
Oh. The first line's
"P. Sherman."
"P. Sherman"
doesn't make any sense!
OK. Second line. "42."
Don't eat me. Don't eat me.
Light, please!
"Walla... walla..."
Waah! Waah! Waah!
The second line's
"42 Wallaby Way."
That's great.
Speed read. Take a guess.
No pressure. No problem.
There's a lot of pressure.
Pressure! Take a guess
now with pressure!
- "Sydney"! It's "Sydney"!
- Duck!
I'm dead.
I'm dead, I'm dead, I'm dead.
I died. I'm dead.
We did it, we did it
Oh, yeah, yeah, yeah
No eating here tonight, whoo!
Eating here tonight
No, no, no, eating here tonight
- Dory.
- You on a diet
Dory! What did the mask say?
P. Sherman,
42 Wallaby Way, Sydney.
I remembered what it said!
I usually forget things,
but I remembered it!
Wait. Where is that?
I don't know.
But who cares? I remembered.
Raar!
P. Sherman,
42 Wallaby Way, Sydney.
I remembered it again!
Nemo.
Nemo
Suivez-moi.
Follow me.
Hahoo wahoo yahoo ho
Hahoo ho ho wahoo ha hee
Ha ho wahee ha ho ho ho
Hoo!
State your name.
Nemo.
Brother Bloat, proceed.
Nemo, newcomer
of orange and white...
you have been called forth...
to the summit of
Mount Wannahockaloogie...
to join with us in
the fraternal bonds of tankhood.
We want you in our club, kid.
- Really?
- If...
you are able to swim through...
the Ring of Fire!
Turn on the Ring of Fire!
You said you could do it.
The Ring of Fire!
Bubbles, let me... Oh!
Ha hwa ha ho ho ho
Isn't there another way?
He's just a boy!
From this moment on,
you will be known as Sharkbait.
Sharkbait, oo-ha-ha!
Welcome, Brother Sharkbait.
- Enough with the Sharkbait.
- Sharkbait!
Ba-ba-do.
Sharkbait's
one of us now, agreed?
- Agreed.
- We can't send him to his death.
Darla's coming in five days.
So, what are we going to do?
I'll tell you
what we're gonna do...
we're gonna get him
out of here.
- We'll help him escape.
- Escape? Really?
We're all gonna escape.
Gill, please.
Not another escape plan.
Sorry,
but they just never work.
Why should this
be any different?
- Because we've got him.
- Me?
- You see that filter?
- Yeah.
You're the only one who can get
in and out of that thing.
We need you to take
a pebble inside there...
and jam the gears.
You do that,
and this tank's gonna get...
filthier and filthier
by the minute.
Pretty soon, the dentist'll
have to clean the tank...
and when he does, he'll take us
out of the tank...
put us in individual baggies...
then we'll roll ourselves
down the counter...
out the window,
off the awning...
into the bushes,
across the street...
and into the harbor!
It's foolproof. Who's with me?
- Aye!
I think you're nuts.
No offense, kid,
but you're not the best swimmer.
He's fine. He can do this.
So, Sharkbait,
what do you think?
Let's do it.
I'm going to P. Sherman,
42 Wallaby Way, Sydney.
Where are you going?
I'm going to P. Sherman,
42 Wallaby Way, Sydney.
If you ask where I'm going...
I'll tell you
that's where I'm going.
It's P. Sherman,
42 Wallaby Way, Sydney.
Where? I'm sorry,
I didn't hear you.
P. Sherman,
42 Wallaby Way, Sydney.
Excuse me.
Hi. Do you know how to get...
Hello? Wait. Can you tell me...
Hey! Hold it!
I'm trying to talk to you!
Fellas, come back here.
One quick question.
I need to...
And they're gone again.
P. Sherman,
42 Wallaby Way, Sydney.
Why do I have to tell you
over and over again?
I'll tell you again.
I don't get tired of it...
OK, all right.
Here's the thing.
I think it's best
if I carry on from here by...
by myself.
OK.
You know, alone.
Without... without...
I mean, not without you.
But I don't
want you... with me.
Am I...
I don't want to hurt
your feelings.
- You want me to leave?
- I mean, not... Yes.
I just can't afford
any more delays...
and you're one of those fish
that cause delays.
Sometimes it's a good thing.
There's a whole group of fish.
They're delay fish.
You mean...
You mean you don't like me?
No, of course I like you.
It's because I like you
I don't want to be with you.
It's a complicated emotion.
Don't cry. I like you.
Hey, you!
Lady, is this guy bothering you?
I don't remember. Were you?
No, no, no, no, no.
We're just...
Do you guys know
how I can get to...
Look, pal, we're talking
to the lady, not you.
Hey, hey. You like impressions?
Just like in rehearsals,
gentlemen.
So what are we? Take a guess.
I've seen one of those.
I'm a fish with a nose
like a sword.
- Wait, wait...
- It's a swordfish!
Hey, clown boy,
let the lady guess.
Where's the butter?
It's on the tip of my tongue!
- Lobster.
- Saw that!
Lots of legs!
Live in the ocean.
- Clam!
- Close enough!
Oh, it's a whale of a tale
I'll tell you, lad...
They're good.
Will somebody please
give me directions?!
"Will somebody please
give me directions?!"
I'm serious!
"Blah blah blah, me, me, blah!"
"Blah blah blah, me, me, me!"
Thank you.
Oh, dear. Hey! Hey, come back!
- Hey, what's the matter?
- What's the matter?
While they're doing their
silly little impressions...
I am miles from home with a fish
that can't remember her name!
I bet that's frustrating.
Meanwhile, my son is out there.
- Your son Chico?
- Nemo?
But it doesn't matter
because no fish...
in this entire ocean
is going to help me.
Well, I'm helping you.
Wait right here.
- Guys!
- Is he bothering you again?
No, no. He's a good guy.
Go easy on him.
He's lost his son Fabio.
Any of you heard of P. Sherman,
42 Wallaby Way, Sydney?
Sydney? Oh, sure!
Ted here's got relatives
in Sydney.
- Don't you, Ted?
- Sure do!
Oh! Hey! They know Sydney!
You wouldn't know how
to get there, would you?
You want to follow the E.A.C.
That's the East
Australian Current.
Big current. Can't miss it.
It's in... that direction.
And then you follow that
for about...
I don't know.
What do you guys think?
About three leagues?
That little baby will put you
right past Sydney.
- Ta-da!
- That's great!
Dory, you did it!
Oh, please,
I'm just your little helper.
- Helping along. That's me.
- Fellas, thank you.
Don't mention it!
Just loosen up, OK, buddy?
Oh, you guys.
You really nailed him. Bye.
Oh, hey, ma'am. One more thing.
When you come to this trench,
swim through it, not over it.
Trench...
through it, not over it.
I'll remember. Hey, hey!
Hey, wait up, partner! Hold on!
Wait, wait, wait!
I gotta tell you something.
Nice trench.
Hello!
- OK, let's go.
- No, no. Bad trench.
Come on, we'll swim over
this thing.
Partner.
Little red flag going up.
Something's telling me
to swim through it, not over it.
Are you looking at this thing?
It's got death
written all over it.
I really, really, really
think we should swim through.
And I'm really, really done
talking about this. Over we go.
- Trust me on this.
- Trust you?
Yes, trust.
It's what friends do.
Look! Something shiny!
- Where?
- It just swam over the trench.
- Come on, we'll follow it!
- OK!
Boy, it sure is clear up here.
Exactly. And look at that...
there's the current.
We should be there in no time.
Hey, little guy.
You wanted to go
through the trench.
I shall call him Squishy,
and he shall be mine.
And he shall be my Squishy.
Come here, Squishy.
Come here, little Squishy.
- That's a jellyfish!
- Bad Squishy!
Shoo, shoo! Get away!
- Let me see that.
- Don't touch it.
I won't touch it.
I just want to look.
Hey! How come
it didn't sting you?
It did. It's just that...
Hold still.
I live in this anemone...
and I'm used
to these kind of stings.
It doesn't look bad.
You'll be fine.
But now we know, don't we...
that we don't want
to touch these again.
Let's be thankful this time
it was just a little one.
Don't move.
- This is bad, Dory.
- Hey, watch this!
Boing! Boing!
Dory!
You can't catch me
Don't bounce on the tops!
They will... not sting you!
- The tops don't sting you!
- Two in a row! Beat that!
Dory, listen to me.
I have an idea... a game.
- A game?
- Yes.
- I love games! Pick me!
- Here's the game.
Whoever can hop the fastest
out of these jellyfish wins!
- OK.
- Rules, rules, rules!
You can't touch the tentacles.
Only the tops.
Something about tentacles.
Got it. Go!
Wait! Not something about 'em,
it's all about 'em!
- Whee!
- Wait, Dory!
Gotta go faster
if you want to win!
Dory!
Boing, boing, boing!
Wait a minute! Dory!
Whee!
We're cheating death now.
That's what we're doing.
But we're having fun
at the same time.
I can do this. Just be careful.
Yeah, careful I don't
make you cry when I win!
I don't think so!
Give it up, old man.
You can't fight evolution.
I was built for speed.
The question is, Dory,
are you hungry?
- Hungry?
- Yeah.
'Cause you're about
to eat my bubbles!
Duck to the left! Right there!
The clownfish is the winner!
We did it! Look at us!
Dory?
Oh, no.
Dory! Dory!
Dory!
Am I disqualified?
No, you're doing fine!
You're actually winning!
But you gotta stay awake.
Where does P. Sherman live?
P. Sherman...
Wallaby Way, Sydney...
That's it!
- Wallaby Way...
- Stay awake!
Stay awake! Stay awake!
Stay... awake!
- Awake.
- P. Sherman.
- 42 Wallaby Way.
Wake up. Nemo...
You miss your dad,
don't you, Sharkbait?
Yeah.
You're lucky to have someone
out there looking for you.
He's not looking for me.
He's scared of the ocean.
Peach, any movement?
He's had four cups of coffee.
It's gotta be soon.
Keep on him.
My first escape...
landed on dental tools.
I was aiming for the toilet.
Toilet?
All drains
lead to the ocean, kid.
How many times have
you tried to get out?
I've lost count.
Fish aren't meant
to be in a box, kid.
It does things to you.
Bubbles! Bubbles!
Potty break! He grabbed
the "Reader's Digest."
- We have 4.2 minutes!
- That's your cue, Sharkbait.
- You can do it, kid.
- We gotta be quick.
Once you get in, swim to
the bottom of the chamber...
and I'll talk you
through the rest.
- OK.
- It'll be a piece of kelp.
Nicely done!
- Can you hear me?
- Yeah!
Here comes the pebble.
Ptoo.
Now, do you see
a small opening?
Inside it,
you'll see a rotating fan.
Wedge that pebble into the fan
to stop it turning.
- Careful, Sharkbait!
- I can't do it!
Gill, this isn't a good idea.
He'll be fine. Try again!
OK.
That's it, Sharkbait.
Nice and steady.
I got it! I got it!
- He did it!
- That's great, kid!
Now swim up the tube and out.
Oh, no! Gill!
- Sharkbait!
- Oh, my gosh!
Get him outta there!
- What do we do?
- Oh, no!
Stay calm, kid.
Just don't panic!
Help me!
Sharkbait, grab hold of this!
- No! No! No!
- Feed me more!
- That's it!
- Sharkbait! Grab it!
I got it!
Pull!
Gill, don't make him
go back in there.
No. We're done.
Dude.
Focus, dude. Dude.
Oh, he lives. Hey, dude!
What happened?
Saw the whole thing, dude.
First, you were all,
like, "Whoa!"...
and then we were
all, like, "Whoa!"...
and then you were,
like, "Whoa."
What are you talking about?
You, mini-man.
Takin' on the jellies.
You got serious
thrill issues, dude.
Awesome.
Oh, my stomach.
Oh, man. No hurlin'
on the shell, dude, OK?
Just waxed it.
So, Mr. Turtle...
Dude. Mr. Turtle is my father.
The name's Crush.
Crush? Really?
OK, Crush. I need to
the East Australian Current.
E.A.C.?
Oh, dude.
You're ridin' it, dude!
Check it out!
OK, grab shell, dude!
Grab wh-a-a-at?!
Righteous! Righteous!
- Yeah!
- Stop!
So...
What brings you on this fine day
to the E.A.C.?
Dory and I need
to get to Sydney.
Dory! Is she all right?
Oh, little blue.
She is sub-level, dude.
Dory! Dory! Dory!
Dory.
I'm so sorry.
This is all my fault.
It's my fault.
Twenty-nine, thirty!
Ready or not, here I come!
There you are!
Dory?
Nice wave!
Up you go!
- Oh, my goodness!
- Kill the motor, dude.
Let us see what Squirt does
flying solo.
That was so cool!
Hey, Dad, did you see that?
Did you see me?
Did you see what I did?
You so totally rock, Squirt!
So give me some fin.
Noggin.
- Dude.
Oh... intro.
Jellyman, offspring.
Offspring, Jellyman.
- Jellies?! Sweet.
- Totally.
Apparently, I must've done
something you liked... dudes.
You rock, dude!
Curl away, my son.
It's awesome, Jellyman.
The little dudes are just eggs.
We leave 'em
on a beach to hatch...
and then, coo-coo-cachoo...
they find their way back
to the big ol' blue.
- All by themselves?
- Yeah.
But, dude, how do you know
when they're ready?
Well, you never really know.
But when they know,
you'll know, you know? Ha.
Hey, look, everybody.
I know that dude!
It's the Jellyman!
Go on. Jump on him!
- Turtle pile!
- Wait, wait, wait!
- Are you funny?
- Where's your shell?
- I need to breathe!
- Are you running away?
Did you really cross
the jellyfish forest?
- Did they sting you?
- One at a time!
Mr. Fish, did you die?
Sorry, I was
a little vague on the details.
So, where are you going?
You see, my son was taken.
My son was taken away from me.
- No way.
- What happened?
No, no, kids.
I don't want to talk about it.
Aww! Please?
Please?
Well, OK.
I live on this reef
a long, long way from here.
This is gonna be good.
I can tell.
And my son Nemo...
See, he was mad at me.
And maybe he wouldn't
have done it...
if I hadn't been
so tough on him.
I don't know.
Anyway, he swam out in
the open water to this boat...
and when he was out there,
these divers appeared...
and I tried to stop them,
but the boat was too fast.
So, we swam out in the ocean
to follow them...
They couldn't stop 'em.
And then Nemo's dad...
he swims out to the ocean,
and they bump into...
three ferocious sharks.
He scares away the sharks
by blowing 'em up!
Golly, that's amazing.
And then dives
thousands of feet...
straight down into the dark.
It's wicked dark down there.
You can't see a thing.
How's it going, Bob?
And the only thing
they can see down there...
is the light from
this big, horrible creature...
with razor-sharp teeth.
Nice parry, old man.
And then he has
to blast his way...
So, these two little fish
have been...
searching the ocean for days
on the East Australian Current.
Which means that he may be
on his way here right now.
That should put him
in Sydney Harbor...
In a matter of days.
I mean, it sounds like...
this guy is gonna
stop at nothing...
till he finds his son.
I sure hope he makes it.
That's one dedicated father,
if you ask me.
Mine! Mine! Mine! Mine! Mine!
Mine! Mine! Mine!
Would you just shut up?!
You're rats with wings!
Bloke's been looking
for his boy Nemo.
- Nemo?!
- He was taken off the reef...
- Take it! You happy?
- Mine! Mine! Mine!
Hey, say that again!
Something about Nemo.
Mine! Mine! Mine!
Whoooa...
Mine?
Last I heard, he's heading
towards the harbor.
Brilliant!
Is he doing OK?
Whatever you do,
Don't mention D-a-r...
It's OK. I know who
you're talking about.
Gill?
Hey, Sharkbait.
I'm sorry I couldn't stop the...
No, I'm the one
who should be sorry.
I was so ready to get out...
so ready to taste that ocean...
I was willing to put you
in harm's way to get there.
Nothing should be worth that.
I'm sorry I couldn't get you
back to your father, kid.
All right. Hey, hey, hey...
What the...
That's one way to pull a tooth.
Darn kids.
Good thing I pulled the
right one, eh, Prime Minister?
Hey.
Oh, Nigel!
You just missed an extraction.
Has he loosened
the periodontal ligament yet?
What am I talking about?
Where's Nemo?
- I've got to speak with him.
- What is it?
Your dad's been fighting
the entire ocean...
- looking for you.
- My father? Really?
He's traveled hundreds of miles,
battling sharks and jellyfish...
Sharks? That can't be him.
What was his name?
Some sort of sport fish.
- Tuna? Trout?
- Marlin?
Marlin! The little clownfish
from the reef.
It's my dad!
He took on a shark!
I heard he took on three.
- Three sharks?
- That's 4,800 teeth!
After you were taken
by Diver Dan over there...
your dad followed the boat
like a maniac.
Really?
He's swimming,
giving it all he's got...
and then three gigantic
sharks capture him...
and he blows them up
and dives thousands of feet...
and gets chased by a monster
with huge teeth!
He ties this demon to a rock,
and what's his reward?
He gets to battle
an entire jellyfish forest!
Now he's with a bunch of
sea turtles on the E.A. C...
and the word is he's headed
this way right now... to Sydney!
What a good daddy!
He was looking for you
after all, Sharkbait.
He's swimming to the filter!
- Sharkbait!
- Not again!
Sharkbait!
No!
You got your whole life
ahead of you!
- We'll help you, kid!
- Get him out!
Get him out of there!
Come on, kid! Grab the end!
Sharkbait!
- No!
- Can you hear me?
Nemo! Can you hear me?
Yeah, I can hear you.
Sharkbait, you did it!
Sharkbait, you're...
covered with germs!
That took guts, kid.
All right, gang,
we have less than 48 hours...
before Darla gets here.
This tank'll get
plenty dirty in that time...
but we have to help it along
any way we can.
- Jacques? No cleaning.
- I shall resist.
Everybody else,
be as gross as possible.
Think dirty thoughts.
We're gonna make
this tank so filthy...
the dentist
will have to clean it.
Good work!
All right, we're here, dudes!
Get ready!
Your exit's coming up, man!
Where? I don't see it!
Right there!
I see it! I see it!
The swirling vortex of terror?
- That's it, dude.
- Of course it is.
OK, first,
find your exit buddy.
Do you have your exit buddy?
Yes!
Squirt give you a rundown
of proper exiting technique.
Good afternoon!
We'll have a great jump today!
OK, crank a hard cutback
as you hit the wall.
There's a screaming bottom turn,
so watch out!
Remember...
rip it, roll it, and punch it!
He's trying to speak to me,
I know it!
You're really cute, but I don't
know what you're saying!
Say the first thing again.
OK, Jellyman! Go, go, go!
That was... fun!
I actually enjoyed that.
Hey, look, turtles!
Most excellent!
Now turn your
fishy tails around...
and swim straight on
through to Sydney!
No worries, man!
No worries!
Thank you, dude Crush!
- Bye!
- Bye, Jellyman!
You tell your little dude
I said hi, OK?
See ya later, dudes!
Bye, everyone!
Nemo would have loved this.
Hey! Crush, I forgot!
How old are you?
150, dude!
And still young! Rock on!
150! 150!
I gotta remember that.
- We going in there?
- Yep.
P. Sherman,
42 Wallaby Way, Sydney?
Yep. We're gonna
just swim straight.
Just keep swimming,
just keep swimming
Dory...
Boy, this is taking awhile.
How about we play a game?
OK.
OK, I'm thinking
of something orange...
and it's small...
- It's me.
- Right!
It's orange and small...
It's me.
All righty, Mr. Smartypants.
And it's orange and small
and white stripes...
Me. And the next one,
just a guess, me.
- That's just scary.
- Wait, wait, wait.
I have definitely seen
this floating speck before.
That means
we've passed it before...
and that means
we're going in circles...
we're not going straight!
- Hey, hey!
- Get to the surface.
We'll figure it out
up there. Let's go!
- Hey! Relax.
- What?
Take a deep breath.
Now, let's ask somebody
for directions.
Fine. Who do you
want to ask, the speck?
- There's nobody here!
- There has to be someone.
It's the ocean, silly.
We're not the only two in here.
Let's see. OK, no one there.
Nope. Nada.
There's somebody.
Hey! Excuse...
Dory, Dory, Dory!
Now it's my turn.
I'm thinking of something
dark and mysterious.
It's a fish we don't know.
If we ask it directions...
it could ingest us
and spit out our bones!
What is it with men
and asking for directions?
I don't want to play
the gender card right now.
Let's play
the "Let's Not Die" card.
- You want to get out of here?
- Of course I do.
How are we gonna do that
unless we give it a shot?
Dory, you don't
fully understand...
Come on. Trust me on this.
All right.
Excuse me! Little fella?
Hello! Don't be rude. Say Hi.
Ha. Hello.
- His son Bingo...
- Nemo.
- Nemo was taken to...
- Sydney.
Sydney! And it's
really, really important...
that we get there
as fast as we can...
so can you help us out?
Come on, little fella. Come on.
Dory, I'm a little fella.
I don't think
that's a little fella.
Oh! Big fella. Whale. OK.
Maybe he only speaks whale.
Mooo! Weee neeed...
- Dory?
- Tooo fiind his son.
What are you doing?
Are you sure you speak whale?
Can youuuu give us
diiirectionsss?
Dory! Heaven knows
what you're saying!
- See, he's swimming away.
- Cooome baaack.
He's not coming back.
You offended him.
Maybe a different dialect.
Dory!
This is not whale.
You're speaking upset stomach.
- Maybe I should try humpback.
- Don't.
- You actually sound sick.
- Maybe louder?
- Rah! Rah!
- Don't do that!
Too much orca.
Didn't it sound orca-ish?
It doesn't sound orca.
It sounds like nothing
I've ever heard.
It's just as well.
He might be hungry.
Whales don't eat clownfish.
They eat krill.
- Swim away!
- Oh, look, krill!
Move, Dory, move!
Look at that.
Would you look at that?
Filthy. Absolutely filthy.
All thanks to you, kid.
You made it possible.
Jacques, I said no cleaning.
I am ashamed.
Look! Scum angel!
Bubbles! I love the bubbles!
Flo? Has anybody seen Flo?
9:00 and cue dentist.
Hello, Barbara. Sorry I'm late.
OK, here we go. Here we go, OK.
Little Davey Reynolds...
Walks to the counter,
drops the keys...
Bloat, that's disgusting!
Tastes pretty good to me.
- Urrrp!
- Eww!
Don't you people realize
we are swimming in our own...
Here he comes!
Crikey. What a state.
Barbara, what's my earliest
appointment tomorrow?
- 10:00, luv.
- Leave it open, would you?
I've gotta clean the fish tank
before Darla gets here.
Did you hear that, Sharkbait?
Yay! He's gonna clean the tank!
We're gonna be clean!
You ready to see your dad, kid?
Of course you are.
I wouldn't be surprised
if he's out there...
in the harbor
waiting for you right now.
Yeah.
Here comes the big one.
Come on! You gotta try this!
- Will you just stop it?
- Why? What's wrong?
We're in a whale,
don't you get it?
- Whale?
- A whale!
You had to ask for help!
And now we're stuck here!
A whale. I speak whale.
No, you're insane!
You can't speak whale!
I have to get out!
I have to find my son!
I have to tell him
how old sea turtles are!
Hey...
you OK?
There, there. It's all right.
It'll be OK.
No. No, it won't.
Sure it will. You'll see.
No. I promised him I'd never
let anything happen to him.
That's a funny thing
to promise.
What?
You can't never let
anything happen to him.
Then nothing
would ever happen to him.
Not much fun for little Harpo.
What's going on?
Don't know. I'll ask him.
- Dory...
- Whaaat's goooing onnn?
I think he says we've stopped.
Of course we've stopped.
Stop trying to speak whale.
You'll make things worse.
What is that noise?
Oh, no. Look what you did.
The water's going down.
It's going down!
Really? You sure about that?
Look! Already it's half empty!
I'd say it's half full.
Stop that! It's half empty!
OK, that one
was a little tougher.
He either said we should go
to the back of the throat...
or he wants a root beer float.
Of course he wants us
to go there!
That's eating us!
How do I taste, Moby?
Do I taste good?
Tell him I'm not interested
in being lunch!
- OK. Heee...
- Stop talking to him!
What is going on?
I'll check. Whaaat...
No more whale!
You can't speak whale!
- Yes, I can!
- No, you can't!
You think you can do these
things, but you can't, Nemo!
- OK.
- Dory! Oof!
He says it's time to let go.
Everything's gonna be
all right.
How do you know?
How do you know something bad
isn't gonna happen?
I don't!
We're alive!
Look! Sy-d-ney... Sydney!
Sydney! Sydney again!
You were right, Dory!
We made it!
We're gonna find my son!
Thaaank yoouuu, sirrr!
I wish I could speak whale.
All we gotta do is find
the boat that took him.
- Right!
- We can do this!
Morning.
It's morning, everyone!
Today's the day!
The sun is shining,
the tank is clean...
and we are getting out...
The tank is clean.
The tank is clean!
But how?
Boss must've installed it
while we were sleeping.
- What are we gonna do?
- What's it say, Peach?
I can't hear you, Peach.
The Aquascum 2003 is
an all-purpose, self-cleaning...
maintenance-free,
salt water purifier...
that is guaranteed to extend
the life of your aquarium fish.
Stop it!
The Aquascum
is programmed to scan...
your tank environment
every five minutes?!
Scan? What does that mean?
Temperature... 82 degrees...
PH balance... normal.
Nice.
Curse you, Aquascum!
That's it for the escape plan.
It's ruined.
Then what are
we gonna do about...
Darla!
Stay down, kid!
False alarm.
My nerves can't take
much more of this.
What'll we do
when that brat gets here?
- I'm thinking.
- Oh! Gill!
- Nemo! I'm coming!
- Help me! Help me!
Swim down! Come on, kid!
- Everybody jump in!
- Swim down!
- That's it!
- What the...?
- Yay!
- Good work!
Gill!
- Nemo!
- Sharkbait!
- Roll, kid!
- Lean! Lean!
Whoops.
That would've been a nasty fall.
Gill! Don't let me go belly-up!
Just calm down, Nemo.
You won't go belly-up.
I promise. You're gonna be OK.
Darla!
Do any of these boats
look familiar to you?
No, but the boat
has to be here somewhere.
Come on, Dory.
We're gonna find it.
I'm totally excited.
Are you excited?
Dory, wake up.
Wake up, come on.
Duck!
That's not a duck.
It's a... pelican!
No! I didn't come this far
to be breakfast!
Hey, Nigel.
Would you look at that?
What? What?
Sun's barely up and Gerald's
had more than he can handle.
Yeah. Reckon somebody
ought to help the poor guy.
Yeah, right. Yeah.
Don't everybody
fly off at once.
All right, Gerald.
Fish got your tongue?
Love a duck!
I gotta find my son Nemo!
Nemo? He's that fish!
The one that's been fighting
the whole ocean!
I know where your son...
Wait! Come back! Stop!
Dory, keep going! He's crazy!
I got something to tell you!
Mine.
Don't make any sudden moves.
Hop inside my mouth
if you want to live.
Hop in your mouth?
How does that make me live?
Mine?
Because
I can take you to your son.
- Yeah, right.
- No. I know your son.
He's orange with
a gimpy fin on one side.
That's Nemo!
Mine! Mine! Mine! Mine!
Fasten your seat belts!
Mine! Mine! Mine! Mine! Mine!
Mine! Mine! Mine! Mine!
Everybody hold on!
Mine! Mine! Mine! Mine! Mine!
Too loud! Too loud for me!
Twinkle, twinkle, little star
Find a happy place!
Darla, your uncle
will see you now.
All right, let's see
those pearly whites.
Raah! I'm a piranha.
They're in the Amazon.
And a piranha's a fish,
just like your present.
I get fishy, fishy
Oh, no. Poor little guy.
- He's dead.
- Sharkbait!
Yay! Fishy, fishy, fishy!
Must've left your present
in the car, sweetie.
I'll go and get it.
- He's still alive!
- He's not dead!
What's happening?
Why is he playing dead?
He's gonna get flushed
down the toilet.
- He's gonna get out of here!
- He's gonna get flushed!
What a smart little guy!
Oh, no! Not the trash can!
Nemo! No!
- Hey! I found his dad!
- Where's Nemo?
- Dentist!
- He's over there!
What's a dentist?
Nigel, get in there!
- I can't go in there!
- Yes, you can! Charge!
What the...?
Darla, sweetie, look out!
Hold still!
Easy! Easy!
Nobody's going to hurt you!
Oof!
Nemo.
Oh, my goodness.
Gotcha! Keep down!
Nemo!
Daddy?
Out with you! And stay out!
Fishy?
Fishy! Wake up!
Oh, no!
To the top of
Mount Wannahockaloogie!
Why are you sleeping?
- Hurry!
- Bloat!
Ring of Fire!
Fishy!
Crikey! All the animals
have gone mad!
Aaah! Get it out!
- Smack her in the head!
- Go, Gill, go!
Fish in my hair!
Gill!
Sharkbait...
tell your dad I said hi.
Go get 'em!
- He did it!
- Yay!
- I'm so happy!
- Is he gonna be OK, Gill?
Don't worry.
All drains lead to the ocean.
Fishy!
Daddy!
I'm so sorry.
Truly, I am.
- Hey.
- Dory...
if it wasn't for you...
I never would've even
made it here.
So, thank you.
Hey, wait a minute.
Wait. Where are you going?
It's over, Dory.
We were too late.
Nemo's gone,
and I'm going home now.
No. No, you can't.
Stop!
Please don't go away.
Please?
No one's ever stuck with me
for so long before.
And if you leave, I just...
I remember things
better with you.
I do. Look... P. Sherman, 42...
42...
I remember it.
I do. It's there.
I know it is because
when I look at you...
I can feel it.
I look at you
and I... I'm home.
Please...
I don't want that to go away.
I don't want to forget.
I'm sorry, Dory, but I do.
- Manna from heaven.
- Sweet nectar of life!
Hey! Hey! Hey!
- This is our spot!
- Get outta here!
Hey! Hey! Hey!
Yeah, that's it, fella.
Just keep on swimmin'.
You got that.
Too right, mate!
Oh! I got a live one here!
Have you seen my dad?
Gotcha! Hey! Hey!
Come back here!
You let him go!
Hey! Hey!
Dad! Dad!
Dad!
Excuse me.
Are you all right?
I don't know where I am.
I don't know what's going on.
I think I lost somebody,
but I can't remember.
It's OK.
I'm looking for someone, too.
Hey, we can look together.
I'm Dory.
I'm Nemo.
Nemo? That's a nice name.
- Dad!
Wait a minute.
Is it your dad or my dad?
- My dad.
- Got it. Dad!
- Where are we, anyway?
- Dad! Dad!
Oh. Syl... Shi... Sydney.
P. Sherman,
42 Wallaby Way, Sydney.
Nemo!
It's you! You're Nemo!
Yes, yes, I'm Nemo!
You're Nemo!
You were dead. I saw you.
And here you are! I found you.
You're not dead.
And your father... Your father!
You know my father?!
Where is he?
This way!
He went this way. Quick!
Hey, hey, hey!
Hey! Hey!
Have you seen
an orange fish swim by?
- It looks just like him!
- But bigger!
Yeah, I saw him, bluey.
But I'm not tellin' you
where he went...
and there's no way
you're gonna make me.
Mine.
All right! I'll talk!
He went to the fishing grounds!
Hey, look out!
I'm sorry.
I'm just trying to get home.
Dad! Dad!
Nemo?
- Daddy!
- Nemo?
- Dad!
- Nemo's alive!
Dory? Nemo!
Daddy!
Nemo! I'm coming, Nemo!
- Dad!
- Nemo! Thank goodness.
It's all right, son.
It's gonna be OK.
Turn around!
You're going the wrong way!
Look out!
Oh, my...
Help! He-e-elp!
- Dory!
- Come on!
Help! Help!
Help! Get us out!
No, no, no! Dory!
- Dad, I know what to do!
- Nemo! No!
We have to tell all the fish
to swim down together!
- Get out of there now!
- I know this will work!
No, I am not
gonna lose you again!
There's no time!
It's the only way to save Dory!
I can do this.
You're right.
I know you can.
- Lucky fin!
- Now, go! Hurry!
Tell all the fish to swim down!
Well? You heard my son!
Come on!
Dory, you have
to tell everybody to...
Swim down together!
Do you understand
what I'm saying to you?
Swim down!
Everybody swim down!
Come on, you have to swim down!
Down! Swim down!
Swim down! Swim down!
Don't give up! Keep swimming!
Just keep swimming!
That's it!
It's working!
Keep swimming! Keep swimming!
Just keep swimming!
Keep swimming!
Come on, Dad!
- You're doing great, son!
- That's my dad.
Let's get to the bottom!
Keep swimming!
Just keep swimming,
just keep swimming
Almost there! Keep swimming!
Keep swimming!
- Oof!
- Hey!
- Dory! Where's Nemo?
- There!
Oh, no. Nemo!
Nemo?
It's OK. Daddy's here.
Daddy's got you.
Daddy?
Oh, thank goodness.
Dad... I don't hate you.
Oh, no, no, no.
I'm so sorry, Nemo.
- Hey, guess what?
- What?
Sea turtles... I met one.
And he was 150 years old.
- 150?
- Yep.
Sandy Plankton said
they only live to be 100.
Sandy Plankton?
Do you think I would
cross the entire ocean...
and not know as much
as Sandy Plankton?
He was 150! Not 100!
Who is this Sandy Plankton
who knows everything?
Time for school!
Get up! Let's go!
- I'm gonna win!
- No, you're not!
- I did it!
- Aw, my own son beats me!
Climb aboard, explorers.
The sea cucumber looks over
to the mollusk and says...
"With fronds like these,
who needs anemones?"
Hello, Nemo. Who's this?
- Exchange student.
- I'm from the E.A.C., dude!
- Sweet!
- Totally.
Seriously, Marty.
Did you really do all
the things you say you did?
Pardon me.
Hello.
Don't be alarmed.
We wanted to make sure our
newest member got home safely.
- Thanks, guys.
- See you next week.
- Keep up with the program.
- Remember, fish are friends...
Not food! Bye!
Hold on, here we go!
Next stop... knowledge!
Bye, son! Have fun!
Bye, Dad!
Oh! Mr. Ray, wait.
I forgot something.
Love you, Dad.
I love you, too, son.
Dad? You can let go now.
Sorry. Go have an adventure.
Good-bye! See ya later, dudes!
- Bye, Elmo!
- Nemo.
- Bye, Nemo!
- See you after school, Dory!
Bye, Dad!
Bye, son.
Barbara, I don't understand it.
Here this thing has
a lifetime guarantee...
and it breaks!
I had to clean the tank myself,
take all the fish out...
put 'em in bags, and...
Where'd the fish go?
- Come on, Peach!
- Hurry!
- You can do it!
- That's it.
Just a little further.
That's the shortest
red light I've ever seen!
Come on, Peach!
Now what?
Somewhere
Beyond the sea
Somewhere, waitin' for me
My lover stands on golden sands
And watches the ships
That go sailin'
Somewhere
Beyond the sea
She's there watchin' for me
if I could fly
like birds on high
Then straight to her arms
I'll go sailin'
It's far
Beyond the stars
It's near, beyond the moon
I know
Beyond a doubt
My heart
Will lead me there soon
We'll meet
Beyond the shore
We'll kiss just like before
Happy we'll be beyond the sea
And never again
I'll go sailin'
I know
Beyond a doubt
My heart
Will lead me there soon
Oh, we'll meet,
I know we'll meet
Beyond the shore
We'll kiss just as before
Happy we will be beyond the sea
And never again
I'll go sailin'
No more sailin'
So long, sailin', sailin'
Good-bye, farewell, my friend
No more sailin'
So long
Sailin'
No more sailin'
No more
Farewell
Auf wiedersehen
Adieu to you and you
No more sailin'
No more
No more, no more
No more sailin'
No more
One more time
No more sailin'