Why didn't you go with them?
Because I want this whole
damned ship to turn back.
Don't mess with me.
I'll do what I like around here.
Just keep the engine running.
Those bastards!
Suddenly they were all there
with their rifles.
I told you all along they were no good.
They'll never make it out of here.
There's only three of us left.
You, me and Cholo.
What, him?
Now we really need some Italian opera.
Don't you agree?
That's the end of it.
The dream is over.
Can you turn here?
A bit narrow, but it'll work.
It won't work.
Did you say something?
Turn around.
Do you see what I see?
Just what we needed.
Breaking through there
would be the end of us.
There's just one way to go...
straight ahead.
You better pull ashore.
Go down to the engine room,
very casually.
They're armed...
with bows and arrows.
But they're keeping their distance.
Ever seen this before?
No, never.
Damn it, now they are
blocking the way.
Are they still there?
Even more of them now.
Maybe a hundred canoes.
Give me a shout when the fun begins.
I wanna brighten up my last hour
with a little fireworks.
Brethren, what time is it, anyway?
Over here, bare-asses,
I'll pour you a beer.
Hurry up, I'll buy you a drink.
Where did you come from?
I just had a nap. Have the others quit?
Shut up!
What do they say?
They're talking about our ship...
...the "white vessel" from which
they expect the promised salvation.
They say there's a curse
weighing on the entire land.
They know that we are not gods,
but the ship has really impressed them.
But why do they play the flute?
What is happening?
My friends, I think we will continue.
See the red cliff on the right hand side?
Yes, I see it.
That must be it.
Good. We can't go much further,
or we'll run onto a sandbank.
That slope may look insignificant...
...but it's gonna be my destiny.
Come on, follow me!
Now he's showing his cards.
This is it.
This is what we were looking for.
Here? This?
Do we have to climb a tree
for you dimwits to understand?
We'll build a nice platform
for the gentlemen. Up there.
I can hardly believe it.
There. There's the Ucayali.
All the river above the
Pongo das Mortes belongs to us.
I know, I know.
We'll make a railway tunnel.
No.
We're going to drag that
ship over the mountain.
And the bare-asses
are going to help us.
How the hell are we going to do that?
Just like the cow jumped
over the moon.
I like this.
Count me in.
Come in.
What is it?
I still don't understand
what you've got in mind.
Come in. I'll show you.
This...
...is the Amazon.
Here is Iquitos.
This...
...is the Ucayali.
Right?
And here...
...this is the Pachitea.
So, first we went up the Amazon...
...and then up the Pachitea.
We are here right now...
...and we'll drag the ship
over this mountain.
Exactly there.
From here to here
we'll operate the ship...
...to collect rubber from
thousands of workers.
Why didn't we move up the Ucayali?
Because of the Pongo das Mortes.
Nobody will ever make it
through those rapids.
Yes, but how do you get the rubber
to Iquitos? We need another ship.
We'll carry it back over the mountain
and build a settlement there.
Soon we'll be so rich we'll have all
the ships we need to take it to Iquitos.
- I've explained our project to the Chief.
- What's his answer?
He just says yes.
More to the left.
A little more.
Stop!
Again, a bit more to the left.
A little more.
Stop!
Yes, yes!
T-square at 42 degrees.
Not a bad start, was it?
Right.
There are even children here.
It's a good sign.
What do you think, Paul...
...will the Indians stick with us?
You can't tell what they really think.
But how the hell are we gonna
get that ship over the hill?
If nothing else works,
then we'll make a tunnel.
I could even do it alone...
...if we had a perfect pulley system.
But I would need ten miles of rope
and it would take me ten weeks...
...to pull the ship ten inches.
Unfortunately, we haven't
got that much time.
We have seven more months
before the option runs out.
We have a winch and the
strength of hundreds of Indians.
We are going to drag this ship
over the mountain.
Who are your little friends?
McNamara, he's my footman.
And this is el comandante.
Here's to you, McNamara.
This is much steeper than we thought.
Now, with the trees cut down...
...you can really see how steep it is.
We have to level the ground,
build a ramp.
And up there we'll have to make
a cut through to the top.
That could take months.
Dynamite!
I hope we have enough dynamite.
Careful, that'll frighten the bare-asses.
We have no choice.
Take cover! Get back!
Watch out! Danger!
Hold it, hold it! Where are you going?
Now go back to work, come on.
Those logs up there.
Huerequeque, come here.
How can this trunk withstand
the pull of hundreds of tons?
It will. See how deep we have
anchored it in the ground.
As tough as iron.
Bring it down here!
Huerequeque, come with me.
Go on.
Slowly.
If we had known that you planned...
...to move the boat on railway tracks...
...I could have told you to
leave the tracks right there...
...back at your Amazon station.
Sorry I can't help you.
I had a bit too much to drink yesterday.
Shouldn't we tell him that it
melts away to nothing?
Doesn't work. There's no
word for ice in their language.
Come on, get out of there!
Out! Out!
Give it a go!
Give it all you got!
I'll be damned...
It's working.
It's moving.
- It's moving!
Watch out!
They've been staring at the river for
two days and two nights now.
I'm sure it's because of
the terrible accident.
I can't get anything out of them.
And?
They're gone.
All of them?
They've really disappeared?
What do you make of this?
I had this strange feeling,
so I went outside.
Not a soul, nothing.
They've all disappeared.
That can mean anything.
It could mean that they'll attack us.
But the boy is still here.
My footman, McNamara.
For that he'll be made Chief one day.
They're back as if they'd
never been gone.
Don't ask me for an explanation.
I can't believe this crazy thing
Huerequeque has thought up.
Amigos, the engine is running.
Now that's what I call brainwork.
All you do is drink!
We could start up the engine and
drive the anchor winch off of it.
That way the ship will pull itself up
the mountain under it's own steam.
Now, what do you say to that?
There are times when a peasant's
brain is good for something.
You ain't no peasant!
You're the finest drunkard ever
to stagger over this earth.
- But we forgot something.
- What?
Enrico! Enrico Caruso!
Why are they doing all this?
Why are they working like dogs for us?
Why?
Why? Why?
- Why?
- No, I don't know either.
The only thing I know is that
there must be a reason for it.
They're planning something, I bet.
You must drink it.
It is yucca.
Yucca with fermented saliva.
Go on, drink!
My God, time is flying
and we are getting nowhere.
Something's up.
The men are preparing barbasco,
a very strong poison.
And they are painted black.
But most of the men have hidden in the
woods and have armed themselves.
What does that mean?
As far as I know, the paint is
supposed to make them invisible.
They only do that when they go
hunting or when they go to war.
Let's return to the ship,
load our rifles.
We wouldn't stand a chance.
It seems to me that they
are planning something.
And I fear that we four will soon
end up as shrunken heads.
I think we're safe for the moment.
How do you know?
There is a sign.
Look...
See those hands on the railing?
What has happened?
The Pongo! We're drifting into
the Pongo! Cholo!
Cholo!
Paul! Cholo!
I must stop the ship!
Start the fire!
We're drifting into the Pongo!
The valves first!
For God's sake, my ship!
Damn it.
Now it's too late.
Do you know what he says?
He says they untied the boat last night.
They knew all along the divine vessel
was only dragged over the mountain...
...so that it could drift
through the rapids.
It had to be done to soothe
the evil spirits of the rapids.
I must stop my ship.
First of all, have a drink.
Running the Pongo das Mortes
with a steamship...
...is a record that will
never be repeated.
Here, have a drink.
Wonderful, gentlemen.
Quite spectacular.
Here's to the reconciliation
of the evil spirits of the Pongo.
I'll tell you a story.
At the time when North America
was hardly explored...
...one of those early French trappers
went westward from Montreal...
...and he was the first white man
to set eyes on Niagara Falls.
When he returned, he told of waterfalls
that were more vast and immense...
...than people had ever dreamed of.
But no one believed him.
They thought he was
a madman or a liar.
They asked him, "What's your proof?"
And he answered...
"My proof is...
...that I have seen them."
Sorry.
I don't really know what that's
got to do with me.
What will you do next?
I don't know.
I'm asking because I'm interested
in buying the boat back.
My business has been
expanding lately.
The damage could be repaired
in a few days.
Oh, I assure you, I don't mean to
exploit your delicate situation.
I just heard, that a European opera
ensemble has arrived in Manaus...
...to give a guest performance there.
Perhaps you should go there.
They are performing an opera of this
fantastic German composer.
One of the very modern ones.
Federico, Roberto... Ricardo...
What's his name, Ricardo...?
Wagner?
He's the one who wrote Parsifal.
Yes, I guess that's the one.
Very Teutonic, his music.
And the name of the Opera
is "The Puritans".
No, no, that's an Italian opera, by Bellini.
Tell me...
...did you mean that about the boat?
Hey, Cholo, Huerequeque,
come over here!
Come on.
Paul, this is the new
owner of the Molly Aida.
But we still have the
ship for two more weeks.
Paul, listen.
You'll travel to Manaus
with all this money.
You'll bring back a tailcoat and
the best cigar in the world.
And from the theater I want
an armchair with red velvet upholstery.
I have to keep a promise to a pig
that loves Caruso so much.
And then...