Jenny and me were just like
peas and carrots again.
She showed me around
and even introduced me
to some of her new friends.
Shut that blind, man!
And get your white ass
away from that window.
Don't you know we in a war here?
He's cool.
He's one of us.
Let me tell you about us.
Our purpose here is
to protect our black leaders
from the racial
onslaught of the pig
who wishes to brutalize
our black leaders,
rape our women, and destroy
our black communities.
Who's the baby killer?
This is my good friend
I told you about.
This is Forrest Gump.
Forrest, this is Wesley.
Wesley and I
lived together in Berkeley,
and he's the president
of the Berkeley chapter of SDS.
We are here to offer
protection and help
for all those
who need our help,
because we,
the Black Panthers,
are against the war in Vietnam.
We are against any war
where black soldiers
are sent to the front line
to die for a country
that hates them.
We are against any war
where black soldiers go to fight
and come to be brutalized and
killed in their own communities.
We are against
these racist and imperial acts...
~ And I gave her the gun ~
~ I shot her ~
Forrest!
Stop it!
Stop it! Stop it!
I shouldn't have
brought you here.
I should have known it was going
to be some bullshit hassle!
He should not be
hitting you, Jenny.
Come on, Forrest.
Sorry I had a fight in the middle
of your Black Panther party.
He doesn't mean it
when he does things like this.
I would never hurt you, Jenny.
I know you wouldn't,
Forrest.
I wanted to be your boyfriend.
That uniform is a trip, Forrest.
You look handsome in it.
You do.
You know what?
What?
I'm glad we were here together
in our nation's capital.
Me, too, Forrest.
We walked around
all night, Jenny and me,
just talkin'.
She told me about
all the traveling she'd done
and how she discovered
ways to expand her mind
and learn how
to live in harmony...
which must be
out west somewhere,
'cause she made it
all the way to California.
~ Love one another right now ~
Hey.
Anybody want to go
to San Francisco?
I'll go.
Far out!
It was a very special night
for the two of us.
I didn't want it to end.
Wish you wouldn't go, Jenny.
I have to, Forrest.
Jenny?
Things got
a little out of hand.
It's just this war
and that lying
son of a bitch Johnson and...
I would never hurt you.
You know that.
Know what I think?
I think...
you should go home to Greenbow,
Alabama!
Forrest,
we have very
different lives, you know.
I want you...
to have this.
Forrest, I can't keep this.
I got it...
just by doing
what you told me to do.
Why are you so good to me?
You're my girl.
I'll always be your girl.
~ To everything,
turn, turn, turn ~
~ There is a season,
~ And a time to every purpose ~
~ Under heaven ~
And just like that,
she was gone
out of my life again.
That's one small step for man,
one giant leap for mankind.
I thought I was
going back to Vietnam,
but instead they decided
the best way for me
to fight the Communists
was to play Ping-Pong,
so I was in the Special Services,
traveling around the country,
cheering up wounded veterans
and showing 'em
how to play Ping-Pong.
I was so good
that some years later,
the army decided I should be
on the all-American Ping-Pong team.
We were the first Americans
to visit the land of China
in a million years or something.
Somebody said world peace
was in our hands,
but all I did was play Ping-Pong.
When I got home,
I was a national celebrity,
famouser even
than Captain Kangaroo.
Here he is, Forrest Gump.
Right here.
Gump, have a seat.
Forrest Gump, John Lennon.
Welcome home.
Can you tell us, um,
what was China like?
In the land of China...
people hardly got nothin'at all.
No possessions?
And in China,
they never go to church.
No religion, too?
Oh.
Hard to imagine.
Well, it's easy if you try, Dick.
Some years later,
that nice young man from England
was on his way home
to see his little boy
and was signing some autographs.
For no particular reason at all,
somebody shot him.
They gave you...
the congressional Medal of Honor.
Now, that's Lieutenant Dan.
Lieutenant Dan!
They gave you...
the congressional
Medal of Honor.
Yes, sir.
They surely did.
They gave you,
an imbecile,
a moron who goes on television
and makes a fool out of himself
in front of
the whole damn country,
the Congressional
Medal of Honor.
Yes, sir.
Well... that...
that's just perfect!
Yeah, well, I just got
one thing to say to that...
Goddamn bless America.
Hey, hey!
Whoa...
Oh, God, whoa!
Ow! Oh! Oh, God!
Lieutenant Dan!
Lieutenant Dan said
he was living in a hotel
and because he didn't
have no legs,
he spent most of his time
exercising his arms.
Make a right. Take a right!
Hey!
Ah, ah!
What do you do here
in New York, Lieutenant Dan?
I'm living off
the government tit.
[Honk]
Hey, hey, hey, are you blind?
I'm walking here!
Ah, get out!
Come on. Go, go, go!
[Singing Silent Night]
I stayed with Lieutenant Dan
and celebrated the holidays.
You have a great year,
and hurry home.
God bless you.
Have you found
Jesus yet, Gump?
I didn't know I was supposed
to be looking for Him, sir.
That's all these cripples
down at the V. A...
That's all they ever
talk about.
Jesus this
and Jesus that. Ha.
Have I... found Jesus?
They even had a priest
come and talk to me.
He said God is listening,
but I have to help myself.
Now, if I accept Jesus
into my heart,
I'll get to walk beside Him
in the kingdom of heaven.
Did you hear what I said?
Walk...
beside Him
in the kingdom of heaven.
Well... kiss my crippled ass.
God is listening?
What a crock of shit.
I'm going to heaven,
Lieutenant Dan.
Oh?
Well...
before you go...
why don't you
get your ass
down to the corner
and get us more Ripple?
Yes, sir.
We're at approximately
45th Street in New York City
at One Astor Plaza.
This is the site of the old...
What the hell is
in Bayou La Batre?
Shrimping boats.
Shrimping boats? Who gives
a shit about shrimping boats?
I got to buy me one
soon as I have some money.
I promised Bubba in Vietnam
that as soon as the war
was over, we'd be partners.
He'd be the captain
and I'd be his first mate.
But now that he's dead,
I got to be the captain.
A shrimp boat captain.
Yes, sir. A promise
is a promise, Lieutenant Dan.
Now hear this!
Private Gump here
is gonna be
a shrimp boat captain.
Well, I tell you what, Gilligan.
The day that you are
a shrimp boat captain,
I will come and be
your first mate.
Ha ha ha!
If you're ever
a shrimp boat captain,
that's the day
I'm an astronaut!
Danny, what are you
complaining about?
Danny, how you doing, huh?
Mr. Hot Wheels!
Who's your friend?
My name is Forrest.
Forrest Gump.
This is cunning Carla
and long-limbs Lenore.
So where you been,
babycakes, huh?
Haven't seen you
around lately.
You should have been here
for Christmas,
'cause Tommy bought a free round
and gave everybody
a turkey sandwich.
Well, well,
I had, uh... company.
Hey! Hey, we was just there!
That's like Times Square.
Don't you just love New Year's?
You can start all over.
Everybody gets a second chance.
It's funny...
but in the middle
of all that fun,
I began to think about Jenny,
wondering how she was
spending her New Year's night
out in California.
~ Don't you love her ways? ~
~ Tell me what you say ~
~ Don't you love her madly? ~
~ Want to meet her daddy? ~
~ Don't you love her face? ~
~ Don't you love her
as she's walkin' out the door? ~
9... 8...
7... 6...
5... 4...
3... 2...
1!
[Crowd]
Happy new year!
[Toot]
~ Should auld acquaintance
be forgot ~
~ And never brought to mind ~
Happy new year, Lieutenant Dan!
~ Should auld acquaintance
be forgot ~
~ In days of auld lang syne ~
~ Together we stand ~
~ Divided we fall ~
~ Come on now, people, let's ~
~ Get on the ball ~
~ And work together ~
~ Come on, come on ~
~ Let's work together ~
Oh! What are you,
stupid or something?
What's your problem?
What's his problem?
Did you lose your packet
in the war or something?
Is your friend
stupid or something?
What did you say?
I said is your friend
stupid or something?
Don't call him stupid!
Hey, don't push her!
You shut up!
Don't you ever call him stupid!
Come on, baby,
why you being so upset, huh?
Get your goddamned clothes
and get the hell out of here!
You should be in a sideshow.
You're so pathetic!
Get out of here!
You big guy!
Loser. You freak!
Oh, no. No.
I'm sorry I ruined
your New Year's Eve party,
Lieutenant Dan.
She tastes like cigarettes.
I guess Lieutenant Dan figured
there's some things
you just can't change.
He didn't want
to be called crippled
just like I didn't
want to be called stupid.
Happy new year, Gump.
The U.S. Ping-Pong team
met with President Nixon today...
Wouldn't you know it?
A few months later,
they invited me
and the Ping-Pong team
to visit the White House.
So I went...
again.
And I met the president
of the United States again.
Only this time,
they didn't get us rooms
in a real fancy hotel.
Are you enjoying yourself
in our nation's capital,
young man?
Where are you staying?
It's called the Hotel Ebbott.
Oh, no, no, no.
I know a much nicer hotel.
It's brand-new. Very modern.
I'll have my people
take care of it.
Security.
Yeah. Sir,
you might want to send
a maintenance man
over to that office
across the way.
The lights are off
and they must be looking
for a fuse box,
'cause them flashlights,
they're keeping me awake.
O.K., sir.
I'll check it out.
Thank you. Good night.
Therefore...
I shall resign the presidency
effective at noon tomorrow.
Vice President Ford
will be sworn in as president
at that hour in this office.
Forrest Gump.
Yes, sir!
As you were.
I have your discharge papers.
Service is up, son.
Does this mean I can't
play Ping-Pong no more?
For the army, it does.
And just like that,
my service in
the United States Army was over.
So I went home.
I'm home, Mama.
I know. I know.
Louise, he's here.
Now, when I got home,
I had no idea,
but Mama had all sorts
of visitors.
We've had all sorts of visitors.
Everybody wants you
to use their Ping-Pong stuff.
One man even left
a check for $25,000
if you'd be agreeable to saying
you like using their paddle.
I only like using
my own paddle.
Hi, Miss Louise.
Hey, Forrest.
I know that,
but it's $25,000, Forrest.
I thought maybe
you could hold it for a while,
see if it grows on you.
That Mama, she sure was right.
It's funny how things work out.
I didn't stay home for long
because I'd made
a promise to Bubba,
and I always try
to keep my promise,
so I went on down
to Bayou La Batre
to meet Bubba's family.
Are you crazy
or just plain stupid?
Stupid is as stupid does,
Mrs. Blue.
I guess.
And, of course,
I paid my respect
to Bubba himself.
Hey, Bubba.
It's me, Forrest Gump.
I remember everything
you said,
and I got it
all figured out.
I'm taking $24,562.47
that I got, that's left
after a new haircut
and a new suit
and took Mama out
to a real fancy dinner,
and I bought a bus ticket,
then three Dr. Peppers.
Tell me something.
Are you stupid or something?
Stupid is as stupid does, sir.
That's what's left
after me saying,
"When I was in China on
the all-America Ping-Pong team,
"I just loved
playing Ping-Pong
with my Flex-O-Lite
Ping-Pong paddle,"
which everybody knows isn't true,
but Mama said it was just
a little white lie,
so it wasn't hurting nobody.
So anyway,
I'm putting all that
on gas, ropes, and new nets
and a brand-new shrimping boat.
Now Bubba told me everything
he knew about shrimping,
but you know what I found out?
Shrimping is tough.
I only caught five.
A couple more,
you can have yourself a cocktail.
Hey, you ever think about
naming this old boat?
It's bad luck to have
a boat without a name.
I'd never named a boat before,
but there was only one
I could think of,
the most beautiful name
in the wide world.
~ Do a little dance ~
~ Make a little love ~
~ Get down tonight ~
~ Do a little dance ~
~ Make a little love ~
~ Get down tonight ~
~ Whoo ~
~ Get down tonight... ~
Now, I hadn't heard from Jenny
in a long while,
but I thought about her a lot.
I hoped whatever
she was doing made her happy.
~ Oh, and the bird
you cannot change ~
~ And this bird
~ Lord knows I can't change ~
~ Lord, help me, I can't change ~
I thought about Jenny all the time.
Hey!
Lieutenant Dan,
what are you doing here?
Well, thought
I'd try out my sea legs.
Well, you ain't got no legs,
Lieutenant Dan.
Yes, I know that.
You wrote me a letter,
you idiot.
Well, well.
Captain Forrest Gump.
I had to see this for myself...
and...
I told you if you were ever
a shrimp boat captain,
that I'd be your first mate.
Well, here I am.
I'm a man of my word.
O.K.
But don't you be thinking
that I'm going
to be calling you "sir."
No, sir.
It's my boat.
I have a feeling
if we head due east,
we'll find some shrimp,
so take a left.
Take a left!
Which way?
Over there!
They're over there!
Get on the wheel
and take a left.
O.K.
Gump, what are you doing?
Take a left!
Left!
That's where we're going
to find those shrimp, my boy!
Ha ha!
That's where we'll find them.
Still no shrimp, Lieutenant Dan.
O.K., so I was wrong.
Well, how are we
going to find them?
Maybe you should
just pray for shrimp.
~ So pray that ~
~ I'm homeward bound... ~
So I went to church every Sunday.
Sometimes Lieutenant Dan came, too,
though I think he left
the praying up to me.
No shrimp.
Where the hell's
this God of yours?
It's funny Lieutenant Dan said that
'cause right then God showed up.
[Dan]
You'll never sink this boat!
Now, me, I was scared,
but Lieutenant Dan, he was mad.
Come on!
You call this a storm?
Come on, you son of a bitch!
It's time for a showdown!
You and me!
I'm right here!
Come and get me!
Ha ha! Ha ha!
You'll never sink...
this...
boat!
Ha ha ha ha!
Hurricane Carmen
came through here yesterday,
destroying nearly
everything in its path.
And as in other towns
up and down the coast,
Bayou La Batre's
entire shrimping industry
has fallen victim to Carmen
and has been left in utter ruin.
This reporter has learned,
in fact, only one shrimping boat
actually survived the storm.
Louise. Louise, there's Forrest.
[Gump]
After that, shrimping was easy.
~ There will be great bounty ~
~ Oh, my God... ~
Since people still
needed them shrimps
for shrimp cocktails
and barbecues and all
and we were the only boat
left standing,
Bubba Gump shrimp's
what they got.
We got a whole bunch of boats.
12 Jennys, big old warehouse.
We even have hats
that say "Bubba Gump" on them.
Bubba Gump Shrimp.
It's a household name.
Hold on there, boy.
Are you telling me
you're the owner
of the Bubba Gump
Shrimp Corporation?
Yes. We got more money
than Davy Crockett.
Boy, I heard some whoppers
in my time,
but that tops them all.
Ha ha ha ha!
We were sitting
next to a millionaire.
Well, I thought it was
a very lovely story,
and you tell it so well,
with such enthusiasm.
Would you like to see
what Lieutenant Dan looks like?
Yes, I would.
That's him right there.
Let me tell you
something about Lieutenant Dan.
Forrest...
I never thanked you
for saving my life.
He never actually said so,
but I think
he made his peace with God.
[Gunshots]
For the second time in 17 days,
President Ford escaped
possible assassination today.
Base to Jenny 1.
Jenny 1. Go, Margo.
Forrest has a phone call.
Yeah, well, you'll have
to tell them to call him back.
He is indisposed at the moment.
His mama's sick.
Where's Mama?
She's upstairs.
Hi, Forrest.
I'll see you tomorrow.
Oh, all right.
Sure got you straightened out,
didn't we, boy?
What's the matter, Mama?
I'm dying, Forrest.
Come on in,
sit down over here.
Why are you dying, Mama?
It's my time.
It's just my time.
Oh, now...
don't you be afraid,
sweetheart.
Death is just a part of life.
Something we're all
destined to do.
I didn't know it,
but I was destined
to be your mama.
I did the best I could.
You did good.
Well... I happen to believe
you make your own destiny.
You have to do the best
with what God gave you.
What's my destiny, Mama?
You're going to have
to figure that out for yourself.
Life is a box
of chocolates, Forrest.
You never know what
you're going to get.
Mama always had a way
of explaining things
so I could understand them.
I will miss you, Forrest.
She had got the cancer
and died on a Tuesday.
I bought her a new hat
with little flowers on it.
And that's all I have
to say about that.
Didn't you say you were waiting
for the number 7 bus?
There'll be another one
along shortly.
Now, because I had been
a football star and war hero
and national celebrity
and a shrimping boat captain
and a college graduate,
the city fathers
of Greenbow, Alabama,
decided to get together
and offered me a fine job.
So I never went back to work
for Lieutenant Dan,
though he did take care
of my Bubba Gump money.
He got me invested
in some kind of fruit company.
So then I got a call from him
saying we don't have to worry
about money no more,
and I said,
"That's good. One less thing."
~ I've got a new hope... ~
Now Mama said
there's only so much fortune
a man really needs,
and the rest
is just for showing off.
So I gave a whole bunch of it
to the Foursquare Gospel Church...
and I gave a whole bunch to the
Bayou La Batre Fishing Hospital...
and even though Bubba was dead
and Lieutenant Dan said I was nuts,
I gave Bubba's mama Bubba's share.
You know what?
She didn't have to work
in nobody's kitchen no more.
That smells wonderful.
And 'cause I was a gozillionaire
and I liked doing it so much,
I cut that grass for free.
But at nighttime
when there was nothing to do
and the house was all empty,
I'd always think of Jenny.
And then... she was there.
Hello, Forrest.
Hello, Jenny.
Jenny came back
and stayed with me.
Maybe it was because
she had nowhere else to go,
or maybe it was because
she was so tired
'cause she went to bed
and slept and slept
like she hadn't slept in years.
It was wonderful
having her home.
Every day we'd take a walk,
and I'd jabber on
like a monkey in a tree,
and she'd listen about
Ping-Ponging and shrimping
and Mama making
a trip up to heaven.
I did all the talking.
Jenny most of the time
was real quiet.
How could you do this?
Sometimes I guess there
just aren't enough rocks.
I never really knew
why she came back,
but I didn't care.
It was like olden times.
We was like
peas and carrots again.
Every day,
I'd pick pretty flowers
and put them in her room for her,
and she gave me the best gift
anyone could ever get
in the wide world.
They're made just for running.
~ Carry me home to see my kin ~
And she even showed me
how to dance.
~ I miss ol'Bammy once again ~
~ And I think it's a sin ~
~ Sweet home Alabama... ~
Well, we was like family,
Jenny and me...
and it was the happiest time
in my life.
You done watching it?
Mm-hmm.
I'm going to bed.
Will you marry me?
I'd make a good husband, Jenny.
You would, Forrest.
But you won't marry me.
You don't want to marry me.
Why don't you love me, Jenny?
I'm not a smart man,
but I know what love is.
Jenny...
Forrest, I do love you.
Where are you running off to?
I'm not running.
That day,
for no particular reason,
I decided to go for a little run.
So I ran to the end of the road,
and when I got there, I thought
maybe I'd run to the end of town.
[TV] President Carter,
suffering from heat exhaustion...
And when I got there,
I thought maybe I'd just
run across Greenbow County.
Now, I figured
since I'd run this far,
maybe I'd just run across
the great state of Alabama.
And that's what I did.
I ran clear across Alabama.
No particular reason.
I just kept on going.
I ran clear to the ocean.
And when I got there,
I figured since
I'd gone this far,
might as well turn around,
just keep on going.
And when I got to another ocean,
I figured since
I'd gone this far...
I might as well just turn back
and keep right on going.
When I got tired, I slept.
When I got hungry, I ate.
When I had to go...
you know...
I went.
And so...
you just ran.
Yeah.
~ Lookin' out at the road
rushin' under my wheels ~
~ Lookin' back
at the years gone by ~
~ Like so many summer fields ~
~ In '65, I was 17 ~
~ And runnin' up one on one ~
~ I don't know
where I'm runnin' now ~
~ I'm just runnin' on ~
~ Runnin' on ~
~ Runnin' on empty ~
~ Runnin' dry ~
~ Runnin' on... ~
I'd think a lot...
about Mama and Bubba
and Lieutenant Dan.
But most of all,
I thought about Jenny.
I thought about her a lot.
For more than two years,
a man named Forrest Gump,
a gardener from Greenbow, Alabama,
stopping only to sleep,
has been running across America.
Charles Cooper
brings you this report.
For the fourth time
on his journey across America,
Forrest Gump, the gardener
from Greenbow, Alabama,
is about to cross
the Mississippi River again today.
I'll be damned. Forrest?
Sir, where are you running?
Are you doing this
for world peace?
for the homeless?
Are you running
for women's rights?
The environment?
They just couldn't believe
that somebody would do
all that running
for no particular reason.
Why are you doing this?
I just felt like running.
I just felt like runnin'.
That's you.
I can't believe it's really you.
Now... for some reason,
what I was doing seemed to...
make sense to people.
It was like an alarm
went off in my head.
I said, "Here's a guy
that's got his act together.
Here's somebody
who has the answer."
I'll follow you
anywhere, Mr. Gump.
So I got company.
And after that,
I got more company.
And then, even
more people joined in.
Somebody later told me
it gave people hope.
Now...
Now, I don't know
anything about that,
but some of those people asked me
if I could help them out.
I was wondering
if you might help me.
I'm in the bumper sticker business.
I need a good slogan,
and since you've
been so inspirational,
I thought you might
be able to help me...
Whoa, man! You just ran
through a big pile of dog shit!
It happens.
What, shit?
Sometimes.
And some years later,
I heard that that fella
did come up with
a bumper sticker slogan
and made a lot of money
off of it.
Another time,
I was running along.
Somebody who'd lost all his money
in the T-shirt business,
he wanted to put my face
on a T-shirt,
but he couldn't draw that well,
and he didn't have a camera.
Here, use this one.
Nobody likes that color anyway.
[Horn Honks]
Have a nice day.
Some years later, I found out
that that man did come up
with an idea for a T-shirt.
He made a lot of money.
Anyway, like I was saying,
I had a lot of company.
My mama always said,
"You got to put the past
behind you
before you can move on. "
And I think that's
what my running was all about.
I had run for three years...
two months...
14 days, and 16 hours.
Quiet. Quiet.
He's going to say something.
I'm pretty tired.
Think I'll go home now.
Now what are we supposed to do?
And just like that...
my runnin'days was over.
So I went home to Alabama.
[TV]
Moments ago, at 2:25 P.M.,
as President Reagan
was leaving the...
[Gunshots]
Five or six gunshots were fired
by an unknown, would-be assassin.
The president was
shot in the chest...
I picked up the mail.
And one day, out
of the blue clear sky,
I got a letter from Jenny
wondering if I could
come down to Savannah
and see her, and that's
what I'm doing here.
Uh-huh.
She saw me on TV... running.
I'm supposed to go on
the number 9 bus to Richmond Street
and get off and go one block left
to 1947 Henry Street...
apartment 4.
Why, you don't need
to take a bus.
Henry Street is just
five or six blocks...
down that way.
Down that way?
Down that way.
It was nice talking to you.
[Horn Honks]
I hope everything
works out for you!
Hey!
Forrest!
How you doin'?
Come in! Come in!
I got your letter.
Oh, I was wondering
about that.
This your house?
Yeah. It's messy right now.
I just got off work.
It's nice.
You got air-conditioning.
Uh...
Thank you.
I ate some.
I, uh, kept... kept a scrapbook
of... of your clippings and...
everything. There you are.
Yes, I got you running.
I ran a long way.
It's a long time.
There...
Listen, Forrest,
I don't know how to say this.
Um...
I just...
I want to apologize
for anything that I ever
did to you 'cause...
I was messed up...
for a long time, and...
[Knock On Door]
Yoo-hoo!
Hey!
Hi.
Hey, you.
This is my old friend
from Alabama.
How do you do?
[Jenny] Next week
my schedule changes, so I can...
No problem. Got to go.
I'm double-parked.
O.K. Thanks.
This is my
very good friend Mr. Gump.
Can you say hi?
Hello, Mr. Gump.
Hello.
Can I go watch TV now?
Yes. Just keep it low.
You're a mama, Jenny.
I'm a mama.
His name's Forrest.
Like me!
I named him after his daddy.
He got a daddy
named Forrest, too?
You're his daddy, Forrest.
Hey...
Forrest, look at me.
Look at me, Forrest.
There's nothing you need to do.
You didn't do anything wrong.
O.K.?
Isn't he beautiful?
He's the most beautiful thing
I've ever seen.
But...
is... is he s-smart? Like, can he...
He's very smart.
He's one of
the smartest in his class.
Yeah, it's O.K.
Go talk to him.
What are you watching?
Bert and Ernie.
Forrest...
I'm sick.
What, do you have
a cough due to a cold?
I have some kind of virus,
and the doctors,
they don't know what it is,
and there isn't anything
they can do about it.
You could come home with me.
Jenny, you and...
little Forrest
could come stay
at my house in Greenbow.
I'll take care of you
if you're sick.
Would you marry me, Forrest?
O.K.
[Man]
Please take your seats.
Forrest?
It's time to start.
Hi.
Your tie.
Lieutenant Dan.
Hello, Forrest.
You got new legs.
New legs!
Yeah. I got new legs.
Custom-made.
Titanium alloy.
It's what they use
on the space shuttle.
Magic legs.
This...
is my fiance.
Susan.
Lieutenant Dan.
Hi, Forrest.
Lieutenant Dan...
this is my Jenny.
Hi. It's nice
to meet you finally.
Do you, Forrest, take Jenny
to be your wife?
Do you, Jenny, take Forrest
to be your husband?
And so I pronounce you
man and wife.
Hi.
Hey, Forrest...
were you scared in Vietnam?
Yes.
Well, l...
I don't know.
Sometimes it would stop raining
long enough for
the stars to come out...
and then it was nice.
It was like just
before the sun goes to bed
down on the bayou.
There was always
a million sparkles on the water...
like that mountain lake.
It was so clear, Jenny,
it looked like
there were two skies
one on top of the other.
And then in the desert,
when the sun comes up...
I couldn't tell
where heaven stopped
and the earth began.
It's so beautiful.
I wish I could've
been there with you.
You were.
I love you.
[Gump]
You died on a Saturday morning.
And I had you placed
here under our tree.
And I had that house
of your father's
bulldozed to the ground.
Mama...
always said
that dyin' was a part of life.
I sure wish it wasn't.
Little Forrest is...
doing just fine.
"But..."
About to start school again soon,
and...
and I make his breakfast,
lunch, and dinner
every day.
I make sure he...
combs his hair
and brushes his teeth every day.
Teaching him how
to play Ping-Pong.
He's really good.
Uh, Forrest, you go.
Uhh!
We fish a lot.
And every night,
we read a book.
He's so smart, Jenny.
You'd be so proud of him.
I am.
He, uh, wrote you
a... a letter.
And he says I can't read it.
I'm not supposed to,
so I'll just leave it
here for you.
Jenny...
I don't know
if Mama was right
or if it... it's
Lieutenant Dan.
I don't know...
if we each have a...
destiny...
or if we're all just
floating around accidental-like
on a breeze...
but l... I think...
maybe it's both.
Maybe both get happening
at the same time.
But I miss you, Jenny.
If there's anything
you need...
I won't be far away.
[Birds Chirping]
Here's your bus.
O.K.
Hey...
I know this.
I'm gonna share that
for show-and-tell
because Grandma used
to read it to you.
My favorite book.
Here we are.
Hey...
here you go.
Hey, Forrest...
don't...
I want to tell you
I love you.
I love you, too, Daddy.
I'll be right here
when you get back.
[Pop]
You understand this is the bus
to school, now, don't you?
Of course, and you're Dorothy
Harris, and I'm Forrest Gump.