May I leave now?
- Good bye!
- Bye.
Definite, come here.
He just left!
Fill up the tank.
Let's go...
Hey, Faizal...
Someone just shot your father.
Someone shot your dad.
Danish... wait, son.
- Get inside, mom!
- I want to come.
You should stay home.
Nothing will happen to dad.
Shama, take her inside.
Let me go with you, son.
Were'nt you supposed to
be with dad, fucker?
- I fell asleep.
- Fell asleep? Fell asleep?
Asshole!
You're always lying stoned
on Fazlu's terrace.
Like you're always lying
on top of your wife!
Enough!
Hurry up!
We were having tea...
when Mr. Sardar Khan's car drove in.
We recognized him as
he comes here often.
Suddenly there was loud firing
and a few guys on motorcycles...
Father!
Who killed him?
Who the fuck killed my father?
Sir, they have arrested one
of the shooters.
Get out, son of a bitch!
Get out!
- Look, you can't...
- Stay back.
Who else was with you?
I said stand back!
I said stand back motherfucker!
Rip the fucker a new hole!
Speak, bastard!
Speak.
He just left!
Hey, Faizal...
lets take father's body home.
But... we're in the midst of
an investigation...
Shut the fuck up!
This is my father's corpse,
and it will go straight home.
So fuck your investigation.
Understood?
Come on, lift him...
Wonderful news, Mr. Singh!
Our officers can finally breathe
easy after 12 years.
Not for long, I'm afraid.
Sardar Khan's gone,
but he's left behind 4 sons.
- Five.
- Sorry?
Five.
Four from the first wife,
and one from the second.
The second one's a cook
at my place.
Meet Sardar Khan's fifth.
What's your name?
- Definite.
- Why "Definite"?
Because I have a definite
mission in life.
Which is?
Sardar Khan's death.
But he's already dead.
- How many rotis are ready?
- About 8.
Hurry up... they're waiting.
I'll serve some curry till then.
How can you all eat in peace?
Even I belong to
brother Sultan's family.
You are now my family.
And my parents?
They are my parents too.
But what about what your
mom just said?
You're just pissed that someone else
bumped off your old man, not you.
Brother Saggir's call for you...
Yes, coming mom...
Go to hell, loser!
You have to stay alert all the time.
Fazlu doped you with weed and
informed Sultan that dad was riding alone.
Sultan was there himself,
with Saggir and another guy.
And like a dumbass you kept
hanging with your 'buddy'!
Wanna play with a two-face,
better leam to carry a mask.
Tomorrow morning, at the shopping centre.
Let me know if you can't do this, Faizal.
Sit.
He's not here.
But Faizal had said he'd
be here by 11 A.M.
What time is it?
Come on...
let's leave, son.
Now what are you doing?
Stay away from long haired girls at school.
Look at this fat lice.
Go to your room, boys.
Where is Shama?
- May I ask something?
- Yes.
Can't you leave this blood shed
and look after the family?
Begging for your brother's life, eh?
No... yours.
Look here Shama Parveen,
don't you ever interfere in my work.
Understood?
DHANBAD POLICE STATION
I surrender...
for stealing wood.
Easy there, buddy!
There are cops here.
Fuck them.
Yes, I was angry and
had threatened to kill him...
but I wasn't even at the
shopping centre that morning.
Why did you surrender then?
I had stopped and unloaded
wood from a train.
When I learnt that it's illegal
I decided to surrender myself.
Do you have any other witnesses?
No, your honour.
You are released with a fine of Rs.500.
Non-payment will lead to...
15 days imprisonment.
Run... run, motherfuckers!
He's completely incapable.
Drugs have made him useless.
The pain of losing one so young...
and Danish was my first-born.
Calm down...
I understand your...
Faizal...
when will your blood boil, son?
Your father paid for your
drugs with his life.
Now your brother has paid the
price for your recklessness.
So when will you pull
the trigger, boy?
When will you leave those potheads and
avenge your father and brother?
Look at your eyes...
dead with drugs.
Enough, Nagma...
If those filthy hands can only eat,
then let me feed you, fucker!
Now what are you staring at?
Where's that knife?
Stop it. Have you lost it?
Here... let me chop those
useless fingers.
- Enough, mother.
- I'll chop them.
This is madness, Nagma!
Shut up!
You will stay out of this.
Father, grandfather, brother...
your son Faizal will avenge them all.
Don't cry, my old lady.
Staying stoned won't help you
forget Danish's death.
Who wants to forget, uncle?
It's been a month since we buried him.
I know that.
Then what are you doing about it?
Same as you...
counting days!
Long live, Fazlu Ahmed!
Fazlu Ahmed...
Long live Wasseypur's new youth leader!
Where are you going?
Fazlu has won the election today.
Take Asgar with you.
He's my friend.
I will congratulate him myself.
Eat something, dear.
How long are you going
to blame yourself?
- Long live brother Fazlu!
- Shut up, cunt.
Fazlu...
Hey, Faizal...
my buddy's here.
Get out of the way.
Where've you been, buddy?
We're partying 'cos I won, man...
where have you been?
Everone spits at me at home.
And people laugh at me outside...
the bastards.
Why?
Because the cunts feel that...
Faizal sacrificed his own
blood for friendship.
My old woman says if I wasn't born,
there'd be no mourning in Sardar Khan's home.
What do you mean?
I mean...
here, light the toke first.
This is some strong shit, dude.
What's with the look, man?
I used to think I'm the angry, young Hero
born in the villian's den...
but I turned out to be just
a silent side-kick.
Someone else turned out
to be the Hero.
Who?
You, son of a bitch!
I'm coming!
She plays with rocks.
She flips and flops...
is made of dew drops.
And makes only holy stops!
Fazlu's death made Faizal a force to reckon with.
People were terrified of him after
the ruthless beheading.
All illegal iron traders were shit scared
and soon became his cronies.
Not an ounce of iron could be cut or sold
without Faizal's consent.
Even the cops were in on it.
Every police station was on his pay roll...
and they happily turned a blind eye
to his illegal affairs.
His business finally became stable
when he set up a massive iron warehouse.
Take me...
Make me yours.
It is time...
make love to me.
Let me wear your body...
while you sprinkle your
honey love on me!
Isn't this song a little... naughty?
Like you.
Huh?
I want your...
permission for something.
What?
You won't mind, right?
Nope.
I want to have sex with you.
Should I beat you to
pulp with my shoe?
That's it. Get out.
- Get out!
- But you said you won't mind.
Yeah, right!
Get out now.
I'll wake up everyone
with one scream.
- "Lover gets the Bride".
- Seen it 4 times.
- "Who am I to you"?
- That film's out.
- "Bollywood Dreams"?
- Seen it.
"Karan Arjun"?
Come on...
let's see that film.
It's got both Shahrukh and
Salman.
No, you'll hold my hand.
- I won't.
- You will.
I swear on my mom, I won't.
And you won't fondle my cheeks?
I swear on mom, I won't.
And you won't grope my lap
to "look for popcorn"?
- I swear on mom, I won't.
- You won't?
- Wiill you stick to me?
- I swear on mom, I won't.
Why don't you just watch it with
your mom then, loser.
Give me a pencil two.
Don't go alone.
What if you're attacked from behind?
Listen, old woman...
in this line of work
one can't trust 2 things.
One, the fear born from
your own heart.
And second... partnership!
Death is certain. If Allah doesn't kill me,
this neighbourhood will.
God forbid!
Fazlu left me fatherless...
when I trusted him more
than myself.
So what's the point!
This button unloads the entire magazine.
I want 15 of these.
And 12 of this.
Anything else?
Boss wants only this many.
What's that?
Pager.
What does it do?
You send messages through it.
You tell them your message and
they send it for you.
Message to whom?
To whoever you have
work with.
But who sends it?
Whoever has work.
Yeah, but who sends it?
Anyone can...
your family or your friends.
So very dark...
My lover is so dark...
His skin is dark...
but his heart is darker.
Dark abuses fall from his
black tongue...
Grey days become dark evenings...
For my lover is a coal criminal.
So very dark...
My lover is so dark.
Dark skin...
with a darker heart.
And black cusses fall from
his black tongue.
Grey days become dark evenings...
For my lover is a coal criminal.
He will find the damn coal...
and steal the damn coal.
He will find the damn coal,
He won't stoke the kitchen fires...
But he sure knows how to
steal that coal.
My lover is a wicked, wicked thief.
The soil is dark,
the dog is blacker.
Black as the kohl in my eyes.
He's black as a raven...
he's darker than fear.
Merely holding
a gun doesn't make you a Don.
Killing Sultan and Ramadhir Singh
is no child's play.
To do that you need guts.
And how many has Faizal
killled anyway?
Just Fazlu...
that too by conning him
with friendship.
For now people seem afraid,
but that fear will soon evaporate.
What say, brother...
Am I wrong?
Check this out.
Brother, any clue what day of the
week it is today?
Such a wicked thief.
Such a wicked, wicked thief.
Such a crazy coal thief.
Dark as sin...
that's my lover.
I've sworn on my mother...
that I'll lay your corpse
at her feet.
Why on earth?
Because you killed my father.
See, if I hadn't killed your father
he would've killed me.
But you also killed his father.
True.
He wanted to kill me too.
See, that's how the story began.
Look, Faizal...
I have nothing against you,
your father or your brother.
I killled them so I could live.
Tell me, who wants to die needlessly?
So what do you want?
I won't come in your way.
You rule Wasseypur.
Do as you please.
Make your millions.
Dhanbad authorities will
back you.
And if my men flout this agreement,
feel free to shoot me.
But if you slip up...
then I will act appropriately.
You shouldn't mind then.
So your dad's merrily
joined hands with them...
and expects us to
get amnesia.
That bastard chopped up Fazlu
and we should forget it?
But you killed his brother
and father... didn't you?
Now father has decided that
no one will touch Faizal.
What if he attacks us?
Then handle it...
but don't involve us.
Black clouds loom,
there will be black rain.
His black flags rebel...
against the dark winds.
But the money in his black purse
is as guilty as his eyes.
The inglorious smoke from
his black flames...
The black sun rules with
its iron heat.
The lamp, the elephant, and all...
is black... pitch black.
God damn that coal...
he will steal the damn coal.
If there is coal,
he will find it and steal it...
for that's all his black heart
gives a shit about.
He's the thief of my heart.
Have you crapped as well?
Where's Khalid?
Khalid was Sultan's main henchman.
And the only one of Sardar's killers
whose whereabouts were unknown.
How much does he pay you?
Dried bones and bread.
If you join me you'll get a whole
goat every month.
Now where do I shoot you...
in the ass?
In the intestines?
Or...
- shall I let you go?
- Let me go.
- What?
Okay, then.
From now you'll shadow
Khalid for me.
And if you tr to decieve me
I'll bury you wherever you're standing.
See, I smoke pot, hash...
I've even murdered Fazlu
and a few others.
Done some jail time too.
So you want to tell me
about your stuff?
Like a wire...
As thin as a wire...
My darling's as thin as a wire...
What in God's name have you done
to him, ma-in-law?
My darling's shrunken like
a dried prune...
He's like a dried prune...
Poor darling...
my poor dear.
Just doesn't eat...
My darling doesn't eat a thing...
What in God's name have you done
to him, ma-in-law?
My darling's as thin as a wire...
My darling walks in dark caves...
His life's a dark mine,
swiftly filling with water...
Where have you led the poor
workers, our leader?
Where have you led the people,
great leader?
Was this the Worker's movement,
dear leader?
Was this the flame you lit,
people's leader?
At the rate of coal...
Sold at the rate of coal...
Sold at the rate of coal,
everday my dear.
My darling, my dear...
My Bihar!
Fountains of lament burst through
mountains of sadness...
Fountains of lament, my dear...
My darling is as thin as a wire.
with a deposit of 11,021 rupees...
and these people as yourwitness,
do you take Mohsina as your wife?
I do.
Do you grant Faizal Khan
permission to marry you?
I permit him.
Say, "I do".
I do!
Congratulations, dear!
Faizal...
What broke?
Either sleep or
lay the mattress on the floor.
Some guy's here with
news of Khalid.
Where's my gun?
In your pants!
Shut up!
But where are you going?
so wash colored and whites seperately...
but only if they're cotton.
Georgettes can be mixed.
Salaam, mother!
Ironing marks are visible here.
And does this look
white to you?
Faizal?
Our enemy is standing
in our porch...
this doesn't seem right to me.
Please take care of the house,
my mother...
and let me handle the
business.
But he's a close aide of Khalid's.
He used to be...
now he's my aide.
Now please look after the house.
Where's Khalid?
He's eating breakfast alone
at the crossing.
His family is on a pilgrimage,
so he eats out often.
No one will follow me.
But if I don't return,
kill him.
Come on, step out.
Everyone out.
Come on...
What's up, asshole!
- Forgive me, brother.
- Shave his head.
Hey, wait!
I'll get you Sultan.
I can get him myself asshole.
We're both Muslims, brother.
- Even Allah forgives once...
- Move that razor, man.
Wear these.
- Please forgive me...
- Wear these.
Check out Dr. Evil!
He shaved and shot him,
should we keep jerking off?
What?
Just talk to your dad, dammit!
It's a tender for a new highway...
from the city of Patna to Kolkatta,
over the river Ganges.
Father.
Sultan called.
Go and arrange tea and snacks.
What is this?
Musical chairs? Get out.
Get out!
Father...
I've told you many times...
don't name thugs in polite company.
Thing is that Faizal has just shot the guy
who killed Sardar Khan.
So what's the problem?
- But he was our man.
- He was Sultan's.
And Sultan is not our
man either.
- But isn't he working for...
- Shut up!
and shove your sentiments in your arse.
Stop playing silly games
with petty politicians here...
why don't you go to your constituency
and motivate your voters instead?
- And where were you last night?
- I was watching a movie.
Which movie?
"The lover gets the bride".
Son... you're simply not upto this.
You're worrying me now.
I don't think this job is for you.
Give him the goat...
and let him go.
Babu Khan a.k.a. Babua a.k.a. Perpendicular!
The youngest brother, merely 14...
but crime was child's play for him.
See this blade?
Nothing will happen if you
use it sideways.
So always hold it like this
and use it perpendicularly.
- Do you know "perpendicular"?
- Yup.
What?
Like I'm perpendicular to this iron slab.
A dead body means the blade must
have cut it perpendicularly.
But a mere slit in the skin means
it was a tangential cut.
Here.
Practice and report.
Perpendicular was more terrifying than Faizal.
A 14 year old who literally played
with a blade in his mouth.
Who simply knew:
Blade + skin = blood!
I hit perpendicular, he hit at a tangent.
He had many run-ins with cops,
but always escaped.
Bullets were whizzing past me...
one even grazed my ear...
ka-pow!
But they couldn't catch me!
It was impossible to get evidence or a witness
against Faizal's brother.
It wasn't him.
And he always got away scott free.
That's Tangent.
Tangent did everything
with Perpendicular...
but was the first to flee
in the face of danger.
Hi, I'm Perpendicular.
Faizal Khan is my elder bro.
I've come to rob your shop.
So please don't call the cops,
or we'll shoot you.
Are you done, uncle?
Go on then.
Open everthing.
We should mask up now,
or they'll identify us.
Here... give me the keys.
Open it... quickly!
Those are my slippers.
Hide this in my room.
Ciao!
Perpendicular got caught again.
And the jeweller said...
It wasn't him.
Perpendicular was released.
Hey, Babua!
- What now?
- Come here.
What's this I hear?
I think you accidentally took my keys
with the other stuff.
If I could get the keys
back please...
What were you shopping for?
He's just a kid.
Mistakes happen.
So beautiful.
Isn't it?
Please send the receipt to Faizal's office.
Babua...
Hello!
What's up, buddy!
What's up?
Wanna make 5 grand?
A new era of change had rung in.
There wasn't just one Ramadhir Singh
or Sardar Khan anymore...
now any Tom, Dick or wanted
to be Sardar Khan or Sultan.
Definite.
His mother had handed him
a pistol at a tender age.
Where's the matchbox
you stole from me?
The world would be in flames
by now if I really had it.
Don't fight with anyone today.
Ever guy thought he was the
studly Hero of his neighbourhood.
But Definite also had the dual blood
of Durga and Sardar Khan.
They are just good friends!
Can a young guy and girl
be just friends?
Here... another cliched friendship!
Definite and Perpendicular
were from the same bloodline.
While new thugs were
mushrooming daily...
Definite was the deadliest!
A boy and girl can never be friends.
This is just to hide hot flames of desire
inside throbbing hearts on those chilly nights.
But I'm your friend!
A boy and girl can never be friends.
Isn't this that villian's dialogue?
Yeah, so?
While you're busy killing
stray dogs and kittens...
Faizal is gobbling up your
father's wealth.
I don't want a thing from
that fucker.
I just want Dhanbad!
Which snake is this?
It's a cobra!
How do you hold it?
Snake Cobra!
- Come to Papa!
- Hey!
He's your brother after all.
Always a problem kid.
That Hindu woman killed last Ramzan
was his handiwork.
Apparently he loved her daughter.
They would screw around anywhere...
the terrace, the yard...
When her mom found out she promptly sent
the girl to her brother's in Calcutta.
This made Definite threaten her,
"Call her back or I'll kill you!"
Her mother threw him out
of the house.
He lost it and bashed her
head in with a rod.
How about making me a
splendid paan, uncle!
Make it with love or
I'll put my friend in your pants.
As you say, sir.
Don't make me wait.
Hey Definite, people are
looking for you.
- Who's issued my warrant?
- Brother Faizal, hurry.
Give me that paan... quick.
Do you know what this 'warrant' means?
My time has begun.
Salaam, uncle!
Salaam, brother!
Do that again.
Salaam-wallekum!
No, do that again.
Do the muffler move again.
Oh, this!
Is it dead?
No, it's alive...
Why did you steal it?
Just like that.
It looked sexy.
Sexy?
Yeah.
Return it.
- Brother, even I wanted to talk to you...
- Later!
This shit shouldn't happen again.
Lets go, Mohsina.
So what do I have to do?
It's 10 feet...
I've measured it.
So you can actually fly
the bike across?
You think I've randomly
come up with the bet?
- Have you done it before?
- Many times.
If I crush a goat,
I'll eat it.
You can shove the hooves up your ass too.
First decide who goes first.
Let's toss a coin.
- Choose.
- Heads.
I win.
Hey, it's my coin.
You go first.
But I have another condition.
- You can't copy my technique.
- Yeah, whatever.
- "Technique"!
- I'll show you, fucking lisp.
Sister fucker!
- What's he doing?
- What's he upto?
He's an expert at this.
He'll go over the planks at a speed of 80,
and fly across the hill.
Do you have a game plan?
Wait...
- What?
- I won the toss, right?
Yes.
I've changed my mind.
I'll go first.
That's not cool, man!
Whatever Perpendicular
does is cool.
You're openly cheating because
you're Faizal's brother.
Why drag brother into this?
Give me the keys.
Come on!
Take it, asshole.
Leave the money.
What a fucking beggar!
Hold this.
Which key is it?
Motherfucking asshole!
Sister fucker tricked me.
I'll kick your ass.
- That's not nice, brother...
- Love being a wise ass, don't you?
I respect you a lot 'cos you're my brother
and you're fearless!
But you should also respect me,
'cos I'm not even afraid of you!
Sit.
And thus began Definite's story.
He always wanted to be the Don.
Meanwhile, a new state had been carved
out of Bihar... Jharkhand.
And all the mineral rich land including
Dhanbad became a part of this new state.
Now ever greedy officer and criminal
got a chance to rape the region.
Jharkhand was being robbed
in broad daylight by all.
Faizal's notoreity gave birth to
many small time criminals.
Most significant amongst them was
Shamshad Aalam.
He used to be a cloth trader...
who then got into transportation and
acquired many trucks.
When he lost interest in that
he decided to get into iron.
We'll get into iron trade.
You can't unless you share profits with Faizal.
Fuck that! I hear one can't even
steal without his blessings.
So now?
He has one weakness...
Money!
He's all guts but has zero
business sense.
The fucker sells to anyone
at any price.
He sells stock worth 5 bucks
at 2 bucks.
If we fix the market price with him,
he won't be able to resist a fat profit.
The guys you sell to aren't even traders,
they're middlemen.
They buy from you at 2 bucks
and sell at 4.
You're being ripped off.
Seriously!
Bengalis don't care for iron anyway.
The communist govemment over there
doesn't care about industry.
Lets sell the iron to Gujarat and Orissa
directly and at higher rates.
There's massive demand over there,
and you have ample supply.
What say?
Even my transportation is sorted.
I swear your meagre 2 bucks
will turn into 3.5 with me.
Salaam, sister!
And I'll keep what's left.
What say?
honorable Dep. Chairman
of our Youth Society.
And the honorable Chairman,
Mr.Faizal Khan.
Please put your hands
together for him.
And the chairperson of the Ladies wing,
Ms. Mohsina Khan.
After making Faizal the Chairman
of a 2 day old society...
Shamshad jump-started his career.
Faizal handed over his father's
warehouse to him...
and soon word spread that
Shamshad was Faizal's man.
This used to be my father's.
It's been lying idle since
brother passed away.
This promptly became a hot-bed for
money and tranny dance.
Why do you call mom 'old lady'?
Its not as if you look 30.
I'd say you look like siblings.
- Don't talk shit.
- It's a fact.
Have you seen your dark circles?
All thanks to weed.
Do you think you look 24?
Hey, don't get irritated.
- I'm just saying that both of you look 40.
- Call back later!
Let's go.
Why'd you marry me if I look
like such a fossil?
Don't get angry,
I'm just stating facts.
Brother, can you guess his age?
I'd say... 40.
What?
How old am I?
40?
- 35.
- Are you sure?
24.
Like I was born today, asshole!
Happy Birthday, sir!
Babua, come here...
What is it?
Go get this stuff from
the market.
- Mother, tea is also over.
- It's on the list.
Quick! Hide the expensive stuff,
Perpendicular's coming.
Pack everthing on the list.
Quickly!
This one's out of stock,
can I give you another washing powder?
How's it out of stock?
It just is!
Then give me the cash,
I'll buy it elsewhere.
So he took your money and my stock,
and left without paying.
That's nothing! These cheeky school brats
broke into my shop at night.
Not only did they eat up all the sweets,
they woke me up and made me fry some more!
When I told Faizal Khan about it,
he just laughed and said...
...'He's just a kid!'
and handed me a measly 100 bucks!
That pint-sized devil's
made our life hell.
- This time my hands are tied.
- Just quote your price, man.
Look, if I get caught,
the authorities won't help me.
We'll tell you the time and place,
the authorities will not know shit.
And what about him...
Faizal?
Hey, I thought you weren't
afraid of him!
Do what you have to.
I'll handle my end.
Don't worry!
How can I sell at 10 when the stock is worth 15?
Atleast pay me my cost price of 14,
then it's yours.
- You just won't learn!
- Who you calling?
Who you calling?
I'll have to check with
brother Faizal, won't I!
- Don't over react, sir...
- My phone...
Please listen...
What?
- How about you make me an offer.
- There he goes again!
The boss has quoted 10, not me.
Talk to him if you like.
- Give me my phone, man.
- No way!
Return my damn phone!
- Give it to me!
- No!
Ok, give me yours.
We have another one, see!
Faizal could shoot us if he's in a bad mood.
Stop, in heaven's name, please!
Fine! This is now between boss
and this guy's family!
Please don't get upset!
Are you sure?
The dealer's told everone that
his stock worth 15, you have bought for 10.
Poor guy's shop is up
for auction.
Hey, Lisp...
Where you going?
To school.
Right, the family scholar!
Just milk cows and
you'll become the Chief Minister.
What's up, asshole?
All good, boss.
Got a good rate from a dealer.
Stuff worth 20, sold for 75.
So has this dealer
gone bonkers?
Why?
He's saying that his stock
was worth 15.
Really?
And you bought it at 10?
Who did he say this to?
He's standing right here.
And you believe this,
brother Faizal?
Brother Faizal...
Why the fuck are you sounding
squeeky like a girl now?
Someone's poisoning your
ears, boss.
My ears are so full of wax,
that nothing can enter.
No discussion!
I don't care about the rates.
You say 75, I believe you.
The dealer says 10,
I believe him too.
10 less from 75 is 65.
So on deliver,
I better have 65 in my hands.
Ooh! What's your name?
Don't you know my name, baby?
I'm Munnabhai, M.B.B.S.!
- Do I look nice?
- Oh, yeah!
I'll never leave this town.
I'm practically a tourist attraction here.
Inspectors here make millions!
I say let your kids become Inspectors too.
See, no matter who you are,
you have to come here... like these two.
- How're you, sir?
- Hello!
How can we work peacefully
if we get extortion threats?
What happened?
- Know what people call cops?
- What?
Ball-strokers of Faizal Khan!
Really?
You find it funny?
See, this complaint will become a formal report.
But our investigation will be futile
without any evidence.
Get my point?
He's inside.
The film gets over in 10 minutes.
Okay, get in.
Tell Guddu that I'm back from the deliveries.
Just do as I say.
He'll call back in 15 minutes.
INSPECTOR SINGH
Munnabhai, M.B.B.S.!
How's it hangin', dude?
I'll be back tomorrow morning!
Let me in or you'll
go straight to heaven.
Give him a Magic Hug, dude!
Here you go!
You're no longer Tangent.
You're my side kick, Circuit!
And from now I'm Munnabhai!
I'm going to Bombay to meet Munnabhai.
I wanna come too.
- What'll you do there?
- Whatever you say.
What'll you do after meeting
the actor, dumbass?
I'll touch his feet.
Then?
What do you mean?
What'll you do after that, slow coach?
- I'll stare at him.
- till when?
till my eyes hurt.
Then?
What do you mean?
What will you do after staring?
I'll close my eyes.
Then?
What's the rush, motherfucker?
Run, Tangent! Go and tell brother that
Sultan's tring to kill me.
Come here you daughterfucker!
Hey, get out of the bus.
Why are you gasping so hard?
Do you know him?
Say something.
It's Faizal!
Hello?
Hey asshole, back from the deliveries?
Where's my money?
What money?
Have you gone mad?
My deal, my work, so my profit.
What's wrong with your voice?
Is Ramadhir's cock stuck
in your throat?
Hey, mind your language.
I say we finish him off tonight.
No, something's fishy.
He wasn't alone.
He was on speaker phone.
He's going to kill Perpendicular!
Who the fuck will kill him?
- He's gonna kill him.
- Who?
- Sultan.
- Motherfucker!
Sir, I've got concrete evidence against Faizal.
I'm on my way to arrest him.
But I don't have a warrant yet.
Could you arrange it while I arrest him?
Okay, Sir Minister.
- Wasn't that Faizal Khan's vehicle?
- Stop!
It is. Turn around.
Sultan... the motherfucker!
What's up, brother?
Brother Faizal!
Please hold on...
You need to come with me.
Why? This is my little bro's body...
Yes sir, but...
Shut Up! He's been murdered.
Then hand over the body to us, sir...
I have a complaint against you.
Offiicer, take the body.
I hope you've come alone...
because the rest think
I'm a fucking fool.
On my way.
Aching to see you, dear.
Mohsina!
Please sing my song.
Why?
I really need to hear it.
Don't feel frustrated, my fool...
Don't be nervous, my fool...
Don't let anything upset your mood...
anytime, my dearfool.
Whatever's wrong, dear...
Whatever's wrong,
set it right, dear.
Don't lose hope,
and try to fight some more, dear.
Fight some more, my dear fool.
Brother Definite?
Yeah?
Shamshad's thrilled after
getting Faizal arrested.
So let him gloat.
If we put him in his place Faizal will notice us.
- But boss is in jail himself.
- But you're not.
What do you mean?
The boss's chair is vacant.
Let's eliminate Shamshad before
he tries to sit in it.
The power will be indirectly Faizal's,
but directly yours.
Once the town accepts you,
rest is upto you.
Shamshad!
Where is he?
Where's Shamshad?
Where's he?
Don't kill me...
- Check that corner.
- Shamshad.
- Where are you?
- Find him.
Where the fuck is your son?
Check the terrace.
Perfect time for this fucking
gun to get jammed.
- Hey, Shamshad!
- He's not upstairs.
Look inside.
He has to be somewhere.
How did you get in without asking, bastard?
Mother...
You hurt my mom, motherfucker?
You were saying?
Why did you hurt my mom?
- Why my mother?
- Keep talking, big mouth.
Don't do it, man...
Motherfucker...
Son of a motherfucker!
Come on.
Catch that motherfucker!
Fuck off, asshole!
Catch that... motherfucker!
Hop on, man.
Why run when we have a scooter?
Stop!
Motherfucker stop!
Meet me in the next lane.
I'll catch that motherfucker!
Hey Definite! Stop!
Control your cock, man.
There he is.
Wait for me...
Stop the car!
Stop the car motherfucker!
Where are you?
He's at the gas station.
Speak up.
He's right in front of me...
at the gas station.
Which station?
The new Bazaar one.
And he's got a gun.
The fucker's got no bullets in it.
Just grab him. I'm on my way.
Fuck your mom, motherfucker!
Come on, asshole.
Hop on, dickface!
You should get into politics.
You see, Wasseypur is a jungle of Hyenas.
Over here brains won't get you far.
Imagine, if Definite's gun
had bullets...
would you be having tea
with us right now?
You may have done this,
but Faizal will suspect father.
See, you trapped Faizal,
and Sultan bumped off his brother.
No sir, that was different...
the Perpendicular
case was different.
Now it's in everone's best interests...
to finish him off while he's in there.
Who, me?
Definite!
That fuckwit?
Look, son...
just as steel cuts steel...
only one fuckwit can
deal with another fuckwit.
But why will Definite kill Faizal?
Because he wants to become Faizal Khan!
You know, I've been here
for decades.
I got Faizal's grandfather killed.
I got Sardar killed.
Then that...
Danish.
But I'm still alive.
Why?
Because sir is the real
Godfather!
You tell me why?
Why?
Because I am not a
big fan of cinema..
Cinema?
In my youth, all my friends used to
watch 'Ganga Jamuna'...
and wanted to be Dilip Kumar.
The girls were crazy about Dev Anand.
Then came another phase.
Women liked Rajesh Khanna.
And guys liked that
Amitabh Bachchan fellow.
And these days they like that...
- he has a very nice name...
- Salman Khan.
- And that...
- Sunil and Nargis Dutt's son...
Sanjay Dutt.
Ever fucker's got his own movie
playing inside his head.
Every fucker is tring to become
the Hero of his own imaginary film.
I swear, as long as there is
fucking cinema in this country...
people will continue to
be fooled.
I won't recognize him by face...
I might not even know
his name...
'cos my heart will recognize
him instantly.
The heart is crazy,
it is unstoppable...
Motherfucking asshole..
..you're alive only because
of Faizal, asshole.
I'll fry you with my AK-47
once we are out, bastard.
Stop this shit.
Definite!
I'm not afraid of your
stupid threats, fucker.
My tiny country revolver is
enough for you.
Fuck your mom!
Worthless piece of shit!
Stay within your limits!
Shamshad's withdrawn the
case against you.
Why? Does he want me to marry his sis?
He's trying to make an alliance with you.
So what should I do?
He's here.
You chill here.
Start the bike.
Now why's he here?
Hey, man.
- What's up!
- How're you?
Got the cash I sent you?
That's how I bought
2 kilos of apples.
- You bought apples for 200 grand?
- But they're from Kashmir.
Our terrorists grew up eating
them... want one?
Sure... sit.
Motherfucker!
Shamshad?
Tear him a new asshole!
Hey, isn't this Faizal Khan's house?
- We are walking into trouble, brother.
- Quiet!
- Gimme a gun.
- Here.
Anyone home?
Faizal Khan?
He's in jail, brother.
I know that.
Brother!
Please come in.
Would you like some tea?
What happened to your arm?
Shama had gone into a coma.
Faizal also mellowed down.
Everone's moves had back-fired.
Shamshad was also
fighting for his life.
Ramadhir knew that Sultan
had made a grave mistake.
This was the first time that a woman
had been shot in Wasseypur.
By custom, she was Danish's widow first
and then Sultan's sister.
And no one knew this better
than me.
An eerie silence had descended,
but I knew it carried a storm in its belly.
Ramadhir and his son knew that
Faizal's ego had been hurt.
They also knew that the town shared
and supported his sentiment.
Their one mistake had him
so powerful...
that it was important to end him
before he realised this.
Shamshad's gang had to leave town
as no one wanted to join them.
Faizal Khan was the new Don.
Don't give Faizal a chance
to stabilise.
He's just been released
from jail today.
His family must be
celebrating his return...
know what I mean?
Just a minute...
Yes, father.
No, I'm not planning a thing.
I'm doing as you had asked, father.
I'm lying really low.
Goodbye, father!
There's going to be a new
police chief in town.
Stay on high alert.
4 jeeps will do day-night
surveillance.
Don't be afraid.
But keep your guns close.
But don't make a move.
Believe me, we won't
be able to anyway.
- You can't, for sure.
- No one can, sir.
Get out!
If you fly so high
you might reach heaven!
Now where's the
Minister's number?
Greetings, Mr. Minister, sir!
It's me, Inspector Singh...
in charge of Dhanbad.
Greetings!
Thought I'd let you know that the new
chief is acting too big for his boots...
What?!
You've posted him here?
What are you doing?
My hands are tired thinking
about you.
- Not now.
- Why not?
You're back after ages,
everone wants to meet you.
But I only want to meet you.
You're incorrigible!
Sis-in-law is in hospital and you're...
Don't drag her between us,
she'll get stuck.
Please...
the show's
about to start.
What's the status on Ramadhir?
And which hospital is
Shamshad in?
Fuck off!
Lower the volume.
Just watch your show.
But what happened?
- I see Faizal Khan, Boss.
- Then get in and kill the motherfucker.
Get out, Faizal.
Come outside, asshole.
Fucker's locked it.
Give me a bomb.
Definite?
Uncle, where are you?
In the offiice.
Where are you?
Stay put. Don't worry.
They're just stray shots.
Stay there till I tell you, uncle.
Get the bombs, quick!
Blow this shit up.
Everbody get down!
Faizal!
You go ahead.
I'll follow.
- Where are you, Definite?
- On my way. Don't worry!
I'll worry if I stay alive, bastard.
Death is certain. If God doesn't kill me,
this neighbourhood will.
But I'll make these
bastards pay.
Just stay calm
and don't make a move.
But where are you going?
- I'll come with you, brother!
- No, you won't.
- But where are you going?
- Keep my phone with you.
But don't pick it up if it rings!
Shut the door
and don't let anyone out.
Faizal!
Don't feel frustrated, my fool...
Don't be nervous, my fool...
Don't let anything upset your mood...
anytime, my dearfool.
Whatever's wrong, dear...
Whatever's wrong,
set it right, dear.
Don't lose hope,
and try to fight some more, dear.
Fight some more, my dear fool.
Hey, Guddu!
Are you okay, brother?
- Faizal?
- Get my Pistol...
- Where did you get hurt?
- Did you get shot at?
Everyone get inside.
I'll kill those fuckers!
And where had you
run off, asshole?
- I was just in the market...
- I phoned you motherfucker!
If only I knew, I'd have killed him
when he passed me by.
Please get inside.
Ladies, please get inside.
- Where are you going?
- Shut the door!
Be careful, son!
Just get inside!
Get the car...
and I don't need you.
You guys guard the house.
Dont let a soul in.
Faizal?
Go home, uncle.
It was that fucking Sultan!
Just guard the house, uncle.
Jabbar!
Sisterfuckers!
The fucker's coming here!
Go back...
Let's get out of here.
Come on, hurry!
Hold on...
Some cops have come home.
Why?
They want to offer protection.
Give me the phone.
Who's the fucking officer?
Put him on.
I don't need your protection.
Faizal can protect himself.
Look, this time you were lucky but...
Shut up and listen.
It's Ramadhir who needs your protection.
So please bring an army
'cos I will riddle him with bullets.
Do not let him stabilise!
Just kill them all... family members,
servants, the laundry guy, even pets!
Hold on.
- What's this?
- Scissor to cut his plaster.
We'll be back soon.
Now please don't get
distracted, ladies!
It's for my daughter-in-law...
- Do you have Pathani shirts?
- Sure, we have several...
Any other styles?
Brother, you're in Dhanbad...
but the address you want
is of Varanasi City.
Varanasi!
This is Dhanbad!
This says Varanasi, man.
You're in another city.
Still don't get it?
Tell you what...
Run!
Shut ever shop.
Shut the whole motherfucking city down.
Son of a bitch murdered my mother
in the middle of the street.
You fucking rat...
Hey, Definite!
This rat lives with the fucker
who killed mom.
I want Sultan, dead or alive.
I know that bastard's behind this.
Open up, bastards!
Where is Sultan?
Where's Sultan?
He doesn't live here
anymore.
He moved out the day his sister
got married to Danish.
BHAGALPUR JUNCTION
Sultan goes to the mosque for
his afternoon prayers.
He parks outside the vegetable market
but leaves his gun behind.
So as soon as he enters the mosque,
you empty his gun.
After that he goes to the
meat market.
He then goes home
via the bazaar.
That's where we should
catch him.
Some bread and stew, please.
Hello.
Sultan was behind me.
He'll go to the meat market now.
Stay with him, and stay on line.
Yeah!
Where are you?
I'm at the bazaar.
He's headed towards you.
So?
- Keep hitting the kick-shaft.
- But then my scooter will start.
So first remove the spark plug
and then keep kicking.
Show me the ripe ones.
Put them in a polythene bag.
- What's the status?
- He's buying fruits.
Why the fuck isn't he
buying meat?
- Which fruit is he buying?
- Banana.
Must be having loose motions!
What else?
- I can't tell. Shall I go closer?
- Let it be.
Poor guy doesn't know we'll eat his fruits.
Shall I ask him to get lychees?
Shut up, asshole!
It's not lychee season yet.
What's up?
Fucker's buying bananas.
For whose ass?
Yours!
Just keep kicking the shaft!
I don't want to break it.
I'll kick it once he's done shopping.
Brother... he's moving.
He's going into the
vegetable market.
Why's he going to the
vegetable market?
But I'm not going anywhere.
I'm not talking to you.
But why won't you talk
to me, sir?
Fucking Dumb and Dumber!
I was talking to Definite.
So talk to one of us
at a time.
Hello?
Bastard disconnected me.
So what fruit do you get in a
vegetable market?
Custard apple?
Isn't that sugar-apple?
Well... some call it pumpkin.
Yes?
He's buying jackfruit.
- Jackfruit?
- Yes, brother.
Now why would he want to
buy jackfruit?
I feel... he wants to pickle it.
Can't one make a curry
out of it?
Sure. Mummy makes mean
jackfruit balls!
My granny used to fr finely chopped
jackfruit and serve it with rice.
Don't Brahmins consider
it their 'meat'?
What's up?
I've been calling you for eons,
you deaf fuck!
But you asked me to
speak to only one.
So talk to me, fuckwit.
I'm suffering in this heat...
Sultan's moving.
But this was your idea...
There's an aquarium inside
my fucking helmet.
Sultan's in the car!
Then chuck the helmet.
Show that pretty face to
the world... come on!
He's right behind Definite.
Shut up!
He's behind you.
No, he's in front of me.
After Sultan's death
Faizal had no threats in Wasseypur.
Danish, his widow, Nagma, Asgar...
Definite had avenged them all.
To cement Definite's lethal reputation,
Faizal asked him to surrender.
Ramadhir was also watching
this keenly.
Ever since Definite was a child,
Ramadhir had hoped to make him his weapon.
But Definite was untamable.
He had no masters.
And Sultan's death had made him
even more fierce.
So Ramadhir used his trump card...
Durga!
Who took care of you and
your son after Sardar's death?
I'd also given you my word that...
Definite will get what is
rightfully his.
Don't worry!
He'll take it himself.
It's not easy.
Definite's not only in jail...
he's also accepted all of
Faizal's crimes.
Sometimes I feel like he is...
not your son...
as much as Sardar's.
Ramadhir wanted to drive a wedge
between Faizal and Definite.
All he needed was Faizal's
one weakness.
And Ramadhir knew which one...
Money... black money!
Whatever the source or amount.
Faizal had no business sense,
people came to him only out of fear.
Ramadhir took advantage of this.
So he first shifted Definite to
the state capital prison.
Prison is in your blood, isn't it?
Please leave.
I'm fine... without you.
I raised a killer,
not a coward.
Shamshad's still in hospital,
and Ramadhir is unarmed.
But he's in the capital
where you can't touch him.
He has to return... someday.
They've shifted Definite to the capital prison.
Who told you that?
He called.
- Why didn't he call me?
- You don't pick up your calls.
Get me the prison in-charge.
Brother...
someone's here to see you.
Let him in.
Hello! This is Faizal Khan.
Why has Definite been shifted
to the capital?
Definite!
I mean the name.
What's the meaning of 'Definite'?
Definite.
- What's his real name?
- Definite.
Yeah,
but what's his real name?
Definite's real name is Definite.
Guddu, what is Definite's real name?
It is Definite.
What had dad named him
before "Definite"?
You know, like Perpendicular's real
name was Babua.
I've always known him as Definite.
So what's the meaning of
the word "Definite"?
- "Definite" is... what is definite!
- So what is definite?
See, "Def" means deaf...
And "nite" means net!
Definite is
that which is certain.
Neither Faizal nor his gang spoke English.
But Iqlakh did.
And Faizal liked that.
However, Iqlakh was
Ramadhir's mole.
He was going to make Faizal pots of money,
and make him forget about Definite.
Indian trains often get derailed.
Ever wondered where
these trains go?
The govemment auctions these trains
but at rates that are 40 years old.
Now an old compartment
is valueless.
But if one breaks it down to its components,
its value multiplies.
The wheels, springs and
sheets sell seperately,
and the rest can be melted
down to make pipes.
And that's how a whole train
gets auctioned.
From the Internet to any government
commodity, it's all auctioned.
Bidders come from all over
the country for this...
But Iqlakh also had a past.
20 years ago, his father had abducted
and raped a Wasseypur girl.
Sardar had forced him to divorce
his first wife to marry this girl.
Iqlakh was Mohsin's son from
the abandoned first wife.
How can Iqlakh be Ramadhir's guy?
He's an educated city-slicker.
Thing is, Iqlakh was left fatherless
because of your dad...
while Ramadhir supported
and educated him.
And here is the result for
the tender issued on...
But Faizal had bought into
Iqlakh's vision.
His ambition now included
all of Dhanbad.
And so he chose to
overlook Iqlakh's past.
I've been sent by Faizal Khan.
And from now we will run a syndicate here.
All bids will go through Faizal Khan.
And only he will approve who gets the tender.
What the hell?
This is hooliganism!
Sit!
- Any other issues?
- You can't bully us like this!
You may now leave your
quotations here and go.
Iqlakh first made Faizal a fearful figure
amongst the traders.
He then took control of the
Auction Room.
And before the next auctions
Faizal himself bribed railway officials.
All you need to do is tell them I'm your guy.
The auction will be led by Iqlakh.
And his word will be the final one.
And all of you will submit to him.
Cool?
You said "submit"
instead of "stand by".
- What is "stand by"?
- Total support.
- So what's "submit"?
- Total surrender.
So I was right.
To break this syndicate, the government
started auctioning on the internet.
So the bids became faceless and
the bidders didn't fear the syndicate.
- The Auction's done.
- When?
The bastards did it on the internet.
The auction is over, brother.
Some guy from Gujarat got the tender.
Well, guess where he'll have to
come to collect the goods?
- Salaam!
- What do you want?
Move it!
What the hell do you want?
And thus things stayed in Faizal's control
and he made pots of money.
His power over the auctions and railways
opened a goldmine of wealth.
Eventually Faizal became blind
with power and black money...
just like Ramadhir had wanted.
Definite was left rotting in jail.
It's all about people's power!
Everone respects you here
since you've opened a school.
If you represent Wasseypur in
these elections you will surely win.
No one can touch you then.
In fact, stand as an independent
candidate and win.
Then any party will want an
alliance with you.
Once that happens
you can openly dictate!
What if I contest against Ramadhir
from Dhanbad, and not Wasseypur?
Against me?
- Find out what his plans are.
- Yes, father.
Full of venom,
I was raised by scorpions.
Bite me if you dare.
I swear by my honour,
I will tear you apart.
Like a snake without a tail,
you will writhe in pain.
You're the bastard child
of honour...
I swear by your whore mother...
as I dare you to enter
my court of evil.
Now Ramadhir got Definite released from jail
and sent J.P. to meet him.
But J.P.'s agenda was not so much Faizal
as much as his own father.
He knew that only one man could
remove Ramadhir out of his way.
Faizal Khan!
How will you get him to
do that?
If you do as I say,
it will all fall into place.
And what do I get?
You get Wasseypur!
And you get?
Ramadhir has promised me your land
and Wasseypur if I kill you.
- He's given mom a million as advance.
- What'd you do?
I kept the advance.
He's asked me to watch you 24 hours
and report to him.
So when's the D-day?
On the Election day.
Iqlakh will kill you.
I'm the back-up!
I'm the Devil's son,
raised in the laps of witches.
I'm the keeper of graves,
dogs are my supper.
That's funny 'cos humans like you
are just a snack for me.
I'm the Serpent King, a vulture...
I'm disease and filth.
So what? I'm a cannibal...
I don't even spare cattle feed.
You don't scare me...
I sold the deed I made with the Devil.
Fuck your deed!
I just sold the fucking Devil himself!
Hallelujah!
Faizal...
What happened?
Tell me...
You know, I never wanted to
get into father's business.
May I get some tea?
In fact, I didn't want anything.
How did all of this happen?
It's okay!
But you're also getting out
of this trap now... aren't you?
Not if I win these elections...
...'cos then I will sink deeper.
Father had a chance to not
retum to Wasseypur.
But he came back...
and everone got caught
in the quicksand.
Enough... hey!
Ramadhir's story could have
ended long back...
with Shahid Khan.
But that blood bath is
still continuing!
I don't want any part of this.
Whatever's wrong...
Set right whatever's wrong...
Don't lose hope,
and fight some more, my dear fool.
12 of the total 26 polling booths
are strongly in our favour.
The remaining 14 will be a worr
and our main targets.
The voting here will be against us and
the booths will be full of armed cops.
So first, 6 of our shortest guys will
enter the booth in burqas.
Meanwhile, we will open firing
in the market and distract the cops.
As soon as the cops leave,
you guys attack and capture the booth.
Give me that camera.
Grab the ballot boxes and run,
but only if there aren't too many civilians.
Or pour ink and shake the box...
or just burn it.
The rest of you will spread out
and riot all day with guns and bombs.
Terrorise all the neighbouring areas of
the polling booths...
so people get scared to
even step out.
A few of you will only keep an eye
on the Polling Offiicer.
When he heads towards us,
one of you will inform him:
"Sir, they're firing in the
market area booth"
The offiicer will rush to that booth
through bad roads.
Just as he realises he's been misinformed,
an 'injured' guy will tell him:
I was at the booth in the college area,
they shot us and cast our votes by force.
And like this, we will keep setting up
decoys and capture all 14 booths.
Everyone get the fuck out of here.
Make sure Faizal Khan
doesn't win!
Where's Definite?
Call him.
Talk of the devil!
Hello...
We've just stepped out
for inspection.
Get there fast.
Okay.
He'll meet us at the booth.
Brother...
how about a quick visit
to the shrine first?
They say all prayers get
answered there.
Alright.
Does everone need to come?
I'm sure everone would
like to pray.
I think more people will
mean more time.
Guddu, ask the others to
stay back.
You guys wait at the gate.
We'll be back soon.
Is this it?
This one's for the tourists.
The real one's ahead.
Why are you sweating
so much?
It's just... this heat, brother.
Guddu!
Who the fuck shot him?
What the...
Guddu, you're shooting me...
Iqlakh, motherfucker!
Want to kill me, motherfucker?
Oh, I won't.
Then who will?
So who'll kill me.
Tell me, motherfucker...
Where is he?
They're behind the wall.
Come out, brother.
Nobody will kill you now.
Where the fuck were you, asshole?
Someone shot Guddu.
That was my mistake, brother.
Their shirts were so similar,
I shot Guddu mistaking him for Iqlakh.
- This was the best time to kill him.
- But who changed the plan?
- Ramadhir, who else!
- Let's go.
- He must be at the hospital..
- Lets go there..
- We can get him at the circuit house..
- Fuck circuit house..
How can he attack suddenly!
Even I need to prepare myself.
Watch before you shoot, bugger!
Same shirts Guddu!
Faizal?
What the hell is this?
You said you were going
to quit!
Let me go today...
I promise I'll quit tomorrow.
You need to be alive to quit.
I swear on you,
I'll come back alive.
Faizal, please don't go.
I am pregnant.
Tell the baby his father
says 'hello'!
Whatever's wrong, dear...
Whatever's wrong,
set it right, dear.
Don't lose hope,
and try to fight some more, dear.
Fight some more, my dear fool.
Whatever's wrong,
set it right, dear.
Don't lose hope,
and try to fight some more, dear.
Fight some more, my dear fool.
Don't feel frustrated, my fool...
Don't be nervous, my fool...
Don't let anything upset your mood...
anytime, my dearfool.
Why are our guys following us?
Hey, Guddu...
Tell them we don't need them.
But we might, brother.
Faizal Khan doesn't need
anyone's protection.
You guys don't have to cover us.
'Cos brother says so, fucker.
Gimme your phone.
No one will shoot...
...'Cos every single bullet in
Ramadhir's body will be mine.
They're saying another
15 days before discharge..
Hello!
Greetings, sir.
Faizal Khan is history.
But in the process
Guddu killed Iqlakh.
So I had to kill Guddu.
Where's his dead body?
I'm on my way to the hospital.
The bodies are with me
in an ambulance.
Yes, he's here.
They're in there.
Hello?
They're firing outside!
Hold this.
Stay alert!
Keep your guns handy.
Definite!
Why are you tring to hold water
in your palms, fool?
Don't you know you can't hold water
in your palms, dear fool?
It's meaningless...
it's nature is to slip away.
It's time to rev that brain, you fool,
time to catch that train, you fool.
It's time to rev that brain, fool...
it's time to ignite.
Please stop your craziness
and act sane, dear fool!
Times are strange,
life is fragile...
so don't be rash, my fool.
And when life gives you
a chance, fool...
you know you shouldn't refuse!
I beg you, dear fool,
please don't refuse!
Want some tea?
I'll have some.
Bring him outside.