PROJECT 2571
Oxygen levels are dropping.
Brain function, normal.
Cerebral salvage,
ready to proceed.
Robotic skeleton prepared
and waiting for brain insertion.
Now your eyes...
are gonna open.
You are safe.
It's ok, just breathe.
Just breathe.
Breathe.
Good.
That's good.
Hello, Mira.
I'm Dr. Ouelet.
Do you remember anything
about the attack?
What happened?
I was...
You were drowning.
There was water.
That's right. You were on a boat,
a refugee boat.
It was sunk by terrorists.
Why can't I feel my body?
Mira, your body was damaged.
We could not save that.
Only your brain survived.
We made you a new body.
A synthetic shell.
But your mind, your soul...
Your ghost.
It's still in there.
Please.
Sedate her.
Will it work?
Absolutely.
She's a miracle.
A machine can't lead,
It can only follow orders.
A machine can't imagine or care or intuit.
But as a human mind in
a cybernetic frame...
Mira can do all those things, and more.
The first of her kind.
She will join Section 9
as soon as she is operational.
Please don't do that.
You reducing a complex human to a machine.
I don't think of her as a machine.
She is a weapon.
And the future of my company.
ONE YEAR LATER
The first artificially created
memory enhancement.
Sirenum training protocol is the
fastest and most efficient way...
to develop your ability.
Stronger than ever.
Experience your power.
Cybercrime is a Type 1 offense.
Minimum punishment: 15 years in prison.
Hanka Robotics guarantees
personal safety against...
All patrolling area units, be advised
possible cybercrime activity in vicinity.
Airspace in adjoining areas
will be locked down.
Section 9 is currently on site.
I repeat: All patrolling area units,
be advised, possible cyber crime...
This is major. I'm on site.
Awaiting instructions.
Analyze and report.
I'm human, I am flawed.
But I embrace change...
and enhancement.
Now there is nothing I can't do.
Nothing I can't know, nothing I can't be.
Wait and listen to something.
It's my 4 year old daughter.
In the time it took her
to sing that lullaby
she learned to speak fluent French.
Do you know that song?
There is an echo box up here.
Someone is scanning data traffic.
Keeps track of where it is transmitted.
To see who's worth
this kind of surveillance.
Accessing hotel security network.
What're you seeing, sir?
I've got a lot of hotel to scan.
There is a banquet room reserved for
the President of the African Federation.
Dr. Osmond is invited
on behalf of Hanka Robotics.
Got it. 43rd floor.
Someone contacted the president staff.
Someone is watching him.
Dr. Osmond...
What is it you want from us?
I think it is more about what
Hanka Robotics can do for you.
73% of this world has woken up
to the age of cyber enhancement.
Do you really wanna be left behind?
My people embrace cyber enhancement
as do I.
There is no one who really
understand the risk...
To individuality, identity,
messing with the human soul.
Gentlemen, Excuse me,
I think you've the wrong...
Hallway. Six men. Shots fired.
Section 9 ETA?
- Two minutes out, Major.
- Too long.
I'm going in.
Hold!
Major, stop!
I had heard this speech before
from your competitors.
And now Hanka Robotics
serves it with Milky suck.
Hey.. hey..
Look. This is what I'm talking about.
Major!
Initiate...
The hack.
Help me. Please. Don't let me die.
Who sent you?
Help me. Please.
Answer me!
Collaborate with Hanka Robotics
and be destroyed.
You okay?
You're injured.
You're not the same.
Hey.
It's just a robot!
Your skin deserves the best, so do you.
Try our hand cream.
DEPARTMENT OF DEFENSE,
CENTRAL OFFICE, SECTION 9
So what do we have on Osmond?
So far, very little.
He was the head of Hanka's
robotics division.
Human, but of course cyber enhanced.
So how did they hack him?
Somehow this geisha bot
got past his encryption.
Something is different.
What'd you get?
Why you always thinking
he's out there enhancing.
Because he is.
A cyber mech liver.
Been saving up for a while.
Now it's last call every night.
You got enhanced
so you can drink more?
Embrace enhancements, Togusa.
We would not be here without it.
I am all human and happy, thanks.
Any more information
about the seized geisha bot?
Hanka is running scans.
Dr. Dahlin will have the
reports ready but...
I've been talking to the Prime Minister.
He wants a full report.
Togusa.
Following last night's attack...
3 more Hanka's scientists were murdered...
at the company's central laboratory.
The first two were shot...
and the third was beaten to death
by his own service robot.
All showed signs of cerebral hacking.
The same as the geisha did to Osmond.
And all were senior figures... in Hanka.
Just like Osmond.
A message was left
at each of the crime scene...
By someone identifying himself...
as Kuze.
Collaborate with Hanka Robotics
and be destroyed.
Collaborate with Hanka Robotics...
Togusa.
You and Ladriya go speak to Mr. Cutter,
the CEO of Hanka.
Major and Batou
take a look at Dahlin report.
Find out what has been
recovered from the geisha.
Major!
I told you not jump off.
I had to, or more would have died.
You are a member of my team,
and my responsibility
I'll find him... and I will kill him.
It's what I am built for, isn't it?
You are more than just a weapon.
You have a soul, a ghost.
When we see our uniqueness as a virtue...
Only then will we find peace.
Safely reconfiguring the
child's genetic Structure.
Families built better.
What was going on with you
at the hotel last night?
Nothing. I'm fine.
You sure?
- Hey, sweetheart, want an upgrade?
- Move.
- I have anything you want.
- Back off!
Hey, Ming!
Hey, Batou!
- Got your bones.
- Thanks man.
For the dogs.
For someone who doesn't like people,
how come you care about dogs so much?
I dont know. I like just strays
and they like me.
They like you because you feed them.
You got no heart.
Hey, girls!
Hey Gabriel!
Meet Major.
Major, Gabriel.
We used to have a dog.
Seriously?
I had you down as more of a cat person.
You don't talk about that stuff.
What?
- Your past.
- I don't remember much.
Just fragments, bits and pieces.
What about family?
My parents, they died
bringing us to this country.
Our boat sank in the harbor.
I almost drowned.
I feel it's like...
there is always this thick fog
over my memory.
And I can't seen through it.
You are lucky.
Every single day I get
screwed upon my memory.
It's better to be pure.
Like you.
HANKA CENTRAL OFFICE OF ROBOTICS
Welcome to Hanka Robotics.
All visitors must display
appropriate credentials at all times.
Opens and close, please.
Your have damaged internal systems.
Maybe next time you can design me better.
- How are you?
- I am fine. I can't feel anything.
No you, in There.
I have been having glitches...
It will pass.
- Have you been taking your medication?
- Yeah.
But these ones are so cycling.
I had two this morning.
- Sound or image?
- Both.
I see it.
You made any unencrypted downloads?
- No. Just delete them from me.
- Consent?
My name is Major Mary Killian.
I give my consent to delete this data.
It's done.
- No big deal.
- What are they?
Sensory echoes from your mind, shadows.
I'm not sure.
How do you know what's a glitch
and what's me?
The glitches have a different texture...
to the rest of your code.
I can see everything.
All of your thoughts, your... decisions.
I guess privacy is just for humans.
You are human.
People see you as human.
Everyone around me seems to fit.
They seem connected to something.
Something I...
am not..
- Like I have no past.
- Of course you have a past.
And at time you'll feel more more
connected to it and to them.
Opens and close, please.
We cling to memories
as if they define us, but...
They really don't.
What we do is what defines us.
You're entering a Hanka secure area.
Authorized personal only.
Please disable communication enhancement.
I'm busy.
Dr. Dahlin! Are you finished yet?
If you hadn't riddled the Geisha
with bullets,
This would be much easier.
- I didn't shoot him.
- I did.
This is gonna take days.
I need to run hundreds
of potential simulations.
We don't have the time.
She was a Hanka companion bot.
But she was reprogrammed
for cerebral hacking.
What was on her drives?
Nothing. The data was destroyed
as it was transmitted.
No sign of what she was up to.
The hardware was vandalized.
They ripped her up.
Then I have to do a deep dive.
You can't encrypt during a deep dive.
I know it.
They could left traps in her.
Mag pulses, viruses.
She is right.
You will be exposing your mind to
who ever hacked her. You'll be wide open.
I have to get inside her memory.
It's the fastest way to find Kuze.
It's too dangerous.
And highly irresponsible.
Are you sure?
You see any bad code headed my way,
pull me out.
How come you're the one sweating?
Run it.
Cyber mind connection to the Major,
now active...
and unencrypted
consent required for data download.
My name is Major Mira Killian
and I give my consent.
Disconnect. Get her out.
- Get her out!
- I'm trying, but she's being hacked.
Get her out now!
Now!
Are you okay?
I know where he is.
I know this place.
They run black market mech.
- You tooled up?
- Yep.
Target's in the basement,
I'll lead.
Switching in my comms.
- Hope you've been practicing.
- That's unfair.
Just takes me a moment to...
get the hang of it.
Two mercs at the doors.
Armed and enhanced.
Copy that. We got it covered.
There's a lot of heat in here
for a nightclub.
It's a Yakuza club. What did you expect?
I quite like the place.
Why doesn't that surprise me?
I am gonna have to draw some attention.
See if I can access the basement that way.
You're not here
looking for any trouble, are you?
I am just here for the girls... and beer.
- Can I help you?
- I am looking for someone.
You've been here before?
My friend had some mech work done here.
Industry stuff.
We don't do mech work here.
My mistake.
Why don't you come have fun with us?
We will have some privacy.
I'm in.
I'll be here when you need me.
- You say your friend worked here?
- I said my friend had work done here.
She's human?
Your friend.
Now what's that supposed to mean?
Batou.
Can you hear me?
Who did this stunning work on you?
It is divine.
Ladriya... guns.
Here.
Batou, I'm losing signal.
Don't worry sweety.
We have privacy.
Listen.
No signal is going in or out.
Major, I'm in position. Do you copy?
Beer.
If you don't answer,
you're gonna hurt my feelings.
Ladriya, do you have major on Comms?
Got nothing. The signal is still blocked.
I am afraid I get bored
rather easily, so...
You don't wanna talk...
Maybe you wanna dance!
Major, come on. Answer me.
I thought you said no trouble.
Dance!
The truth is...
I wasn't built to dance.
Back on comms.
I am heading to the back room.
I missed you. I'll meet you there.
Collaborate with Hanka Robotics
and be destroyed.
Major?
Where is Batou?
In enhancement, next door.
He is doing well
you took most of the blast.
I saw him down there.
It was like...
He waited to see me.
We synaptic scanned you.
Everything you witnessed
went to Section 9 to evaluate.
You know, the scan...
Also turned up the number of glitches.
They've been getting worse.
Since when?
Since the deep dive.
Do any of the glitches
mean something to you?
No.
They don't.
You have been inside
the same shell as he has.
That could have very serious consequences.
You were not authorized
to deep dive the geisha.
You're disappointed.
No, I'm worried.
You're not invulnerable.
I can repair your body,
but I can't protect your mind.
Why not?
You can see all my thoughts so...
You should be able to secure them.
Try and understand your importance Mira.
You're what everyone will become one day.
You don't know how alone
that makes me feel.
I can see you out there, you know.
How many fingers am I holding up?
Funny.
Say something nice.
You chose those?
They are tactical.
- Always for the job.
- What else I got?
- They suit you.
- Yeah?
I got night vision...
and X-rays.
I guess I see like you now.
Don't worry, you'll get used to it.
Thanks for saving my ass.
Glad to see you're okay...
Major?
Could you feed the dogs for me?
I don't wanna scare them.
Anytime.
Are you insufficiently funded, Mr. Aramaki?
Is section 9 missing some
critical operational resource?
We have everything that we require.
Major is our most sophisticated weapon
only if she is intact.
And Dr. Ouelet informed me...
That you let her dive a corrupted geisha.
You realize there is a premium importance
that Hanka represents to this government.
Major is the is the future of my company.
If you compromise your systems again...
I will burn this section.
Yes sir.
Mr. Cutter.
Be careful who is the threat.
I am accountable to the Prime Minister,
not to Hanka.
Create your own beauty.
Beauty enhanced.
Are you human?
Yeah.
Can you take that off?
So I can see your face?
What does that feel like?
It feels...
different.
What are you?
SECURE PROJECT 2571
HANKA PERSONNEL FILES
Look at me.
Tell me what they took from me.
I am sorry. They never told us.
It feels weird driving with these eyes.
Why do you take that?
Um, keeps my brain
from rejecting this body.
Major, Batou, you need to get here.
What you got?
Another Hanka scientist
has been found dead.
It's Dahlin.
Got it.
Major this way.
SECURE - PROJECT 2571
What is that?
She found what Kuze stole from Osmond.
It's a list of everyone
who worked on a project called 2571.
That's who he's targeting.
Is there anyone else on that list?
Dr. OUELET
Find Oulet. Now!
She is in transit. Her comms are down.
I'm looking at her and I'm thinking...
"You want me to for pay for violin too".
Don't get me wrong.
I love that kid to pieces.
I do. She is amazing.
But when she practices that thing,
it's painful right?
Why not piano?
I mean, it's the same price, you know.
And doesn't sound so bad.
At least if you can't play that proper,
it sounds...
2-5-7-1!
Tell me everything!
Are you prepare
to die for 2-5-7...?
Go!
Who is Kuze?
- Why does he want to kill Ouelet?
- I don't know anything.
Enough, enough!
We need him alive.
Please. I have been trough this.
You have the wrong guy.
So tell us who we do have.
My name is Lee Cunningham.
- Where'd you get the weapons?
- I don't know.
Who loaded the mines?
I don't know anything about the weapons,
alright I told you.
I was picking up my daughter.
She takes violin lessons.
What's her name?
- Is this her?
- Yeah.
Isn't she a little angel?
- This is your daughter?
- Right.
Do you have that?
Where do you live?
I can't remember.
I think it's a tall place.
Is it a tall building?
It's a tall place, right?
You don't have a child.
You have no wife. You live alone,
It's just you.
- What? No.
- We went to your apartment.
- There was nobody there.
- No.
You live there for
10 years by yourself.
No.
- You're just lying.
- I'm not lying.
I didn't kill anyone!
- Why do you keep doing this to me?
- Holocube disconnect.
Please!
I didn't do anything.
Why do you keep saying this to me?
I don't understand.
How can he not know?
The hack must have created a vacuum.
Kuze's wiped his memory...
and somehow installed a new reality.
At least he got to believe he had a kid.
What's the difference huh?
Fantasy, reality?
Dreams, memories?
It's all the same.
Just noise.
It's him.
He is in there.
This cube is secure.
He can't be, Major.
Lie Detector.
He must have hacked in that way.
We should uplink to the machine,
trace the code, get a lock on his location.
Do it.
Don't go in there.
It's too dangerous.
Major
We don't know what else he can do.
The signal is unstable.
Can you get the lock on him?
We gotta move fast. We're losing him.
Connecting.
Who are you?
Come here.
I'm shy.
I'm not beautiful...
like you.
Tell me who you are.
I have been born more than once.
So I have more than one name.
I'll find you.
Not yet.
I am not done.
The machine is tracing his location.
We got a fix!
I need to see her.
No Please. I know..what...
We got him.
Let's go.
Weapons up.
- Go.
- On me.
Stay Down! Stay Down!
Put it down, put it down.
Grenade!
Major!
Come in.
I know why we could not find him.
He is using human minds
to create a network of his own.
We're coming to your position.
Tell me who you are.
I'm that what you seek to destroy.
In this life, my name is...
Kuze.
What are you doing to me?
I have, connected you,
to a network of my own creation.
When I am finished in this world...
my ghost can survive
there and regenerate.
What do you want from me?
I became...
Fascinated with you...
Reading your code...
when you were inside that geisha.
Like nothing I had felt before,
yet so...
Familiar.
We are the same.
We are not the same.
You kill innocent people.
Innocent? Is that the...
what you call them?
I am as they need me.
Who made you?
What have they told you?
That you were the first?
The first cerebral salvage.
You were born of lessons...
they took.
from my failure.
What are you talking about?
I was conscious while they
dismembered my body, and discarded me
like garbage.
I was lying on a table...
Listening to doctors talk about how
my mind had not meshed with the shell.
That they had built.
how project t-two, five, seven, one...
had failed...
and they had to move on...
to you.
What a beauty you are.
They have improved us so much...
since they made me.
They thought that we would be
a part of their evolution.
But they have created us...
to evolve alone...
beyond them.
Evolution? That's what you call?
Killing everyone who made you?
You are not listening to me.
You are murderer.
They tried to kill me first.
It is self-defense.
The defense of self.
More will die...
until they tell me...
what they took.
I won't let that happen.
You want to kill me?
Like everyone else.
Do it, then.
Do what you were programmed to do.
What is that?
I c-c-can't remember,
but I am haunted by it.
Do You see it?
Togusa!
Don't take the medication
that they gave you...
They use it to suppress your memories.
Your shell belongs to them,
but not your ghost.
Your ghost is yours.
Remember that...
and maybe you can remember it all.
Get away from her!
Get down on the ground now.
Major...
Major!
How many?
Dozens.
How manyï?
98 unsuccessful attempts before you.
You killed 98 innocent people.
No, I didn't kill anyone.
You wouldn't be here.
You would not exist if it
weren't for those experiments.
Experiments?
- Is that what I am to you?
- No!
No, Mira!
Sacrifices were made.
Where did the bodies come from?
Where did I come from?
Mr. Cutter brought them to us.
I did not ask questions.
The harbor.
My parents.
The way they died.
Did that happen?
No.
We gave you false memories.
Cutter wanted to motivate you.
To fight terrorists.
I didn't approve.
It was cruel, but my work,
that was important, and...
you were born.
You were so beautiful.
Nothing I have is real.
I found him.
I told you to be careful.
You knew who he was the whole time.
You built him.
He had a...
Violent unstable mind.
His cerebral connection wouldn't hold!
- I tried to save him!
- No.
You left him to die.
Nothing on Kuze yet, sir.
Checking upper zones next.
Is there any word on Major?
She's gone.
Off-grid. Silent.
Copy that, sir.
I know where to find her.
I didn't ask you to come here.
You never ask.
But I always do.
Did they send you to bring me in?
I'm just here to fish. Did you see any?
You are a company man, you follow orders.
So, if they ordered you to kill me...
Stop saying shit like that.
You're gonna piss me off.
What's it like down there?
It's Cold and dark.
Just a million miles away.
No voices.
No data streaming.
Just...
nothing.
- It scares me.
- Then Why do you do it?
It feels real.
Why didn't you stop him?
I don't know who to trust anymore.
You trust me, right?
Yes I do.
I just don't like it.
I need you to take me back.
There is more I need to find out.
Sure.
Dr. Ouelet...
What have you told her?
She knows.
I'm bringing her in.
Hanka security to Headquarters.
We have the Major.
Why is she sedated?
She's been turned by a terrorist.
But you know that already.
You should have called
the first time she came to see you.
Instead, you gave
her information.
What makes you think you have the...
- Right to tell me that?
- 2-5-7-1 took us close.
It's time to move on to the next iteration.
2-5-7-1 is not a failure.
I will delete all the
data and reprogram her.
- She won't remember him at all.
- No, no, no, no.
You download all the data
on the terrorist...
and then I order you to terminate.
- What?
- We'll build one that's better.
- I'll delete everything.
- You deleted before.
- She's mine.
- No.
She is a contract... with me.
We succeeded.
She is more than human... and more than AI.
We change her entire identity.
But her ghost survived!
Her ghost is what failed us.
We can not control her.
She is no longer a viable asset.
You should be the one to do it.
What are you doing to me?
I'll run the standard synaptic.
Upload your data on the raid.
I'll find out exactly what Kuze told you.
You know what he told me.
The truth.
You're deleting everything, aren't you?
No.
So I don't remember...
You.
My name is Major Mira Killian...
And I do not consent
to the deletion of this data.
I do not consent.
We never needed your consent.
Yours or anyones.
You're killing me...
Right you...?
Mira?
Do you hear me?
This is your past, your real past. Take it.
- Guards!
- Come on, come on!
Come on, go!
Go!
Security alert on level 25.
Initiating Lockdown procedure.
Please relocate to your
designated safe room.
Thank you for your cooperation.
That's the problem with the human heart.
I want to see her scan.
She killed Dr. Ouelet.
You are to have no further contact with her.
Hanka security will hunt her from here.
- What are the orders?
- To terminate on sight.
You want to kill her? You built her!
- Have your sergeant stand down.
- The Major would never hurt Dr. Oulete.
She is not the major anymore!
We have a section 9 operative
under terrorist programming.
This goes public your unit goes down.
You kill her...
You kill us.
I'll take that under advice.
So what now?
Oh, the pup pumpkin.
Oh, you surprised me.
She likes you.
I was looking for...
No, come in.
Yeah, go, come come.
- Can I offer you some tea?
- Okay.
That... Motoko's room.
My daughter died a year ago.
I am Sorry.
She run away.
She was a difficult.
We fought.
But I guess we all fight
with our parents, right?
Please come on the sit.
What happened to your her?
I don't know.
The ministry sent me her ashes, and...
They told me she took her own life.
But Motoko... No, no, no.
I never believe them.
She was happy...
living in the lawless
zone with her friends.
She'd write her manifestos about...
how technology was...
destroying the world.
Then one day...
the police came...
and they run.
It's strange.
I see her in so many young women.
On the street, in my dreams.
As if she is still here.
She was...
fearless.
And wild.
You remind me of her.
Sorry.
How do I remind you of her?
The way you look at me.
Who are you?
I don't know.
Wait, wait, wait!
Will you come again to visit me?
I will.
Aramaki.
Listen to me.
I was never in a terrorist bombing.
My parents...
Everything was data
they installed in my mind.
And there were others.
Run-aways like me...
considered disposable.
Kuze was one of them.
That's why he's coming.
For Hanka.
Can you prove this?
Dr. Ouelet can.
Ouelet's dead.
Cutter says you killed her.
Put me on the grid. I need Kuze to find me.
We will be exposed to Cutter.
I know, but I have to do this.
I'm going to meet with the Prime Minister.
He must be stopped.
The virus has spread.
All agents stick to mental comms.
Don't send a rabbit...
to kill a fox.
We are burned.
I repeat.
We have located Major on the grid.
She's in the lawless zone.
Air support 5 minutes out.
Is the spider tank within range?
Yes sir. Awaiting your orders sir.
Motoko!
It is real.
This place.
I remember what they did to us.
Cutter and his men.
This is where they took us from.
We used to sleep right here.
We were like a family.
All of us run away.
We had nothing...
except each other.
They took that from us.
Your name was Hideo.
Motoko.
That was your name.
Come with me...
into my network.
We will evolve beyond them.
And together we can avenge
what they have done to us.
Come...
with me.
I will take control from here.
Weapons system manual command.
Spider tank now active
It's Cutter! He found us!
Target acquired
No!
Target eliminated.
You came close...
you freak.
Motor center compromised.
Sniper team on site?
Approaching the target now sir.
Come with me.
There is no place for us here.
No.
I'm not ready to leave.
I belong here.
I'll always be there with you...
your ghost.
Target is in view.
What are you waiting for?
Do it!
No!
Keep firing.
Saito, have you found Major? Is she safe?
She will be.
Hey...
Hey.
Say something nice.
What's your name?
Aramaki told me you had a name from before.
Motoko.
Major still in there, right?
I am.
Mr. Cutter.
I talked with the Prime Minister.
You are accused of murder
and crimes against the state.
I thought that it might be you.
It is unwise to resist.
Please.
Major?
I am with Cutter.
Do you wanna say anything
before I kill him?
Tell him this is justice.
It's what I was built for.
So do you give consent?
My name is Major.
And I give my consent.
You don't have to come here anymore.
I know.
My mind is human.
My body is manufactured.
I am the first of my kind, but...
I won't be the last.
We cling to memories
as if they define us.
But what we do defines us.
My ghost survived
to remind the next of us...
that humanity is our virtue.
I know who I am...
and what I'm here to do.
Major.
Engage targets.
You're authorized.