Millenium breaking disaster...
All river traffic has been halted and
police divers search for survivors.
Surrounding area
remains closed.
The man, known to...
Harry Potter.
Who's Harry Potter?
Um, no one.
Bit of a tosser, really.
Funny
that paper of yours.
Couple of minutes ago, I could have sworn
I saw a picture move.
Really?
While I was going
around the train.
- Okay, I was wondering--
- Eleven.
That's when
I get off.
You can tell me all about
that tosser Harry Potter.
You've been reckless
this summer, Harry.
I like riding around
the trains.
Takes my mind
off things.
All unpleasant to be old,
isn't it?
The tale is thrilling,
if I say so myself.
But now is not the time
to tell it.
Take my arm.
Do as I say.
I hardly just Apparated,
didn't I?
Indeed.
Quite successfully too,
I might add.
Most people vomit
the first time.
Can't imagine why.
Welcome to the charming village
of Budleigh Babberton.
Harry, I assume right about now
you must be wondering...
why I brought you here?
Am I right?
Actually sir, after all these years,
I just, sort of, go with it.
Wands on, Harry.
Horace!
Horace.
Merlin's beard!
You don't need
to disfigure me, Albus.
Well I must say you made
a very convincing armchair, Horace.
It's all
in the upholstery.
I come by this stuffing naturally.
What gave me away?
Dragon's blood.
Oh yes, introductions.
Harry, I'd like you to meet
an old friend and colleague of mine--
Horace Slughorn.
Horace...
Well you know who this is.
Harry Potter.
So for love of theatrics,
Horace...
You're, by any chance,
waiting for someone else, were you?
Someone else?
I'm sure I don't know what you mean.
Alright. The Death Eaters
have been trying
to recruit me
for over a year.
Do you know
what's that like?
You can only say no
to these people so many times.
So I never stay anywhere
more than a week.
The Muggles who own this place
are in the Canary Islands.
Well, I think we should put it
back in order for them,
- don't you?
- Yes.
Fine.
That was fun.
Do you mind
if I use the loo?
No, of course.
Don't think I don't know
why you're here, Albus.
The answer is still no.
Absolutely,
and unequivanetly, no.
You're very like
your father.
Except the eyes,
of course.
- You have your--
- My mother's eyes, yeah.
Lily, lovely Lily.
She's exceedingly bright,
your mother.
Even more impressive
even though I could say
that she was Muggle-born.
One of my best friends
is Muggle-born.
- She's the best in our year.
- Oh please don't think
I'm prejudiced.
No, no, no.
Your mother was
one of my absolute favorites.
Look, there she is.
Right at the front.
All mine.
Each and every one.
Ex-students, I mean.
You recognise Barnabas Cuffe?
Editor of the Daily Prophet.
Always takes my owl
should I wish to register an opinion
on the news of the day.
Gwenog Jones,
captain of the Holyhead Harpies.
Free tickets
whenever I want them.
Of course, I haven't been
to a match in some time.
Ah, yes!
Regulus Black.
No doubt, there is
his older brother Sirius,
died a few weeks ago.
I taught the whole Black family,
except Sirius.
It's a shame.
A talented boy.
I got Regulus when
he came along, of course, but...
but I'd like to set.
Horace!
Do you mind if I take this?
I do love
knitting patterns.
Yes, of course,
but you're not leaving, are you?
Oh, I think I know
a lost cause when I see one.
Regrettable, I would have considered it
a very personal triumph
if you consented
to return to Hogwarts.
Ah well, you're like my friend
Mr. Potter here.
One of a kind.
Well, bye-bye Horace.
Bye.
Alright. I'll do it.
But I want Professor Merrythought's
old office,
not the water closet
I had before.
And I expect a raise.
These are mad times
we're living, mad!
They are, indeed.
Sir, exactly what was
all that about?
You are talented,
famous and powerful.
Everything Horace values.
Professor Slughorn's gonna try
to collect you, Harry.
You would be
his crowning jewel.
That's why
he's returning to Hogwarts.
And it's crucial
he should return.
I fear I may have stolen
a wondrous night from you, Harry.
She was truthfully...
very pretty.
The girl.
It's alright, sir.
I'll go back tomorrow,
make some excuse.
Oh you'll not be returning
to Little Whinging tonight, Harry.
But sir, what about Hedwig?
And my trunk?
Both
are waiting for you.
Hedwig?
Mom?
Ginny, what is it?
I was only wondering
when Harry got here.
What?
Harry-- Harry, who?
Harry Potter, of course.
I think I'd know if Harry Potter
was in my house, wouldn't I?
His trunk's in the kitchen...
and his owl.
But no, dear.
I seriously doubt that.
Harry?
Did someone say Harry?
Me, nosey.
Is he up there with you?
Of course not.
I think I'll know if my best friend's
in my room, wouldn't I?
Is that an owl I heard?
You haven't seen him,
have you?
Apparently, he's wandering
about the house.
- Really?
- Really.
Harry!
Harry.
What a lovely surprise!
Why didn't you let us know
you were coming?
I didn't know.
Dumbledore.
Oh, that man!
What we won't do without him?
A bit of... toothpaste.
So when did you
get here?
A few days ago.
Day or for a while,
I wasn't sure I was coming.
Mum...
sort of lost it, last week.
Said Ginny and I have
no business going back to Hogwarts.
It's too dangerous.
Oh, come on.
She's not alone.
Even my parents.
They're Muggles,
know something
bad's happening.
Anyway,
Dad stepped in.
Told us she was
being barmy and...
Took a few days,
but she came around.
But, this is Hogwarts
we're talking about.
It's Dumbledore.
What could be safer?
There's been a lot of talk
recently that...
Dumbledore's
got a bit old.
What rubbish!
Well, he's only...
How old is he?
150?
Give or take a few years?
Cissy, you can't do this!
He can't be trusted.
The Dark Lord trusts him.
The Dark Lord is mistaken.
Run along, Wormtail.
I-I know
I ought not to be here.
The Dark Lord himself
forbade me to speak of this.
If the Dark Lord has forbidden it,
you would not to speak.
Put it down, Bella, we mustn't
touch what isn't ours.
As it, so happens,
I'm aware of your situation, Narcissa.
You?
The Dark Lord told you?
Your sister darts me.
Understandable, over the years,
I've played my part well.
So well, I've deceived one of
the greatest wizards of all time.
Dumbledore is a great wizard.
Only a fool would question it.
I don't doubt you, Severus.
You should be honored,
Cissy.
As should Draco.
He's just a boy.
I can't change
the Dark Lord's mind.
But it might be possible
for me to help Draco.
Severus.
Swear to it.
Make the Unbreakable Vow.
It's just empty words.
You'll give it his best effort...
when it matters most.
He'll just slither back
to his hole.
Coward.
Take out your wand.
Will you, Severus Snape,
watch over Draco Malfoy
as he attempts to fulfill
the Dark Lord's wishes?
I will.
And will you,
to the best of your ability,
protect him from harm?
I will.
And if Draco should fail,
will you yourself
carry out the deed
the Dark Lord has ordered
Draco to perform?
I will.
Step up, step up!
We got fating fancies.
- And he's made me go.
- At just in for time for school.
Puking Pastilles.
Meeting's in the cauldron,
Hanson.
- Peruvian Instant Darkness Powder.
- How real many spinned it at that one?
Handy if you need
to make a quick getaway.
Hello, ladies.
Love potions, eh?
Yeah.
They really do work.
Then again the way
we heard you, sis...
You're doing just fine
on your own.
Meaning?
Are you not currently dating
Dean Thomas?
It's none of your business.
How much for this?
- Five galleons.
How much for me?
I'm your brother.
- Ten galleons.
Come on, let's go.
Hi, Ron.
Hi.
How are Fred and George
doing it?
Half the alley's
closed down.
Fred reckons people
need a laugh these days.
I reckon he's right.
Oh, no.
Everyone got their wands
from Ollivanders.
Harry...
Is it me
or do Draco and Mummy
look like two people who
don't want to be followed?
Quibbler!
Quibbler.
He's lovely.
They've been known to sing
at Boxing Day, you know?
- Quibbler?
- Oh, please.
What's a Wrackspurt?
Invisible creatures,
they flow in your ears
and make your brain go fuzzy.
Quibbler!
So what was Draco doing
with that weird-looking cabinet?
And who were
all those people?
Don't you see?
It was a ceremony.
- An initiation.
- Stop it, Harry.
- I know where you're going with this.
- It happened.
- He's one of them.
- One of who?
Harry's under the impression
Draco Malfoy is now a Death Eater.
You're barking.
What would You-Know-Who want
with a sod like Malfoy?
Oh, then what's he doing
in Borgin and Burkes?
Browsing for furniture?
It's a creepy shop.
He's a creepy blood.
Blood? His father is a Death Eater.
It only makes sense.
Besides, Hermione saw it
with her own eyes.
I told you,
I don't know what I saw.
I need some air.
- What's going on?
- What's in that?
What's that?
What is it?
- I don't know.
- What was that?
Relax, boys. It's probably just
a phantom messing around.
Come, Draco. Sit down.
We'll be at Hogwarts soon.
Hogwarts.
What a pathetic excuse for a school.
I think I pitched myself
off the astronomy tab
I thought I had to continue
for another 2 years.
What's that supposed
to mean?
Let's just say I don't think
I see me wasting my time
in Charms class
next year.
Amused, Blaise?
Let's see just
who's laughing in the end.
You two go on.
Wanna check something.
- Where's Harry?
- He's probably on the platform.
Come on.
Didn't Mummy ever tell you
it was rude to eavesdrop, Potter?
Petrificus Totalus!
Oh yeah...
She was dead before you could
wipe the drool off your chin.
That's for my father.
Enjoy your ride
back to London.
Ennervate!
Hello, Harry!
Luna.
How'd you know where I was?
Wrapspurts,
your head's full of them.
Sorry I made you miss the carriages,
by the way, Luna.
That's alright.
It was like being with a friend.
Well,
I am your friend, Luna.
That's nice.
Oh, about time.
I've been looking
all over for you two.
Right...
Names?
Professor Flitwick,
you know me for five years.
No exceptions, Potter.
- Who are those people?
- Aurors.
Security.
What's this cane here then?
It's not a cane, you cretin.
It's a walking stick.
And what exactly will
you be doing with all...
be construed
as an offensive weapon.
It's alright, Mr. Filch.
I can vouch for Mr. Malfoy.
Nice face, Potter.
Would you like me
to fix it for you?
Personally, I think
you look a bit more...
devil may care
this way but...
It's up to you.
Well, have you ever
fixed a nose before?
No, but I've done
several toes...
How different
are they really?
Um, okay, yeah.
Give it a go.
Episkey!
- How do I look?
- Exceptionally ordinary.
Brilliant!
Hermione...
I'm here in a minute.
Will you stop eating?
Your best friend is missing.
Why won't you
turn around, you lunatic?
He's covered in blood again.
Why is it
he's always covered in blood?
Looks like it's his own
this time.
Where have you been?
What happened to your face?
Later.
What did I miss?
The Sorting Hat says we ought to be
brave and strong in these trouble times.
Easy for it to say, though.
It's a hat, isn't it?
- Very best of evenings to you all.
- Thanks.
First off, let me introduce
the newest member of our staff.
Horace Slughorn.
Professor Slughorn, I'm happy to say,
has agreed to resume his old post...
as Potions Master.
Meanwhile, the post of
Defense Against the Dark Arts...
will be taken by
Professor Snape.
As you know,
each and every one of you
were searched
upon your arrival here tonight.
And you have the right
to know why.
Once,
there was a young man.
Like you,
sat in this very hall.
Walked this castle's corridors.
Slept under it's roof.
You see, to all the world,
a student like any other.
His name:
Tom Riddle.
Today of course, is known
all over the world by another name.
Which is why
as I stand,
looking out
upon you all tonight,
I'm reminded
of a sobering fact.
Every day, every hour,
this very minute, perhaps...
dark forces attempt
to penetrate this castle's walls.
But in the end,
that greatest weapon...
is you.
Just something
to think about.
Now off to bed,
beep beep.
That was cheerful.
History of Magic is upstairs,
ladies, not down.
Mr. Davis, Mr. Davis,
that is the girls' lavatory.
Potter.
Oh, this can't be good.
Enjoying ourselves,
are we?
I had a free period
this morning, Professor.
So I noticed.
I would think you would want
to fill it with Potions.
Or is it no longer your ambition
to become an Auror?
Well, it was, but I was told to have
to get an Outstanding in my O.W.L.
So you did, when Professor Snape
was teaching Potions.
However, Professor Slughorn's
perfectly happy
to accept N.E.W.T. students
with "Exceeds Expectations".
Brilliant, um...
Well, I'll head there straight away.
Oh, good, good.
Potter, take Weasley with you.
He looks far too happy over there.
I don't want
to take Potions.
There's Quidditch trials coming up,
I need to practice.
Attention to detail in the preparation
is the prerequisite of all plan.
Harry, my boy,
I've been beginning to worry.
You brought someone
with us, I see.
Ron Weasley, sir.
But I'm dead awful at Potions.
A menace, actually so.
I'm probably just gonna--
Nonsense,
we'll sort you out.
Any friend of Harry's
is a friend of mine.
Get your books out.
I'm sorry, sir, I haven't actually
got my book yet and nor is Ron.
Not to worry,
get what you want from the cupboard.
Now as I was saying,
I prepared some concoctions
this morning.
Any ideas
what these might be?
- Yes, Miss...?
- Granger, sir.
That one there is
Veritaserum.
It's a truth-telling serum.
And that one--
It's terribly tricky to make.
This is Amortentia.
The most powerful
love potion in the world.
It's rumored to smell differently
to each person
according to
what attracts them.
For example, I smell...
Freshly mown grass
and new parchment and...
Spearmint toothpaste.
Now Amortentia
doesn't create actual love.
That would be impossible,
but it does cause
powerful infatuation or obsession.
And for that reason,
it is probably the most
dangerous potion in this room.
Sir, you haven't told us
what's in that one.
Oh yes. What you see before you,
ladies and gentlemen,
is a curious little potion,
known as Felix Felicis.
But it is more commonly known
referred to as--
- Liquid luck.
- Yes, Miss Granger.
Liquid luck.
Desperately tricky to make,
disastrous should you get it wrong.
One sip and you'll find
that all of your endeavours succeed.
At least
until the effects wear off.
So this is what I offer
each of you today.
One tiny vial of liquid luck
to the student
who in the hour that remains,
manages to brew
an acceptable
Draught of Living Dead.
Recipes for which can be found
on page 10 of your books.
Issue one doubt, however.
Only one set of student
manage to brew a potion
of sufficient quality
to claim this prize.
Nevertheless,
good luck to you all.
Let the brewing commence.
How did you do that?
You crush it,
don't cut it.
No, the instructions
specifically says to cut.
No, really.
Merlin's beard!
It is perfect!
So perfect I'd just say
one drop would kill us all!
Here we are then,
as promised.
One vial of Felix Felicis.
Congratulations.
Use it well.
Oh Harry,
you got my message?
Come in.
How are you?
I'm fine, sir.
Enjoying your classes?
I know Professor Slughorn
is most impressed with you.
I think he overestimates
my abilities, sir.
Do you?
Definitely.
What about your activities
outside the classroom?
Sir?
Well, I notice you've spent
a great deal of time with Miss Granger.
I can't help wondering if--
Oh, no, no, I mean...
She's brilliant
and we're friends.
- But no.
- Forgive me.
I was only being curious.
But enough chit-chat.
You must be wondering
why I summoned you here tonight.
The answer lies here.
What you're looking at
are memories.
In this case,
pertaining to one individual:
Voldemort.
Or as he was known, then:
Tom Riddle.
This vial contains
the most sufficient memory.
On the day
I first met him.
I'd like you to see it.
If you want.
I'm to admit to some confusion for
receiving your letter, Mr. Dumbledore.
In all the years Tom's been here,
he's never once had a family visitor.
There have been incidents
with the other children--
Nasty things.
Tom, you have a visitor.
How'd you do, Tom?
Don't.
You're the doctor,
aren't you?
No, I'm a professor.
I don't believe you.
She wants me
looked at.
They think I'm...
different.
Or perhaps they're right.
I'm not mad.
Hogwarts is not a place
for mad people.
Hogwarts is a school.
School of magic.
You can do things,
can't you, Tom?
Things other children can't.
I can make things move
without touching them.
I can make animals do
what I want without training them.
I can make bad things happen
to people who mean to me.
Can make them hurt.
If I want.
Who are you?
Well, I'm like you, Tom.
I'm different.
Prove it.
I think there's something
in your wardrobe
trying to get out, Tom.
Thievery is not tolerated
at Hogwarts, Tom.
At Hogwarts, we'll be taught not only
how to use magic, but how to control it.
You understand me?
I can speak to snakes too.
They find me.
Whisper things.
Is that normal for someone like me?
Did you know, sir,
then?
Did I know I just met the most
dangerous dark wizard of all time?
No.
If I had, I...
Over time
while here at Hogwarts,
Tom Riddle grew close
to one particular teacher.
Can you guess
who that teacher might be?
You didn't bring Professor Slughorn back
simply to teach potions, did you, sir?
No, I did not.
You see, Professor Slughorn possesses
something that I desire very dearly.
He will not
give it out easily.
You said Professor Slughorn
would try to collect to me.
I did.
Do you want me
to let him?
Yes.
Okay,
so this morning,
I'm gonna be putting you all
for a few drills
just to assess you
straight.
Quiet, please!
Shut it!
Thanks.
Alright, um,
now then, remember,
just because you made
the team last year
does not guarantee you
a spot this year.
Is that clear?
Good.
No hard feelings, Weasley,
alright?
Hard feelings?
Yeah, I'll be going out
for Keeper's, well,
It's...
nothing personal.
Really?
Such a big guy like you?
You've got more of a Beater's build,
don't you think?
Keepers need
to be quick, agile.
I'll have my chances.
Say, um, you think you could
introduce me to your friend, Granger?
Wouldn't mind, eh,
getting on a first-hand base,
you know
what I mean?
Come on, come on.
Go, Cormac.
Come on, Ron!
Come on, Ron.
Confundus.
He's brilliant.
I have to admit I thought
I was going to miss that last one.
I hope Cormac's
not taking it too hard.
He's got a bit of a thing for you,
Hermione-- Cormac.
He's vile.
Have you ever heard of the spell:
Sectumsempra?
No, I haven't.
If you had a shred of self-respect,
you'd hand that book in.
Not bloody likely.
He's top of the class.
He's even better than you, Hermione.
Slughorn thinks
he's a genius.
I'd like to know
who's that book was.
- Let's have a look, shall we?
- No.
Why not?
The binding is fragile.
"The binding is fragile"?
Yeah.
- Who's the Half-Blood Prince?
- Who?
That's what it says
right here.
This book is property
of the Half-Blood Prince.
For weeks,
you carry around this book.
Practically, sleep with it,
and yet you have no desire
to find out
who the Half-Blood Prince is.
I didn't say I wasn't curious
and I don't sleep with it.
Well, it's true.
Well, I got a nice chat
before I go to bed.
And all you do is that bloody book.
It's like being with Hermione.
Well, I was curious
So, I went to--
- The library?
And?
And nothing.
I couldn't find a reference
anywhere
to the Half-Blood Prince.
There we go.
That settles it, then.
Yeah, uh...
hoping to find you
in the Three Broomsticks.
Uh no, emergency choir practice
from the freighthorse.
Does anyone fancy
a butterbeer?
A chum of mine
was sledging down Clagsby Hill.
We had a very long, home-made
Norwegian style sledge.
We hurtled down,
we hit what most...
Ron, sit aside me.
Okay.
Something to drink?
Three butterbeers
and some ginger in mine, please.
Oh, bloody hell.
Ron, see they're only
holding hands.
And snogging.
- I'd like to leave.
- What?
You can't be serious.
- That happens to be my sister.
- So?
What if she looked at me
and saw you snogging me?
Would you expect her
to get up and leave?
- Hey, my boy.
- So wonderful to see you.
And you, and you.
So what brings you here?
Oh, Three Broomsticks and I go way back
further than I care to admit.
I could remember
when it was One Broomstick.
All hands on deck, Granger.
Listen, my boy,
in the old days, I used to throw together
the occassional supper party.
Select a student
or two.
Would you be game?
I consider it
an honor, sir.
You'd be welcome too,
Granger.
- I'd be delighted, sir.
- Splendid!
Look for my owl.
Good to see you, Wallenby.
What are you playing at?
Dumbledore's asked me
to get to know him.
- Get to know him?
- Dunno.
It must be important.
If it wasn't,
Dumbledore wouldn't ask.
You got a little bit...
Katie, we don't know
what it could be.
- Harry, what...
- I know what I'm doing.
Did you hear
what she was saying
back in the pub there
on me and her snogging?
I warned her.
I warned her not to touch it.
Don't get any closer!
Get back, all of you.
Oh no, no, no.
Do not touch that,
except for the wrappings.
Do you understand?
You're sure Katie did not have this
in her possession
when she entered
the Three Broomsticks?
It's like I said.
She left to go to the loo.
And when she came back,
she had the package.
She said it was important
that she deliver it.
- Did she say to whom?
- To Professor Dumbledore.
Very well. Thank you, Leanne.
You may go.
Why is it
when something happens,
it is always you three?
Believe me, Professor,
I've been asking myself
the same question for six years.
Oh, Severus.
What do you think?
I think Ms. Bell
is lucky to be alive.
She was cursed,
wasn't she?
I know Katie.
Off the Quidditch pitch,
she wouldn't hurt a fly.
If she was delivering that
to Professor Dumbledore,
she wasn't doing it
knowingly.
Yes, she was cursed.
It was Malfoy.
That is a very
serious accusation, Potter.
Indeed.
Your evidence?
I just know.
You "just" know.
Once again, you're astonished
with your gifts, Potter.
Gifts mere mortals can only
dream of possessing.
How grand it must be
to be the Chosen One.
I suggest you go back
to your dormitories.
All of you.
What do you suppose
Dean sees in her-- Ginny?
And what does
she see in him?
Dean--
He's brilliant.
You called him slick git
not five hours ago.
Yeah, well, he was running
his hands all over my sister,
wasn't he?
Something snaps.
You've got to hate him, you know?
Old principle.
I suppose.
So what do you think
he sees in her?
I don't know.
She's smart,
funny, attractive--
Attractive?
You know,
she's got nice skin.
Skin? You're saying Dean's
dating my sister because of her skin?
For blood, I mean.
I'm just--I'm just saying
it could be
a contributing factor.
Hermione's got nice skin.
When you say it,
as skin goes, I mean.
I've never really
thought about it.
But I suppose, yeah.
Very nice.
I think
I'll be going to sleep now.
Right.
So tell me, Cormac, do you see anything
of your uncle Tiberius these days?
Yes, sir, in fact I'm meant
to get hunting with him
and the Minister of Magic
over the holidays.
Oh, well, be sure
to give them both my best.
And what about
your uncle, Belby?
For those of you
who don't know well,
Marcus' uncle invented
the Wolfsbane Potion.
Is he working
on anything new?
I don't know.
He and my dad
don't get along.
'Prolly cause my dad
says potions are rubbish.
His only potion worth having
is a stiff one at the end of the day.
And what about you,
Ms. Granger,
what exactly does your family do
in the Muggle world?
My parents are dentists.
They attend to people's teeth.
Fascinating.
And is that considered
a dangerous profession?
No.
Although, one boy, Robby Fenwich,
did bite my father once.
He needed ten stitches.
Ah, Ms. Weasley.
Come in, come in.
Look, her eyes.
They've been fighting again.
Her and Dean.
Sorry,
I'm not usually late.
No matter,
just in time for dessert.
That is if Belby
has left you any.
- What?
- Nothing.
Goodbye.
Bye-bye.
Potter!
I'm sorry, sir, I was
just admiring your hourglass.
Ah yes,
most intriguing object.
The sand runs in accordance
with the quality of the conversation.
It is stimulating,
the sand runs slowly.
- If it is not...
- I think I'll be going, then.
Nonsense.
You have nothing
to fear, dear boy.
Actually,
some of your classmates...
Well, let's just say
they're unlikely to make the shelf.
Shelf, sir?
Anyone who aspires to be anyone
hopes to end up here.
But then again, you already
are someone, aren't you, Harry?
Did Voldemort
ever make the shelf, sir?
You knew him, didn't you, sir?
Tom Riddle?
You were his teacher.
Mr. Riddle had a number of teachers
who was here at Hogwarts.
What was he like?
I'm sorry, sir.
Forgive me.
He killed my parents.
Of course, it's only natural
you should want to know more.
But I'm afraid
I must disappoint you, Harry.
When I first met
young Mr. Riddle,
he was a quiet,
albeit brilliant boy,
committed to becoming
a first-grade wizard.
Not unlike
others I've known.
Not unlike yourself,
in fact.
If the monster existed,
it was very deep within.
You okay, Ron?
I'm counting on you, Ron.
I've 2 games on Gryffindor, ya?
- Be good, Ron.
- Loser!
What's he wearing?
- So how was it, then?
- How is what?
- Your dinner party?
- Pretty boring actually.
But I think
Harry enjoyed dessert.
Slughorn's having Christmas,
do you know?
I'm about to bring someone.
I expect
you'll be bringing McLaggen.
He's in the Slug Club,
isn't he?
Actually,
I was going to ask you.
Really?
Good luck today, Ron.
I know
you'll be brilliant.
I'm resigning.
After today's match,
McLaggen can have my spot.
Are you alright?
- Juice?
- Sure.
Hello, everyone.
You look dreadful, Ron.
Is that why you put
something in his cup?
Is it a tonic?
Liquid luck.
Don't drink it, Ron.
- You could be expelled for that.
- What are we talking about?
Come on, Harry,
we've got a game to win.
- Weasley! Weasley! Weasley!
You shouldn't
have done it.
I know. I supposed I could have just
used the Confundus charm.
That was different.
That was try-outs,
this was a natural game.
You didn't put in?
Ron only thought
you did.
Charm spell.
Just practising.
Very good.
How does it feel, Harry?
When you see
Dean with Ginny?
I know.
I see the way
you look at her.
You're my best friend.
Oops! I think
this room's taken.
What's with the birds?
Oppugno.
It feels like this.
I can't help it if
she's got her knickers in a twist.
What Lav and I have, well,
let's just say,
there's no stopping it.
It's chemical.
Will it last?
Who knows?
Point is
I'm a free agent.
He's at perfect liberty
to kiss whomever he likes.
I really couldn't
care less.
Was I
under the impression
he and I would be attending
Slughorn's Christmas party together?
Yes. Now,
given the circumstances,
I had to make
other arrangements.
- Have you?
- Yes.
Why?
Well, I just thought
seeing is not the risk at going
with who
we'd really like to,
We should go together,
as friends.
Why didn't
I think of that?
Who are you going with?
Um, it's a surprise.
Anyways, you have got to worry about.
You can't take anyone.
You see that girl
over there?
That's Romilda Vane.
Harry, she's been been trying
to smuggle you a love potion.
Really?
Hey!
She's only interested in you because
she thinks you're the Chosen One.
But I am
the Chosen One.
Okay, sorry, um...
Kidding.
I'll ask someone I like.
Someone cool.
I've never been
to this part of the castle.
At least,
not while awake.
I sleep-walk, you see.
That's why
I wear shoes to bed.
Harmonia nictere passus.
Drink?
Neville.
I didn't get
into the Slug Club.
It's okay, though.
He's got Melvin hanging up
towels in the looroom.
I'm--I'm fine, mate.
Thanks.
Okay.
Hermione,
what are you doing?
What happened to you?
No, I've just escaped.
I mean, I left Cormac
under the mistletoe.
Cormac?
That's who you invited?
I thought it would
annoy Ron the most.
Thank you very much.
We will catch up with you.
He's got more tentacles
than a Snargaluff plant.
- Dragon tails?
- No, I'm fine, thank you.
Just this one.
They give one horribly bad breath.
On second thoughts,
it might keep Cormac away.
God, here he comes.
I think she just went
to paddle her nose.
She's a little minx,
your friend.
Nice to work.
How nasty isn't she?
Yeah, yeah,
yeah.
What is this I'm eating,
by the way?
Dragon balls.
You've just brought yourself
a month's detention, McLaggen.
Not so quick, Potter.
Sir, I really think I should
rejoin the party. My date--
Can surely survive your absence
for another minute or two.
Besides, I only wish
to convey a message.
- Message?
- From Professor Dumbledore.
He asked me to give you his best
and he hopes you enjoy your holidays.
He...
He's travelling.
And he won't return
until term resumes.
Travelling where?
How are you?
Get your hands off me,
you filthy Squibb.
Professor Slughorn, sir.
I just discovered this boy
lurking in an upstairs corridor.
He claims to have been
invited to your party.
Okay, okay,
I was gate-crashing.
Happy?
I'll escort him out.
Certainly, Professor.
Alright, everyone carry on,
carry on.
Maybe I did hex that Bell girl.
Maybe I didn't.
What about you?
I swore to protect you.
I made the Unbreakable Vow.
I don't need protection.
I was chosen
for this.
I don't know
what all this mean,
- but I won't fail him.
- You're afraid, Draco.
You attempt to consider,
but it's obvious,
- let me assist you.
- No.
I was chosen.
This is my moment.
Unbreakable Vow.
You sure that's what Snape said?
Positive. Why?
It's just, you can't break
an Unbreakable Vow.
I-I worked that much out
for myself, funny enough.
I don't understand.
Oh bloody hell.
I miss you.
Lovely.
All she wants to do
is snog me.
My lips
are getting chapped, look.
Then I'll take
your word for it.
So what happens
to you?
What happens
if you break an Unbreakable Vow?
You die.
Voldemort has chosen
Draco Malfoy for a mission?
- I know it sounds mad.
- Has it occured to you, Harry,
that Snape was simply pretending
to offer Draco help
so he could find out
what he was up to?
Ginny!
That's not
what it sounded like.
Perhaps Harry
is right, Remus.
I mean, to make
an Unbreakable Vow--
It comes down to whether or not
you trust Dumbledore's judgement.
Dumbledore trusts Snape,
therefore, I do.
Dumbledore
can make mistakes.
- He said so himself.
- You are blinded by hatred.
- I'm not.
- Yes, you are.
People are disappearing,
Harry. Daily.
We could only place our trust
in a handful of people.
If we started fighting
amongst ourselves,
we're doomed.
Ginny!
Open up, you.
Don't you trust me?
It's good.
Just, uh, get...
- Pie?
- Not for me. No.
You'll have to forgive
Remus.
It takes its toll,
his condition.
Are you alright,
Mr. Weasley?
We're being followed,
all of us.
Most days, Molly doesn't
leave the house.
It's not been easy.
Did you get my owl?
Yes, I did.
If Dumbledore is traveling,
then perhaps news to the Ministry,
but perhaps that's the way
Dumbledore wants it.
As for Draco Malfoy...
I know a bit more.
- Go on.
- I sent an agent to Borgin and Burkes.
I think from
what you described...
What you and Ron
saw at the end of summer,
the object that Draco
is so interested in,
is a Vanishing Cabinet.
A "Vanishing Cabinet"?
They were all the rage
when Voldemort first rose to power.
You can see the appeal.
Should the Death Eaters
come knocking,
one simply have to slip inside
and disappear for an hour or two.
It transports you
practically anywhere.
Tricky contraptions, though.
Very temperamental.
What happened to it?
The one
at Borgin and Burkes?
Nothing.
It's still there.
It was delicious,
Molly, really.
Are you sure
you won't stay?
No, we should go.
The first night of the cycle's
always the worst.
Remus?
Sweetheart.
Has Ron
gone to bed?
Um, not yet. No.
Shoelace...
Merry Christmas, Harry.
Merry Christmas.
- Harry, no!
- Harry! Remus.
Ginny!
I killed Sirius Black!
You coming to get me?
Get me!
He's trying to get me!
Harry?
Stupefy!
Harry!
Ginny!
Molly.
It's so easy for them
to get to you.
You're bloody lucky
you weren't killed.
You have to realise
who you are, Harry!
I know who I am,
Hermione, alright.
Sorry.
Hon, go somewhere.
That's my Won-Won.
Excuse me,
I have to go and vomit.
...Always you ruin
half the start.
Sir, is it true that
Professor Merrythought is retiring?
Tom, I couldn't tell you
if I knew, could I?
And by the way,
thank you for the pineapple.
You're quite right.
It is my favorite.
But how did you know?
Intuition.
Good gracious,
is it that time already?
Off you go, boys, or Professor Dippett
will have us all in detention.
Look sharp, Tom.
Don't be caught
out of bed after hours.
Is something
on your mind, Tom?
Yes, sir.
See, I couldnt think of
anyone else to go to.
The other professors...
Well, they're not like you.
They might
misunderstand.
Go on.
I was in the library
the other night.
In the restricted section.
And I picked something
rather odd about this rare magic.
I thought perhaps,
you could illuminate me.
It's called, as I understand it,
Hor...
I beg your pardon?
I don't know anything about such things
and if I did,
I wouldn't tell you.
Now get out of here
at once
and dont let me ever catch you
mentioning them again!
Confused?
I'd be surprised if you weren't.
I don't understand.
What happened?
This is perhaps the most important
memory I had collected.
It is also a lie.
This memory has been tempered with
by the same person whose memory it is.
Our old friend,
Professor Slughorn.
But why would he temper
with his own memory?
I suspect
he's ashamed of it.
Why?
Why, indeed.
I asked you to get to know
Professor Slughorn
and you had done so.
Now I want you to persuade him
to divulge his true memory.
Any way you can.
I don't know him
that well, sir.
This memory is everything.
Without it, we are blind.
Without it, we leave
the fate of our world to chance.
You have no choice.
You must not fail.
I highly recommend,
reacquaint yourself
with the chapter
on antidotes.
Now, I'll tell you more about
bezoars in our next class.
Right, off you go.
Elise, don't forget your rat tail.
Aha! It isn't
the Prince of Potions himself!
What do I owe
this pleasure?
Oh, sir, I wondered
if I wanted to ask you something.
Ask away, dear boy.
Ask away.
Well, you see the other day,
I was in the library
in the restricted section,
and I came across something
rather odd
about a very rare piece of magic.
Yes, what was
this rare piece of magic?
Well, I don't know,
but I can't remember the name exactly.
But it just got me wondering,
are there some kinds of magic
you're not allowed
to teach us?
I'm Potions Master,
Harry,
I think your question better be
posed to Professor Snape.
Yes, he and I don't
exactly see eye-to-eye, sir.
What I mean
to say is...
Well, he's not like you.
He might misunderstand.
Yes, it would be no light
without the dark.
And so
it is with magic,
myself I always strive
to live within the light.
I suggest
you do the same.
Is that what you told Tom Riddle, sir,
when he came asking questions?
Dumbledore put you up to this,
didn't he?
Didn't he?
Yes?
Oh, it's you, Potter.
I-I'm sorry,
I'm busy at the moment.
That's beautiful,
isn't it?
The moon.
Divine.
Had ourselves a little
late night snack, did we?
It was on your bed, the box.
I just thought I'd try one.
Or twenty?
I can't stop
thinking about her, Harry.
Honestly, you know, I reckon
she was starting to annoy you.
She could never annoy me.
I think I love her.
Well, brilliant.
Do you think
she knows I exist?
I very well hope so.
She's been snogging you
for three months.
Snogging?
Who are you talking about?
Romilda, of course.
Romilda Vane.
Okay, very funny.
What was that for?
It's no joke.
- I'm in love with her!
- Alright, fine.
You're in love with her.
Have you ever actually met her?
No.
Can you introduce me?
Come on, Ron.
I will introduce you to Romilda Vane.
I'm sorry, sir.
I wouldn't bother you
if it weren't absolutely essential.
- Where's Romilda?
- What's the matter with Wimby?
Very powerful love potion.
Very well,
better bring him in.
I always thought you could whip up
a remedy for this is in no time, Harry.
Well, I-I thought this called
for more practised hands, sir.
Hello, darling.
Fancy a drink?
Perhaps, you're right.
I'm sorry, by the way, Professor,
about earlier today.
Our misunderstanding.
Oh, not at all.
Old water under the bridge, you know.
Correct?
Well, I expect you're tired a bit,
after all these years.
And the questions
about Voldemort.
Don't use that name!
Here you go, boy.
Bottom's up.
- What's this?
- Tonic for the nerves.
What happened to me?
- A love potion.
- A bloody strong one at there.
- I feel really bad.
- You need to pick me up, my boy.
Got butterbeer, wine,
dazzling oak-matured mead.
I had other intentions for this,
but I think, given the circumstances.
Here you are, Potter.
To life!
Ron!
Professor, do something.
I-I don't understand!
Come on, Ron,
breathe!
These girls...
They're gonna kill me.
Quick thinking on your part,
Harry, using a bezoar.
You should be very proud
of your student, Horace.
Ah, yes.
Very proud.
I think we agree
Potter's actions were heroic.
The question is:
Why were they necessary?
I, indeed.
This appears to be a gift,
Horace.
You don't remember
who gave you this bottle?
By the way,
it possesses remarkably
subtle hints
of liquorice and cherry.
When not polluted
with poison.
Actually, I had intended
to give it as a gift, myself.
To whom,
might I ask?
To you, headmaster.
Where is he?
Where's my Won-Won?
Has he been
asking for me?
What's she doing here?
I might ask you
the same question.
I happen to be
his girlfriend.
And I happen to be his...
friend.
Don't make me laugh.
You haven't spoken
in weeks.
I suppose you want
to make up with him
now that he's suddenly
all interesting.
He's been poisoned,
you daft dimbo!
And for the record,
I've always found him interesting.
See?
He senses my presence.
Don't worry, Won-Won.
I'm here.
Hermione.
Oh to be young
and to feel love's keen sting.
Well, come over,
everybody.
Mr. Weasley's well attended.
About time,
don't you think?
Thank you.
Just shut up.
Stop it, Ron.
You're making it snow.
Tell me how I broke up
with Lavender again.
Well, she came to visit you
in the hospital.
And you talked.
I don't believe it was
a particularly long conversation.
Don't get me wrong.
I'm bloody thrilled to be shot of her's.
She seems a bit...
put out.
Yes, um...
She does, isn't she?
You say you don't remember
anything from that night.
Anything at all?
There is something.
It can't be.
I was completely boggled,
didn't I?
Boggled.
Harry...
That's Katie.
Katie Bell.
Katie,
how are you?
I know you're going
to ask, Harry.
But I don't know
who cursed me.
I've been trying
to remember. Honestly.
But I just can't.
Katie.
I know what you did,
Malfoy.
You hexed it,
didn't you?
Sectumsempra!
You have
to get rid of it.
Today.
Take my hand.
It's the Room of Requirement.
We need to hide
the Half-Blood Prince's book.
Where no one'll ever find it.
Including you.
- What was that?
See, you never know
what you'll find up here.
Alright, close your eyes.
That way you can't be tempted.
Close your eyes.
S    u    B:
V  e R  d  i K  T
That can stay hidden
up here too if you like.
So, did you and Ginny
do it then?
What?
Well, hide the book?
Oh, yeah.
Oh, g--
Still no luck with Slughorn then,
I take it?
Luck.
That's it.
All I need is a bit of luck.
Well, how do you feel?
Excellent.
Really excellent.
Remember, Slughorn usually
leaves early, takes a walk,
and then
returns to his office.
Right.
I'm going down to Hagrid's.
What?
No, Harry, you've got
to go to speak to Slughorn.
We have a plan.
I know but I've got a really
good feeling about Hagrid's.
I feel it's--it's
the place to be tonight.
Do you know
what I mean?
- No.
Well, trust me.
I know what I'm doing.
Or Felix does.
Hi!
- Merlin's beard, Harry!
- Sorry, sir.
I should have announced myself.
Clear my throat.
Coughed.
You probably thought
I was Professor Sprout?
Definitely.
What makes you think?
Ah well,
just your general behaviour, sir.
Just sneaking around,
jumping when you saw me.
- Are those tentacular leaves, sir?
- Yes.
They're very valuable,
aren't they?
Ten galleons a leaf
to the right buyer.
Not that I'm familiar with
any such back alley transactions
but one does hear rumours.
My only interests
are purely academical.
I mean, personally,
these plants always kinda freak me out.
Exactly how did you get
out of the castle, Harry?
Through the front door, sir.
I'm off to Hagrid's, you see.
He's a very dear friend
and I just fancy paying him a visit.
So if you don't mind,
I will be going now.
- Harry!
- Sir?
It's nearly nightfall.
Surely, you realise
I can't allow you to go
roaming the grounds
by yourself.
Well then, by all means,
come along, sir.
Harry, I must insist you
accompany me
back to the castle
immediately!
That would
be counterproductive, sir.
And what makes
you say that?
No idea.
Horace.
Merlin's beard!
Is that an actual Acromantula?
A dead one,
I think, sir.
Good God.
Dear fellow, however
did you manage to kill it?
"Kill it"?
My oldest friend,
he was.
I'm so sorry,
I didn't--
Ah, don't worry yourself.
You're not alone.
Seriously misunderstood creatures,
spiders are.
The eyes I reckon,
they unnerve some folk.
Not to mention
the pincers.
Yeah,
I reckon that too.
Hagrid...
The last thing
I wish to be is indelicate
but Acromantula venom
is uncommonly rare.
Would you allow me
to extract a vial or two,
purely for academic purposes,
you understand?
Well I don't suppose it's gonna do him
much good now is it.
My thoughts exactly.
I have a ampoule or two about my person
for just such occassions as this.
Old... Potion master's habit,
you know?
I wish you could have
seen him with his prime.
Magnificent, he was.
Just magnificent.
Would you like me
to say a few words?
Yes.
Had a family, I trust?
Oh, yeah.
- Farewell...
- Aragog.
Farewell, Aragog.
King of the arachnids.
Your body will decay...
but your spirit lingers on
and your human friends
find solace,
the loss
they have sustained.
# Laid to rest, #
# And his wand,
snapped in two, #
# Which was sad, #
I had him from an egg,
you know?
Tiny little thing he was
when he hatched.
No bigger
than a Pekingese.
A Pekingese, mind you.
How sweet!
I once had a fish.
Francis.
He was very dear to me.
One afternoon,
I came downstairs and...
it vanished.
Poof.
That's very odd,
isn't it?
Yes, doesn't it?
But that's life!
I suppose,
you--you go along with
and suddenly...
poof.
Poof.
It was a student
who gave me Francis.
One spring afternoon,
I discovered the bowl on my desk...
With just a few inches
of clear water in it...
And floating on the surface
was a flower petal.
As I watched, it sank.
But just before
it reached the bottom,
it transformed
into a wee fish.
It was beautiful magic.
Wondrous to behold.
The flower petal
had come from a lily.
Your mother.
The day I came downstairs,
day's the bowl was empty.
That's the day
your mother...
I know
why you're here.
But I can't help you.
It would ruin me.
Do you know
why I survived, Professor?
The night I got this?
Because of her,
because she sacrificed herself...
Because she refused
to step aside.
Because her love was more powerful
than Voldemort.
- Don't say his name.
- I'm not afraid of the name, Professor.
I'm going
to tell you something.
Something others
have only guessed at.
It's true.
I am the Chosen One.
Only I can destroy him,
but in order to do so,
I need to know
what Tom Riddle asked you
all those years ago
in your office
and I need to know
what you told him.
Be brave, Professor.
Be brave
like my mother.
Otherwise,
you disgrace her.
she died for nothing.
Otherwise,
the bowl will remain empty.
Forever.
Please, don't think badly of me
when you say it.
I had no idea
what he was like, even then.
I was in the library
the other day.
In the restricted section...
and I read something
rather odd about this rare magic.
It's called, as I understand it,
a Horcrux.
- I beg your pardon?
- Horcrux.
I came across the term
while reading...
and I didn't fully
understand it.
I'm not sure
what you were reading, Tom,
but this is very dark stuff.
Very dark, indeed.
Which is...
why I came to you.
A horcrux is an object
in which a person has concealed
part of their soul.
But I don't understand
how that works, sir.
One splits one's soul
and hides part of it in an object.
By doing so,
you are protected,
should you be attacked
and your body destroyed.
Protected?
That part of your soul
which is hidden lives on.
In other words,
you cannot die.
And how does
one splits his soul, sir?
I think you already know
the answer to that, Tom.
Murder.
Yes, killing rips the soul apart
and it is a violation against nature.
Can you only
split the soul once?
For instance,
isn't seven--
Seven?
Merlin's beard, Tom!
Isn't it bad enough
to consider killing one person?
To rip the soul
in seven pieces!
This is all hypothetical,
isn't it, Tom?
All academic?
Of course, sir.
It'll be our little secret.
Sir.
This is beyond anything
I imagined.
Do you mean, sir,
he succeeded, sir?
- In making a Horcrux?
- Oh yes, he succeeded, alright.
- And not just once.
- What are they exactly?
It could be anything.
Most common place
of objects.
A ring, for example,
or a book.
Tom Riddle's diary.
It's a horcrux, yes.
Four years ago when you saved
Ginny Weasley's life
in the Chamber of Secrets,
you brought me this.
I knew then,
this was a different kind of magic.
Very dark,
very powerful.
But until tonight,
I had no idea just how powerful...
- And the ring?
- Belonged to Voldemort's mother.
Difficult to find.
Even more difficult to destroy.
But if you could find them all,
if you did destroy each Horcrux--
One destroys Voldemort.
How would you
find them?
They could be hidden anywhere,
couldn't they?
True, but magic,
especially dark magic...
leaves traces.
It's where you've been going,
isn't it, sir?
When you leave the school.
Yes, and I think perhaps,
I may have found another.
But this time,
I cannot hope to destroy it alone.
Once again, I must ask
too much of you, Harry.
Have you ever considered
that you ask too much,
that you take too much
for granted?
Has it ever crossed
your brilliant mind
that I don't want
to do this anymore?
Whether it has or hasn't
is irrelevant.
I will not negotiate
with you, Severus.
You agreed.
Nothing more to discuss.
Oh, Harry...
You need a shave,
my friend.
You know, at times,
I forget how much you've grown.
At times, I still see
the small boy from the cupboard.
Forgive my mawkishness, Harry.
I'm an old man.
You still look
the same to me, sir.
Just like your mother,
you are unfailingly kind.
A trait people never fail
to undervalue, I'm afraid.
The place to which we journey tonight
is extremely dangerous.
I promise you for the company of me
and I stand by that promise.
But there's one condition.
You must obey every command
I give you without question.
Yes, sir.
You do understand
what I'm saying.
Should I tell you to hide,
you hide.
Should I tell you to run,
you run.
Should I tell you to abandon me
and save yourself,
you must do so.
Your word, Harry.
My word.
Take my arm.
Sir, I thought you couldn't
Apparate within Hogwarts.
Well, being me
has its privileges.
This is the place.
Oh, yes.
This place has known magic.
Sir.
In order to gain passage,
payment must be made.
Payment intended
to weaken any intruder.
You should have
let me, sir.
No, no, Harry. Your blood's
much more precious than mine.
Voldemort would not have made it easy
to discover his hiding place.
He would put
certain defenses in position.
Careful.
There it is.
The only question is
how do we get there?
If you would, Harry.
Do you think
the Horcrux is in there, sir?
Oh, yes.
It has to be drunk.
All of it
has to be drunk.
You remember the conditions
on which I brought you with me?
This potion
might paralyze me.
I may risk
to get what I'm here.
I'd cause me so much pain
that I'd beg for relief.
You are not to indulge
these requests.
It's your job, Harry, to make sure
I keep drinking this potion.
Even if you have
to force it down my throat.
Understood?
Why can't I drink it, sir?
Because I'm much older,
much cleverer and much less valuable.
Your good health, Harry.
Professor.
Professor!
Can you hear me?
You have to keep drinking
like you said, remember?
- Stop.
- I will stop. I will stop.
But only--
only if you keep drinking.
- Don't make me-- Kill me.
- I'm sorry, sir.
Kill me!
All my fault.
My fault.
Just one more, sir.
One more, I promise.
- I promise I'll do what you say.
- No, no.
I promise!
Please!
Harry.
Water.
- Water.
Look, you did it, sir.
Look.
Harry...
water.
Aguamenti!
Water.
Lumos.
Lumos maxima!
Stupefy! Stupefy!
Sectumsempra!
- Harry...
- Incarcerous!
- Stupefy!
- Harry...
Harry...
Partis Temporus!
Go to your houses!
No toddling!
We need to get you
to the hospital wing, sir.
To Madam Pomfrey.
No...
Severus, Severus is awakening.
Wake him.
Tell him what happened.
Speak
to no one else.
Severus, Harry.
Hide yourself below,
Harry.
Don't speak or be seen by anybody
without my permission.
Whatever happens,
it's imperative you stay below.
Harry, do as I say.
Trust me.
Good evening, Draco.
What brings you here
on this fine spring evening?
Who else is here?
I heard you talking.
I often talk aloud to myself.
I find it extraordinarily useful.
Have you always been
to yourself, Draco?
Draco,
you are no assassin.
How do you know
what I am?
I've done things
that would shock you.
Oh, like cursing Katie Bell
and hoping that in return
she would bear
a cursed necklace to me?
Like replacing a bottle of mead
with one lace with poison.
Forgive me, Draco,
I cannot help feel
these actions are so weak
that your...
heart can't
really have been in.
He trusts me.
I was chosen.
I shall make it
easy for you.
Expelliarmus!
Very good.
You're not alone.
There are others.
How?
The Vanishing Cabinet
in the Room of Requirement.
I've been mending it.
Let me guess, it has a sister.
A twin.
In Borgin and Burkes.
- They form a passage.
- Ingenious.
Draco, years ago, I knew a boy
who made all the wrong choices.
Please let me
help you.
I don't want your help.
Don't you understand?
I have to do this.
I have to kill you.
Or he's gonna kill me.
Oh,
look what we have here.
Well done, Draco.
Good evening, Bellatrix.
I think introductions aren't over,
don't you?
Love to, Albus,
but I'm afraid
we're on a bit of tight schedule.
Do it!
He doesn't have
the stomach.
Just like his father.
Let me finish him
in my own way.
No, the Dark Lord was clear
the boy has to do it.
This is your moment, Draco.
Do it!
Go on, Draco,
now!
No.
Severus.
Please...
Avada Kedavra.
Hagrid!
Snape,
he trusted you!
Go on!
Incarcerous!
Fight back, you coward!
Fight back!
No, he belongs
to the Dark Lord.
Sectumsempra!
You dare use my own spells
against me, Potter?
Yes,
I'm the Half-Blood Prince.
Potter...
Enlighten
what has happened.
If you should have the need
to talk to someone...
You should know...
Professor Dumbledore...
You meant
a great deal to him.
Do you think
he would have done it?
Draco.
No.
No, he was lowering
his wand.
In the end,
it was Snape.
It was always Snape.
I did nothing.
It was fake.
Open it.
To the Dark Lord:
I know I will be dead
long before you read this
but I want you
to know
that it was I
who discovered your secret.
I have stolen
the real Horcrux
and intend to destroy it
as soon as I can.
I face death in the hope
that when you meet your match,
you will be mortal
once more.
R.A.B.
- R.A.B.?
- Don't know.
But whoever they are,
they have the real Horcrux.
It means
it was all a waste.
All of it.
Ron's okay with you,
you know.
You and Ginny.
If I were you when he's around,
I'd keep snogging to a minimum.
I'm not coming back,
Hermione.
I got to finish
whatever Dumbledore started.
And I don't know
where that'll leave me,
but I'll let you and Ron
know where I am...
when I can.
I've always admired
your courage, Harry.
But sometimes,
you can be really thick.
You don't really think
you're going to be able
to find all those Horcruxes
by yourself, do you?
You need us, Harry.
I never realised
how beautiful this place was.
Transcript: VeRdiKT
[SubScene.com]
Special thanks to BackFire
And also to HoneyBunny and Lavalamp
[Addic7ed.com]