Yeah, you can leave her
in the hallway for now.
Stabilizing here.
Where's the portable x-ray?
Check, charge or cash?
Cash. And, uh...
...make it out
to Jack's Demolition, Tucson.
Seven eighty-eight thirty.
Okay.
Hey.
Taking me to breakfast?
I can't, I'm meeting Bosko.
Hey, Vincent.
- Mom, where are my barrettes?
Hi, sweetie.
- I saw them on the kitchen table.
- They're not there. I already checked.
- Want me to make coffee?
- No school today?
My dad's taking me to the new building
and then to lunch.
Try under the cushions on the sofa.
He's already a half an hour late.
He gonna show? Or that son of a bitch
gonna stand her up like last time?
- I'll make coffee.
- I'm out of time, babe.
Mom, where are my barrettes?
They're not in the couch.
Wear the blue ones.
I don't wanna wear the blue ones.
They don't match.
Did you check in your bathroom?
- I checked everywhere.
- Well, what do you want me to do?
- Find them.
- Mom, pay attention.
- All right, sweetie, all right. What?
- Daddy's gonna be here.
- Okay, he's gonna...
I'm not gonna be ready. I can't be late.
- You won't be late.
- No, I will be late.
Okay. Before Daddy comes,
we can find them if we look together.
- It's all right, baby. It's all right.
- [SOBBING] No.
It's all right. It's all right.
We'll find them together, you and me.
We'll find them together.
Just relax. He won't come
before we find them. I promise you.
Hey. Give me another refill.
Now he wants a refill.
- What's your name?
WAINGRO: Waingro.
You're Michael, huh?
You guys always work together?
All the time.
- Real tight crew, huh?
- Real tight.
Yeah, if this works good,
I'd consider going again, you know.
Yeah. Stop talking, okay, Slick?
- How's he doing?
- A hundred percent.
Right on schedule.
Made a right on Venice Boulevard.
- We're a mile and a half from you.
- Okay.
Just crossed over the number-one lane,
300 yards from you now.
- Get set.
- I am.
Put that on.
Here we go.
Two eleven! Two eleven!
We're being held up!
Two-eleven alarm. Armored car.
There's the call. Three minutes.
Clear!
Eighty seconds left!
Get back. Get back.
Get back!
Hey, Slick, you see that shit
coming out of their ears?
They can't fucking hear you. Cool it.
I got it.
Got it.
You had to fuck with me.
You wanna fuck with me?
Come on! What the fuck are you doing?
- What did you do?
WAINGRO: I had to, man.
- Guy was making a move.
Let's go.
Dumb motherfucker.
- Step back, please, sir.
- I heard them.
A million six.
Forty cents on the dollar,
640,000 to you.
Here's a 150 front money.
Get you the rest in two, three days.
Know who owned these?
"Malibu Equity and Investments."
Roger Van Zant.
Owns banks in the Caymans.
Runs investment portfolios
for offshore drug money. Stuff like that.
- So?
- So you ripped off his bearer bonds.
He's got insurance.
That's the point.
He collects 100 percent from the insurance.
He's a player. Maybe he buys his bonds
back from us for 60 percent of their value.
And make 40 percent
on top of the 100 percent.
Sell it back to him instead of going to
the street. That's an extra 320,000 to you.
Try it on him.
- Kelso called.
- About what?
A score he's putting out
and wants you to look at.
What do I need his score for?
I got my own.
Says it's clean and low eight figures.
- Nine a.m. Tomorrow.
- What happened out there?
Don't ask.
Find the ambulance?
- Dumped it four blocks from here.
- 22nd Street between Figueroa and Flower.
They torched it. Burned everything.
The guns, clothes, everything.
REPORTER:
Investigators are still working the scene...
They were airborne.
Taped the last few seconds...
...of the black-and-whites
doing demolition derby.
Stolen out of Fresno two weeks ago.
Yellow pickup truck out of Whittier
day before yesterday.
You taking this one, lieutenant,
or does it stay in Division?
This look like gangbangers
working the local 7-Eleven to you?
- Robbery-Homicide's taking it. Yeah.
All yours.
We got three motorists. All they saw
were men with masks. They were distant.
Console TV man over there however,
he was closer.
He ID anybody?
Well, he was hiding. He heard it mostly.
Okay. What about them?
HEINZ: Right. Now, according to TV man,
this guy started mouthing off.
Smart.
- Yeah, somebody called a guard "Slick."
- Slick?
- Yeah.
Now, this guy... I figure this guy went
for that holdout piece, ankle holster, right?
From here.
Bang. Bang. Bang, bang, bang.
To his side.
This guy here has got what appears to be
a double-tap entry wound to the sternum.
Tattooing around the head wound,
scorched bone, close range.
Probably executed.
And it was a million six in bearer bonds,
and they ignored the loose cash.
Because they had no time,
because they were on a clock.
Which means they knew
our response time to a 211...
...had our air, immobilized it, entered...
...escaped in under three minutes.
It's a good spot here.
We got good escape routes.
- Two freeways within a quarter of a mile.
- Traffic video camera?
Probably disabled. Check it anyway.
You recognize the M.O.?
M.O. Is that they're good.
Once it escalated into a murder-one beef
for all of them...
...after they killed the first two guards,
they didn't hesitate...
...popped guard number three
because what difference does it make?
Why leave a living witness?
Drop of a hat,
these guys will rock 'r roll.
The shape charge.
The shape charge indicates
that they are technically proficient.
Proficient enough to go in on the prowl.
So let's start looking for recent
high-line burglaries that have mystified us.
Run "Slick" as an alias to the FBI.
You're gonna get the phone book.
Do it anyway.
Who's moving the bearer bonds?
Check the usual fences.
You and I will check Cusamano and Torena.
I want you to take Goldstein and Alfaro.
Hang in with Forensics.
From the bomb squad,
I want the explosive.
If we're lucky, it's exotic.
We can trace the sale.
Get your hand out of that mars pocket,
Rachel.
Oh, Vince.
Want some pie?
Gotta go to the john.
Look, I had to get it on, man.
He was making a move. I had to get it on.
Split's in the car.
I took out of ours evenly...
...to make up for his full end.
Because I wanna pay off and get rid
of this motherfucker right now.
Okay.
Hold it!
Hey.
Where's the rest?
- We're late.
Ooh, you look too good to go out.
I could just jump you right here.
Where is it?
- Uh, squared the bookies, baby.
There's more in a couple days,
so don't sweat it. We really are late.
Yeah, come on, you gotta be kidding me.
Honey, it ain't won'th the risks you take
for 8000.
Like in risk versus reward, baby.
Let's go. Get your coat.
There is no point talking to you.
All you are is a child growing older.
What's that supposed to mean?
It means we're not making forward progress
like real grown-up adults, living our lives.
I'm married to a gambling junkie
who won't listen.
Charlene, get in the fucking car.
What am I doing
in this rat-bastard situation?
You're not! What do you want from me?
Leave the bankbook and car keys...
...in the kitchen on your way out.
Are we going, or am I going alone?
You could keep that other crap
but Dominick would go with me.
Don't you even think about...
Yeah. Tell me Albert Torena called back.
- Albert Torena call Vincent?
- No.
No. Report came in.
The explosive was Dynex,
linear-shaped charge used in demolition.
You can pick it up with a driver's license
in Nevada, Arizona, New Mexico.
- Too common to trace a sale, Vincent.
- Oh, that's wonderful.
Are you all right?
What happened? Where you been?
Work.
Laurers dad show up?
Didrt call, didn't show.
We waited for you till 10:30.
Now, does this guy have any idea
what's going on with his kid?
I don't know.
Fucking jerk.
Well, is she okay?
She's been in her room all day.
So no, she's not okay. Neither am I.
Uh, I made dinner for us,
four hours ago. Um...
Every time I try to maintain a
consistent mood between us, you withdraw.
I got three dead bodies on a sidewalk
off Venice Boulevard, Justine.
I'm sorry...
...if the goddamn chicken...
...got overcooked.
- Seven men in Denmark,
to a key defendant here.
Did you find it?
Not yet.
There it is.
It's over here, somewhere.
Interior design?
It's on the back wall.
Coffee, sir?
- Please.
Will you pass the cream?
- Thanks.
- What did you get?
What?
What are you reading?
Book about metals.
"Stress Fractures in Titanium."
What kind of work you do?
Lady, why are you so interested
in what I read or what I do?
I've seen you in the store
from time to time.
What store?
Hennessey + Ingalls. I work there.
Uh...
If you don't wanna talk to me, it's okay.
I'm sorry I bothered you.
I didn't mean to be rude.
I didn't recognize you.
I work in metals. I'm a salesman.
My name's Neil.
I'm Eady.
You like working there?
Sure.
I get a discount and there's
a whole section of books in my area.
What area's that?
Graphic design.
I do, um, letterheads
and logotypes at night...
...and the store's a day job
till I get enough going.
Who do you do that for?
Uh, a restaurant.
I did their menus, and, um...
...a small, uh, record label.
CDs. I've done two so far.
You go to school for that?
Heh, yeah.
- Yeah, I went to Parsons.
- Where's that?
New York City.
How long you been out here?
About a year.
- You like it?
- Ha, ha.
Not really. I'm mostly here for the work.
- Live in this neighborhood?
- Ah, no...
...I live, um, kind of above Sunset Plaza.
It's actually kind of...
It's a little house that I rent.
And it's just kind of run-down,
but a beautiful, beautiful view.
What about you?
- I live up here.
- That's very funny.
So where's your family from originally?
Um...
I'm Scotch-lrish.
They, um, emigrated to Appalachia
in the late 1700s.
Where are you from?
The Bay Area.
Are your folks there?
Uh, my mother died a long time ago,
and my father, I don't know where he is.
Got a brother somewhere.
You have a tight family. I can tell.
- Yep.
- Right?
You're right.
Yeah...
City of lights.
In Fiji, they have these iridescent algae.
They come out once a year in the water.
That's what it looks like out there.
You been there?
No, I'm going there someday.
Oh, yeah?
You travel a lot?
- Yeah.
- Traveling makes you lonely?
L... I'm alone. I am not lonely.
You?
I get lonely.
Albert!
- Shit.
Albert.
Vincent, what you doing coming here, man?
You crazy? This ain't Disneyland.
You were supposed to get back to me
last night, Albert. Where the fuck you been?
- I couldn't break free, Vincent. You know.
- Let's violate his ass right now.
I do for you, you don't do for me,
is that it?
Vincent, man, I swear,
I was out all night, man.
I'm hitting like one of them
flamingo-matador guys.
Flamingo?
That's got nothing to do with me.
I was cutting it real smooth.
I'm generating leads and shit for you.
- I'm a dancer, man. You know.
Bullshit.
I paged your ass all day.
I can't stand paging.
You're a speed freak,
jacking methamphetamine again.
Where is your empathy, brother?
It's a substance-abuse problem.
Empathy was yesterday.
Today you're wasting
my motherfucking time.
- Vincent, man, look...
- Did you fall in love?
Come on. Did you fall in love last night
and you went off somewhere?
- Vincent...
- Just tell me that. I'll settle for it.
- I'll buy that.
- Vincent.
Give me all you got!
- Vincent...
- Give me all you got!
I swear, man, my brother, man...
My brother Richard's gonna talk to you.
I heard "Richard"?
- He's gonna talk to you.
- Richard?
Richard.
- Richard.
- He's gonna meet you, I swear, tonight.
- He's not here, is he?
- No, he's gonna meet you tonight.
- Tonight? What happened to now?
L... l... I implored him
because I knew you was coming this a.m.
This is a bunch of bullshit.
- No, no, I swear.
- He said no because he in Phoenix.
- Ahh.
But this, man, I swear... I swear, man...
Tonight's the best I can do for you, man.
You know?
He'll meet you at BJ's on Alvarado...
...at 2 a.m. Be there.
You be there too.
Vincent, I can't be there, man.
I got things to do, Vincent.
- I got things to do, places to be. I got...
- Hey, hey, hey.
Be there.
Don't waste my motherfucking time!
What is it?
It's a bank.
It depos cash on Thursday
for distribution to all the other branches...
...to cover Friday payroll checks.
So on Thursdays,
the command branch has got a full whack.
- On the prowl or strong?
- Strong. Through the front door.
- How many guys?
- Eh...
Four, or three plus a driver.
Walk in, knock them over, walk out.
And you want a 100,000 advance...
...against a 10-percent cut for that?
- Uh-huh.
Sounds like an address to a cowboy score.
They hit the holdup alarms...
...I gotta get out before the cops show.
What is that?
They hit three holdup alarm systems.
Two telco and a cellular.
See, but the signals
aren't going anywhere because...
See, the night before, you cut in
and trick out the alarm-system computer...
...to turn itself and the video recorders off
20 minutes before you walk in the door.
Architectural,
electrical-engineering plans?
I got all that. Schematics, got the boards
already built. They go straight into the CPU.
What's the estimate?
Twelve-point-one-, 12.2 million.
You're on.
Congratulations.
And to give you a little idea of where my
estimates come from, this is a printout...
Nobody knew the merch was yours.
Be that as it may, my way you get
100 percent from the insurance company...
...and take the bonds from us
at 60 cents on the dollar...
...and make yourself another 40 percent.
Your operation doesn't skip a beat.
Everybody makes out.
Sure, you got a deal.
Good, because there's no percentage
if everyone gets their underwear in a twist.
Yeah, so you have your man call me
and we'll set the meet.
Yeah, okay.
Nice talking to you.
You gonna deal with these guys?
So word's out on the street
it's okay to steal my stuff.
I'm gonna kill the sons of bitches.
Have Harry bring me the spreadsheets
for Canary Islands' offshore.
That's not really an estimate.
Those are exact figures.
I have a printout of the, uh, cash flow
of the bank for the past two months.
- How'd you get this information?
- Just comes to you.
This stuffjust flies through the air.
They send information out
and it's beamed out all over the place.
All you have to do is know how to grab it.
See, I know how to grab it.
Um... Okay, here we go.
Thirteen-point-nine million.
- I bought it.
- Good.
What did I tell you?
Here.
We're on.
Call Van Zant, collect the money.
- How is he?
- He's a businessman.
Okay.
Avocado.
- "Avocado."
- Hello?
NEIL [OVER PHONE]: Yeah, hello.
Chris is at my place.
- What's wrong?
- Husband-and-wife stuff.
I'll let him sleep it off here.
What happened to you?
- When you gonna get some furniture?
- When I get around to it.
Charlene's gonna leave me.
Why?
Not enough steaks in the freezer.
With everything we've been doing?
Vegas and the Super Bowl
cleaned me out.
- When you gonna get an old lady?
- When I get around to it.
You got something else on the side?
Nothing regular.
She got something else on the side?
- No.
- You sure?
Yeah, I'm sure.
I don't know what you're doing.
Remember Jimmy MacAwain on the yard
used to say:
"You wanna be making moves
on the street?
Have no attachments.
Allow nothing to be in your life...
...that you cannot walk out on
in 30 seconds flat...
...if you spot the heat around the corner."
Remember that?
For me,
the sun rises and sets with her, man.
Yeah?
Yeah.
Okay.
Today we take delivery of cash
from Van Zant...
...then I drop our deposit on Kelso
for this bank.
Bank? What bank?
What about the platinum thing?
It's ready to fall.
That goes too, then the bank.
- You want some breakfast?
- Yeah.
Are you okay?
Yeah, sugar.
Yeah.
- For real.
- Okay.
Gonna do good. I'll see you later.
You Solenko? I'm Don Breedan.
Grierson, my parole officer, told me to come
by here and see if you had a job for me.
- You're familiar with this kind of operation?
- Yeah, man. I'm a great grill man.
Good. Good for you. Here,
you'll mop the toilets, hit the dishwasher...
...bus tables and empty the garbage too.
Give me a hard time,
I'll report you loaded, drunk or stealing.
And I will violate you back so fast
your head will spin.
Twenty-five percent of your take-home
kicks back to me.
Rules of the game.
Call Grierson, check it out.
Change in the back.
Well, what are you waiting for?
Malibu Equity and Investments.
- Yeah, Roger Van Zant.
- Please hold.
Yeah, this is Roger Van Zant.
I'm supposed to collect something.
Give me your number, and somebody
will call you right back from a different line.
818-133-6089.
Yep.
I got a package for you.
There's a drive-in on Centinela.
Two-thirty tomorrow.
Okay, just send one man, alone.
- Who was that guy?
- Nobody.
Who the...? Who...? Who was that guy?
- He's nobody.
- I gotta know who he is. Who is he?
- He's nobody, Neil.
- Listen, you...
He's a legit liquor wholesaler
from Las Vegas.
- Alan Marciano.
- Chris is gonna straighten it up with you.
- It's too late. I'm sick of it. I'm sick of it!
- Shut up!
Here's the deal.
You'll give Chris one last shot.
After that, he fucks up,
then I will finance setting you up myself...
...on my own, anywhere you want.
Dominick will go with you.
And my word counts.
But right now,
you will give him the chance.
Clean up. Go home.
Give me all your money.
One day you gonna get smoked
with that shit.
Ain't gonna be you, fool.
- He's coming in alone. Send him through.
- Yeah, got it.
Vincent, hey, man.
Vincent. This is my brother, Richard.
Richard, Vincent.
- Richard.
- Yo, it's all right.
What have you got for me?
Before we even get into that...
...there's this crew ripping rides
all along the beach areas, all right?
Now, the back of a trim shop on Irvine...
...if somebody was to pay a little visit
this weekend...
...they might find two Turbos
and a 911 Slope.
You're looking to rid yourself
of your competition.
- Hmm?
- Eh, I'm a good citizen.
I'm Donald Duck.
So you got something to tell me or what?
Check this out, coz.
How do I know
if I tell you what you need to know...
...you're gonna do
what the fuck I need to get done?
Richard, man, Hanna is straight up, man.
We do business all the time.
I ain't your coz, you rat motherfucker.
And you know because I say so
after I hear what the fuck you gotta tell me.
Look here, man.
You understand what I'm saying?
I can get killed for telling you this shit.
Or you're gonna get killed
walking your doggie.
All right.
There's this cat I was locked up with
in Folsom.
Did a couple, two, three years.
He got out and I ran into him.
And so?
He's a big fiend for action.
Now, if he'd have said nothing,
I'd have thought nothing...
...but he goes on and on, running down
to me how he ain't been doing nothing...
...and nothing's been going on,
and all this bullshit.
So right then and there I know
this cat's got something going down.
Pretty fucking great.
Albert, what's wrong with you?
You drag me here,
waste my time like this.
You saw a guy on the street
who's an ex-con?
- That's right.
- Well, I am over-fucking-whelmed.
What do you want for that,
a Junior G-man badge?
You gonna make the call
on them Porsches or what?
Is he kidding me?
- Vincent...
- I'm telling you, this Slick is no joke.
You know what I'm saying?
- Say what? Say what?
- What?
- You said, "Slick." What does that mean?
- Slick. That's what he calls people, "Slick."
And tell me about him.
About 6 feet tall, lot ofjailhouse tats.
Got a big-ass peacock right here.
What's his name?
Cheritto.
Michael Cheritto.
Thirty-three busts since 1976.
Eleven for armed robbery,
three convictions.
Two out of a three-to-five-year beef
in Attica. Three years in Marion.
Five years in Folsom off a knock-back
to involuntary manslaughter.
- Jacket's 2 inches thick.
- Okay.
- Who do I have there now?
- Drucker and me, boss. And Schwartz.
Tell SIS I want full surveillance.
That's 24 hours.
Round the clock, day and night.
We never close. Open seven days a week.
Bug the car, the house, the work.
When he moves or sits,
like in a restaurant...
...I want pictures
of who he moves and sits with.
Then run makes on them. They got jackets,
I wanna see who they move and sit with.
I want it up and running
by tomorrow night.
- Put your hands where I can see them.
- What?
- All right.
I tell you what to do,
I tell you how to do it.
Now, with your right hand only,
your right hand only...
...take the package and throw it in here.
Fuck. Behind you. On the right.
Yeah, Roger Van Zant?
- Yeah, who's this?
- You know who this is.
Yes, I do. Yes, I do.
I sent a guy to deliver the package.
He didn't call. Is everything right?
Tell you what, forget the money.
- What?
- Forget the money.
Wh...
It's a lot of money. What are you doing?
What do you mean, "Forget the money"?
What am I doing?
I'm talking to an empty telephone...
I don't understand.
- Because there is a dead man
on the other end of this fucking line.
Oh, my.
Do you like it?
- Look at my ring.
- Wow.
- Ha-ha-ha.
Did you know about this?
It's so beautiful.
You are insane.
Do you like it?
- It's beautiful.
- Yeah, it's pretty good.
- Just don't ask him where he got it.
Yeah, that's right. Ha-ha-ha.
What do you wanna be
when you grow up, honey?
I don't know.
She doesn't know.
Just like me. I don't know either.
Hello?
Hi, it's me.
Hey. I was wondering if you'd call.
I've been busy. Can I see you?
I was afraid that was just the one night,
you know?
No, not for me, it wasrt.
Yeah, me neither.
Can I fall by?
- Yeah.
- Okay, I'll see you in a little bit.
Thank you.
- Good night.
- Ha-ha-ha.
Goddamn convention.
- Which one's Slick?
- The wide one.
Got two transmitters.
One's in the wheel well,
backup's in the firewall.
Okay, get ready.
- Did you say good night to Neil?
- Good night.
One with the blond hair is Chris Shiherlis.
SIS has got a revolving tail...
...and hung a wire on the house phone.
Cheritto's cruised the precious-metals
depository three times.
Platinum, silver, and some bullion.
Sammy and I think that's gonna
be their next score.
Who's the loner?
First time we're seeing him.
We're not on him yet.
Well, get on it.
Okay.
When these guys walk out the door
of whatever score they're gonna take next...
...they're gonna have the surprise
of a lifetime.
Hey, baby. Time to go.
WAINGRO:
I showed you a good time, didn't I?
Oh, yeah.
You fly. You cool.
You're lying to me.
I can always tell when people lie to me.
Mm, I ain't lying. You a hot dog.
A regular rodeo rider.
And this was the monster fuck
of my young life.
Now I got to get my ass
street side, sugar.
You don't have a truth-telling style.
- What are you talking about?
- You don't know what this is.
The Grim Reaper's visiting with you.
Where you been?
SHU at Pelican Bay.
New Folsom, B-wing.
I am a cowboy
looking for anything heavy.
Billy Ricketts said come see you.
That is why I am here.
Why don't you...?
Why don't you call this guy?
This guy's always putting guys on.
Thank you, brother.
I'll buy you a drink?
Buy me a drink.
- What's so funny?
- Nothing.
- It's really dumb.
- Something smells negligent.
You two are perfect for each other.
How did you meet?
- I knew this guy in, uh, grade school.
- Uh-oh.
He was named Raoul, uh... Whatever.
Anyway, the guy could take his fingers
and fold them over, one over the other.
Then he'd turn his eyelids inside out...
I can't keep my hands off you,
and that's the truth.
That's what's so wonderful about you,
in that bestial sort of way.
Woman.
This better be earth-shattering.
That's what she tells us. To Raoul.
- Raoul.
- To Raoul.
Yeah, Vincent Hanna.
Here's how we found her.
- How old?
- Sixteen, seventeen.
Been here about six hours.
How'd she die, Rachel?
Beat her head in, same as the others.
Cerebral hematoma.
Who's that?
- Mother and siblings, I guess.
- What the hell they doing here?
Because it's fucked up. Somebody inside
knew the girl and called the family.
Okay, let's go.
That's nice.
When I run a DNA check on the semen, my
intuition says it's coming up the same guy.
So it's a series,
and ending up in your court.
- Sheriff"s Homicide getting anywhere?
- Not yet.
- Get her.
- Get off me. Get off me.
Oh, whoa, whoa, whoa!
- Oh, my God.
- Hold it, hold it.
- Where is she?
- Easy, easy, easy.
Please. Please, come on.
- It's okay. It's okay.
- Who did this?
Where's my baby? Where is she?
I need to know what happened.
I guess the Earth shattered.
So why didn't you let Bosko
take you home?
I didn't wanna ruin their night too.
What was it?
You don't wanna know.
I'd like to know
what's behind that grim look.
I don't do that. You know it.
Let's go. Come on.
You never told me I'd be excluded.
I told you when we hooked up, baby,
that you were gonna have to share me...
...with all the bad people
and all the ugly events on this planet.
And I bought into that sharing
because I love you.
I love you fat, bald, money, no money,
driving a bus. I don't care.
But you have got to be present
like a normal guy some of the time.
That's sharing.
This is not sharing, this is leftovers.
Oh, I see. What I should do
is, uh, come home and say:
"Hi, honey, guess what?
I walked into this house today...
...where this junkie asshole
just fried his baby in a microwave...
...because it was crying too loud,
so let me share that with you.
Come on, let's share that,
and in sharing it...
...we'll somehow, uh, cathartically dispel
all that heinous shit." Right?
Wrong. You know why?
Because you prefer the normal routine:
We fuck,
then you lose the power of speech.
Because I gotta hold on to my angst.
I preserve it, because I need it.
It keeps me sharp, on the edge.
Where I gotta be.
You don't live with me.
You live among the remains
of dead people.
You read the terrain.
You search for signs of passing...
...for the scent of your prey...
...and then you hunt them down.
That's the only thing
you're committed to.
The rest is the mess you leave
as you pass through.
What I don't understand is
why I can't cut loose of you.
Hey. Miss Lillian.
Let's go, baby.
I met the manager. Is that the boss?
I did time for what that motherfucker does
every day.
Baby, can you just handle it
till we find you something new?
Can you do that?
Ain't a hard time been invented
that I cannot handle.
What you hanging with me for, Lillian?
Because I'm proud of you.
- You're proud of me?
- Mm-hm.
What the hell you proud of me for?
Come on home.
What were you doing there?
- I was skiing.
I was trying to ski.
That's what people do there.
You go skiing and you, um...
...you meet people.
You try to have a good time.
- Did you have a good time?
- No.
Why not?
I'm not good at meeting people.
You met me.
Well, that happened
without my thinking about it.
Which is why, probably.
No, it's because you were fine.
Eady.
Take off with me for a while.
- Where?
- New Zealand.
When?
I have to go separate,
but you could meet me there.
But my job, my...
I got money. You don't need money.
You could set up a studio, do work there.
- I don't know.
- What's there to know?
Are you married?
- What?
- You come and go...
The last thing I am is married.
I'm a needle starting at zero
going the other way, a double blank.
Then, all of a sudden...
...someone like you comes along.
- You don't know me, Neil.
- I know enough.
Come with me.
What's wrong, baby?
Nothing's wrong. Everything's right.
Will you go?
Yeah.
Good.
- Hey, sweetie.
- Hi.
What happened?
You forget your mom was picking you up?
No.
So, what's going on?
I felt like being alone.
Okay. Come on, I'll drive you home.
- Hey, Mike.
MIKE: Hey, Lauren.
What's happening?
Lieutenant. Sir.
Captain Jackson wants to know
what's going on.
Nothing's going on. Stay off the air.
Technique.
Open sesame. Right there.
There he goes.
- We walk.
- I'm right there.
We walk! Now! Come on.
He's heard it.
Heads up.
- One's coming out.
- Hold it, captain.
- Vincent, he's not carrying anything.
- Yeah, I see.
- Here we go.
- Not till my boss says so.
Vincent, both of them
are not carrying anything.
- Okay, let them go.
JACKSON [OVER RADIO]: What?
What are you gonna take them on?
Breaking and entry?
They didn't steal anything.
Don't you get it?
It gets knocked back
to some misdemeanor...
...they do six months and they're out.
No fucking way.
I'm not taking the heat from my boss.
They're not walking.
That's exactly what they're gonna do.
They're gonna walk. This is my operation.
I have tactical command
that supersedes your rank.
They will walk away
and you will let them. Fuck.
Back to work.
L.A.P.D. Gee, what?
Where the fuck did this heat come from?
Maybe it's the score they were onto.
The place, not us. Because
it's been hit a couple of times, you know.
Assume they got our phones,
assume they got our houses...
...assume they got us right here,
right now as we sit.
Everything. Assume it all.
How we gonna buy the bank package
from Kelso?
- I'll front that. That's not a problem.
- What happens to Van Zant?
With the heat we got, do you wanna play
World War II in the streets with Van Zant?
No, I want my 750. And he gets a pass?
I got more motivation to whack Van Zant
than either of you. He is a fucking luxury.
Our problem is,
take the bank or split right now?
Do not go home, do not pack, nothing.
Thirty seconds flat from now,
we are gone on our separate ways.
That's it.
Chris.
The bank is won'th the risk.
I need it, brother.
We should stay and take it down.
That's where I come out.
I roll with you, Neil. Whatever. Whatever.
No, not on this one, Michael.
On this one, you're on your own.
You figure this is the best thing to do?
This is the best thing to do?
I got plans. I'm going away after. So for me
the reward is maybe won'th the stretch.
But Elaine takes good care of you.
You got plenty put away.
You got T-bonds, real estate.
If I were you, I would be smart.
I would cut loose of this.
Well, you know, for me,
the action is the juice.
I'm in.
- You too?
- Yeah, sure.
Ha-ha-ha.
- Let's go.
Fuck them, let's do it.
All right, let's go.
We got a lot of work to do.
You can't go in there.
Watch this.
Excuse me...
Tim, I gotta call you back.
You have to have an appointment.
Can I help you?
- Are you Alan Marciano?
Yeah, and who the fuck are you?
- Who am I?
- Ow! Hey. Hey.
- Lieutenant Vincent Hanna, L.A.P.D.
L.A.? This is Las Vegas.
You don't even have jurisdiction here.
Hey. Hey, I don't know who the fuck
you guys think you're pushing around...
...but I know people here, okay?
- Las Vegas P.D. Takes you into custody.
You are extradited to Newark
on a New Jersey warrant...
...for smuggling cigarettes
up from North Carolina three years ago...
...or you go to work for us.
Cut and dried.
- That is it.
- Oh, shit.
Charlene Shiherlis.
- Who?
Who? What are you, a fucking owl?
SCHWARTZ: The lady you been talking dirty
to on the telephone every day last week.
Yeah, you know what?
You can't tie me to her.
Who needs to? Your ass is on a plane
back to New Jersey, jack off.
Oh, man, I just...
Why did I get mixed up with that bitch?
Because she got a great ass!
And you got your head all the way up it.
Jesus.
When I think of asses, a womars ass...
...something comes out of me.
- So?
So no big thing.
All I want is her husband
and his whole fucking crew.
Now, you're gonna work
with Sergeant Drucker here.
- San Clemente Road and Hermosa.
- Uh-huh.
That's where we cut through the fence.
That's the access.
Right.
The security systems around here
are a joke.
St. Vincent Thomas Bridge,
that's Escape Route Number 1.
Number 2, over here,
Anaheim to the 110.
- Good.
- Okay?
- Yeah. That's fine.
- Got it? Good. Let's go.
They were looking back...
...in this direction.
A container facility?
- For a can'tage theft?
- Too visible. Too lowball for them.
Next door's an oil refinery,
over there's a scrap yard.
Refinery only pays by check.
No cash around.
Same for the scrap yard.
Maybe they're stealing hubcaps.
A refinery and a scrap yard.
- What the hell is going on?
- That's what we're trying to figure out.
We thought we had it.
Thought we had it.
I got an idea
of what they were looking at.
- You wanna know what they're looking at?
- What?
I mean, is this guy something,
or is he something?
This crew is good.
You know what they were looking at?
What?
Us.
The L.A.P.D.
The police department.
We just got made.
Yeah.
Okay.
Okay, motherfucker!
Kelso come through?
Yeah, you can build a bank with these.
Name is Hanna. First name Vincent.
I smeared this sergeant in Vice five yards.
Hanna's all over you.
He's on all the work cars.
Michael's house, Shiherlis'.
Not yours,
they've been losing you at night.
Hanna's a hot dog. Graduate school.
Marine Corps.
Lieutenant, Robbery-Homicide,
Major Crime Unit.
He's taken down some heavy crews.
Blew away Frankie Yonder in Chicago.
And he was a fucking maniac.
He was working Narcotics before that.
Had some problems, divorced twice.
Current wife's Justine.
He's why the extra heat.
The Vice sergeant...
...says Hanna likes you.
Thinks you're some kind of star.
You do this sharp, you do that sharp.
Look how sharp this guy is to figure that.
Funny as a heart attack, man.
Three marriages.
What the fuck do you think that means?
He likes staying home?
Means the man is one of those guys
out there...
...prowling around all night, dedicated.
With this guy and this much heat,
you should pass.
It's won'th the stretch.
This guy can hit and miss.
You can't miss once.
You sure?
I'm sure.
Let's go to the garage.
Justine.
Justine?
Where we going?
- Okay, where are you going?
- Out.
- What are you on?
MAN [OVER RADIO]: TAC 9.
[MAN SPEAKING INDISTINCTLY
OVER RADIO]
This is Vincent Hanna in Air 18.
Who have I got?
Hey, Vincent, it's JJ.
I'm in Air 40. Richard Glover's with me.
It's on the 105 eastbound
approaching the 110 interchange.
You running a revolving tail?
Yeah, I got two units in front, three behind.
Okay, have one of them pick me up
at the Vermont on-ramp.
Let's go.
Am I 100, uh, yards, or what?
Am I close or far, or what?
MAN [OVER RADIO]:
Three hundred yards, center lane.
How you doing?
What do you say
I buy you a cup of coffee?
- Yeah, sure. Let's go.
- Follow me.
Seven years in Folsom.
In the hole for three.
McNeil before that.
McNeil as tough as they say?
You looking to become a penologist?
You're looking to go back?
You know, I chase down some crews...
...guys just looking to fuck up,
get busted back. That you?
You must've worked some dipshit crews.
I worked all kinds.
You see me doing thrill-seeking
liquor-store holdups...
...with a "Born to Lose" tattoo
on my chest?
- No, I do not.
- Right.
I am never going back.
Then don't take down scores.
I do what I do best, I take scores.
You do what you do best,
trying to stop guys like me.
So you never wanted a regular-type life?
What the fuck is that?
Barbecues and ball games?
Yeah.
- This regular-type life like your life?
- My life? No, my life...
No, my life's a disaster zone.
I got a stepdaughter so fucked up...
...because her real father
is this large-type asshole.
I got a wife. We're passing each other
on the down slope of a marriage...
...my third...
...because I spend all my time
chasing guys like you around the block.
That's my life.
A guy told me one time:
"Don't let yourself get attached
to anything...
...you are not willing to walk out on
in 30 seconds flat...
...if you feel the heat around the corner."
Now, if you're on me,
and you gotta move when I move...
...how do you expect to keep a...
A marriage?
Well, that's an interesting point.
What are you, a monk?
I have a woman.
What do you tell her?
I tell her I'm a salesman.
So then, if you spot me coming
around that corner...
...you're just gonna walk out
on this woman?
Not say goodbye?
That's the discipline.
That's pretty vacant, no?
Yeah, it is what it is.
It's that, or we both better
go do something else, pal.
I don't know how to do anything else.
Neither do I.
- I don't much want to either.
- Neither do I.
You know, I have this,
uh, recurring dream.
I'm sitting at this big banquet table...
...and all the victims of all the murders
I ever worked are sitting at this table...
...and they're staring at me
with these black eyeballs...
...because they got eight-ball hemorrhages
from the head wounds.
And there they are,
these big balloon people...
...because I found them two weeks
after they'd been under the bed.
The neighbors reported the smell...
...and there they are,
all of them just sitting there.
What do they say?
Nothing.
- No talk?
- None.
Just...
They don't have anything to say.
See, we just look at each other.
They look at me.
And that's it, that's the dream.
I have one where I'm drowning.
And I gotta wake myself up
and start breathing, or I'll die in my sleep.
You know what that's about?
Yeah. Having enough time.
- Enough time to do what you wanna do?
- That's right.
- You doing it now?
- No, not yet.
You know, we're sitting here...
...you and I,
like a couple of regular fellows.
You do what you do,
and I do what I gotta do.
And now that we've been face to face...
...if I'm there and I gotta put you away,
I won't like it.
But I'll tell you...
...if it's between you
and some poor bastard...
...whose wife you're gonna
turn into a widow...
...brother, you are going down.
There's a flip side to that coin.
What if you do got me boxed in
and I gotta put you down?
Because no matter what,
you will not get in my way.
We've been face to face, yeah...
...but I will not hesitate.
Not for a second.
Maybe that's the way it'll be.
Or who knows?
Or maybe
we'll never see each other again.
They dumped us.
What?
- They dumped us.
- What do you mean, they dumped us?
Chris slipped his tail.
He doesn't talk about scores
with Charlene...
...so there's nothing for me to get
from Marciano. I tried.
- What about Cheritto?
Same.
Transponders got put on a bus
to San Clemente.
- They dumped all our surveillance?
- Yeah, at the same time. Nine p.m.
I had coffee with McCauley
half an hour ago!
We were on you.
Then McCauley drives into LAX...
...where surveillance can't fly over
because of flight paths.
His car's still there. He's gone.
Does anybody have any idea
where the fuck these people are?
You hear from him yet?
Not a thing. And not hearing
bothers me more. Where's this guy?
This guy here. We put him on.
Says he knows McCauley.
Who are you?
Waingro. My name's Waingro.
I've been living in this office day and night.
How well do you know him?
Oh, we took some major scores together.
How come I haven't heard from him?
Well, he's probably busy right now,
but he's real thorough.
- He ain't gonna forget about you.
- Oh, that's reassuring.
Well, I got some moves
I could make here.
Probably be a big help to you.
You recognize the grill man?
- No.
- Folsom. D-block. Housed with Dobie Rush.
- Ain't got my break yet, man.
- Cisco and Pancho didn't show.
Haul out the garbage. Mop up the back.
Take your break later.
Piece of shit. Pick up.
Where the hell is he?
- I wanted to check the slot for a work car.
- So did I.
Yeah?
Hang on.
- Yeah.
- Hey.
Use a landline. Call me at 103-7206.
All right.
- Where are you?
- There's cops all over me, man.
They're on me like a cheap suit.
I can't dump them.
- After the fact you spotted them?
- No, no. They're doing parallels.
I can try to dump them again.
How are we gonna know if you did?
If you didn't, you'll draw them to us.
Head for Ventura. Pull them out of here.
All right. Hey, I'm sorry, man.
Last thing I wanna do is let you down.
Come on, man.
Pick up.
- Hey, hey, Neil, man. What up?
- What's up, brother?
Man, what you doing here?
What I am doing is I'm looking for a driver
who can handle scanners and a radio.
Right now, today. You remember the drill?
- Yeah, man, sure.
- You cool?
Oh, man, now, you know I'm cool.
One answer, yes or no. Right now.
Yeah, man. Fuck, yeah. You're on.
Out back in five.
- What's burning? What's burning?
CHEF: Nothing I'm doing.
What is this?
Where do you think you're going?
Just came across a first edition
of Kandinsky's Theory of Color.
Yeah. No, it's in good condition.
MAN [ON TV]: And it wjll not stop
or answer radio communication.
The 180-foot vessel is called
Jin Yin Number 1...
...and is suspected of smuggling
Chinese illegal aliens.
It was spotted Saturday by patrol aircraft.
Stay down.
Don't move! Don't fucking move!
Put your hands in the air!
Put your hands in the air! Put them up!
Down, down! Get on your knees.
Give me the keys.
Get on your knees.
Get on your knees!
Hey. Hey! Get over there.
Get the fuck... Get down.
Turn around! Put your hands behind you.
Behind you!
Get down! Stay down!
Get down! Get down!
Down, you stupid son of a...
Down! Down, now!
Keys! Keys! Keys!
All of you stay down.
We want to hurt no one. We're here
for the bank's money, not your money.
Your money's insured.
You're not gonna lose a dime.
Think of your families. Don't risk your life.
Don't try and be a hero.
Right now I want you to sit on the floor
and put your hands on your head.
Anybody feels sick, anybody got heart
trouble, go ahead and lean against the wall.
- Give me the key.
- What key?
[MAN GRUNTS AND CROWD GASPS]
Get down and stay down!
Sit there. Sit there.
Don't move. Let it bleed.
Get down!
Hey. Hey!
Put your head down.
- Look at me again, I'll kill you.
Stay down. Down.
Put your head down!
Get down. Get down.
- Hey, Casals.
- Yeah.
You guys working a case
on a Neil McCauley?
This CI, Hugh Benny, called in about a bank
they're looking at or something.
Vincent.
Far East National Bank, 11:30!
I want a block at Figueroa and 5th...
...and I want a block
northbound Flower at 6th.
They're already coming out.
Okay, we're gonna have to take them
in the car. Wait till they are all in.
Get clean shots. Watch your background.
Police! Move!
What's going on?
Move. Move. Get down.
Look out.
Move it, come on.
L.A.P.D. Get down.
Move it. Down, down, down.
We did it, right, Neil? Huh?
- Move!
- Aah!
Get down.
Fuck. Fuck!
- Start the car!
Go! Go! Go!
Son of a bitch!
Go, go!
Go!
Come on. Come on. Ugh!
Get him out of here.
Get down! Now!
Shit.
Out of the way! Down! Out of the way!
Get them down! Now, now!
No, out of the way. Out of the way.
Mommy? Mommy!
Come here, honey.
Come on, honey.
I got you. It's okay now.
Tragedy in a Southland neighborhood today.
A bank robbery spilled out into the street.
Claudia Newman, live on the scene.
She has the latest. Claudia?
This afternoon, this neighborhood was
terrorized by a bank holdup gone wrong.
With the streets full of mid-day shoppers
and kids, police and armed robbers...
- Excuse me, bartender?
One minute, lady.
- Robbery, pursuit and, finally, death.
A Los Angeles neighborhood is shaken
by a bank robbery...
...that ended in homicide and terror.
One suspect, Michael Cheritto, is one
of four men involved in the foiled robbery.
- He died at the scene.
What can I get you, miss?
Also fatally wounded,
suspect Donald Breedan...
Miss?
- During the extensive gunfire
between police and suspects.
- Ugh. Un!
- All right, hold him. Hold him.
- All right. All right.
- It's all right.
So?
BOB: Well, he's got blood loss and shock.
I'm gonna give you quarter-grain morphine
for the pain. Subcutaneous injection.
Bottom line.
It's mostly tissue damage, which is good,
but his, uh, clavicle's fractured.
- Can he rest for a while?
- Six, seven hours.
- That's it?
- That's it.
- Take off your shirt.
- What?
Take off your shirt.
My... Look, my daughter gave it to me
for Father's Day.
I don't give a shit who gave it to you.
Take it off.
Chris. Hey.
- Chris, listen to me.
- Mm.
Nate's gonna pick you up.
He's gonna take you to his place.
- Where's Charlene?
- We gotta get out of here.
We're all over the 6:00 news.
- I'm not going without her.
Think about that.
I will meet you at Nate's.
Where are you going?
I gotta find out if our out got spilled
along with every other damn thing.
Who did it?
Who wasrt there?
Trejo.
I'll see you at Nate's.
Yeah.
Yeah. You still want me?
You come down here right now
and you get me. Dominick and me. Okay?
Okay, baby, okay.
I'll be there in two hours, all right?
- Okay?
- All right.
Goddamn you, Chris. Goddamn you.
- You're on a plane for Los Angeles.
- Great.
Why'd you do it? What happened?
- They made me.
- Who?
Where's Anna?
She's dead.
So is Michael and Breedan,
the guy who stood in for you.
- Who did it? Who did it?
- They had Anna, man.
Who had her?
Waingro.
On his own?
- For someone.
- Who?
The other he worked for.
Zant.
- Van Zant?
- Yeah.
Van Zant.
- Are you sure?
- Van Zant.
Did you say anything
about how we're getting out?
- I don't think so, Neil.
- Come on.
I don't remember, Neil.
- I'll call a medic.
- I'm not gonna make it.
I can't feel nothing.
My Anna's gone.
She's gone.
Don't leave me like this, Neil.
Please, holmes.
Don't leave me like this.
- Yeah?
NEIL [OVER PHONE]: Nate.
You on a cellular? Use a hard line.
It's a new one.
The guy lives on Hillside Terrace, Encino.
- 10725.
10725, okay.
- Chris?
- He's with me, at my place.
Next, Waingro, okay?
You got the time?
I'll make time,
and I need a new out laid on.
How do you know it's blown?
How can I trust it?
Okay, you got it.
Stay healthy.
Charlene Shiherlis.
Drucker's got a safe house in Venice
to stash her in.
Our Neil's transportation.
When we're done here, get on the phone.
Somewhere, someone's trying
to put it together for him.
You don't believe McCauley
already had a getaway?
Sure he did. Now he needs another one.
Would you trust yours after this afternoon?
This rat motherfucker,
where did we get him?
He's a CI for a burglary cop.
Called in the tip on the bank.
On Neil McCauley,
how much time we got?
Eight, 10 hours for him to set up a new out.
After that, he's gone.
Bye-bye. Bam.
You ratted McCauley to us.
How'd you know? Who told you?
Who told you, you rat motherfucker?
Who?
Connelly back in for Murphy.
Murphy with Leggat right there with him.
Murphy tees it up behind the net...
- Miller out front.
Now here's Murphy with the referee...
Waingro, where is he?
- Where is he?
- How the hell would I know?
Well, what do we have here, hmm?
Isn't this pretty? It's pretty. Aah!
- You slimy piece of shit.
- You told me you wanted out from under.
You're scared to death, right?
You want out? This is out, Charlene.
- Yeah, what's your end?
- L... You stupid broad.
- How'd I get into this?
- Hey, hey, hey. Easy.
- Huh?
- You heard me.
She had a rough ride.
Why don't you fix her a drink or something?
- Look in the cabinet above the sink.
- Fuck her.
- You'd better get in there and stay in there.
- All right, all right.
Well, lookie here.
My name is Sergeant Drucker,
L.A.P.D. Homicide.
- You wanna put Dominick in the bedroom?
- He stays with me.
There we go.
So, what now?
Well, he's right,
because you want out, this is out.
- You believe you have to betray Chris.
- No shit.
That's right. You would have to.
See, if you don't betray Chris,
you victimize Dominick.
Because he becomes an orphan
when you go to prison as an accessory...
...because you got no living parents
to take him.
So he ends up state-raised in foster homes,
juvenile facilities.
Then he steals a car.
Then he winds up in gladiator academies
like Chino and Tracy.
Fucked for life.
You know what happens,
because you've been there.
Dominick didn't get a chance yet
to choose his life, but Chris did.
If you give up Chris, you get off clean.
You can do it for your kid,
so you can raise him.
- What else are you selling?
- All kinds of shit.
But I don't have to sell this and you know it,
because this kind of shit here sells itself.
DRUCKER [OVER PHONE]:
Okay, Danny, here's an update.
- Drucker's on Line 2.
- Lieutenant, hold on for a second.
Lieutenant, I have Drucker
on the other line.
Oh, well, conference him in.
- Go ahead.
- Vincent, it's me.
I want an answer. What's it gonna be?
We're set here. She'll make the call.
Okay, that's good. Here's the deal here.
Hugh Benny has reformed his wayward life
and become a born-again good citizen.
Apparently, Neil got sold out to us
by this cowboy named Waingro.
Waingro used to be a part
of Neil's crew...
...then he went to work
for a money launderer named Van Zant.
Units are at Van Zant's house as we speak
because he got shot dead earlier tonight.
Now, if Neil goes after anybody else,
it's gonna be Waingro.
Waingro just got himself a suite
at the airport Marquis...
...under the name "Jameson."
He's there now.
I want you to get that
to bail bondsmen, bookies...
...assignment officers
and snitches in County.
Anyone you can think of
who'll put it on the street.
Deploy a team at the hotel and personally
check their coms every 30 minutes.
Because maybe Neil will go for him.
Okay? How you feeling?
- Banged up, but I'll live.
- Okay.
He's here.
Neil is still here.
I can feel it.
- But for how long?
- Uh...
Seven, eight hours, max.
What did you do?
- That was you?
- It's what I don't do, I don't sell metal.
Would have been okay, you fly out after.
Now it's jammed.
- Now we gotta go together.
- Those other people were with you?
My friend, Michael...
...he knew the risks.
He didn't have to be there.
It rains, you get wet.
Get packed and let's go.
Eady.
Why did you do this to me?
Who are you?
It's gonna be all right.
You understand? Lt'll be all right.
Right.
There's this Camaro at this address,
Level D, Slot 18.
Here's some cash.
Whers it over?
Twenty-two hours from now.
- Then we get out of here clean.
- When will you let me leave?
Go now. You want out? There's the door.
Will you let me leave later?
It will be different.
Do you understand?
It's ready.
Vincent.
This is my friend Ralph.
RALPH:
You didn't tell me you were...
- Oh, my God.
- Where's Lauren?
- She's at Lisa-Beth's.
- Look, this has nothing to do with me.
- I didn't know. I'm terribly sorry.
- What are you sorry about? Sit down.
Don't you even get angry?
- I'm angry, yeah.
- Oh.
I'm very angry, Ralph.
You know, you can ball my wife
if she wants you to.
You can lounge around here on her sofa.
In her ex-husband's...
...dead-tech, post-modernistic,
bullshit house, if you want to...
...but you do not get to watch
my fucking television set!
For God's sake.
Put the television set down.
- I never cheated on you, bitch.
- Maybe you should have.
- I should have?
- In a way, you're a party to this.
Oh, yeah. I made Ralph fuck you
because it makes me feel good.
Our situation is absurd.
- Look, maybe I should...
- Shut up, Ralph. Sit down!
Why is it that I have to figure things out
and explain them to you? What do you do?
- I say what I mean, and I do what I say.
- Mm, how admirable.
- You bet.
- Except none of it's about us.
No.
I may be stoned on grass and Prozac...
...but you've been walking
through our life dead.
Now I have to demean myself with Ralph
just to get closure with you.
Passports, traveler's checks, plastic.
The plane, charter terminal, LAX,
Hangar 17.
Call letters are 1011 Sierra.
Touches down, holds for you five minutes,
then splits.
The plane will stand an FAA check.
Filed a flight plan, the works.
- Hey, where's Chris?
- He's gone.
What?
Said he's going on his own.
Went to look for Charlene.
- Didrt you bring him here?
- Yeah, I brought him here.
What happened?
It's a free country, brother.
Check in with me at 9.
Everything's still cool.
All right.
I don't even know
what I'm doing anymore.
I know life is short.
Whatever time you get is luck.
You wanna walk?
You walk right now.
Or on your own...
On your own,
you choose to come with me.
All I know is...
All I know is there's no point in me
going anywhere anymore...
...if it's gonna be alone...
...without you.
Eady.
- Yeah.
- Yeah, Vincent, I got a live one.
Okay, I'll hold.
Come on, sugar. Show yourself.
- Yeah, do it.
- Shut up!
Now, just one second at the window...
...and it's all over.
Hey, man.
- Yeah?
- You know any, uh...
...place to rent around here?
Yeah.
Alberiz's Grocer on Dell Avenue
got cards on the wall.
Yeah, thanks.
It's not him. It's not Chris.
Unit 2, this is Command.
Take him at the street and check him out.
10-4.
Sergeant?
- Yeah.
This guy's John Peterson. Valid ID.
Car's registered to the last name Bukowski,
first name Gene.
Ran it to DMV. It's clean.
- Let him go.
- Roger.
Thank you very much.
Have a good evening.
It's a no-go, Vince.
Would you like a cup of coffee
while we wait, Mrs. Shiherlis?
Yeah, that'd be nice.
MAN [OVER PHONE]: Yeah?
- Yeah, what do you got?
Nothing's happening.
- Yeah?
- Hello, it's Vincent.
What do you got?
Nothing's going on. Waingro went for ice.
That's it.
You know what?
Neil is gone.
Bam!
- Flying like a bird.
- Come on, Vincent, how do you know?
- We still got bait. Maybe some time!
- Got, got. What do we got?
What do we got?
Bon voyage, motherfucker.
You were good.
I'm going to the hotel.
I'm gonna take a shower.
Gonna sleep for a month.
Over here.
Come on, baby.
Okay, okay.
Shit.
Let me tighten this.
What a fucking waste.
Okay, here.
Assholes shoot themselves all fucking day.
Not you, baby. Not you.
Where would she be?
Her name is Lauren, Lauren Gustafson.
I'm supposed to be here with her.
But the police...
- Help me. I need somebody to help...
- It's okay.
I got you.
I got you, baby.
It'll be all right, honey. I swear.
It's okay, baby.
Let's get a doctor! Let's go!
A doctor here! There's your mama.
- Let's just calm down.
- Your mama's here.
- Is she on any drugs?
- No.
I want you to get a trauma surgeon
and a vascular surgeon.
I think she cut both arteries.
Also, I could hardly feel her pulse.
Her pressure's down. So is her respiration.
You have to intubate her.
It's ready.
- Oh...
- Whers the last time anybody saw her?
- I don't know.
- Where did you find her?
- The bathtub.
Call Respiratory stat. Give her large-bore
normal saline. Wide open.
Let's keep pressure on those bleeders.
I need two units, O-negative.
- Let's type and cross her for six.
NURSE: Looks like she's in sinus tach.
Where is Respiratory? We need more help.
Can you have Respiratory come now?
Let's have X-ray ready
for post-intubation chest x-ray.
Hi. Your daughter's out of surgery
and she's in the recovery room now, okay?
Her vital signs are stable. The surgeon will be
out to speak to you in a few moments.
- She's okay?
- She's doing good.
- She's gonna be okay.
She's gonna be okay.
- Oh, my baby.
- She's gonna be okay. It's all right.
- It's all right.
- Why'd she do this to herself? Why?
Look what she did.
Look what she did to herself.
There.
It's all right, honey.
It's gonna be all right.
I'm here. I ain't going anywhere.
- You understand?
- Yeah.
I ain't going anywhere.
- Yeah?
- It's me.
Plane's in the air now.
It'll be right on time.
On the driver's end, I still can't
find nobody, so that's in the trust.
One other thing.
You asked, so I gotta tell you.
The guy you wanted checked into
the Marquis under "Jameson"...
...if you still give a shit,
which I figured you wouldn't.
- You figured right.
- So, so long, brother.
You take it easy.
You're home free.
Take it easy.
- What is it?
- Nothing.
Home free.
- I gotta take care of something.
- Is there time?
There's time.
I'll be right back. Just leave her running.
Regjstration.
- Yeah, this is Room Service.
A Jameson ordered a BLT. They screwed up
his room number. Could you give it to me?
- They're always doing that.
- Yeah, I know.
- 1735.
- Thank you.
Your attention, please.
We are currently experiencing
a fire alarm.
Please do not panic.
Please do not take the elevators.
Shit.
- Waingro's not moving. I'm staying here.
I'm checking the stairs.
If there's smoke, I'm pulling you out.
What about her dad?
You want me to call him?
He's somewhere in the Sierras.
And she chose you.
She picked your place.
It's not right, what happened to her.
No, it's not.
Ugh, okay.
Is there any way...
...that it could work out between us?
I wish I could say yes, you know.
But in the end...
You know, it's like you said:
All I am, is what I'm going after.
I'm not what you want, Justine.
Well, go on, if you have to.
No.
- I'll stay.
- No, I'm okay. I can... I can handle this.
Just be careful.
Call me here. Let me know you're okay.
Okay?
Take the stairs.
Yeah?
Security. There's a fire on 3.
We have to evacuate all the floors.
I can't leave here.
Why don't we just talk about this a bit,
huh, brother?
He's here on 17.
Look at me. Look at me.
Look at me.
L.A.P.D. Don't move.
Put your hands on your head, now.
Switch me to TAC 5.
Casals? JJ?
Drucker, JJ?
I'm at the lobby level by the stairwell.
What have you got?
Teams are moving up the other
elevators to the 17th floor elevators.
All out of commission
because of the fire alarm.
- It's a mess. People everywhere.
- Fine. 10-4.
Let's go, get out of the way.
Stay out of the way.
Let's go. Go that way.
We gotta go, all right? Go, go.
I got it, sir.
Come on, come on.
Come on, sir.
Watch your backs, ladies.
I got it, I got it.
Keep moving, ma'am.
Let's go.
Come on, let's go.
This way, ma'am.
Get back, get back.
- Let me have that shotgun.
- Yes, sir.
Told you I'm never going back.
Yeah.