Damm it
Turn around.
Put the gun down, Sun
Please.
And now the envelope, Mr. Cobb.
You said
or you knew all along?
Who came to rob me
or that every time we sleep?
I wonder who hired him.
In the dream, that threaten Down
You can not, is mal?
Depends výhružce.
Death, he only wakes up ...
But the pain,
headache.
And judging by the decor that
Now in his head, Arthur.
--What is happening is still very early!
I know, but the dream is deteriorating.
I'll try to keep it still uspaného.
I almost was.
Stop it!
SECRET
We think it worked.
Wake him.
He did not want to wake up!
Give him a kick.
--What?
Throw it in water.
Is out.
Are you ready?
Neither the security did not know anything about that post.
How did you find?
For a man of his position does not
easy to hide the love nest ...
Especially when it was
invited a married woman.
"She never ...
--And yet here we are.
Better hurry, they are close.
You get what you want.
This is not true.
You left there is a significant
information, is not it?
You hid, because you
knowing that stealing it.
Why are you doing?
Test.
--What is the test?
It does not matter.
You failed.
Were extracted
any of your information.
But you was too obvious.
It's over.
Send me a deadline.
I think you understand, Mr. Saito.
The Corporation hired us
admit failure.
We have only a few days.
I guess I'll have to
make it easier.
Say what you know!
Immediately tell us!
This carpet
I always hated.
And his strange and ugly
raffishness and omšelost.
I certainly was wool.
Now certainly
lying on the polyester.
Which means I'm
on the carpet of his apartment.
Confirmed his reputation, Mr. Cobb.
We're still in a dream.
--How you doing?
--Wrong.
A dream within a dream?
I was amazed.
But in my dream you
play by my rules.
--Yes, but you know that Mr. Saito ...
--This is not your dream.
It's mine.
Idiot with the carpet you're fucked.
--How would I know?
You're the architect.
--If nezaboril your nose!
Enough.
--What the hell was that?
--I have everything under control.
So I do not want to see if you do.
At this time we do not.
In Kyoto vystopím.
--You can search the entire train.
I do not like trains.
Every man for himself now.
"Yes, Hello?
--Hi, Dad.
Kids, Hello!
How are you?
--Ok.
"I guess.
Ok?
--Who said good? Is this James?
--Yes.
You come home, Dad?
I can not, honey.
We talked about it, remember?
I said I was gone,
because I work.
Yeah?
The grandmother said she had not returned.
Phillip, are you?
Give me a grandmother on the phone.
Shakes his head.
We hope that they are wrong.
Father?
Yes Jamie,?
Mom is with you?
I told you ...
Mom was not with us.
Why?
Well--Child, Say goodbye.
I send you some gifts for grandpa.
And forgive me ...
The helicopter is on the roof.
Are you okay?
Yes, I'm fine.
Why?
In the dream showed Mal
Sorry for the lower leg.
That will not happen again.
Getting worse?
An apology is not enough?
Nash--s Where?
Still--appeared. Let's wait?
There, he went to the COBOL
two hours ago. They know that we have failed.
--Where are you?
--Buenos Aires.
--I have some work to do. And you?
--The E.U..
Say Hello there.
Sold you.
He came to the company asking for his life.
I offer you a reward.
I do not do that.
What we do with it?
I am nothing.
But I can not speak
Engineering for the Cobol.
What you want from us?
Inspiration.
--Is it possible?
--Of course not.
When you are able to steal the idea
mind, why you can not even put it?
Well, now you inspire the idea.
Say, "I do not think of elephants."
What do you think? "
For elephants.
Yes, but it is not your idea
knowing that I gave to you.
Mind always know the origin of ideas.
Inspiration can not be falsified.
This is not true.
"You can?
Give me a choice?
Because the COBOL
I can help.
So you have a choice.
And I chose to leave, sir.
Tell the group to go.
How would you like to go home?
For America.
Their children.
This can not.
Nobody can do.
inspiration as well.
Cobb, c'mon.
As this is a complicated
thought to be?
Very simple.
Nothing is simple when you have someone
implanted in his mind.
My rival is a very old man.
Coming soon die and the son inherits the business.
I have decided
sell his father's empire.
Not to let it be.
--Wait.
If you're going to try ...
If possible,
I guarantee it.
How do I know that you also make a deal?
No.
But I'll do it.
So ...
Decide on possible hope
or older with no remorse?
Waiting for a lonely death.
Gather your team.
Time and choose carefully.
I know how much you want to go home.
But that does not take us.
Lead.
--Just have to go deeper.
I do not know.
I have achieved.
Who did you do?
Why fly to Paris?
We need a new architect.
You never had an office like this?
The chamber, there is no place
to think.
Not for you
dangerous to be here?
Issue of criminals between France and the E.U.
bureaucrats is a nightmare. They do not like him.
In your case, you will surely find.
Look, I wish you
this could pass for children.
animals want things
to prove that the loss of a parent?
Just do what I do and
Because you taught me.
I taught you to be a thief.
Ucils me to control the human mind.
And after what happened
Now I can legally use.
What are you doing here, Don?
I think I found my way home.
Too much work for
influential people.
People who can delete
my permanent record.
But I need your help.
You're here to bring the
avert my best students.
You know what to offer.
Must decide for yourself.
--Money.
--Not only that, remember?
Chance to build a cathedral and the city
that could not exist in reality.
So you want to take you to your
fantasy followed by another person.
May not enter. Fair
elaborate and explain them spácum.
Suggests that it is himself.
mal does not allow me.
Snap back to reality, Sun
Please.
My children, grandchildren,
waiting for his father. That is the reality.
And this latest work
I stand with them.
I was there,
I knew otherwise.
I need an architect as well
as good as I was.
I have someone better.
Ariadne?
I would like to introduce you
Mr. Cobb.
Mr. Cobb is for you
employment.
--Employment?
--Not quite.
You do not want me first
sth about?
Before doing so, I know
you have.
Why?
It's not exactly legal.
Draw a maze in two minutes,
whose solution will take a minute.
Stop.
Again.
You need to do better.
That's better.
When we awake, we use only
a small part of the brain's capacity.
"When we sleep, it's the opposite.
--What do you mean?
Imagine it as a
designing buildings.
You create each detail. But sometimes it
as would be suggested itself.
--Know what I mean?
--Yes.
--How it to appear.
Auto inspiration.
In the dream, we do it constantly.
We create and perceive the world.
Mind does well there,
do not realize.
And we're right in the middle.
--How? --Here is the creative part
for what you need.
You create a world of dreams.
Bring it to our body
and he filled my subconscious.
How could it be possible to create
many details, then everything fell realistically?
In the dream we all seem real, right?
Only when you wake
realize, as were special.
You never knew you
Top remembered dream?
You were always right
middle of the action, right?
--Probably.
--And how did we get here?
We come from ...
Think Ariadne,
How did we get here?
Where exactly are we?
--We are in a dream?
"You're lying in our office.
Calm down, this is the first lesson.
Although it is only a dream
Why protect your face?
It is never just a dream.
Fragments in the face of insane pain.
Headache is real.
Therefore, the Army began to develop.
For military training.
Soldiers were able to kill and
only by touch.
Why you need an architect?
Someone has to dream design.
Five minutes?
We talked for an hour.
During sleep
brain works faster.
So, time passes slowly.
Five minutes in the real world
Is the time in a dream.
This is the basic peripherals.
Library, coffee, almost everything.
Who are these people?
Projection of my subconscious.
--Your?
You can talk to
My subconscious.
It then extracts information.
What else are you doing?
Create something safe,
as safe or phone.
The subconscious mind will automatically
filled with information that he wants to protect.
"Okay?
--There and steal it?
I thought the dream is primarily
visual, but it's basically a feeling.
What happens when
pohrajete you with physics?
--These are things?
That's true.
Why look at me?
Because my subconscious feels
someone who creates this world.
The more you change,
the subconscious will be more aggressive.
Aggressive?
It's natural protection.
As the white blood cells attack the virus.
Attack us?
No..
Just for you.
Nice, but really you
She has not changed much.
Let me
unconscious in the bedroom.
It is the subconscious control over it.
Really impressive.
I know this bridge.
It's true.
Yes, I pass here every day to school.
Never Do not create in its memory.
Always the latest news!
You must know
based on things they know.
Use only the details.
Streetlight, a telephone booth.
Never in the entire region.
Why not?
Since the stop
distinguish reality from dreams.
It has happened to you?
Look, this is not a game, right?
Then you need me,
I formed a dream?
Give your room.
Get out!
mal!
Wake me!
Are you okay?
Because I could not wake up?
Nedobehl longer. Otherwise
You can wake up only to death.
Explain totem.
--What?
Totem is small --
This is your subconscious
beautiful woman annoying!
So you see Ms. Cobb?
It was his wife?
Yes Totem is so small
object that only you know,
'What nobody needs to know.
--Like a coin?
None unikátnejšího something.
Ping as a hub.
You can not borrow it, which is its meaning.
I just know that your balance and weight.
When we look at your totem, you will
I know you dream of someone.
I do not know if I can not see, or ignore,
But Cobb has serious problems
trying to hide there.
She returns.
Nobody learned so quickly.
The reality of today will not suffice.
Returns.
Explain you then maze.
--Where you going?
Visit Eames.
"But he is in Mombasa.
--It is around the corner.
Must--risk.
It is full of good--thieves.
--We need more than that.
We need to counterfeiters.
You rub all you want
But nerozmnoží.
You never know.
Come for a drink.
You pay.
So what's the idea
you need to give?
Heir of large companies should
dissolve the empire of her father.
It stretches very political
motivation and ambition of antitrust.
Lots of emotions and prejudices of the body ...
You would have to begin to complete the foundations.
What is it?
Relationship with his father.
--You have a chemist?
--No, not yet.
Okay, there's a man, Yusuf,
what confuses its own revenue.
--Will you marry me for it?
--First, get rid of the monitor.
--The man at the bar.
Cobol Engineering.
Place a reward for me.
You do not know whether dead or alive?
I have no idea.
See if it starts firing.
Let's get together for half an hour here.
--Here?
The last place to look.
Fred!
Simmonds Fredy?
--What?
--Yes you are!
Well, probably not.
This does not seem to you huh?
A cup of coffee.
You need a taxi, Mr. Cobb?
--What do you do in Mombasa?
, Protect your investment.
--So you finally got caught?
But somebody else.
Cobb said he will return.
--I do not want to go back.
But nothing compares to it.
It's just ...
pure creation.
Let's see
architecture paradoxical?
You have to learn a few tricks, if
To create complex worlds.
Sorry.
--What are the tricks?
Unable to create forms.
Make a closed loop.
Like this ...
Endless stairs.
See?
Paradox.
Similar loops help
hide the borders of dreams.
--How great can it be?
--From a walk to entire cities.
But it must be quite complicated,
we hide from projections.
--So the Maze?
--Maze.
Or, even better.
Where we are
projection get?
Exactly.
My subconscious behaves
pretty decent.
Just wait, you will also rebel.
Nobody can resist when he dig in his head.
Cobb could not create it?
Do not know if you can, but do not want.
He says it's safer,
he does not know the details.
Why?
"I do not tell me.
I think because of mal
His ex--?
Not the former.
Are they still together?
No..
Is dead.
You saw only a projection.
--How was it?
"She was amazing.
Are you looking for a pharmacy to prepare
compost in your order.
And go with us in the field.
I do not do that, Mr. Cobb.
We want substance
our specific needs.
What are they?
stability.
A dream within a dream?
Thus, two levels ...
Three.
It is impossible.
The level is very unstable.
--Can.
We have to use a tranquilizer.
No, a heavy sedative.
--How many team members?
Five.
Six.
I'll go with you to know
who have completed the task.
There is no place for tourists,
Mr. Saito.
This time will be.
This is a good start.
I use daily.
--What?
Let me show you.
Maybe you do not want to see.
Please.
Have ... Twelve subscribers.
How do you prove it?
They come here every day,
to dream of a common dream.
See? Very stable.
--How long are they connected?
--A few hours.
Every day.
One time in a dream?
About forty hours per day.
--Why do they do?
--Tell him, Mr. Cobb.
After some time, is
only one way to dream.
"You have dreams, Mr. Cobb?
Dream--come here every day?
No.
They come here to awaken.
Dream became reality.
You have the right to require that, otherwise?
Let's see what you can do.
You know how to find me.
You know what to do.
Fair, right?
You're right, Mr. Cobb?
Yes.
Fine.
Robert Fischer, heir
energy conglomerate.
And what you have with this
Robert Fischer?
This is not your thing.
Mr. Saito, the
no ordinary spy.
Calls for inspiration and I hope
you understand the seriousness of this requirement.
We planted a seed in your mind that
men who grow up in the idea.
The idea is to define.
He can change his personality.
We're the last company that makes
the monopoly of global energy.
And you can not stay long.
Coming soon will be marked
power supply for half the world.
Thus, if in fact
new superpower.
World needs, Robert
Fischer changed his position.
And here we have on.
What is the relationship with your father?
--Said to be a little tricky.
--We need more than just talk.
Organize my approach to this one man?
Browning.
Right elder Fischer,
Fischer sponsored youth.
This should not be difficult
You just need a good reference.
Referrals are my
specialty, Mr. Saito.
She walked me patience.
Get rid of them.
Joschka Fischer, Maurice Browning
always trying to avoid court.
You want to check it myself
directly with Maurice?
"I think it is not necessary.
--No, I think we should.
How is he?
I would not bother you if
It was not necessary, but ...
It must be your precious memories.
I put him to bed.
Also recorded.
We need to talk about
legal issues.
--Not now.
"But it's important.
As Maurice Fischer loses power
Peter Browning receives it.
I had many opportunities
Browning observed.
Learn to imitate his speech,
studying the sign ...
Thus, the first level, I dream
I am a Browning.
The nadhodím Fischer
mind to think about it.
When we get a deeper level, their own
Browning design he recalls.
--He can create the idea?
--Exactly.
Only then will be stable,
must create it.
Eames, I'm impressed.
I greatly appreciate your disdain,
Thanks Arthur.
You connect with yourself?
No, I did some testing.
I did not know anyone there.
I finished my totem.
View.
"You learn quickly.
An elegant solution for the recognition of reality.
It was his idea?
No, really evil thought
This was her. When he turned
in a dream, never stop.
Just more spin.
Arthur told me he died.
--As he continues with the labyrinth?
At the lowest level will be
Hospital, where he finds his father Fisher.
I should have
request for this area ...
No, do not show me the details.
Only one person should know who sleeps map.
Why it should be?
Because there are our projections.
We do not want to know the details.
You mean like when you bring mal?
Can not get rid of it, right?
--Yes.
So netvoríš.
When you know the details, he knows it too.
Sabotaged the entire operation.
Cobb--know the rest?
--No, I do not know.
You should be warned
you could do worse.
Nothing will get worse.
I just need to get home
Nothing else was irrelevant.
Why can not you home?
Because he thinks he killed her.
--Thanks.
--For what?
Nepta that if I did.
"Divide the empire from his father."
That was never Fischer did not.
Therefore, we must find a way
How to give it.
The subconscious mind is driven by emotion.
We must find ways
how to translate that emotion.
How do you want to convert the business to the emotions?
Now it should come.
We can use the relationship with his father Roberto.
We suggest that the destruction of his father
Empire is an appropriate revenge.
No, positive emotions
have much more power.
We need reconciliation, catharsis.
We must do everything
Robert had a positive emotion.
So try to be ...
"My father wanted me alone accounted
if not, just go in his footsteps. "
--Can run.
-- "It"?
--We need more than that.
--Thanks for your feedback, Arthur.
Excuse me, I want something specific.
Specific.
Whispers of the individual is not
issues, should solve the mind.
Should be sown and let it grow.
At the highest level
open relationship with his father.
Say something like
"I will not go into his father's footsteps."
At the next level
priživíme the idea.
"This will create something for himself."
At the lowest level
sharper pull gauge.
-- "My father wants me to follow him?
--Exactly.
At the third level, we agree
the slightest disturbance.
Sedatives.
To deal with three levels, will
extémne need strong sedatives.
Good night.
Cobb, prepare it
three levels.
It accelerates the activity of the brain.
We get more time at each level.
Brain activity in a dream
about twenty times faster.
If you dream a dream within a dream ...
He is constantly growing.
Three dreams of ten hours.
Sorry, mathematics
not my forte.
Week of first level.
The second half of the year.
--The third --
--Ten years!
Who wants to live
in ten years, a dream?
Depends on the dream.
And how do we leave?
We find something more elegant,
a shot in the head, yes?
Kick.
--What is it?
--This is a kick.
Feel that you fall.
Well, wake up.
She'll feel more sedation?
I arrange.
I mixed them
the inner ear is working.
All you deeply,
still feel the fall.
I pushed.
It is crucial to synchronize
Kicks at all levels.
You can use the music.
scheduled surgery,
or dentistry. Nothing.
--He's not going to knee surgery?
--Nothing.
No chance
he would sleep.
And what we need at least
ten hours of sleep.
The flight from Sydney to Los Angeles.
One of the longest in the world.
He flies them every two weeks.
Must be a private jet.
This may have an unexpected failure.
--We need 747
Why?
You have a cockpit on top.
The first class is way ahead.
Nobody passes through it.
We will have zkoupit
Bribery and one stewardess.
I bought airline.
It seemed easier.
It seems that we won
his ten hours.
Ariadne, excellent work,
incidentally.
You know what to do.
Remember when you me
asked for her hand?
Absolutely.
You say you dream about it ...
How to grow old together.
Still, we can.
Here you should not be.
I wanted to see what the
"Tests" in the night doing.
--This has nothing to do.
--Sure you do. We share your dreams with you.
These sun
These are my dreams.
Why are you doing?
It's the only way
I can still dream.
Why is
both of you?
In dreams, we're always together.
These are not just dreams.
These are the memories. You said
should not be used.
I know.
Trying to keep her alive.
Do not let her go.
You do not understand.
These are the memories,
I have to change.
What is hidden below?
There is one thing
for me, you understand.
Your house?
Where is he?
More.
This is my son, James.
Something dug. On earthworms.
This is Phillip. I would call them,
I last saw them ...
smile and beautiful
but it is too late.
Now or never, Cobb.
And then I started to panic.
I know I'll regret that moment,
when I've last seen.
Everything we do,
it will not change at this time.
They called it ...
and they are gone.
If I get home
And never see.
In the real world.
What are you doing here?
--I ...
"I know who you are.
What are you doing here?
I'm just trying to understand ...
How could you understand?
You know what being in love?
Being half a whole?
No.
Let me tell you a riddle.
Waiting for the train.
Train that will take him now.
I hope he will take you anywhere you want.
But you can be sure.
But no matter.
Why do you care,
where you can catch the train?
Because we'll be together.
How did you get here
could bring, Don?
What place is this?
Suite Hotel,
where we celebrated the birthday.
What happened here?
You promised!
I just take it, I'll be back.
You promised we'll be together!
I will be back again.
I promise.
You think you can simply
stuck in their memories?
Do you think it will live?
Come on. Maurice Fischer
just died in Sydney.
--When is the funeral?
--On Thursday.
--Los Angeles.
Robert with a coffin--fly on Tuesday.
--We have to hurry.
--Claro.
I'll fly with you. "
I can not, I promised my father.
You need someone there,
who understands their problems.
And if not me, then you should
Arthur shows what I saw.
Make another ticket.
If you get on the plane
and you do not keep our agreement,
After closing the landing to my life.
Complete your task, I will call the aircraft,
and you will not have problems.
Sorry.
Yes, sorry.
Sorry, but I think this is yours.
You had to leave.
Want something to drink?
Ice water, please.
"Me too.
Thank you.
Not coincidentally, the relationship
Maurice Fischer famous?
Yes it is ...
It was my father.
It was an inspiring man.
His loss I'm sorry.
--Here.
--Thanks.
For his father.
Rip.
Q: Could you pee before you fly?
--Sorry.
Very champagne--free?
--Great fun.
At least he will need a taxi.
You're an idiot?
Skirt.
Gotta go. Taxi!
--What do you do?
"I thought it was free.
Absolutely not. You ...
Great.
Come on.
There is U.S. $ 500
portfolio is more expensive.
Take me at least
where I wanted.
Cover us!
Stop it!
Are you okay?
Yes, I'm fine.
Fischer, too. He took comfort.
Saito?
Make it back!
--Death? "
"I do not know.
--Where were you?
He hit us trains.
--What a train in the street?
"I have not given you there!
Where there are married?
--Can you tell me what's going on?
These were not normal
projections are training!
As they have the training?
Fischer learned Extractor
unconsciously avoid infestation.
So they are armed.
I had to find out.
--And why not?
--Peace.
Do not tell me to calm me.
It was your responsibility!
Able to examine it
Fischer's past.
We're not ready
for this event!
Experience
'll be more careful!
This was part of the plan.
He dies!
"I'll spare you the pain.
--Do not shoot!
No!
He is in agony, only to wake him.
No, wake up.
When you die in a dream, wake up.
Not this time. With this dose
Sedation me awake.
What happens when we die here?
You fall in the desert.
--Are you serious?
The Waste Land?
Raw desert dreams.
--And what?
Only remnants of the subconscious
that's all there is.
Remains unconscious man
there was only one of us.
What is you.
How long can we stay?
Not run--up to the sedatives --
How long?
Decades, perhaps forever.
He was there, ask him.
Thanks.
We're stuck in the mind of Fischer,
haunted by his army,
and if they kill us, will remain in
Desert, until our brains neshnijou.
You knew about the risk?
--And all that tell us?
"There's nothing to threaten us.
We did not have the
middle of a firefight.
Nemels law.
--The only way to reach the third level.
--And you know it.
"I believed him.
Believe? How much you gave me,
half of you?
No. I gave it everything.
--He said he tried it.
Experienced? Who, with mal?
This nevyvedlo--lot!
--I did it just because their children.
You brought us through
war without an exit.
This is a way to leave.
Let us conclude our work
As he goes quickly and
We were expelled.
Forget it. Can not go anywhere.
We kept odsedím here.
Fischer guard around us.
At this level is 10 flight hours per week.
We guarantee that
Here we all die.
The only option is to continue
as soon as possible.
The fall is our only way.
Prepare yourself.
Let's try a little to deteriorate.
I have insurance against kidnapping
10 million. Will it lightly.
Shut up!
In the office, his father
is a personal insurance.
We want to know the combination.
I do not know about the safe.
--That does not mean you do not know the code.
Tell us.
I know him.
Source told us something more.
What is this source?
Worth $ 500.
--What's inside?
Money, cards, cards.
And this.
It will be for anything?
Maybe. Your turn.
You have one hour.
Time?
I had to have all night.
The Saito had
a bullet hole on his chest.
You have one hour. Learn
useful, please.
What?
Our source.
Uncle Peter.
If you stop.
Tu combination.
"I do not know.
I do not know. Let me
talk to him and I'll find out.
You have one hour.
So start talking.
Are you okay?
The bastards me
processed by two days.
Get access to offices
his father and wants to open the safe.
I thought the combination I know,
But this is not true.
Furthermore, I know.
What?
Maurice told me that after he dies,
you just opened.
He never told me
any combination.
Maybe said ...
I just know it's a combination.
--So what?
I do not know, something that applies
to their common experiences.
We just have a lot of
common experiences.
Perhaps, after his mother died.
"You know what I said then?
"Robert, you have nothing to say."
--He was upset by it.
"I was eleven!
--How is he?
"My great pain.
Elsewhere, it will improve.
And if you die?
In the worst case
wakes up with an empty brain.
Cobb, will keep our agreement.
I appreciate that but after waking
not even need to know that some were.
The forest becomes your reality.
Will you be there so long,
she gets older.
complete remorse.
--They will kill us because of that.
Only one of us wants to --
I heard that we
sheds in the car in a river.
--What is safe?
--Something for you.
Maurice has always said
is a precious gift for you.
Testament.
Maurice is a lawyer.
--It removes it. Divide into small businesses.
That would be the end
our whole empire.
Destroy my inheritance?
Why would something like this?
He loved you, Robert.
--As a special ...
--In a special mode.
In the end he called me.
Barely spoke. But he gave
effort to tell me one last thing.
I leaned over and detected
I have only one word ...
"Disappointed."
What awaits us in the desert?
You can convince the rest of the team,
but they do not know the whole truth.
--What truth?
--Mind your can summon the train.
Barely surviving
in his subconscious.
And that, to deepen their
Fischer, who go deep inside you.
And maybe we do not like,
what they think.
We work together
Research on the dream of a dream.
But we did not know
time there fluently much more slowly.
When you're long in the subconscious
forget what is real.
It took years,
but we build it.
How long were you there?
--About fifty years.
Jeez.
How did you do that?
The first years were not
as bad as if he were God.
But it was not fair.
I could not live like this.
--And what happened to her?
--Something hidden inside.
Law, who requested anonymity.
She wanted to forget it.
Wasteland has become a reality.
What happened when you woke up?
After so many decades, when he wakes up
old souls in young bodies ...
I've seen is something.
She would not admit it.
She was enthusiastic about the idea.
This simple
I thought everything had changed.
Believe that reality is not true,
they should wake up again.
To be able to return home
must be killed.
--What are your children?
"I thought we were designing.
This right for our children
We're waiting somewhere.
I'm your mother, you know the difference!
--When is a dream, why did not he speak?
--Because you know what you eat!
It was clear that there is nothing
do it no matter how they try.
Failed to kill,
she loved me too.
Developed a plan for our anniversary.
--Darling what are you doing?
Join me.
Go back inside.
Yeah? Back.
No.
And you jump with me.
No, I'm not falling.
Listen to me.
When I jump, wake up.
Die, then go back inside.
talk--Let 's.
--We've talked a lot.
Go to the edge
or go straight.
talk--Let 's.
--I ask you to go with me.
I can not, you know it.
Think of our children.
For James, Phillip.
When neskocíš,
as they will not.
--What do you mean?
"I left a letter with a lawyer.
I write it as
I fear for my safety.
How can you threaten death.
--Why did you do?
"I love you, Dom
--Why did you ...?
--So I got rid of guilt.
You could go back home to
our children real.
--Mal, listen. Look at me.
--Waiting for a train ...
--Damn it, stop it!
--Train, which will take you far.
--Damn, look at me!
"But no matter.
Because we'll be together.
None Christ Jesus!
She had three psychiatrists
confirm that it is healthy.
I could not tell them,
what comes from his madness.
--I flew ...
--Now or never, Cobb.
I left there and the kids
had to start somewhere else.
The thought set.
Unable to what happened.
If we succeed here,
You have to forgive and deal with it.
"You have to do it.
No..
And for others, why not
no idea how you have to take risks.
--We have to hurry.
--Time ".
Look, I know
any combination. Not consciously.
Now someone
is prepared in the vault.
Tell him that the first six
numbers, what you think.
"I do not know.
--Come on!
I said come on!
.. 5th 2 .. 8 .. 491
"You'll have to try harder.
Pick--up.
We increased the price of life.
Can you hear me?
--So? --His relationship with his father
is worse than we thought.
--Go to help?
This greater catharsis.
--What is with them?
--Working on it. --Click Add.
We need to get there.
Do not be afraid to dream big, baby.
--We have to turn them against the Godfather.
Destroy the only functional relationship?
Nah, we find the godfather
and atonement with the father.
Indeed we must Fischer
pay more than Saito.
As you walk down, it gets worse.
"Maybe it's time for Mr. Charles.
"Who is Mr. Charles?
--Bad idea.
When we got to the hotel
Fischer keeps attacking us.
Used as Charles Stein.
So, have you tried this?
Yes, and it did not work. Body
realized he was sleeping and destroy us.
Well it will be fun!
--We need a distraction.
--Use again the lovely lady.
Listen, be careful. Downstairs
It will be terrible to play with us.
We care
Synchronize the kick.
I go to the music in time
the rest is up to you.
--Are you ready?
--Can!
Sweet dreams.
I'm boring you? I told you
its history, but you probably do not care.
I am now in my head.
Here comes Mr. Charles.
Mr. Fischer, right?
Glad to see you again.
Rob Green marketing.
--And you?
On--leave.
If you got bored with.
Vypekla you or have your
only six phone numbers?
In addition, she stole his wallet.
--Hell happened ...
$ --500?
Do not worry
My people came after it.
Who or what is Mr. Charles?
Way to navigate Fischer
against his own subconscious.
--How does he do?
Body say, that dream.
What can summon a lot of
unwanted attention.
Cobb did not want, right?
--At least you see how often violates the rules.
--Mr Saito, I can stop it?
Excuse me, but ...
"You're alive.
--Very funny, Mr Eames.
Turbulence in plane?
No, it was close. Auto.
--How do you say your name?
--Rob Green marketing.
But this is obviously not true.
Mr. Charles
remember me?
I have to worry about security.
Get off at different floors.
Reject the portfolio, looking for her.
We need more time to ensure Cobb.
Security, yes?
You work for a hotel?
No, I read with great
specific type of security.
Security awareness.
--You talk about dreams?
The extraction?
"I'm here to protect you.
I'm here to protect you
accidental infections of your mind.
You're safe here.
They go for you.
special time, eh?
Can you feel it?
--What is happening?
Cobb--Fischer said only that dream.
Subconscious now looking for a sleeper.
Then me. Quickly, kiss me.
Still, watching.
The attempt of the cost that.
We must go.
Can you feel it? This is what you
was committed, Mr. Fisher.
Feel time zláštnost
changes in gravity.
Nothing out this is not true.
You're in a dream.
The best you can when you
Remember how you came to the hotel.
Well, I ...
--Breathe, remember the training.
You will find that you're in a dream
and I'll protect you.
--Not true?
"I'm not.
Protect your subconscious
extracting attack.
And it is now
happening, Mr. Fisher.
"You can go out?
Follow me.
What are you doing?
Did you take. If you want
help you to calm down.
I need your cooperation.
--If you dream that I wake up, right?
"I would not, Mr. Fisher.
Surely you have given sedatives.
You do not wake up.
You were in my dreams.
You know what I mean ...
Remember the training,
what I said?
--This room is directly below 528?
--Yes.
Think about what you
Down you remember the dream?
Lots of shooting ...
It rained.
Uncle Peter!
Kidnapped us.
--Where did you accomplish?
Led us in the van.
--This explains the changes in gravity.
Now you're in the van.
Let us remember more.
Somehow, he was associated with a safe.
I do not remember.
Like remembering a dream
Awakening, he wants to years of practice.
Browning and you sleep because
You want to steal something from your head.
I need you
concentrate and remember what it is.
--What is it, Mr. Fisher?
--Combination!
They wanted to know the top six
numbers, which makes me wonder.
Trying to extract numbers
from your subconscious.
They could say anything.
Now we're in a hotel ...
Let's try the room number.
How was that number?
Try to remember
It is very important.
--5 ... 2 .. It was a long number.
--Enough for now.
Fifth floor.
Roger.
--You can use a timer?
No, the trigger alone.
When you sleep at 528
I'll give you a kick.
--How do you know when?
--Highlights of my music.
When a car breaks down barriers
on the bridge, I can not make a mistake.
We need a good
synchronized kicking.
Very early he kicks us
late again down.
Why?
Because auto--flight in freefall.
Gravity does not kick.
--Claro.
These are my people.
Charles Sir!
--Do you recognize this, Mr. Fisher?
--Did you sleep.
After all, we are in a dream.
Again.
--Do you dream in a dream?
"You've changed.
--What?
Sorry, I confuse you.
Surely with a piece?
This is Fischer
projection of Browning.
Their behavior may know
if she ever suspected.
Why? Why We Fischer
instructed to take it as an obstacle.
--Peter?
"You said it kidnapped along?
--He had two days, tortured him.
"You saw that torture?
You're the kidnapper sent?
--Robert ...
You tried to open the safe,
will have a big?
I gave all of us
your life. I will not let you destroy it.
I do not want to destroy their heritage,
Why would I do?
I could not let it
succumbing to the last race of his father.
--Trick?
--This will be his last crime.
Says you're worthy of his legacy,
you wanted to build something yourself.
Cobb?
What's down there?
I mean, what's wrong with you?
Have you seen this? "
Eames, his dream, to have
attention to safety.
Zašplhá--Who?
--I do not.
We have to divide.
--I do not propose here.
"You're with me.
--I mastered it.
Reaching the top of the building.
Fisher, you go with it.
Leave it on, I
all the time to listen.
Windows are on top big enough
I'll be able to cover the south tower.
Are you going there?
No..
To discover the truth about his father
Browning it means to you.
Come on Fisher.
Start the Clock!
Hope you're ready.
It's still early.
Cobb, hear it? Noticed
It was twenty minutes ago.
"I thought it was a breeze.
"I hear it, is music.
--What do we do?
Hurry.
You have ten seconds to jump.
So Arthur has three minutes.
--Who are we?
Sixty minutes.
--I have it in an hour?
It should be across the courtyard.
So they need a shortcut.
--It is a maze.
We entered the hall.
Eames Altered something?
I do not know if I can say that.
--There could be hardly appear.
--No time! Has anything changed?
Added fan under the main hall.
--Ok, explain it to them.
Paradox.
--What?
--Kopanec.
--Cobb, we lose it?
--Served.
Would not it be better to have a dream about a beach?
--What do we do now?
--Finish this before the next kick.
--That will be when?
--When the car crashes into the water.
As you kick without gravity?
Arthur has a couple of minutes,
we are about twenty.
Are you okay?
Something's wrong,
as if they knew anything about.
In little time to fix it, yes?
Before us is secure?
What should secure window?
--Not too hard.
Inside, he finds Fischer.
--This is the projection of your subconscious?
--Yes.
--Nenicíš your mind?
--There are only projections.
Near us, the entire army.
I'm here.
--Someone is there.
Fischer is a trap!
A little down.
Cobb, no she is not real!
--How do you know? "
--It 'projections!
Fischer is real!
Eames, immediately to the safe
Barely got here!
--What happened?
Mal--killed Fisher.
Nice shot.
It makes sense to revive him
his mind is already in the desert.
It's over.
--This is the whole, no?
It is, after all.
Sorry.
Well, you are not the only ones
see the family, right?
Too bad it did not open.
I would like to see what's there.
Prepare specifications.
There is also an option.
Just as we have nowhere to Fischer.
We do not have time.
No, there is no time to spare.
And when we meet and listen to music,
give him a kick electroshock.
We'll make it there.
We stayed there and listen
music tee hospital, all
and it wakes us all.
Worth a try.
But Saito is keeping guard.
Saito dies.
--Cobb, we have to try.
But if the return
before the kick, I'm done with you.
He's right, he can go.
"You can do this? mal will be there.
"I know where I can find it.
Fischer will be with her. Will want
I came here for him.
He wants me there with him.
Are you okay?
, This is your world?
--It.
Their waste.
Saito, I need to keep
guards prepare the charges.
Now I have a good proposal.
Neblbnete.
Everything you build?
That's incredible.
We had to years.
I started with memories.
This way.
This is our neighborhood.
Places in the past.
Our first apartment.
Until then, the building next door
Then he moved.
When Mal pregnant
We live here.
All you have to build
just the memories?
I said
We had a lot of time.
--What is it?
--The house of my childhood.
--Will there?
No..
We always wanted to live in a house
we love skyscrapers.
Here we have both.
Fisher--Getting back?
--We need to find some kick.
Maybe?
Listen, something you should know about me.
Inspiration ...
The idea is like a virus.
Parasite.
Highly contagious.
Grow from small seeds.
Or you define, or destroy.
Even the slightest idea how
"The world is not real"
can change everything.
You're so sure of your world.
Do you think this is true?
Or is it also
lost, as I was?
I do not know what is real.
You have terrible doubts?
Not feeling the victim, Don?
You're running around the world
Anonymous corporations?
Like when the projection
pursuit of a bed, right?
Admit it.
No longer believe in reality.
So now you choose.
Stay and pick me up.
You know I gotta go back
for children, which you left.
--Since you left us.
"You're wrong!
"I'm not mistaken.
"You're confused.
Our children are here. And you
I saw your face again.
Yes, but see
As in the real world.
You're mistaken.
Hear what you say.
These are our children.
Look.
--James, Phillip?
--Stop, they are not our children.
Repeating,
because you believed.
No, I know!
--And if you're wrong?
And if I'm real?
Repeat what you know
But what do you believe?
What do you think? "
Guilt.
I feel guilty, Mal
No matter what I do,
or how I'm desperate,
I am confused as ...
That the fault is still there.
--Reminds me of the truth.
--What truth?
That the idea of challenging
Indeed, I vnuknul.
You planted the idea
in my mind?
What are you talking about?
I know that inspiration can
because I have already done.
--My wife.
Why?
We're lost in the desert.
We needed to escape.
But she did not agree.
Something hidden.
Somewhere inside of me.
True, who requested anonymity.
They wanted to forget.
Could not free himself.
And so I started searching.
Ultimately, I find this hidden place.
Robbed there
and planted the idea.
A simple idea
everything changed.
That our world is not real.
And death is the only way out.
Waiting for the train.
On the train that will take you far.
You expect that will take you anywhere you want.
Can not be sure.
But it does not matter.
Tell me why!
Because we'll be together!
I should have known that
the idea will grow even more.
When she returned to reality ...
Also believed that the world is not real.
And death is the only way out.
Mai, Jesus Christ!
You infected my mind?
"I wanted to save.
You deceived me?
You can still keep his promise,
can still be together.
Right here. In a world
we built together.
Here it is!
Have to go back.
--Make sure that everything was fine.
"You can stay here with her.
I will not stay. Saito died
so here somewhere.
I must find him.
I will not be with you,
because they do not exist.
The only way we can be together.
I would like, but ...
I can not imagine you in all your vysnít
complexity. Perfection and imperfection.
You'll be fine.
--Look for yourself.
You're just a shadow of my real woman.
I can not do better.
But still not enough.
Is this enough?
Is this real?
--What are you doing?
Zachranuju us.
No, no!
Open it, do it.
--I was disappointed ...
--I know, Dad.
I know you're disappointed,
I'm not like you.
No, I was disappointed,
you are so difficult.
It was a kick, you jump!
Meet Saito, and come back!
"I'll do it!
--Remember when you asked me a hand?
--Yes.
You say you dream
they grow old together.
But growing old together.
We age, remember?
I miss you so,
until it is unbearable ...
But we have already spent your time.
I told you about it.
And now I must go home.
Sorry, Robert.
He just wanted me
be on your own.
Not only was his heir.
And me, uncle.
--What happened?
Cobb--stay there.
--Why mal?
No, to find Saito.
Dissipates.
No, I can handle it.
You've come to kill me?
I'm waiting for someone.
For someone in the middle
forgotten dreams ...
Cobb?
Not possible.
Together, they were young.
"I'm an old man.
Full--censorship.
Waiting for a lonely death.
I returned to you.
Remember me tell you something ...
Something you already knew.
--To be satisfied with our agreement.
He dragged his chance to finish.
Come back, we can
to be young again.
Come back to me.
Back.
They are landing, sir. We
in Los Angeles for twenty minutes.
hot towel?
Need immigration form?
Thank you.
--Towel, sir?
No..
Need immigration form?
--Thanks.
Welcome home, Mr. Cobb.
Welcome home.
Look who's here.
--Kids!
--Daddy!
Hello