Halt! Halt!
-Stop!
-What?
Stop! Stop!
You're going the wrong way.
We have to get to Berlin.
Brody's this way.
My diary's in Berlin.
We don't
need the diary, Dad.
Marcus has the map.
There is more in the diary
than just the map.
All right, Dad. Tell me.
Well, he who finds the Grail
must face the final challenge.
What final challenge?
Three devices
of such lethal cunning.
Booby traps?
Oh, yes.
But I found the clues that
will safely take us through,
in the Chronicles
of St. Anselm.
Well, what are they?
Can't you remember?
I wrote them down in my diary
so that I wouldn't have
to remember.
Half the German army's
on our tail,
and you want me to go
to Berlin?
Into the lion's den?
Yes.
The only thing that matters
is the Grail.
What about Marcus?
Marcus would agree with me.
Two selfless martyrs.
Jesus Christ.
That's for blasphemy.
The quest for the Grail
is not archaeology.
It's a race against evil.
If it is captured by the Nazis,
the armies of darkness
will march all over
the face of the Earth.
Do you understand me?
This is an obsession, Dad.
I never understood it.
Never.
Neither did Mom.
Oh, yes, she did.
Only too well.
Unfortunately, she kept
her illness from me
until all I could do
was mourn her.
My boy, we are pilgrims
in an unholy land.
Fraulein Doctor.
Where is it?
How did you get here?
I want it.
You came back for the book? Why?
My father didn't want
it incinerated.
Is that
what you think of me?
I believe in the Grail,
not the swastika.
But you stood up to be counted
with the enemy of everything
that the Grail stands for.
Who gives a damn what you think?
You do.
All I have to
do is squeeze.
All I have to do is scream.
I've got it.
Let's get the hell out of here.
What did you get?
I don't know.
First available flight
out of Germany.
Good.
Well, we made it.
When we're airborne,
with Germany behind us,
then I'll share
that sentiment.
Relax.
Tickets, please.
Guten Tag...
Herr Jones.
Tickets, please.
Oh, we should
get out of here.
No ticket.
Ticket.
-Ticket!
-Ticket! -Ticket!
You know,
sharing your adventures is
an interesting experience.
That's not all we shared.
It's disgraceful.
You're old enough
to be her fa...
her-her grandfather.
Well, I'm as human
as the next man.
I was the next man.
Oh.
Of course. Well...
Ships that pass
in the night.
Do you remember the last time
we had a quiet drink, hmm?
I had a milkshake.
Hmm?
What did we
talk about?
We didn't talk.
We never talked.
Do I detect
a rebuke?
A regret.
It was just the two of us, Dad.
It was a lonely way to grow up.
For you, too.
If you'd been an ordinary,
average father,
like the other guys' dads,
you'd have understood that.
Actually, I was
a wonderful father.
When?
Did I ever tell
you to eat up?
Go to bed?
Wash your ears?
Do your homework? No.
I respected
your privacy,
and I taught
you self-reliance.
What you taught me was
that I was
less important to you
than people
who'd been dead
for 500 years
in another country.
And I learned it so well
that we've hardly spoken
for 20 years.
You left just when you
were becoming interesting.
Unbelievable.
Dad, how can you...?
Very well.
I'm here now.
What do you want
to talk about?
Hmm?
Well, I...
Uh...
I can't think of anything.
Then what are
you complaining about?
Look, we have work to do.
When we get to
Alexandretta,
we will face
three challenges.
The first,
''The Breath of God.
Only the penitent
man will pass.''
Second,
''The Word of God.
Only in the footsteps
of God will he proceed.''
Third,
''The Path of God.
''Only in the leap
from the lion's head
will he prove his worth.''
What does that mean?
I don't know.
We'll find out.
We're turning around.
They're taking us back
to Germany.
Well, I thought
it would take them a lot longer
to figure out
the radio was dead.
Come on, Dad. Move!
Come on, Dad. Come on!
I didn't know you
could fly a plane.
Fly, yes.
Land, no.
Dad, you're going to have
to use the machine gun.
Get it ready.
Eleven o'clock!
Dad, eleven o'clock!
What happens at eleven o'clock?
Twelve, eleven, ten.
Eleven o'clock, fire!
Dad, are we hit?!
More or less.
Son, I'm sorry.
They got us.
Hang on, Dad.
We're going in!
Nice landing.
Thanks.
Those people are
trying to kill us!
I know, Dad!
Well.
It's a new
experience for me.
It happens to me all the time.
This is intolerable!
This could be close.
Faster, boy! Faster!
Well, they don't come
any closer than that!
Dad, he's coming back!
I suddenly
remembered my Charlemagne.
''Let my armies be the rocks
and the trees
and the birds in the sky.''
These pages are taken
from Professor Jones'
diary, Your Highness,
and they include a map
that pinpoints the exact
location of the Grail.
As you can see, the Grail
is all but in our hands.
However, Your Highness,
we would not think
of crossing your soil
without your permission,
nor of removing the
Grail from your borders
without suitable
compensation.
What have you brought?
Precious valuables,
Your Highness,
donated by some
of the finest families
in all of Germany.
Ah!
Rolls-Royce
Phantom Two.
Four-point-three liter,
30 horsepower,
six-cylinder engine,
with Stromberg
downdraft carburetor.
Can go from zero to
100 kilometers an hour
in 12.5 seconds.
And I even
like the color.
The keys are in the ignition,
Your Highness.
You shall have
camels, horses,
an armed escort, provisions,
desert vehicles
and tanks.
You're welcome.
We have no time to lose.
Indiana Jones
and his father have escaped.
We go this way.
Get that camel
out of the way.
What happened
to Marcus, Sallah?
Ah, they set out across
the desert this afternoon.
I believe they took
Mr. Brody with them.
Now they have the map.
And in this sort of race,
there's no silver medal
for finishing second.
Care to wet your
whistle, Marcus?
I'd rather spit
in your face.
But as I haven't
got any spit...
Must be within
three or four miles.
Otherwise we are
off the map.
Well, Marcus,
we are on the brink
of the recovery
of the greatest artifact
in the history
of mankind.
You're meddling with powers
you cannot
possibly comprehend.
Ah, I see Brody.
He seems okay.
They've got a tank.
Six-pound gun.
What do you think
you're doing there?
Get down!
Dad, we're well out of range.
That car belonged
to my brother-in-law.
Come on, come on!
I can't see anyone up there.
Maybe it wasn't
even Jones.
No, it is him,
all right.
He's here somewhere.
Put Brody in the tank.
Well, in this sun,
without transportation,
they're as good as dead.
It's Jones, all right.
Now, who are
all these people?
Who cares?
As long as they're
keeping Donovan busy.
Dad, you stay here
while Sallah and I
organize some transportation.
I'm going after those horses.
I'll take the camels.
I don't need camels.
But, Indy...
No camels.
Who is he?
A messenger from God.
For the unrighteous,
the Cup of Life
holds everlasting damnation.
Marcus!
Oh.
''Genius of the Restoration...''
''Aid our own resuscitation.''
Henry, what are you
doing here?
It's a rescue, old boy.
Come on.
Search him.
What is in this book?
That miserable
little diary of yours.
We have the map.
The book is useless.
And yet you come all the way
back to Berlin to get it.
Why?
What are you hiding?
What does the diary
tell you
that it doesn't
tell us?
It tells me that goose-stepping
morons like yourself
should try reading books
instead of burning them.
Colonel!
Jones is getting away.
I think not,
Herr Donovan.
Not that Jones,
the other Jones!
Sallah, I said no camels!
That's five camels.
Can't you count?
Compensation for
my brother-in-law's car.
Indy, your father
and Brody...
Where's my father?
They have them.
In the belly
of that steel beast.
Hyah!
Hyah, hyah, hyah!
Hey-ah, hey-ah, hey-ah!
Fire!
Dad! Dad!
Dad!
Junior?
Junior?!
Junior!
Dad!
Dad! Get out!
Henry, the pen...
-What?
-But don't you see?
The pen is mightier
than the sword.
Look what you did.
It's war.
Didn't I tell you
it was a rescue, huh?
Dad!
Yeah?
You call this archaeology?
Get out of there, Dad.
How does one
get off this thing?
Where's Marcus?
Dad!
Hang on, Dad!
Father of Indy,
give me your hand!
Sallah!
Get Dad!
Give me your hand!
Junior!
Indy!
Oh, God.
I've lost him.
And I never told him anything.
I just wasn't ready, Marcus.
Five minutes
would have been enough.
I thought
I'd lost you, boy!
you had too, sir.
Mmm...
Well...
Well done. Come on.
Let's go, then.
Why are you
sitting there resting
when we're so near the end?!
Come on, let's go!
The Canyon
of the Crescent Moon.
Helmut, another volunteer!
I never expected
to see you again.
I'm like a bad penny;
I always turn up.
Step back now,
Dr. Schneider.
Give Dr. Jones some room.
He's going to recover
the Grail for us.
Impossible?
What do you say, Jones?
Ready to go down in history?
As what?
A Nazi stooge like you?
The Nazis?!
Is that the limit
of your vision?
The Nazis want
to write themselves
into the Grail legend...
take on the world.
Well, they're welcome.
But I want
the Grail itself.
The cup that gives
everlasting life.
Hitler can have
the world,
but he can't
take it with him.
I'm going to be
drinking my own health
when he's gone the way
of the dodo.
The Grail is mine...
and you're going
to get it for me.
Shooting me
won't get you anywhere.
You know something,
Dr. Jones?
You're absolutely right.
Dad?
Dad?!
Junior...
-No!
-Get back!
You can't save him
when you're dead!
The healing power
of the Grail
is the only thing
that can save your father now.
It's time to ask yourself
what you believe.
''The Breath of God...
...only the penitent man
will pass.''
''The penitent man will pass.
The penitent man will pass.
The penitent man...
''Only the penitent man
will pass.''
''Only the penitent
man will pass.''
The penitent man will pass.
The penitent, penitent...
The penitent man...
The penitent...
The penitent man
is humble before God.
Penitent. Penitent...
The penitent man...
Penitent man
is humble...
...kneels before God.
Kneel!
I'm through!
We're through.
He's all right.
No.
The second challenge:
''The Word of God.''
''Only in the footsteps
of God will he proceed.''
The Word of God...
The Word of...
Proceed in the footsteps
of the Word.
''The Word of God...''
No, Henry.
Try not to talk.
The name of God...
Jehovah.
But in the Latin alphabet,
Jehovah begins with an ''I.''
J...
Oh, dear.
Idiot!
In Latin, Jehovah
starts with an ''I.''
''I''...
''E''...
''H''...
''O''...
Oh!
''V''...
''A''...
''The Path of God.''
''Only in the leap
from the lion's head
will he prove his worth.''
lmpossible...
nobody can jump this.
Indy!
Indy, you must hurry!
Come quickly!
It's a leap of faith.
Oh, geez...
You must believe, boy.
You must... believe.
Oh.
I knew you'd come,
but my strength has left me.
Who are you?
The last of three brothers
who swore an oath
to find the Grail
and to guard it.
That was 700 years ago.
A long time to wait.
You're strangely dressed...
for a knight.
I'm not exactly...
a knight.
What do you mean?
I was chosen
because I was the bravest,
the most worthy.
The honor was mine
until another came
to challenge me
to single combat.
I pass it...
to you who vanquished me.
Listen, I don't have
time to explain, but...
Which one is it?
You must choose,
but choose wisely.
For as the true Grail
will bring you life,
the false Grail
will take it from you.
I'm not a historian.
I have no idea
what it looks like.
Which one is it?
Let me choose.
Thank you, Doctor.
Oh, yes.
It's more beautiful
than I'd ever imagined.
This certainly is the cup
of the King of Kings.
Eternal life.
What is happening to me?
Oh!
Tell me, what is happening?
He chose...
poorly.
It would not be made
out of gold.
That's the cup
of a carpenter.
There's only one way
to find out.
You have chosen wisely.
But the Grail cannot pass
beyond the Great Seal.
That is the boundary
and the price of immortality.
Drop your guns. Please.
Dad, come on,
get to your feet.
We have got it. Come on!
Elsa! Elsa, don't move!
It's ours, Indy--
yours and mine.
Elsa, don't cross the Seal.
The knight warned us
not to take
the Grail from here.
Junior!
Elsa...
Elsa, don't. Elsa...
Give me your other hand, honey.
I can't hold you!
I can reach it.
Elsa, give me your hand.
Give me your other hand!
Elsa!
Junior, give me
your other hand!
I can't hold on.
I can get it.
I can almost reach it, Dad.
Indiana...
Let it go.
Dad...
Please, Dad.
Elsa never really
believed in the Grail.
She thought she'd
found a prize.
What did you find, Dad?
Me?
Illumination.
And what did you find, Junior?
''Junior''? Dad...
Please, what does
it always mean,
this... this ''Junior''?
That's his name:
Henry Jones, Junior.
I like Indiana.
We named the dog Indiana.
May we go home now,
please?
The dog?
You are named after the dog?
I've got a lot of fond memories
of that dog.
Ready?
Ready.
Indy! Henry! Follow me.
I know the way! Ha!
Got lost
in his own museum, huh?
Uh-huh.
After you, Junior.
Yes, sir. Ha!