Hey... Hey... Hey... Hey...
Hey... Hey... Hey...
l need to reverse my car
Where are you going
lrrr.... lrrr friend?...
you park the car like this?
What do you said?
Hey... l'm going to kill you.
Stop the car
No
What happen?... are
you getting in or out
Get in
What are you doing?
What are you doing in air?
You are trying to get in...
...are you trying to steal the radio?
Help me!
Please... Listen to me
Why are you asking for help...?
are we trying to rape you?
are you going to shout for the police?
Do you know? Who am l...
We don't know... Who are you?
G.S Gay today...
Deputy Chief Engineer...
Maha Nagar Palika
What is this municipality?
your status can't allow
you to argue for a radio
Hey... Hey... What is
this...? Who are you people?
What do you need?
What...? ....can l seal your shop?
... l'm going to cancel
you driving license.
There is only one bullet in it...
l'll pull the trigger as many times
you ask the questions... Now Talk...
But... Where are you taking me?
l'm enjoying? ask me...?
Where to go Bhai (Brother)...?
Why you ask the
question...? Are you mad...?
Ask...? Understand...?
Alam... move towards
the Lucky Singh's office
This... This is correct.
Hey... Photo studio...
Write it down that Mr. Lucky
Singh President Mumbai Builder...
...association in serious talking
with George. Bush President of America.
You never visit America... Sir.
do one thing... replace white
house with our farm house
Your mother can't taught
you any common sense:::
Sir... Circuit's here...
Circuit... My Dear...
Some times people face
the betrayal in this world
you're not attending
my calls now these days
Right now he's going to pick up
Circuit! we're rocking
Get a side... Koko
Look... l'm unable
to give you any favour
Why...
you got the permission
of 8 story building....
last time and you build
a 1 1 story building...
lt has been completed by the time and
my counting is very poor since childhood
l'm going to lose my job
Leave this 10,000 job
- Do you hear about Parana Builders
-Yes
My daughter engaged over there
- Koko show him that map
- Yes
They purchased the Property that...
...is behind the Varsua Pump House
But only this yellow
house is not for sale
l Said, l'm going to buy it
Just count it as a wedding gift
This Bungalow is on liaison
for 99 years
- Next month lt's expires
- lt's going to renewed
Don't send the renewal paper's
Default it
No... No.... lt can't be done...
lt's a question of reputation
l already committed it
l need this bungalow
Now it's over you
You choose the difference
between this valet and bullet
Ask for the price?
Ten
Ten... Just ten... you take twenty
Koko give him twenty thousand
New notes... Happy...
No... No... One million...
30 thousand
Nine hundred thousand
Thirty one
l m leaving
Leaving
l'm kidnapped you
Pistol is in my hand and that one
is sitting brake few bones in a day
Brake it... Brake it...
You must've some fear
Look Lucky Bhai.... Midway...
- Five hundred thousand
- That's right
Now your's not mine....
midway... 2,50,000
The deal is done
- Offer him sweets
- Yes
With best complements
Circuit.... Give Munna good news
A bungalow evacuation
order... Where is he...
Bhai (Brother) can't work
till 9:00am to 12:00pm
is he rise late...
He can't sleep now these days
He is low... Low...
On the river bank all the day
lt's very cheap... flags
are empty... use it...
lt's not like that... He's
listening radio over there
Radio... What's special on radio
Our Madam is on the radio
Good Morning Mumbai
This is Janvi on worried famous radio
My today's message before leaving
For all of them are running in the city
What to do in the race of the city
lf that's the life then what is death
The reason being late for
the train in first rain
knowing everything about
the serial characters...
but don't have time to
care about your mother...
Now... Can't walk on the beach sand...
...108 channels are on without enjoyment
Connected to the Global
village with internet...
but can't know who's in our neighbors...
Life's full with Mobile and
Land line but don't have...
...that line that connects
you with your best friend
Remember last time
when you see the sunset
and remember when the evening is over
So Friends... why you
wants to run in the race
Wow... Janvi
lf this is life then what is death
So Good bye Mumbai now it's time to go
Bye bye Janvi
See you soon tomorrow
100% right here right now
Friends till then don't
worry be happy sayonara
Remember this tomorrow is 2nd October...
...and we're having the Mahatma Quiz
Who ever wins be my special guest
Yes, l'm going to invite him
for an interview in my studio.
So bye bye and don't forget
to tune in tomorrow at 9:00
- Bhai
- Circuit
What happened on 2nd October
lt's dry day
Do l purchase the stock
Dry day why?
lt's holiday
l'll find out don't take any tension
Birthday Bhai
2nd October is the
happy birthday of Bapu
Who's Bapu
Bapu Means Mahatma Gandhi
The Person on the bill...
correct he is the one...
What else do you know about him
He don't have any muscular body but he
was very daring l only know that much
- Bhai he over ruled English men
- What
Everybody escapes do to his fear...
He gives us freedom
ls he in army?
Bhai, l can't see his
Photograph in uniform
And his close-up is on the note
Look... A quiz on Bapu
is on radio tomorrow
l can meet Janvi lf l win
Madam... Bhai, it should be done
Circuit... What shirt l'll wear
Bhai, don't take any
kind of wearing tension
Nobody can see your shirt on radio
Correct
Concentrate on you voice Bhai
You voice should be prominent
Are you going to impress her?
Concentrate Bhai and l'll
going to take care of everything
Janvi Ji, l'm Murli Persad Sharma
l'm fine and how's about you
Don't be afraid it's very simple
On radio she's going to ask
the question's about Bapu
You answer them
Right...
Collect the prizes for the right answers
Look... that's not fair
l' m late for the college
Professor... these people
go to your home to...
...say hello to you wife
if you go to the college
- We can take what we want
- Yes, Answer perfectly
and take what ever...
you want, that mixer,
that gasket, that stove
Janvi Ji, Your voice make me mad
Bhai, they really think that we are...
... vagrants if you use
this king of language
Do as they professor do
Hey... Take out the Phone
make it on redial
As she ask question push the button
Nobody can able to call her
Tersu... what're you doing Come here
Marriage... Not till yet
Truth is that l'm interested in no one
Bhai, Come on
Alam, rise the volume
Till that time l ask the question
from each caller till he'll wrong
And anybody who'll answers the 10
question correctly will be our winner
Everybody is ready on his
phone and our number is 22666888
My first question
Gandhi called by which name
in south Africa by his fellows?
- lt's on Bhai
- Give it to me
First call has been received
before the question ends
- Hello
The network is busy
write now please try later
- Hello... Hello
- Yours.....
- Hello...
- This one Bhai...
Why showing it give it to me
- Hello
Who's this?
l'm... l'm Murli Parsad Sharma
So Murli what's the right answer?
- Bhai?
- yes
- Bhai... Bhai
- Yes speak
- Bhai... Bhai...
- l'll give a slap
Gandhi's fellows honored him by
the name of Bhai in South Africa
Murli you do have only 10 seconds
- Are you sure
- Think before answer
- Yes
- Either these Bhai's can't leave you
100 percent sure
- Hello
ln South Africa Gandhi Ji....
- ...Honored
-...Honored ... Honored by the name of Bhai
Well that's the right
answer, congratulations!
Now l'm going to ask you the question
till that time your answer is wrong
No chance Janvi ji
2nd Question, How many offspring's
Gandhi Ji have and their names?
- Rajeev Gandhi and lndraa Gandhi.
- Wow
Eldest Son name was Hari Lal
Hari Lal, Mani Lal, Ram Das, Devdas
Bhai... Bhai... Bhai l need the cooker.
- Hari Lal, Mani Lal
- Ram Das
- Devdas
- And Devdas
Wow! that's absolutely right.
Thank you... Thank you
Now third question
What was the difference among
the weapons of Gandhi and Hitler?
- lron
- lron, are you sure?
Justice and peace
Give me the lron
Well done Murli
What was the age of
Gandhi when he got married?
- 13 years
Thirteen years
Hey Keep this Madam
Kastoor was also thirteen
Bhai (Brother), Bhabhi
(Madam) was 13 years old
When they got married
See the tragedy of life
Why? Bhai, still a bachelor
What kind of noise is this?
They're my family members
They are little bit angry...
They said that you'll get marry because
Bhai was being married at thirteen
All that's on is wrong
- Quite you
- l'm going to call police
l'll can't let this happen
- Go
- l'll can't let this happen
- What's your name notebook?
- Office Ranta Shawati Kurti.
Look Woti Kuti, Help
each other in the life
...You've all the
information regarding Bapu
and we don't have it,
that's why l need it...
Right or not?
lf you need the information
of Shakeel Haira, Dagro...
...Dada, Afzal Tonda then
ask us we'll not refuse you
...Swear
Why are you hiding the knowledge?
... instead of spreading it
That's wrong and l'm
not let you to do that
l'm going to call the police
- Your cloth's are wet...
- That's wrong
- Forget it
Dry clean, Keep him dry... ...Bhai wins
This year our first caller Murli
Parsad Sharma win this contest
Janvi Ji, l'm the biggest
fan of Bapu (Gandhi)
Then Mulri whish you best of
luck for tomorrow at studio
l'm dying to meet you
Me too.
- Good bye Mr. Sharma
- Good Bye Janvi
Bhai wins
Bhai, How she looks like?
But how can he's able to see her
- lf she's tall or short
- Heavy or slim in size
Bhai you're taking the risk
you're going to mad
Hey lnquiry where is
Bhabi Ji (Brother's wife)
- Bhabi Ji (Brother's wife)
- Janvi Ji
My self Murli Parsad
Sharma contest winner
He stands first... First...
She is waiting for you over there
Good morning
Hello
l can't here your voice
Who's speaking
l'm Murli Pardas Sharma
Can't here you from
where are you talking
l'm talking from outside
l'm Jainpur
So Ok! what song you
would like to listen
To see a boy then
Alright my friend from
Jainpur your song is...
...coming up right after
this commercial break
Circuit... Move from here
What happens Bhai?
l'm not willing to meet her
But why Bhai?
My first impression is very bad
l say hello... hello in the air
in front of that sound proof glass
l'm an idiot she's thinking that
Bhai don't speak Mamoon (ldiot),
today's you said Bapu (Gandhi)
Tinchu Lequage, Go from here... Go...
Go outside, do anything you want to do
An emergency meeting is on... Go...
- l'm failed
- What happened Bhai?
lsn't she good looking?
No... She's pretty
Artistic eyes
What do you say that
hair fall on your cheek?
- Shandy (Hair)
- No
- Curl... curl... curl...
- curl...
That one curl moving on her cheek
Pat her cheek with love
Then... then... then... then...
Then she arrange her curl
with her finger behind her ear
l lost my heart
You're a jam Bhai
lf you hit somebody then
he's also loose his heart
Don't take any kind of tension
Full confidence
Talk with politeness
and with full confidence
Who's he?
ln means polite in Hindi
Professor Tell me that.
He said that, Bapu (Gandhi) do
so many works with politeness
Can you stop for a while
But
l'm requesting you with
full politeness that...
...wait for a while why
are you spoiling our meeting
We also do politeness
l know that with politeness
work has been done
- Carry On
- Use your words precisely
Like this our country is ruined
You can say that our
country is insolvent
Bhai use some profound words
Like, revolutionize
self-esteem
- Like this
- More words
And talk less regarding Bapu (Gandhi)
We don't know sufficient about Bapu
we'll be ruined
We'll be embarrassed
- So regarding Bapu
- Your's...
Who are you?
Are you Murli Parsad Sharma?
l'm Polite
Then who is Murli Parsad Sharma?
l'm
Then who is polite?
- What do you want?... Because Janvi
Madam is looking for Murli Parsaad Sharma
Then Get a side...
What are you talking?
- Hey... Turn on the radio
- Come outside
Good morning Mumbai
Welcome back to you
favorite show today...
we're with Mulri Parsad
Sharma in our studio...
How can you know that
much about Gandhi Ji?
You can say that, l'm
a very big fan of Bapu
What kind of man he is, alone
he get rid over english men
Means he ruined them
Not ruin... insolvent... insolvent
What a man!
- What sir?
- ls this our Munna?
- Yes
- Rise the volume
What do you think that people
are forgetting them now a days?
Absolutely not...
Due to his honor we celebrate
Dry day on 2nd October
l can't drink if that's not a dry day
No jokes apart, are
you following his way?
Yes l do... every day
l walk three kilometers
on Mahatma Gandhi Road
l means to say that, are you
following his set of laws?
Total... l'm a true follower
You mean that you're a Gandhi devotee
Total and you?
Me, not really
But l like some of his rules
Like?
Like l never lie
Then we're thinking on the same lines
We'll meet regularly
You never lie?
Once in 1992
A kid lost his 50 paisa and he is crying
l gave him mine 50 paisa
and said that's your
Mark my words he's
heading towards politics
What do you do?
l'm a professor
Professor
l'm teaching history
l mean your language?
What can l do the language
of the country is ruin...
.... means insolvent
Nobody can understand the real Hindi
He can say that every thing is changed
lt seems that one could
bare a heart attack
You means that intentionally
you use that kind of...
...language which is easily
understandable by the students
Correct
That's every one stood
first in his class
No one stood 2nd
Well from today l'm also
following the same style, what...
...kind of song you would like
to dedicate to your students?
Any kind of rocking song.
Fantastic Show really professor!
Hope, my kids listen that
- Your children
- Yes l have six children
Bhai... Bhai... we got to go
l'm Sarkeshwar
l'm a student
Alright! Pull-up the chair, be seated
Sit down... Sit down
Meet My Children
are they cute?
- Look... Look
- They are really cute
They are expert like
you in Gandhi devotee
- Who're these people?
- My grandpa's college friends?
They've difference among their
families so grandpa invite them at home
They live at your place?
2nd innings home named by grandpa
He Said that, this is the last over of
the life so play it on the front foot
Correct!
Your grandpa is great!
l wants to meet him?
Actually can you give him
a lecture on Gandhi Ji?
- Lecture on Gandhi Ji
- Yes they love it
- How about Friday?
- Day for the college
- Then Saturday...? -
Yes - There's a tension
Sunday is done.
That's great
So l'll see on Sunday
l've to rush now my 7th
child is coming today
- Ok bye! See you! see you then!
- Thank you... Thank you
Dad! l hope you understand
lf you stay alone that is
better for you and Bindu
Don't worry about myself
All of them are my friends
We'll enjoy together
You'll take care of your wife
you spend your life with her
How much l'll live?
Then what? can l come in?
No... No... l can do it by myself
Dad... Dad... l getting very late ok.
Son lf you get some
time then remember me
l brought up four children
in single room house
And now they don't have a single room
in there four houses for there father
You spend two hours for telling this
What's new in it?
lt a same story of every home
How is he crying?
Like a girl
The water problem of the country will...
...solve if all the aged
are going to cry like you
Give him the corner room
he is going to disturb us
l'm serious...
...and you think that l'm kidding
The serious talks are
restricted in 2nd innings house
- 2nd innings house
- Look Atma Ram
We played our 1st innings
in search of food and shelter
Now in our 2nd innings die trying...
... or find a way for life
l'll travel by an aero plane just once
l'll pay a visit to Lahore
before passing away...
l'll like to see my home and my streets
l want to be a singer
l wish to see my photograph on a
cassette cover before passing away
l wish to marry again
before l'm passing away
Marry... are you able
to bat in this age?
l practiced Atma Ram
Grandpa, l arrange a professor
for your friends on Sunday
Very good... very good
He'll deliver you a lecture on Gandhi Ji
You all need it.
Bhai, don't get tense
Professor's will make the
key and putting it in...
...your pocket and pasting in you
leg and drop it in you underwear
Put it in my underwear?
They ask questions and
l put my hand in my...
...underwear and take out
the key and answer them
You're talking nonsense.
Ajeet why are putting you hand
in you underwear frequently
We use the phone
They ask the question
and you said l'll be back
Call us from the washroom
- Professor's will answer the questions
- How many times l go to the washroom?
That is not operated by the phone
Bhai then there is only one way
And there is no other way
The other radio station...
over there is an item Anphwa Choppra...
You meet her
She talk about the
Shahrukhan all day long
Granted her children are
the fan of Dalip Kumar
You can take care of them
Stop this nonsense.
Let me think
Bhai we don't have any other way
We only have five day study
as much you can about Bapu
Ok! l'm leaving
Ok! Bhai...
What are you doing Bhai?
Concentrate on you studies
Bhai, l'll take care of business
- Don't take tension
- Come here
Bhai! you can go.
Hello!
Anybody around
Namshkar (hello)... l'm Harri Ram
May l help you?
Can l'm able to find
some information on Bapu?
What happens
After so many years some
one come here l' m very happy
You can find every book written
on Gandhi Ji, feel free for reading
l send tea for you
All the old books are over here
Munna
Who is it? Mohan Das Karamchand Gandhi
Look Uncle l'm up from three nights
- Don't waste my mind
- The what else do you do?
Unique just because of your age
Let me study either...
Moreover, you beat me up?
lf you slap me on my right cheek
then present my left cheek, professor.
Who tell you about that professor thing?
-Tea
- Serve it to the fancy dress
and ask him to be quite...
- To whom?
- That duplicate of Bapu
Where?
There you can't see him
Everyone crazy come over here
Who are you?
You can call me Bapu
Don't touch me
Don't be afraid, l never
harm anybody till that day
Boss, here is some problem
Are you not a soul?
You can call me spirit instead of Soul
- l'm unable to understand Baap (Father)
- Not Baap (Father), lt's Bapu (Gandhi)
You love to much with Janvi
You'll going to her home on Sunday
How can you know?
- Hari Ram
- Don't be afraid Son
- l come to help you
- Hari Ram
l'll leave because you're afraid
Whenever you need me call me
from the depth of your heart
- l'll come
- Hari Ram
What happens?
There some one over there
Who's it?
lllusion, what is this?
May times you hear voices due to the...
...mental tiredness and
the chemical imbalance
See that kind of things that's
not real... that's illumination
Mahatma Gandhi was there
l saw him over there
He's the soul of Bapu
lf there's a sprit then why
only you're able to see him
lt depends upon the mood of the sprit
From past three nights
you are researching...
...on Gandhi without
having rest and food
That's why a restless
mind show you Gandhi Ji.
What do you mean to say? that l'm Mad...
Don't worry, take this medicine
- Just a minute... Look...
Bapu said that lf l call
him from heart... he show up
l'll try
How're you Murli Parsad
Don't touch me Don't touch me
Don't be afraid son l hear to help you
Look... look over there Bapu
Now what do you think l'm mad
Nobody is over there Mr. Sharma
l see him clearly
lt's in your mind
Circuit, do you see him?
Hello Bapu... Last time
you showed up amazingly
He's scared
He's brave and he reorder so many guys
Circuit, He's over here
l'm offering him water
Bapu, would you like to have
cold rink, tea or anything?
What is this?
Don't reinforces hallucination
l'm going to slap you
Bhai Says it there it means that over...
...there, now l show
you the stars in day time
Not really but they are
you can say that Hallucination
Come here... Come here...
Bhai you may sit with Bapu
l'll take care of him
You mental hospital
What're you saying?
l know that there is no Bapu
and why are you spoiling his mind
are you making him mad?
Give me the medicine
l'll give him the doze
- Circuit...
- Bhai...
Why Bapu only shows in front you and me?
Because of you will power
he came out from the book
Just like Aladdin's lamp
l went also along with you
lt's Gandhi... that's
why he says hello to us
Don't take any kind of tension
He spent two or there
days over here and after...
...seeing the state of
our country he returns back
Don't take any tension
Why to spoil while thinking?
He said, he's going to help us
May l directed him towards
the Lucky's job of that house
Take the medicine
Murli Parsad... What favour
can Mohan Das do for you
Bapu...
- Like that Bapu
- Where's the bottle
l need your help...
l can't kill and kidnap any one
l'm weak in these kind ofjobs
No Bapu... l can do that...
Tomorrow you accompany
me at Janvi's place...
Just like that...
invisible
Like Mr. lndia
They ask about your self
you'll answer me in my ear
My history is weak
l do that favour for then
you must do a favour for me
l'll do 10 favors for you
But do this favour for me
Listen my job
Bapu promise... what ever
you said l'll do it...
l'm giving you oath
My job is not easy
Bapu, Nothing is
impossible in Mumbai for me
You work has to be done
Ok! l've to go...
l'll be there...
Circuit... No more worries
Now Grandpa ask what ever he wants
to because the history is with me
Thank you... Thank you...
l've a question Professor Saab (Mr.)
Just a minute, just a minute...
before any question we recall Bapu
Bapu... Thank you... thank you...
Take care of myself
lt's done... lt's done
Now leave it... leave it
Ask any question...
Son yesterday a youngster
through a stone in front of me...
....on the sculpture of
Bapu and break his hand...
... and he's laughing
l can't understand how can l teach him?
lt's simple...
....go to his home
and take him from there
and stand him in front
of Bapu's sculpture
And...
And give him a stone and ask
him to brake my whole sculpture
What're you saying Bapu?
Say what l said...
Are you sure?
Give him a stone and ask him
to brake his whole sculpture
Lay down every sculpture
of mine in this country
lay down all the sculpture
of Bapu in the country
Take off my all picture from the walls
Take off all the pictures
of Bapu from the walls
Remove my name from every building,
every roundabout, every road
Remove his name from every
building, every note, every road
l you want to keep me then
keep me in your hearts...
lf you want to keep him
then keep him in your hearts
Understand...
Over here... ln you heart...
He do so many things for us...
He's go to Jail, do fastening and
visit the whole country in one cloth
He do a lot for us
and what we do for him
put his portrait on the wall
and beneath it we take bribe easily
He think we made our country stronger...
just like developing countries
and we ruined this country
Son, that's not so bad
Country is developing now these days
What kind of development?
Tap without water
electric bulbs without electricity
Roads with less
vehicles and more gullies
You can't walk on the
footpath because of the shops
Names are on the
waiting list of the train
Train will be cancel
if the ticket is confirm
Hospitals are without beds
lf the bed is available
then there is no one for care
Nobody going to solve your complaints
Ask the minister and
he recommends Bapu....
and Bapu is busy in meeting
Call him at home and
he is in the bathroom
When he'll meet you he
ask for an application...
that will be in duplicate form
and then that application
will in the process
Round and round.... Round and round...
lf Bapu is present today...
then he said that, country is ours...
but the people are departed
Thank you... Thank you.... Thank you...
Thank you... Thank you....
Hey Professor?
are you in love with her
What? l can see it in you eyes...
How can that possible?
Don't lie
You don't have control on your eyes
Eyes see towards her side and
your head faces on the other
l've problem with my eyes
are you afraid to tell her?
Right...
Me too...
- What?
Look this...
This is Tina...
She is my college fellow
l'm willing to marry her
My Papa Says, lf you marry with a...
...Non-Parse then
l'll Kick out from home
Then l married with Ferozah
l meet Tina after 50 years
Her husband and Ferozah are no more
Then marry her
Children says, Dad don't embarrass us
Listen to your father
first then children
l do have my so l left
my home and come here
Then what's the tension
How can l say her that l love you
- l don't understand
- lsn't she says you that she loves you?
l think so
Look it... lt's 50 year's old
That's the same car
Yes, lt's raining like
dogs and cats that day
lt's to dark and on the back
seat of that car l kissed Tina
- She ran off
- You...
Ask for the keys if you ever need it
lsn't this a lovely car Murly
Ask why we name it kissing car?
lf you want to go for a drive then go
Any song might be the
reason to call Bapu
- Look over there
- you sing love songs over here
And Janvi fallen in
love with some one else
To whom Bapu
- There's a professor
- Who's he Bapu?
- Some professor
- Tell me the name? l'm going to hit him
Professor Murli Parsad Sharma
What Bapu? are you kidding with me
That true my son she's fallen in
love with that professor not you
Tell her the truth tomorrow, she'll
leaves you one day if you'll lie
lf l tell her the truth
then she'll leave me tomorrow
You promise me that
you do a favour for me
What kind ofjob is this?
tell me some otherjob
That's my job, walk on the line of truth
Circuit! Show him the way of his home
Bapu... Hey Bapu...
Lets go Bapu... Lets go
lt's not right to walk
alone in Mumbai... Let go
- Circuit
- Where're you looking at?...
- Bapu is over here
- Son, speak truth
and live with honor
Bapu, why are you
wandering here and their
if we miss the last local
train then we go by taxi
Circuit... you are drunk
Take his hand and go
l can't see him then how
can l'm able see his hand
l find Bapu... Let's go
Bapu, wandering at late
night must effect your health
and make dark circle beneath you eyes
Sit down... Ok... bye bye....
Drop him...
- Whom l'll drop
- l don't know
The path you choose brings
trouble for you one day
That day call me l'll come
- Hello
- Yes Janvi
- Hey Murli, where are you?
- ln college
- yes
- l'm taking class
- Guess what
l'm in your college
- But why?
- To meet with principal
- Why?
- First meet me then l'll let you know
Look, l'm coming don't
meet with principal
Why?
Look... wait for me in the
canteen l'll be there in 10 minutes
Ok... Please
Ok... Relax... l'm waiting you over here
Circuit... lt emergency... Move
- Hello Janvi
- Hi Murli
Look don't trust on this principal
he's very talkative, sometimes
he's going to unbearable
- ln my class, he asked who are you?
- Relax
- Why are you so exited?
- Excuse me
Just a minute l'm busy
unmannered... you come to
college once in three months
And you sit in the canteen all the day
- Go... - Who's he? - Go
in... - He... He's a professor
- Who's he
- Must be his father
But why you meet with principal
Tomorrow is the birthday Atama Ram
Ji and l through a surprise party
Atma Ram... dropped by
his son in front of home
Humm... Hari
Hey barber shop... Go...
He miss him a lot
Continuously he dial his
phone and he don't respond
and don't call him back
- Good morning Sir
- Good morning... Good morning
- Bye bye sir...
- Bye bye... Bye bye
- Do you know that principal...
- Good morning professor
- Good morning...
- Good morning... Good morning
Wow... Professor your style of teaching
He's going to spoil the whole scene
l'm little bit busy Dobay Ji
You will be the principal... Principal
Do you see the principal?
ls he look like a principal
He's a fool, do you see his
wearing he's look like a laundryman
- We all are laundrymen in front of him
- Mr. Dobay
Madam Phatkehli is calling you
Thank you Bye....
- Who's she Madam Phatkay
- l'm going to slap you
25 paisa Chicken and 75 paisa powder
That much over acting move from here
- Good morning sir
- Good morning
- Do you know what to do?
- Yes Bhai
Hello
l talk with Harri, He said he can't come
Atma Ram ji is really low
l really wants to cheer him up
- Ask principal to call the police
- Police
Without any reason he can't leave me
But what's the principal
connection with this story
Principal and Atma
Ram ji are old friends
l'm going to invite him
l think that all the
friends enjoy together
That principal is a very depressing
person, he attempt suicide three times
Take less food instead of sleeping pills
Tino... l'm Shyam
Look towards you glasses
you're confused due to black shirt
Hey... Where is he...
Do you see him? Call the police...
Call the police... Call the police...
- Call the police...
- Look at him...
Student don't done his home
work and he's calling police
Right now he's over
here right now he ran off
- He's the principal
- Bhai Let's go
- Sir should we start the class
- Sir should we move
Now l've to go because
the 2nd class is on
Don't get tense, l'll bring a...
...surprise which
makes Atma Ram Ji happy
- Hey You
- l'm coming sir... coming
Hey Full moon will like to race
Let's Go... Come...
You get prepared for the
birthday you need smile...
...on Atma Ram's Ji face
its my problem now its done
hey Taxi...
Where is he...?
- l'm looking for Harri Desai
- Your name?
- l'm Murli Parsad Sharma
- What kind of work?
lt's private
He's in a meeting if you have
any message then give it to me
Tell him that the work has been done...
...that dead body is in the trunk
of the car behind the bungalow
l'm here for the payment
Where are the office?
don't take tension
Ok Fine, we'll meet in theater
on Sunday, remember 3 to 6
Make it 6 to 9
5'o clock is you father's birthday
You bring the cake and write
on it happy birthday Papa
Ok, See you on Sunday... bye...
You... How can you come in?
From the door, are you
coming from the window?
Ok leave this... what kind
of a gift you bring for him
Look, please don't interfere,
it's my family matter
- Ok
- Don't show your anger on birthday
How many birthdays of
your father celebrated...
...for you just come for half an
hour and say happy birthday to him
Smile will be on his face all day long
- Please Come with...
- Yes... Go.... Go...
Tank you very much... After
you... Good bye... Get out...
- What do you mean by get out?
- Out
You didn't want to understand that...
You want to fight me...
You want to fight me... C'mon...
You know l was used
to be a boxing champion
lf you're a boxing champion
then l'm a slapping champion
Little bit up... little bit left...
That's Uncle fault, if he slaps you
six and seven times your childhood...
... then today's not come.
Hello... Hello... Bindu
- What...?
- How are you honey?
- where are you?
- l'm outside from my office.
Do one thing... Order a birthday cake
and happy birthday Dad will write on it
... and beneath it write
Haari you beloved son
Darling... lsn't it necessary?
Honey try to understand he's my father
But darling
Just shut up do what l say organize...
...a birthday party
and buy an expensive...
...gift and send the
carpenter at my office l...
...need to fix some grills
into my balcony Urgent...
- Now take it off
- Happy birthday to you
Happy birthday to you
Happy birthday dear Atma Ram
Happy birthday to you...
You're the best dad ever
We forget you never
Happy birthday to you dearest dad
Happy birthday to you...
How can you do that?
l go to his office and
teach him with politeness
and he understand
He fought if l was not there
He's going to slap him and hang him
upside down from a 12 story building
- Then he can't come
- This is really unbelievable
- Thank you so much Murli
l've another surprise for you?
Can you accompany me
for an hour, tomorrow?
Where?
Bobby Uncle, can l have your car keys
Lucky l hear this, that in every
2 seconds a child is born in lndia
Might be then?
That means in each second
some one going to marry
Then?
Then in every half second a boy
tells his heart feeling to a girl
lt's up to 2 months and
l don't have guts to talk
What to talk?
- That
- l mean that...
- What that....
That... That l like you very much
Will you be my wife?
Do that work which suites you
...evacuate the bungalow, break the bones
and l'll talk to her father for your marriage
Her father died, she lived with
some six or seven aged peoples
Where she live?
We don't know where she lives
He don't take us over
their, he went alone
That's the address and that will
be the house which will be evacuated
Give it to me... Sir Ji if they don't
have the address then how come they find it
Like you born in this
worried without any address
Ask you mother you born
with a map in your hand
Munna you leave this
work, you need to relax
Do one thing, take her and move to Goa
Goa!
lt's a very romantic
place, Sea waves, on them...
...a motorboat and both
of you are in that boat
All alone...
Girls are very emotional
Take her far away to the sunset and
ask her marry me or leave the boat
lt's my boat, she's not
die alone in the water
Why she go alone with us?
No... No... No... Not alone
Take all the aged along with you
Koko my dear, arrange the Goa air
tickets and hotel l'll pay the dues
lf You consider me as friend
don't think go to Goa and...
...don't come back without
give her the engagement ring
l'll evacuate the house
Ok
- Done
- No and yours
l call her and she's out Saroon says
Why she's left with a smiling face
What you think it's a joke
What...? You're just bamboozle
You go to tell her a joke in the car
- Give me the keys
- lt's in the car
Careless bugger, you left the
keys in the car idiot... stupid...
Hurry up, pack your bags
we're leaving for Goa
- Goa... Goa... Goa...
- But why...?
A wedding ceremony
Wedding... Who's wedding?
You tell them l can't
All of you favour that or not?
No... No... but we want to
know who's wedding is this
- Listen... Listen...
- No... No...
Who's marriage tell us?
- l can't tell
- Where you people going?
Tell us, we'll not say anything
Tell us what's the matter it is?
Why you can't tell me
who's wedding is this?
- who is he?
- Surprise gift
- Bobby's Tina
- Yes