Recommended by the World Wildlife Fund
Tokuma Shoten and Hakuhodo present
Another village destroyed
Let's go, soon, this will also
be consumed in the Sea of Decay
1 ,000 years after the collapse
of industrial civilization,
the Sea of Decay, a swamp
exuding toxic vapors,
covered an earth strewn
with rusting ruins,
threatening human survival
NAUSICAÄ OF THE VALLEY OF THE WIND
Executive Producers
Yasuyoshi TOKUMA Michitaka KONDO
Original story and screenplay by
Hayao MIYAZAKI
Based on the serial graphic novel
"Nausicaä of the Valley of the Wind"
Music by
Joe HISAISHI
Producer
Isao TAKAHATA
Director
Hayao MIYAZAKI
An Ohm's tracks
They're still fresh
An Ohm's shell
Amazing
I've never seen a perfect shell
Lovely sound
It chipped my ceramic sword
The villagers will be pleased
They'll have plenty to
make into tools now
What an eye
I wonder if I can carry it
It came free
It's incredibly light
Mushigo Palm spores
So beautiful...
Though in this forest of death,
your lungs would rot
in 5 minutes without a mask
Who is that?
What can it be?
My heart's pounding
Those are gunshots
An insect is
attacking someone
Oh, I'm sorry!
Over there!
What a thick spore cloud
An Ohm!
That must have been its shell
Don't run that way
Look this way!
They answered!
They're coming
Who's that?
What a magnificent Ohm
Go upwind!
Thank you!
Return to the forest, Ohm
This is not your world
Be a good boy
It's blinded by rage
I've got to calm him
The flares stunned it
An insect charm
Awaken, Ohm
Return to the forest
It's awake
The Ohm's returning to the forest
She tamed that Ohm with
flares and an insect charm
Lord Yupa!
Nausicaä
I hardly recognized you
It's been a year and half
Father will be glad
I must thank you
You've become a great wind-rider
Oh, no, not according to father
Oh, of course
I'd completely forgotten about him
A fox-squirrel
I've never seen one
When a winged insect snatched him,
I took him for a human child
I had to fire my gun
That's what enraged the Ohm
He'd fainted so was
spared the poison
Better not touch him
Even young, they're savage
Come
Here
Hey...
You're not scared
See... you're not scared
See...
You were just frightened
Lord Yupa, may I have him?
Why certainly...
Thank you
Kai and Kui
Remember me?
A mysterious power
You must be tired
You ran so far
Is everyone well?
What's wrong?
My father...
He can no longer fly
Jihl...
The forest poisons?
Yes
He says it's fate for those
living by the Sea of Decay
I should have come sooner
Oh, no
Thank you for coming
Lord Yupa, there's something
I want to show you
My secret room
It's a secret
I don't want to scare them
I'll tell them you're coming
Come soon!
Lord Yupa
Would you carry this?
It's hard to fly with
She certainly reads the wind well
Not far now
Oh...
Lord Yupa
Welcome
Are you in good health?
The waters and winds
are clear and calm
Lord Yupa
Hello all, you're well
We've missed you
Princess, he has come
Wait
Lord Yupa
Old Mito, you're hard at work
Tonight I'll hear
tales of your travels
OK, start it
Seems to work
Yes
This is excellent
Tomorrow, we'll send
people to get the rest
Come, Toeto
Lord Yupa
This is Toeto's baby, born this year
Oh, let's have a look
A fine baby
Reminds me of Nausicaä
as a baby
Please be her godfather
Name her that a fair wind
may favor her
I will indeed
I'll find her a fine name
Thank you
May she grow up
as strong as our Princess
She's as strong as they come
But we won't want her
playing in the Sea of Decay
But that's where
I found the Ohm shell
Put yourself in my shoes
I'm responsible for this castle
She's made me sick with worry
Let her play in the Sea of Decay
if she finds us Ohm shells
Indeed, her presence
there saved me
Saved by the girl?
This is a fine valley
Being here calms my spirits
How was your journey?
It was terrible
The Sea of Decay consumed
2 more countries to the south
It's spreading all the time
And yet war and hunger
are everywhere
Nothing but bad omens
Why can't they live
as you do in this valley?
The ocean winds protect our valley
The Sea of Decay
can't reach us here
What do you say, Yupa?
Isn't it time you
settled in this valley?
Look at my condition
It would please everyone
Don't bother
Yupa's a man who is fated
to search forever
Fate, huh...
Obaba, what's
he searching for?
Oh, my, don't you
know, Nausicaä?
Look, see the tapestry on the wall...
I no longer see it
The figure in the left corner
"...clothed in blue robes,
"descending onto a golden field,
"to join bonds
with the great earth
"and guide the people
to the pure land, at last"
Lord Yupa, I always thought
that was only a legend
You mustn't tease me, Obaba
It's the same thing
I only wish to solve
the Sea of Decay's mysteries
Are we humans but a tribe
destined to be swallowed
and ruined by the Sea of Decay?
That is what I wish to know
If only I could help Lord Yupa...
Princess, Princess
What is it, Mito?
A strange scent on the wind
It's nearly dawn
I'll be right there
How is it?
It's one fine storm,
but something's amiss
Over there!
Look!
It's a ship
Why would a ship be here?
What is it?
Lord Yupa
It's a ship
A ship!
It's coming closer
It's huge!
It's a Tolmekian ship
It's not flying right
It's an emergency landing
Help me up, Gol
Princess, you mustn't!
I'll guide them to the shore
It's coming about
Off you go!
Teto!
How dare they!
They must have landed before
and killed some insects
Turn away!
You'll crash!
Turn!
It crashed
The Princess
The cliffs
Let's go!
Everyone to the rescue
Even the boys!
It's that girl, she's alive
Where am I...
The Valley of the Wind
Save your strength
My name is...
Lastel of Pejite
My cargo...
Burn the cargo...
The cargo...
Please, burn it
Your cargo, I understand
Don't worry
It's all in flames
Thank goodness
Princess!
That's...
The Princess of Pejite
An insect!
An Ushiabu's alive
Oh, no, it's calling its friends
It can't fly
Bring guns!
No, if you shoot it,
it'll call others
I'll kill it now
Guns won't kill an Ushiabu
Then what!
Wait
Mito
Bring my glider
Princess!
Return to the forest
You're strong, you can fly
That's a good boy
Princess
Thanks
Thank God
No telling how we'd suffer for
even a single insect's death
An Ohm...
Found one!
Come!
Here!
So those were spores
stuck to that ship
They haven't released
any toxins yet
We're almost done
I know
We can't miss a single one
What on earth is this?
The fire didn't destroy it...
Leave this mystery
for later, folks
Go and help burn the spores
Be careful, now
Why'd she bring this
bundle of trouble here
Mito, look here
It's pulsing
Almost like it's alive
Lord Yupa, what is this...
On my journey
I heard ominous rumors...
That a monster from the
old world that had slept
beneath Pejite,
had been unearthed
A monster from the old world?
Giant Warriors...
The Giant Warriors!
They say they were destroyed
in the Seven Days of Fire
This...
The Giant Warriors were all
said to have turned to stone
But a single one slept in
the earth for 1 ,000 years
In... In a way, the thing
looks almost human
Tolmekia's a savage military state,
far to our west
And remember the Pejite
captive who perished...
Keep up the good work
What's that?
Tolmekian ships!
Everyone to the castle!
To the castle!
Gather in the castle!
The castle!
Father!
Obaba, hide yourself
I'll stay right where I am
Princess!
How dare you!
Nausicaä...
Stay where you are!
Move and this sword,
carved of insect shell
will pierce your ceramic armor
That's Yupa...
I ask you Tolmekian warriors
Last night, these villagers toiled
desperately to save one of your ships
We have just now gently
laid one of your dead to rest
Is this how you Tolmekians treat
such a nation, however weak!
If you would make war,
you must have reasons
You should first send a messenger
to declare them
Nausicaä...
Be calm, Nausicaä
If you fight now,
they will slaughter the villagers
We must survive
Wait for our chance
You...
Little wench
Put it down, Kurotowa
But...
Look at this mess
Killed them all
Your rebuke stings
Are you Yupamiralda,
the greatest swordsman of this region?
We have not come for slaughter
We wish to talk
Lay down your sword
The Princess!
Princess!
Listen well!
Her Highness Kushana, Division
Commander of the Tolmekian
Frontier Forces will speak
We have come to unify
the frontier nations
and build peace in this region
You live on the brink of extinction
beside the Sea of Decay
Accept our rule
and join our enterprise
We shall burn away the Sea of Decay
and resurrect the earth!
Burn away the Sea of Decay
Is that possible?
We have revived the
miraculous skills and power
that once allowed humans
to rule this earth
For those who submit to us,
I promise a life free from fear of
the toxins and insects of that swamp
Wait!
You must not harm the Sea of Decay
What's that, you old hag
Take her away
Let her speak
In the 1 ,000 years
of the Sea of Decay,
countless times have humans
sought to burn it away
Yet... each time herds
of Ohms, blind with rage,
have swarmed the earth,
like a tidal wave
Destroying nations,
swallowing cities,
the Ohms' rage would not quiet
until they starved to death
In time, the spores
took root in the Ohms' rotting flesh,
and engulfed our vast
earth in this Sea of Decay
You must not touch
the Sea of Decay
Enough!
No more of your ravings
Ah! What will you do?
Kill me, too?
You!
Kill me if you will!
Easy work to murder
an old blind woman
Just as you murdered Jihl
Not Jihl!
How cruel!
He was helpless!
Shut them up!
Show no mercy to impudence!
Wait, everyone!
Please listen to me
I don't want anymore sacrifices
Please
Princess...
You, too, Obaba
We must submit to these people
Step on it
Hurry up
It really is a lovely valley
I'm against it
We have orders to send the
Giant Warrior back at once
An order we can't possibly fulfill
Even our biggest ship
collapsed from its weight
But you can't be serious
about building a nation here...
And what if I am?
You expect me to hand over that
monster as a toy for those fools?
You have a point...
I am but a simple soldier
Such a decision is beyond my position
You're a sly fox
While I'm in Pejite, your priority
is to revive that Giant Warrior
Yes
Can this gun ship fly?
Yes, we found it here
Get this straight
I'm not asking you
But take the Princess to Pejite....
5 hostages, the gun ship and food...
You pick the hostages
Prepare everything
for the morning
Thanks for going as a hostage
We're fine, but look
They're taking everything in sight
I will slip away, return in secret
and await my chance
We must prevent that
monster's resurrection
Yes
Nausicaä
Teto, where is she?
Nausicaä! What on earth is this?
These plants are from
the Sea of Decay
I've grown them
from spores I collected
Don't worry, they're not toxic
Not toxic...
The air here is pure indeed, but...
Why... with this deadly poisonous
plant blooming
The castle windmill draws
water from deep within the earth
The sand, too, comes from
the very bottom of the well
With pure water and soil,
the plants from the Sea of Decay
are not poisonous
The pollution lies in the earth itself
Even the earth of our valley
Why...
Who made such a
terrible mess of the world?
Did you do this all yourself?
Yes
To cure my father's illness
and that of others
But...
I'm closing it down
I just shut off the water and
they'll soon wither and die
Nausicaä
I frighten myself
I don't know what my rage
will make me do
I don't want to kill anyone
Princess
We gathered these for you
Chiko nuts
They're for you
All of you...
So many
You've worked so hard
Thank you
They're very precious
It's not fair, Princess
All aboard!
We're taking off
There, now
You mustn't cry
Don't worry
I'll be home in no time
Really?
Why, have I ever lied to you?
No
Right?
Yeah
Promise?
Yes
Go along, it's dangerous
OK
You promised!
Take care of the Princess!
Aren't we in Pejite yet?
My back is killing me
Boy oh boy, did the Princess
ever pick a bunch of losers
Hey, isn't this strange?
Why do they fly so close together?
Like they're afraid of an attack
Toxins swirl below the clouds
Don't move
A gun ship!
Enemy fire!
They've hit ship #2!
I told you so
Wow, terrifying!
Defense formation!
That's a Pejite gun ship
Pejite!
Damn! They got #3
What's the Korvet doing?
Their ships just crumble
Oh no, he's hit our tail
The Barge tether snapped
Hurry, Teto
Oh, no, we're going down
Princess!
Stop! No more killing!
No more!
Princess
Hurry, Mito!
Princess, we're doomed
Maybe I can fly it
Are you crazy!
Hurry, Mito!
What? Right!
Start the engine!
Blast open the door!
Come!
Hurry
Get inside
Mito, ready?
Ready or not!
Full throttle when we take off!
Roger!
Ready
Go!
Put on the toxin mask
Drop below the clouds
to find the Barge
You're still warm
Don't give up, Teto
What is this place!
I've never seen
such dense toxins
Keep an eye on the right tail
It's nearby
It's still aloft
Hey! You're right!
There it is!
It's the Princess!
Princess!
Don't give up, everyone
I'll throw you a rope
Our hook's broken
You can't hook us in mid-air
I don't want to crash and
become insect food!
We'll leap to our deaths!
Don't panic!
Ditch your cargo
Good bye
Farewell!
Listen to me!
Toss your cargo!
Kill the rear engine
What?
The engine noise is too loud
Hurry!
Yes!
What?
Princess...
What are you...
Your mask, Princess!
You'll die!
Put your mask on!
I promise you'll be safe
Trust me and dump that cargo
We'll do whatever you say
Please! Put your mask back on!
The Princess is smiling
We're going to be OK
Hurry! Lose the cargo
Princess, we're in a nose-dive!
Re-start engines!
I inhaled
Hurry, hurry
Princess!
Everyone safe?
Don't move!
You!
Thanks for saving me
Why'd you save her, Princess?
You're a fool
You thought I'd grovel
in gratitude?
You know nothing of the Sea of Decay
It isn't like the human world
There's no knowing what
a single gunshot will bring
That battle hurled
ships into this forest
The insects are furious
Look up
The Yamma are sentries
They'll quickly bring other insects
We must escape now
Throw me your extra rope
Mito, fix the hook
Don't move
I give the orders
What are you so afraid of?
You're just like
a lost fox-squirrel
How dare you!
Don't be afraid
We just want you to go back
to your own country
You...
They're here!
Quiet! Don't anger them
This is an Ohm's nest!
We're surrounded
They're examining us
Forgive us, Ohm,
for disturbing your nest
Please understand,
we're not your enemies
Princess!
He's still alive
Wait, Ohm!
What's happening?
Their eyes have turned blood-red
What will you do with the glider?
When the waters quiet,
take off and wait for me above
If I'm not back in 1 hour,
return to the valley
But...
Princess!
She's gone
Hand it over
All right, everyone
We'll do as the Princess said
Princess...
Damn!
Who are you?
You think only of killing
My flares and charms
won't help now
It's quicksand!
Damn!
It's been 2 hours already
More and more insects
Princess!
Nausicaä
Come here
Father
Mother's here, too
No, I don't want to go
Stay away!
There's nothing here
I said, there's nothing!
Stay inside
It's a baby Ohm
She's being used by the insects
Give it to me, Nausicaä
No! It's not doing anything bad
Insects and humans can't
live in the same world
Please, don't kill it!
Please!
Teto...
What a strange place
Hey!
I finally found it
How are you feeling?
Where are we?
First, let me thank you
I'm Asbel of Pejite
Thank you for saving me
I'm Nausicaä of
the Valley of the Wind
Where are we?
No wonder you're surprised
We're beneath the Sea of Decay
Beneath the Sea of Decay?
Look, we fell from up there,
along with the sand
We're not wearing masks
That's right
The air here is pure
Couldn't believe it myself,
finding this place
under the Sea of Decay
What is it?
Nausicaä, don't wander too far
What a wonderful tree
Even though it's dead,
water still flows through it
Just like the sand
at the bottom of our well
Grains of petrified wood
sifting down from above
Nausicaä
Are you crying?
Yes
I'm so happy
Lastel was my twin sister
I should have been with her
I'm sorry I didn't
tell you sooner
Oh, no...
I'm sorry
I nearly killed the person
who eased my sister's pain
I see...
So it's in the Valley of the Wind
This nut tastes really weird
It's a chiko nut
It's really good for you
It doesn't taste great,
but I could eat a whole boot-full!
Why the Sea of Decay was born...
You think the strangest thoughts
The trees of the Sea of Decay
grew to cleanse
a world polluted by humans
They absorb toxins from the earth,
generate pure crystals,
die and turn to sand
That's what created
these underground caverns
The insects protect this forest
In that case, we're doomed
We can't possibly survive,
living in terror of toxins and insects
for thousands of years
At least we can find a way
to keep it from spreading
You sound just like Kushana
No! We don't plan to use
the Giant Warriors!
You'll see when you
meet my friends tomorrow
Let's go to sleep
We have far to go tomorrow
All's well
On schedule?
The torso is solidifying well
You're one cute monster
Makes a poor soldier think
of dusting off old ambitions
It's grinning
You should've slept beneath
the earth 'til the end of time
Counselor!
Her Highness' planes were
attacked by Pejite survivors
All crashed, except the Korvet
What about Her Highness?
Her ship exploded in flight
Counselor
- The villagers don't know yet?
- No
OK, we'll head out
You stay here and keep working
Either fortune's finally smiling
on this lowly soldier...
Or it's a trap set to destroy me...
Mito and the others have returned,
waiting at Acid Lake, Lord Yupa
In shame we return without her
No, no, I'm pleased you're safe
Releasing me?
Drown the Giant Warrior
deep in Acid Lake,
and return to your country...
Few of your soldiers remain here
We could easily start a fight,
but why sacrifice more people?
Fire and water are powerless against it,
and it's only a matter of time
before it starts to walk
Don't you see?
It's far too late to turn back
My orders to invade Pejite
were motivated by fear
that another country had
harnessed its strength
Once its presence here is known,
the great powers will
send their armies
You have but one choice left
Revive the Giant Warrior,
defy both great powers
and learn to live with that thing
Look
An insect did that...?
Whoever becomes my husband
will see worse than that
Burn the Sea of Decay,
kill the insects,
and restore the human world
Why do you hesitate!
Steal it from us, just as
we stole it from Pejite
We shall not give
the Giant Warrior life
Emergency!
What's the password?
I'm in a hurry!
Wind
Valley!
OK
Some spores survived!
What!
They're spreading toxins
and the valley's going crazy!
Hand 'em over
Hurry up!
Hurry, or the valley's doomed
We need our tools back
The tools that burn spores
can also be used as weapons
We have no choice
Release everything but their guns
The Korvet's taking off
Get through this time
Summon all our troops
from Pejite to this valley
Good grief, now
this is a real mess
Hurry
Find the Princess
Look after the valley
Be careful until we return
We're going to the valley
It's no use, the spores
are already here
And on this side, too
Move!
What are you doing!
Oh, no, here, too
Obaba
We've no choice but to burn it
This forest is doomed
If we hesitate, the Sea of Decay
will consume our valley
Isn't there anything to be done?
This forest guarded
the reservoir for 3 centuries
Damn! If only they'd never come
This is getting out of hand
Let's go help them
You think so?
I think it looks the same as ever
The insects have gone
I wonder why my heart's
pounding so hard
We're almost there
My friends are just
over that mountain
Pejite looks strange
What is that haze?
Asbel, your mask
Insects! All dead
Head for Pejite
Be careful, the Tolmekian
army must be there
Even an Ohm...
It attacked the Great Dome
Pejite's finished
They wiped out the Tolmekians,
but this is...
They wiped out?
What do you mean, Asbel?
It's a Brig
My friends' ship!
They're landing, let's go!
Asbel!
You're alive!
What have you done?
We can't rebuild it
You've seen the city
Don't worry, if the Sea of Decay
swallows it, we'll burn it away
But the Giant Warrior isn't here
I know, it's in the Valley of the Wind
How did...
We haven't exactly been idle
We've launched our 2nd phase
We'll wipe out the Tolmekians
in the valley tonight
What!
What are you going to do?
Who's this, Asbel?
Nausicaä from
the Valley of the Wind
I owe her my life
Valley of the Wind...
Tell me, what will happen?
You must know, Asbel!
Tell me
They'll provoke an insect attack
So you made them
attack Pejite, too!
You're... horrible...
We simply have to recover the
Giant Warrior before they revive it
We're doing it to save the world
And so you'll murder
everyone in the Valley!
Stop it! Call it off! Please!
It's too late
Once they've started,
no one can stop them
We've lost most of our
people to the Tolmekians
This is the only way
Let go! Let me fly!
It's horrible now, but the Giant
Warrior will purge the Sea of Decay
and rebuild the human world
Liar! You're just like the Tolmekians
No, they want to use it for destruction
You drink water from the wells, too
Do you know what purifies that water?
The trees in the Sea of Decay
cleanse all the lakes
and rivers that humans polluted!
And you want to destroy that!
Why did you dig up
that Giant Warrior!
What choice do we have?
Subject ourselves to Tolmekian rule?
Never, never!
Tell them, Asbel, how
the Sea of Decay came to be
How the insects protect this world!
Please, Asbel!
What are you doing!
Don't move!
Release her
Calm down, Asbel
I'm serious
Release her
Nausicaä, go and warn them!
Asbel
Let me go!
Fools
No stopping fighting once it starts
But he warned us to be careful...
Quit dawdling and use the tanks
to rescue our men
Counselor! They got the last man!
Coming our way?
I don't know
The whole village is gathering
Why do they go berserk
over a little forest or two?
Just as it was with Pejite
They got our tank!
Hurry, get it moving
Don't panic
Incoming fire!
Forward!
Hurry up!
Maybe this is it?
It's moving!
Which way?
Forward, move forward
I know that
Damn! Mobilize all the tanks
She survived...
So much for my dreams...
Your Highness!
We'll hold 'em off here
Lead everyone to safety
by Acid Lake
All right
It's just until the Princess
returns with the gun ship
Hurry everyone!
Stop gawking and help me
My aching back
The tanks are coming!
Hurry!
I know that
Are you sure?
It's a Pejite Brig
I saw it peeking through the clouds
OK!
Watch out, she's a wild one
Quickly
Nausicaä, you may go free
Go warn your Valley
Your glider may get you
there in time
It's waiting
Asbel told me everything
I'll take your place
Put this on
You're...
Lastel's mother
Thank you
I'm so very sorry
Everything we've done is wrong
Hurry!
What about her?
She'll be all right, don't worry
Be careful
We've treated you so badly
Over here, Nausicaä
Hurry
Thank you, everyone!
Sorry it took so long
Can you launch from here?
I'll try
A Korvet!
Take cover in the clouds!
Stop firing!
Idiots! Nothing but wind
and lightning in there
It's useless! I've lost control!
The ship is breaking apart
We have to leave
the clouds and fight
They were expecting us
What are they up to?
Forcing us into the clouds
so they can board us
Here they come
This is your last chance
No, I'll stay with you
I can't abandon all those people
and the girl who took my place
Only you can save your people
Please, go, for our sakes!
The ship is ours
Take no prisoners
Destroy them
Go, Nausicaä!
Asbel!
Princess!
Mito!
Mito! Lord Yupa!
Princess
Hurry, everyone's in...!
I'll engage the hook now
Lord Yupa, that red lever!
This is their last stronghold
The door won't hold
Any time
Show them some Pejite pride
What is that?
A bird?
A ship, a gun ship from the Valley
What!
You...
It's Lord Yupa, here's
a chance for glory!
Surrender, your Korvet
won't be back
This guy's tough
Princess, you're crazy
The engine'll blow
Just make it to the Valley
Speed up!
Dear God, God of the Wind
Please protect my people
They won't budge
They're waiting for her return
Return?
They believe that girl will
return with their gun ship
That gun ship's a pain
It's our chance to attack
Do you know what that ship is?
It's from before
the Seven Days of Fire
The one they say
went as far as the stars...
It's too strong for our guns,
but bury it in a hole...
I, too, wish to wait
If she really does return from
deep in the Sea of Decay...
I'd like a chance
to really talk to her
Made up your minds?
If you'll aid our attack,
I'll let you go
You want to end up like Pejite?
You're a Princess, too
You're nothing like our Princess
Look at my hand
That's what King Jihl had
In 6 more months
it will be stone
But our Princess said,
she liked these hands
They were the beautiful hands
of a hard worker
You want to live
with the Sea of Decay
even as its toxins ravage you?
You use fire
We use it a bit, too
Too much fire
and nothing will grow
Fire can turn the forest
into ashes in a single day
Water and wind sustain
a forest for 1 00 years
We like the water and the wind
The sight of our forest
will grieve the Princess
Counselor, we await your orders
Shut up
Yes sir
Who knows what happened,
but she sure looks cute
Let them go, Kurotowa!
Huh? You want to wait?
Feed the soldiers
We attack in 1 hour
Food, huh?
Finally, a real meal
Someone's coming!
It's Gol and the others
What is it?
There's no wind
No wind?
You're right, the wind's stopped
Obaba, what is it?
Obaba
Someone...
Someone take me outside...
The wind's never stopped before
Obaba, my ears hurt
The air...
The very air is thick with rage
We're close!
We're clear of the Sea of Decay!
3 minutes to Acid Lake!
Idle the engines
Drop beneath the clouds
What's this glow!
Ohms!
The Sea of Decay is spreading
They're headed for the Valley
How did they stampede the Ohms...
Someone's baiting them
Mito! Turn towards Sirius
Yes!
It's there
Mito, a flare!
Ready
Fire!
What is that?
How cruel...
They're baiting them
with a baby
I'll shoot 'em down!
No, Mito!
Don't shoot!
Why not! Why shouldn't I?
Kill the baby,
and the stampede will never end!
What can we do!
They'll destroy the Valley
Calm down, Mito
Return the baby to them
Let's try
What are you doing, Princess!
You go ahead and warn them
Princess!
You're not even armed
That's not one of our flares
How far?
20 leagues
The other side of the lake
Is it a gun ship?
Probably
That's a distress signal
It's definitely the gun ship
It's been an hour, let's go
Why not wait?
The bloodshed is inevitable
Infantry advance
Your Highness, get inside
I'm fine here
The gun ship!
Fire!
Hold your fire!
Stop it! Stop!
Princess!
Stand-by
Don't fire
Your Highness
Where's the girl!
The Princess!
She's not here
The Ohm, a stampede
It's coming this way
What!
The Ohm!
The Princess stayed behind
to stop them
This is no time for battle
Everyone run, find the
highest place you can! Now!
Obaba, I see a red glow
It's spreading
It's coming this way
You hold on tight
There's no stopping them now
Don't panic
There's still time
If I have to die,
I want to die in the Valley
No, you mustn't give up,
not while the Princess has faith
Listen, hold them off
as long as you can
I'll return soon
Your Highness, not that...
It's not ready yet!
If not now, when!
Go!
Don't shoot! Listen to me!
Damn! She flies like a bird
She's not an enemy
She wants to say something
Anyone who interferes is an enemy
We'd better drop the bait in
the Valley soon, or die ourselves
Here she comes!
Let her come in close, then fire
Now! Fire!
No!
That's Lastel!
Move!
Ohm...
Don't be angry
Don't be frightened
I'm not your foe
I'm sorry
I can't ask your forgiveness
It's too cruel
Don't move!
You'll bleed to death
Be good, little one, keep still
They've found us
They're coming
Stop! Not with those wounds!
The lake is poison...
You...
Good baby
I'm fine
They're coming for you
They're turning away
Ohm! Don't!
The Valley's that way
They've forgotten us in their rage
If I don't calm them, the Valley...
Fools! Drawing them
with their own fire
We're safe
We'd better get away
Check the engine
No, no!
We can discuss this
Take us to them
I must give them the baby
What's the point, it's too late
They'll never stop
Drop us in front of them, then
Take us
But you'll die, too
Obaba, will we all die?
If that's our fate,
we must accept it
They don't even waver
Let's retreat
Idiot! There's nowhere to go
Don't retreat!
Hold your ground
for Her Highness
Highness...
Your Highness!
Get them!
The Giant Warrior...
Giant Warrior
It's rotting
It's too soon
Burn them!
What's wrong
Are you not descended from
Earth's most evil tribe!
Incredible...
No wonder the world caught fire
Your Highness Kushana, hurray!
Destroy them!
What's wrong with you?
Hurry up and fire!
We're done for
The Giant Warrior is dead
It's for the best
The Ohm's rage is
the fury of the Earth itself
There's no reason to live
if our lives depend on a monster
Princess!
The Princess!
Not there
It's madness
Princess!
The Ohms are changing color
Their rage has vanished
They stopped
The Ohms stopped
Princess!
The Princess is dead
She calmed them
with her own life
She saved our Valley
Look...
What is that light?
Teto...
Wonderful
Thank you, Ohm
Thank you
It's a miracle
A miracle
Such friendship and sympathy
The Ohms have opened their hearts
Children, watch well and tell me
what I cannot see
The Princess is wearing
strange blue clothes
It's like she's walking
through golden fields
"...clothed in blue robes,
"descending onto a golden field..."
Obaba...
The ancient legend was true
Look!
The glider
The wind!
The wind has returned
VOICES
Sumi SHIMAMOTO
Ichiro NAGAI
Goro NAYA
Yoji MATSUDA
Yoshiko SAKAKIBARA
Iemasa KAYUMI
English translation by
Linda HOAGLUND with Judith ALEY
Nao AMISAKI and Steve ALPERT
English subtitles by Aura
Production
Top Craft
The End