Of vampires and bloodsuckers.
Of corpses which devour their own flesh.
Of incubuses and succubuses.
Of the living dead who follow strangers
in the night...
...and attack them.
Hmm...
Transylvania... Nosferatu,
beyond death...
...a curse that will last till the end of time.
The curse of Nosferatu.
Coachman, could you take me to
the Borgo pass?
I'll pay you well.
There is no road to the Borgo pass.
But it's right there.
I need your coach.
I haven't got a coach.
Then I'll take one of your horses.
I'll double the price.
Sorry, sir, but I don't have any
horses. Don't you see?
Well...
I guess I'll have to walk there.
Count Dracula?!
I am Count Dracula.
Welcome to my castle.
You must be Jonathan Harker.
Yes.
Come in.
The night is cold and you must be
tired and hungry.
I've got the papers here.
This is the layout of the house...
...which I'm sure you'd like to see.
Yes, yes.
Please, help yourself.
Please, I'm afraid you must dine alone.
It's nearly midnight and I partake of
nothing at this hour.
Unfortunately, the servants
are not at our disposal.
So allow me to see to your comfort.
Listen.
The Children of the Night
make their music.
Ah, young man...
...you're like the villagers who cannot
place themselves in the soul of the hunter.
The knife is old and could be dirty.
It could give you blood poisoning.
Please let me do it. It's the oldest
remedy in the world.
Oh, forget it. It's hardly worth
mentioning. Just a little cut.
You... you know...
...it's only for the best.
Let's sit down for a while.
It's still many hours till dawn.
And during the daytime
I am always away.
Lucy, my love...
...there is no postal service
from here...
...but I shall write a diary, preserving all
my thoughts and feelings for you.
Last night after a tiresome journey,
I finally reached my destination...
...the castle of Count Dracula.
I had a bad dream,
but I hope it will pass.
This castle is so strange.
At times I wonder if it isn't
part of that dream.
Everything about it looks so unreal.
I don't attach importance to the
sunshine anymore...
...or to glittering fountains,
which youth is so fond of.
I love the darkness and the shadows.
Where I can be alone with my thoughts.
I am the descendent of an old family.
Time is an abyss, profound as
a thousand nights.
Centuries come and go...
...to be unable to grow old is terrible.
That is not the worst.
There are things more horrible than that.
Can you imagine enduring centuries...
...experiencing the same futility
each day?
I'm glad you found such a large
old house for me.
Very near your lodging, I understand.
Yes, it's just around the corner.
Ah...
...may I have a look at the contract?
What?...
What a lovely throat.
It's my wife, Lucy.
Your hand.
Your hand is so cold.
The document... the contract for
the house, I must sign it immediately.
Yes, but we haven't settled on a price.
It doesn't matter between gentlemen...
...I accept whatever you find just.
How long did it take you
to get here from Wismar?
Four weeks.
I...
...it takes a while to travel on land.
From the seed of Belial is the
vampire born.
He who feeds on the
blood of mankind...
...who, unredeemed, taketh
his refuge in caves, tombs...
...coffins filled with the unblessed soil
of cemeteries...
...wherein the black death
has reaped its harvest...
...the plague.
Jonathan!
She has a sudden fever.
Her pulse is too fast.
She needs to rest.
Call me if you think it is necessary...
...but I don't think it's something serious.
Oh, God, he must be going to Wismar.
Lucy...
Lucy's in danger.
I've got to get out of here.
It's strange...
...but the papers are all in order.
Let me see them...
From Varna to Wismar.
Garden soil for botanical experiments.
Open one of them.
I want to make sure.
This one.
Mother Superior...
stop the black coffins.
The patient who came yesterday
had a seiZure.
Which one?
The one who had bitten a cow.
Oh, yes.
We put him in isolation.
I'll go with you.
Blood is life.
Has he done it for long?
He has, and he also refuses food.
Blood is life.
Let's go.
Help! Help me!
Be quiet...
I hear the sounds of sails
fluttering in the wind.
Still, there's no letter from him.
But, don't worry, Lucy...
The mail from Transylvania is very slow.
Something has happened to Jonathan.
Have courage, Lucy.
God is listening to our prayers.
God is far away when we need him.
Young man. You're not yet well.
You shouldn't travel.
The black coffins...
I must get to Wismar before the coffins.
You should at least wait for the doctor.
He'll be here tomorrow.
Lucy, my wife, is in danger.
I must save her.
The black coffins.
Evil is on the way.
I'm writing because I believe
there is a curse on my ship.
One by one, four sailors and the
second mate have taken ill and died.
Another sailor and our cook have
disappeared without a trace.
A rumor of a mysterious stranger
on board scares everyone to death.
We searched the boat and we found
nothing, except rats.
We are maintaining our course.
Northwest at 30 degrees.
The wind is steady. 12 knots.
Mr. Renfield...
...you sent my husband
to Transylvania...
...and I haven't heard
from him in weeks.
I'm very concerned...
...I want to go there and look for him.
Don't go yet.
My master is coming.
Who did you say is coming?
The Lord of the Rats.
He's bringing with him thousands
and thousands of rats.
Orderly, give him some more food.
I think we should leave now.
The plague.
The Master has arrived.
Lay a gangplank across.
We need to search the ship.
Cut him loose.
There's not a soul on board.
Just some freight.
But there are rats everywhere.
Here's the ship's log.
It's truly a mystery.
I think, gentlemen, that the ship's log
may give us a clue.
Varna, June 6. Myself, the Captain, five
hands, two mates and a cook...
...direction, the Dardanelles.
Course westward.
Today a third man died of a high fever.
Last night, while on his watch,
a mate disappeared without a trace.
June 20th. Course northward
towards Biscaya.
Speed 40 knots. Tall waves.
Fear grows among my men.
Now only the first mate
and I remain alive.
There are rats everywhere.
Could it be a plague?
Go home quietly, please.
Shut the doors and windows,
gentlemen.
Gracious lady, we brought this man.
He says he lives here.
Lucy!
Jonathan!
Who is this woman?
Bring him in, please.
It looks like he's suffering
from brain fever.
The sun is hurting my eyes.
Dr. Van Helsing. Do you think
we've all gone mad...
...and that one morning we'll all wake up
and find ourselves in straight-jackets?
Excuse me for not knocking...
...I am Count Dracula.
I know who you are.
I read Jonathan's diary.
He wrote everything that went on
in your castle, while he was there.
- Don't worry, he won't die.
- Yes...
...he will. Death surrounds us.
We're all at his will.
The rivers continue to flow without us.
Time flies by.
Even the stars...
...they wander towards us
in a very strange way.
Only death is certain.
Only death is cruel.
Death is cruelty
against the unsuspecting.
But that's not what I perceive as cruel.
Cruel is when you can't die
even if you want to.
Give me some of your love...
...which you give Jonathan.
I never will.
I won't even give that love to God.
If Jonathan can't have my love...
...then, no one else will.
If I wish, he'll recogniZe you again.
But first, come and give me your love.
Only then, will I give you
your husband back.
And as for me...
...the absence of love...
...is the most abject pain.
The power of my love
will bring him back to me.
And you may be assured...
...even the unthinkable will not
deter me...
...that you want to lay for me.
Good night.
Stop!
Help! Help!
Nosferatu, the undead.
He drinks the blood of his victims, and
turns them into phantoms of the night.
Like a shadow, he has no reflection.
He goes through walls and closed
doors...
...as if they never existed.
Like a bat, he wafts into dark bedrooms.
Masquerading as a black wolf,
he hunts his fleeing victims.
Abandon all hope,
you who cross his path.
Yet even vampires, who are
considered unnatural creatures...
...are subject to some laws of nature.
The sight of the cross bans him.
The consecrated host...
...can bar his retreat.
And if a pure hearted woman...
...diverts his attention
from the cry of the cock...
...the first light of day will obliterate him.
What is your wish, Master?
Go north...
...to Riga.
The army of rats and the Black Death
will follow you.
Oh... Thy will be done.
Amen...!
The plague! The plague!
What are you doing here?
I must talk to the town council.
It's been dissolved.
It doesn't exist anymore.
Then, I must see the mayor.
He's dead.
Go back home, as fast as you can.
I know why this evil is happening!
Why won't you listen to me?!
I know the reason why.
My child. It's all a figment
of your imagination.
But Dr. Van Helsing...
...you've read
Jonathan's diary.
You've seen what has
happened to him.
It's getting worse here every day.
The plague. The rats.
And this book about the vampires.
This book explains it.
This is an enlightened century.
Science has refuted the superstitions
you're talking about.
I know it exists.
I believe what I see with my own eyes.
Faith... Faith...
Yes, faith.
Yes, faith, Dr. Van Helsing.
Faith.
Faith is the faculty in men...
...which enables us to believe things...
...we know to be untrue.
You must come and help me
destroy this monster.
We must look for him.
Coffins have come by boat
from the Black Sea.
We can search for them tonight,
and destroy them.
My child, you need some rest.
Your husband's condition has
worn you out.
No, Dr. Van Helsing.
Tonight.
I need to study this matter
scientifically.
No! Tonight! There's no time to lose.
Even a farmer knows that there's
a time to plant and a time to sow.
He doesn't dig up the wheat to check
if it is growing.
Only children playing farmers
would do such things.
I guess I'll have to do this alone!
Well, then.
Mother Superior, my medicine.
My lady, how exactly did we meet?
Join us, please.
Would you like a drink?
Be our guest.
We've all contracted the plague. Let's
enjoy whatever time we have to live.
Madam Lucy! Madam Lucy!
Open up!
Come quickly to the Schraders...
Something terrible has happened there.
Lucy, calm down.
You can come closer.
It is not the plague.
My God! What happened?
I don't know exactly.
She was already dead, when I arrived.
He lost his sanity over it,
he started to rave.
We shall study this
matter scientifically...
...without prejudice,
and without superstition.
Enough! Enough. Stop acting like
you know everything.
I know, now, what I've got to do.
The consecrated host
bans the vampire.
And if a pure hearted woman, diverts
his attention from the cry of the cock...
...the first light of day will obliterate him.
Too late. Oh, God...
...if I had only listened to her.
A stake and a hammer.
I have to dispatch this demon forever.
Stop. Don't do it!
Van Helsing!
Get him! Yes, him!
That man has murdered the Count!
Have you done that?
With that stake?
Yes...
But I had a good reason for doing it.
That's for the courts to decide.
You're under arrest, Dr. Van Helsing.
Arrest this man.
Arrest him?
- I can't arrest him.
- Then get the police.
The police don't exist anymore.
Then take him to prison.
There's no one there to guard him.
It's your duty as a town employee
to handle it.
I don't have a weapon.
I don't care!
I want you to arrest this man!
Where will you take me, then?
I don't know where I'm taking you.
Take me wherever you want.
Don't just stand there.
Get a broom. It's all dusty.
Seal the room for
an official investigation.
And bring me my horse.
I have much to do.
Now!