People might laugh
and say it's just a fairy tale.
That these mysterious things
couldn't really happen.
But this is the true story of my mother.
The man that Mother loved...
...was a wolf man.
Mother was a student at
a university just outside of Tokyo.
--Her tuition was paid for with
scholarships --This is what Socrates said:
..."The wise men of the world
may have great knowledge of many things--
but goodness, truth, beauty, and arete..."
One day in early summer,
Mother saw Father for the
first time at the university.
Wearing a shirt with a stretched-out
collar, using no textbook--
Mother said he was completely
different from the other students
as she watched him
from behind earnestly taking notes.
Please wait.
This is the attendance sheet. If you don't
turn it in, you'll be marked absent.
--So--
--I'm...
...not a student here.
What?
If that bothers you, I won't come anymore.
Please, wait!
I don't care if you are a student or not,
but the lecture can be hard
to understand without a textbook.
Do you want to share mine?
"Hokushin Dry Cleaners"
Thank you for waiting.
I'll put this here, then.
I'll take this.
Here, thank you.
The accusers in this case
were the poet Meletus,
the politically powerful Anytus,
and the sophist Lycon.
Meletus acted as their representative,
but Anytus is said to have
pulled the strings from behind.
What do you think is fun?
What kind of food do you like?
What were the people you loved
in the past like?
Why are you called "Hana"?
My name?
Yeah.
When I was born,
cosmos were blooming in the garden.
They hadn't been planted by anyone,
but grew there naturally.
My dad said that looking at them
made him think of my name.
He wanted me to be a child
who always smiled, like the flowers.
Even when things got hard,
to just keep smiling,
even if the smile became forced.
Because then I could
overcome most things, he said.
That's why during Dad's funeral,
I was smiling the whole time.
But then, my relatives said that was
improper, and they were very angry with me.
But... I suppose
it really was improper, wasn't it?
It wasn't improper.
I'm glad.
"Hokushin Dry Cleaners"
"Hakujuji"
Even in the same housing complex,
each room is completely different inside.
Families with money, poor families,
big families, people living alone,
families with babies,
elderly living alone...
I bet it'd be nice to have my own house.
To say, "I'm home" and take off my shoes, wash
my face and hands, and sink into a chair.
That'd be nice.
I'd build a bookcase.
And once that bookcase was full of books,
I'd build a new bookcase.
I'd be able to do whatever I wanted
because it'd be my own house.
Then, I'll say "Welcome home," if you want.
Hana.
What is it?
There's something I have to tell you.
You can tell me anything.
Actually--
I'll tell you tomorrow.
Okay.
"Hokushin Dry Cleaners"
"Hakuiuji"
"Hakujuji"
"Christmas Cakes" "Western Sweets & Coffee"
"Hakuiuji"
Hana.
I'm sorry, Hana.
I'm sorry.
I've never told anyone before.
I was scared.
I was afraid you'd leave if I told you,
but I should have told you sooner.
I should have shown you.
Shown me?
Close your eyes for a second.
For longer than that.
Can I open them yet?
Hana,
what do I look like to you?
She found out that
transforming during the full moon
and attacking people was just a legend.
"The world is full of things
I don't know," Mother thought.
Were you surprised?
Will you leave me now?
But you're shaking.
Are you afraid?
I'm not afraid.
Because it's you.
Father was a descendant
of the Honshuu wolf,
which had become extinct
about a hundred years ago.
With both wolf and human blood,
he was the last of his kind.
When Father was a child, his parents told him
about the history of his extinct ancestors.
They told him not to reveal the truth
to anyone, and then died.
After that, he was taken in
by relatives who knew nothing of this
and had a hard time as
he grew into an adult.
After getting his driver's license,
he went to the city to look for work.
Unknown and unheeded by men, Father said
that he had lived in hiding until now.
"Natural Birth: Kind to your body and soul"
"Hakuiuji"
Mother gave birth to me
in that small apartment.
It was snowing.
Not at the hospital,
without even a midwife,
my parents delivered me by themselves.
Mother was worried that
if I had been born as a wolf,
the doctors would have been surprised.
I'm glad she was born safely.
This is just the beginning.
Do you think she will be a kind child?
She might be a smart kid.
I wonder what kind of adult she will be?
A nurse, a teacher, or a baker--
whatever it is, I want her
to have a job she loves.
I want her to have a happy,
healthy life free of troubles.
Let's watch over her until she grows up.
Yeah.
My little brother was born
in the spring of the next year.
It was raining that day.
Suddenly, Father was nowhere to be seen.
I don't know what Father
was thinking that day.
Maybe he instinctively went
to hunt for food for his new baby.
Maybe he wanted
something nutritious for Mother,
who was recovering from the birth.
"Driver's License"
"I'm leaving the kids to you,"
Mother thought she could hear him say.
Leave them to me.
I'll make sure to raise them properly.
Mother had a lot of trouble with us after
that, but I don't remember anything about it.
Num nums.
Wait a minute, Yuki. I'm making it now.
Num nums!
I said, it's almost done.
Yuki!
When I was angry or upset,
my fur would bristle,
and I would turn into a wolf.
Oh all right, you can have a biscuit first.
Apparently, I was always hungry,
crying for food from morning until night.
Completely different from
my sickly brother, Ame, who ate little.
Mother had to quit school
and leave her part-time job
in order to take care of us.
That was close...
We lived on the small savings
Father had left behind.
That was close...
According to Mother, my brother
and I seemed like we weren't sure
if we were supposed to be humans or wolves.
"Pediatric Care"
They got me...
"Child Care Encyclopedia"
she had no choice but to study on her own.
Breastfeeding every two
hours, day and night.
When Ame wouldn't suck on his own,
she learned to feed him
with cotton pads dipped in breast milk.
But when he wouldn't
drink any milk or stop crying,
she didn't know what to do
except pat him on the back
and comfort him the whole night.
As a result, Mother was
quickly becoming exhausted.
I'm okay.
Thanks to this, even if it
was just for a short time,
she could fall asleep at a moment's notice.
Mommy?
What is it?
What really caused problems
was when we got sick.
Yuki?
Yuki--!
The pediatrician or the veterinarian--
she didn't know which one to take us to.
My daughter swallowed
some desiccant by mistake--
She's two years old.
Yes, she threw up.
There was no blood.
It says "silica gel" on it.
Um, is it dangerous...?
What? Her appetite?
I'm hungry!
Is that so? She's okay?
She regretted not asking Father
about how he was raised as a child.
I wanna go for a walk.
Yuki, that's--
Walk!
You were sick just a little while ago. So--
Okay, okay.
Now, put your ears away.
Okay, let's go for a walk!
I said, put your ears away!
Okay!
Hello. Aw, how cute.
He said you're cute. Isn't that nice?
Oh, sorry!
It's okay.
But that wasn't the only problem.
What time do you think it is?!
Shut him up!
I'm very sorry.
You keep making such
a racket night after night!
I'm really very sorry.
At least discipline your kids properly--!
Shh... It's okay.
The contract said pets
are not allowed here, didn't it?
I don't have any pets.
Don't lie to me.
I know what's going on.
If you think you can do whatever you want,
then I'll have no choice
but to have you go elsewhere.
You're caseworkers?
Yes, we have some serious
misgivings about your children.
What do you mean?
Our records show that they've
never had regular checkups or vaccines.
It's all right. They're healthy.
If that's the case, can
we at least see them?
No, that's--
Just a look will do.
We just want to see if
what you're saying is true or not.
You're not welcome--
If you don't let us in, you could
be suspected of abuse or neglect!
Please, leave!
Hey--
What is it, Mommy?
What do you want to do from now on?
Do you want to be human, or wolf?
Huh?
I'm thinking of moving.
So that you can choose
whichever one you want.
Ever since the town hall
started presenting unoccupied houses,
people who want to live
in the country have been coming steadily,
but they never last long.
As you can see, there's nothing here.
The elementary school and hospital
are both thirty minutes away by car.
The junior high is two and a half hours
by bus and train, one way.
That's five hours round trip!
No matter how much you want to raise
your children in a good environment--
The town is a lot more convenient,
in my opinion.
Wow...
It's so big...
And I know the rent is practically free,
but you know, the cost of repairs
is nothing to laugh at.
Instead of calling it an unoccupied house--
oh, you can keep your shoes on--
--it's more like an abandoned house.
But at least there's electricity,
and the mountain stream isn't dried out,
and they said you could use
whatever is in the shed.
That's a field, isn't it?
Oh, this place isn't really suitable
for growing your own food.
Animals come down from the mountains
and damage the crops.
Even if you make the effort
to grow vegetables, they'll all get eaten.
This place is full of unoccupied houses
because the humans are getting kicked out.
Then, the neighbors are--?
Neighbors? There isn't anyone around for miles.
Shall we look at a different place?
There might be a better
place near the village...
I've decided.
What?
I've decided on this place.
Why?
Wow! What is this place?
Our new home.
Oopsie daisy!
It's slanted!
Oh, hello Mr. Ant!
Wow, what's this?!
Stomp! Stomp!
How is it? Do you like it?
I like it!
I want to go home.
She said she wanted a place
with no neighbors close by.
She was a little different,
if you know what I mean.
What about her husband?
I don't know...
Her income?
I'm not sure...
Then how does she expect
to take care of her kids?
Oh, Grandpa Nirasaki!
We'll be in your care from now on.
Look, look! Mommy, look!
Tada--!
Come here, birdie--
C'mon, come here--
"Yuki - Age 5"
"Ame - Age 4"
Thank you very much.
Thank you.
Good evening.
Hey, wait, is that her?
Let's go--
Smash!
I guess we'll have to be
more frugal from now on.
Frugal?
I was just thinking that we should at least
be able to grow our own vegetables.
I'll help!
Wait here, okay?
Okay.
"Home Garden"
These please.
Okay.
These, too.
It's our little secret that
you two are wolf children.
Right.
If you were to suddenly become wolves,
everyone would be very surprised.
So you cannot become wolves
in front of other people.
Promise?
Promise!
And one more thing.
If you meet other animals in the mountains,
you can't act like you are better than them.
Why not?
Because Daddy will feel sad about it.
Okay?
Okay!
"'We'll never forgive you!' The angry
villagers chased after the wolf with guns."
"'I'm sorry! I won't do it again, '
the boastful wolf cried as he ran away."
Oh no!
Why?
I don't know. I wonder what happened...
Hello? Excuse me!
What?
Is it okay if I take
the fallen leaves from the woods?
What did you say?
The fallen leaves!
No one would ask
for permission to take that stuff!
Thank you very much!
I wonder how long she'll last.
She'll start talking about convenience
stores and karaoke soon enough.
You got that right.
I'll get it right this time...
Mom... my...
What?
Ame!
What happened?
You calico cat!
You're weak even though you're a wolf,
so they've got it in for you.
They're just scratches.
Nothing to worry about.
You won't be able to survive like that!
Yuki.
Do the "all better" thing.
All better, all better.
I wouldn't lose to a wild boar!
You saw a wild boar?
Yup, and a monkey and a serow.
But I wasn't scared at all.
It was fun when they ran away
when I chased them.
And--
Yuki.
And then when I peed--
Do you remember your promise?
That you wouldn't act like
you were better than the other animals?
But--
Please.
Fine.
Thank you.
Do the "all better" thing again.
All better, all better.
But, how do wolf children
become adults, anyway?
Yuki, wait!
Piggyback.
Already?
You're too slow! Hurry up!
"Wolves start learning to hunt
at around four months old.
First, they learn what hunting is
with mice and other small animals.
As they get older,
they form teams with adult wolves..."
We're a team!
No, we're not.
Fine, be that way.
Don't go too far!
I know!
Let's go home...
Ame, I wonder if this
wild grass is edible... Let's see...
I got it!
Got it!
Oh, look at that, Ame!
All better, all better.
Mommy, look at this! It's a cormorant!
There was a stream over there, and...
Shh...
Mommy...
Hmm?
Why is the wolf always the bad guy?
You mean, in the picture books?
Everyone hates them,
and they're always killed in the end...
If that's the case,
I don't want to be a wolf.
You're right. But you know,
Mommy likes wolves.
Even if everyone else hates the wolf,
I'll take the wolf's side.
Mommy! Mommy!
What's wrong?
They wilted again.
What?
Diseased... All of them? Don't tell me...
Mommy...
What's going to happen to us now?
Mommy's no good like this.
I've got to learn more!
Will you help me again?
Sure.
Thanks.
Go inside.
Okay.
Hello!
I was going to visit earlier,
but it got so busy around here...
It's hard to grow your own food, isn't it?
Even when I do what it says in the book,
I keep messing up.
But this is a nice place, isn't it?
With nature all around us.
Nature, ha!
Plants don't grow overnight, you know.
Huh?
At this rate, it'll be the same
no matter how many times you try.
Isn't that what you think?
T-That's...
Don't smile! Why do you smile?
Even if you smile,
you won't be able to do anything.
That person's scary.
No, it's Mommy's fault
for not knowing anything.
Even though you're an adult?
I should have asked
your Daddy about more things.
It's raining cats and dogs!
Hello...
Um...
Here, this is for you.
What are they?
Seed potatoes.
You mean the ones you plant in the fields?
Is there anything else
you can do with them?
Don't worry about what Dad said.
That's just how he is.
No, it was my fault.
Hello!
Sorry.
Don't worry about it.
Here.
Grandpa Nirasaki,
thank you for the seed potatoes.
Ah, are you trying to let them go to waste?
You have to start over from the soil.
You won't get anything
done hoeing like that.
I'm sorry...
Um, what about the fertilizer...?
Did you use leaves when
you prepared the soil?
Yes.
Then you don't need fertilizer.
When you're done, clear this field, too.
I don't need such a big field. I just
need to grow enough for my kids and me.
Did you hear me?
Yes...
Make ridges in the soil.
Okay.
Leave more space in between.
That's too low. Make them higher.
Okay.
In a week, plant them cut-side down.
Don't water them. Just leave them!
Um, thank you for teaching me how to...
Mommy, are you okay?
Ow...
Hello!
Come with us.
Huh?
It's okay, just come.
What?
Come on, let's go.
Hey--
Yes?
If you plant chamomile
and cabbage together,
bugs won't attack
and the flavors will be better.
No, you want celery with your cabbage.
No, no, it's better for
novices to use this.
NO, no! no!
You can't fill up a stomach on chamomile.
You should plant them shallowly like this.
No, you should water the hole
before you put anything in.
No, no, you can water them later.
Plant them first.
No, no, you're wrong.
You should just sprinkle
the extra fertilizer like this.
If you put too much,
it'll just bring more bugs.
No, give me that. You have to pile it on.
No, you only need a little.
If you do what this guy says,
you'll definitely fail.
That's you!
What?!
What did you say?!
Wood vinegar?
It's made from the smoke
when charcoal is produced.
And poultry manure.
There are instructions inside.
Thank you for coming all this way to help.
No, no.
Sorry about showing up
without warning like this.
It's no problem.
It's hard working the land
if you're not used to it, isn't it?
I still have a lot I have to learn.
There are a lot of city folks
who get discouraged
and leave right after moving here.
Other young people...?
Oh no, these were retired old men. It was
hilarious how weak they were mentally.
I don't know if it means anything if I say it, but
this isn't an easy place to live off the land.
The drainage isn't very good.
And we get a lot of snow.
We have to help each other.
We thought you didn't want
anything to do with the neighbors.
There are only a few young mothers around,
so it's nice to have someone else around.
Let us know if you have any questions.
Then“.
What? You're living off your savings?
But I need to start working soon.
It's hard to find work around here.
Everyone leaves their kids
at the preschool and commutes to work.
Right?
What's a preschool?
What?
Why don't Ame and I go?
--Well, that's because...
--I want to go to preschool, too!
No.
I wanna go!
No!
I wanna go I wanna go I wanna go...!
I wanna go!
I wanna go to the preschool...!
Yuki, hurry up and finish your food.
I know it's supposed to be a secret...
...but I can stay human.
But you know...
I can do it...
Y-Yuki...!
Hana, did you get a dog?
Um, yeah...
Isn't that a wolf?
--What? N-No, that's...
--isn't it, dear?
Don't be stupid!
There are no wolves in Japan anymore. That's
a shepherd mixed with something else.
Right, Hana? Am I right? Am I right?
Oh? The dog's gone.
Hello, Mrs. Nirasaki!
Oh hello, Yuki. Aren't you friendly today.
Oh, you and the dog have matching clothes!
That's cute.
Yu... Yuki...
What's wrong, Hana?
Hello?
Hello!
I wonder where Grandpa Nirasaki is...
Oh, these grew nicely.
It was thanks to everyone's help.
Ours were destroyed, so
this'll really help.
Destroyed? By what?
By a wild boar.
Here, take this.
This much--?
The boar, that bastard...
Oh, thank you for bringing this.
It came and dug everything up
without making a sound.
It came all the way down
to Sakai's fields this year.
Here, take this in return.
Watch out, it's heavy.
The only fields with
no animal damage are yours, Hana.
It's strange, even though
you're so deep in the mountains.
Do you have some kind of trick?
No, I don't...
Everyone wants to know how you did it.
What's a trick?
I need to pee!
Yuki's a lively child, isn't she?
Could it be...?
What is it?
Oh, no, never mind.
Wow, thank you very much.
Don't mention it.
Thanks for the potatoes.
It's been a while since we had eggs.
I'm glad to help.
Let me know when you run out!
Oh my, isn't that cute!
Hmm?
What?
Ready, lift.
Oh, you don't have to give us
something so big...
Don't worry about it.
It was just sitting in the storage shed.
But--
Please take it. If we bring it
back, Gramps'll get mad at us.
Grandpa Nirasaki?
He's always talking about you, Hana.
Because he's fallen for her.
Come on, he's already ninety.
But he even told everyone
to help her and everything.
Idiot! He said not to say anything
about that, remember?!
So that's what it was...?
I finally understand
why I needed a bigger field.
I don't like it.
What?
Why are you always smiling and laughing?
Don't laugh.
What's so funny?
We moved here trying
to get away from prying eyes...
When did we end up in the care
of the people from the village?
It was hard at first,
but I think we'll do fine here.
Wow, look at that!
M-Mommy--!
Mommy--! Mom--
Ame!
Mom! Ame's fallen--!
Mommy! Mommy--!
Ame!
Ame! Ame!
Ame“!
Mom... my...
Ame!
Ame... Ame!
A-Ame!
Open your eyes! Ame!
Open your eyes!
Ame, Ame, Ame...
Open your eyes...
Mommy... That's... too tight...
Ame!!
You know what?
I found a crested kingfisher.
It was a really nice-looking bird.
I felt like even I could catch it today.
It was completely different
from how it usually feels.
I wasn't scared. Suddenly,
I felt like I could do anything.
So then, I--
Why are you crying?
What are we doing here?
Mother said later that she had
never been more frightened in her life.
After that incident, Ame seemed
like a completely different person.
"Yuki - Age 6" "Ame
- Age 5" "Yuki - Age 5"
However--
No matter what happens--
I won't turn into a wolf. I know already!
Don't forget your promise!
I'll be fine!
Then remember,
"Piggy promise, promise kept."
What's that?
It's a charm to keep you
from becoming a wolf.
A charm?
♪ Piggy promise, promise kept.♪
That's how you do it.
Piggy...
...promise, promise kept.
♪ Piggy promise, promise kept! ♪
♪ Piggy promise, promise kept.♪
Hurry UP!
It was the first time in my life
that I had ever been surrounded
by so many people.
--Don't push me!
--I had wanted to go so badly...
--Stop pushing me!
--...but when it finally came down to it,
I wasn't sure if I would be okay or not.
But that was just at the beginning.
Daddy, I'm off!
I'm going now!
Okay, be careful.
I will!
'Morning, Shino!
Good morning, Yuki!
I saved you a seat!
Thanks!
"1st Grade"
"2nd Grade"
Who knows the answer to this question?
--I do!
--I do! I do! I do! I do! I do!
No running in the halls!
--You can do it!
--Go, Yuki!
Wow, Yuki!
--You're so fast!
--You're amazing!
"Townspeople Division"
This is...
"Niikawa Nature Sanctuary"
"Nature Conservationist Assistant Wanted"
"Hometown Nature"
Thank you for waiting. Shall we go?
My name is Tendo, and I
am a nature conservationist.
Welcome to Niikawa Nature Sanctuary.
I look forward to working with you.
A nature conservationist's job
is not just to protect nature.
Environmental education, field surveys,
the conservation of plants and animals--
These three pillars of conservancy are made
possible by the support of volunteers.
We do many different types of work,
so while we are specialists,
we also need to be able to do
a little of everything.
So, we are looking for someone who can help
the conservationist with all the work, but...
Honestly speaking, we can't pay very much.
We can pay enough to cover training expenses
for someone studying
to become a conservationist,
but we can't afford much more than that.
A high schooler's part-time job
pays a lot more per hour.
Even knowing all that...
...do you still want to do it?
Um... I heard that you have a wolf here...
This is our timber wolf.
He's very quiet.
He's not that young anymore.
Excuse me, Director--?
Excuse me for a moment.
Nice to meet you. I came
because I have something to ask you.
He's a wolf's child.
His father, the wolf, died.
I'm his mother,
but I don't know how to raise a wolf.
How did you learn the ways of the wolf?
Will you tell us how
you were raised in the forest?
Sorry about that.
A wealthy person got
special permission to keep him as a pet,
but when the owner died there was no one
to take him, so he came to live with us.
Apparently, he was born in the Moscow Zoo.
So he isn't from the wild?
I think it's rare to see
wild wolves in zoos.
If they're bred, the babies
are sent out to be fostered.
There are also wild birds and raccoon dogs
who are brought here when they get hurt.
After we treat them--
I'm going to start coming here from now on.
Ame, you'll be okay coming with me, right?
I'll learn about
the mountains and nature as I work,
and teach you the things I learn.
It was my first time seeing a real one.
A wolf?
Was Daddy like that, too?
No, not at all.
I'm glad.
Why?
Because he seemed kind of sad, somehow.
I wanted to meet Daddy.
Mommy wants to see him again, too.
As Mother settled into her new job,
I was undergoing a huge shock.
Bunko, yours is so nice!
Keno, yours is pretty, too!
I found a four-leaf clover!
Me, too!
Yuki, did you find anything?
Yeah, look!
I found out that no other girls
played with rat snakes for fun.
Look, these used to be my mom's.
They're so pretty.
My parents bought this for me
for my last birthday.
Lucky!
Yuki, show us your treasure box, too!
Okay!
Ooh, what's inside?
Look!
I was also the only girl who collected
small animal bones and dried reptiles.
The moment I realized
that other girls didn't do those things,
I was so embarrassed.
Hurry UP!
That was when I decided.
From then on, I was going to act
more graceful and ladylike.
Don't laugh! I'm seriously
worrying about this!
Why don't you just do what you want, Yuki?
I don't want people looking at me funny!
I guess it can't be helped.
Huh?
When Mother made a new dress for me,
I remember being really happy.
Good morning.
Thanks to the dress,
I was able to fit in with my class
--and get along with my friends.
--Good morning!
Good morning!
Oh, Yuki, your dress is so cute!
It's wonderful!
--Lucky! --Heaven only knows
how much that dress helped me.
--Okay! --Heaven only knows how
much that dress helped me.
The next year,
it was hard to get Ame to school.
Get it? It's "Piggy promise, promise kept."
School's this way!
"Happy first day of school!"
"1st Grade"
"Let's get along!"
"2nd Grade"
"Full of energy!"
"1st Grade"
"Let's be friends!"
"2nd Grade"
"Please and Thank You"
"3rd Grade"
"Let's fly together!"
"4th Grade"
"Let's figure it out!"
"3rd Grade"
Good morning.
Oh, Ame, is it a school holiday?
No.
So you're skipping?
Yeah.
You can come here anytime.
Sorry for always bringing him here.
--Yes, this is the observation pond.
--Ah, you're going bird-watching.
--You can see frogs that still have their tails.
--One moment, please. You'll find it...
--Hana, can you help me for a sec?
--...over there on your right.
Coming!
Attention, everyone!
Let me introduce a transfer student.
This is Sohei Fujii.
Why don't you greet everyone?
I'm Sohei. Nice to meet you.
Nice to meet you!
Hey, do you have dogs at your house?
Huh? Why?
You smell kind of like animals.
We don't have any dogs.
Really? That's weird.
I totally thought you had dogs.
What is it?
Huh? Oh, the smell--
Smell? What smell?
Maybe it's just my imagination...
Which one should I pick...?
I'll go with this one!
Aw man, seriously?
Oh, Yuki!
Yuki, you should come join us.
Sohei's funny.
Oh, I have to return this book.
What's up with her?
She's not usually like that...
Hey, Yuki, you know--
Oh, Yuki--
You know what?
Hey. Yuki!
Yuki--
C'mon, Yuki--
Tell me the truth!
About what?
Did I do something to you?
You didn't do anything.
Do you dislike me
because I'm a transfer student?
That's it, isn't it?
I said, it's nothing.
Then why are you avoiding me?
I'm not avoiding you!
Piggy promise, promise kept.
--Piggy--
--Hey!
Wait!
Piggy promise, promise kept.
Stop following me!
Don't come any closer!
What are you doing?
Don't touch me!
Yuki! Yuki!
"Tsururindo"
Sorry to bother you during work.
Do you know how much
his head was bleeding?
It was my ear.
Yuki.
She wouldn't talk no matter
what we asked her...
Were you really the one who hurt him?
Did you apologize?
Apologize.
I said, apologize.
I'm sorry.
I'm very sorry for what my child has done.
That's how it is, Mrs. Fujii.
There is the school's insurance
for the medical bills, so--
Do you really think this can be
taken care of with just an apology?!
What were you planning to do
if he lost his hearing?
Parents are responsible
for their children's actions, aren't they?
Would you go into debt
or sell your house to compensate us?
Now, now, this isn't the place to--
If you don't let me
hear what she's thinking, I'll--
A wolf.
What?
It was a wolf that did it.
A wolf did it.
Sohei?
What are you saying?
Sohei!
Sohei?
Don't decide whose fault it is already!
I know!
She's been different lately--
Sum it!
That's what I thought.
What happened to Sohei?
He left early.
Why?
Because he got hurt.
How did he get hurt?
That's--
Who hurt him?
Um...
Yuki!
--Yuki!
--I thought it was her.
--Thought so.
--What's wrong?
I'm like a detective--
Quiet! Everyone, quiet down!
It didn't work.
No matter how many times I tried the charm.
Will I be chased out of school?
Will we have to leave our house?
I'm sorry...
I'm sorry!
Mom, I'm sorry!
All better, all better.
"School Bus"
Sohei?
Homework. From Sohei.
From Sohei.
Ow...
Sohei!
She went to play at Shino's house today.
I see...
Oh, wait a minute.
You came a long way, didn't you?
Thank you for coming by every day.
I don't want Yuki to stop coming to school.
You know, that day,
you said that a wolf did it, right?
What did you mean by that?
That was... I mean...
You might not believe me, but that
day, I saw a wolf for a split second,
and when I came to, I was bleeding.
So the wolf was the one who did it.
I mean, it wasn't Yuki's fault.
I know other kids
are saying stupid things, but...
I see.
Can I ask you one more thing?
Do you hate wolves?
Not really.
Me neither.
Hey, you wanna see this?
What?
It's cool, isn't it? Wanna touch it?
Here.
Does it hurt?
It itches.
Let's go!
I'm going now.
Where are you going?
I'm going to Sensei's place.
Who's Sensei?
Sensei... is Sensei.
I see. Will you be okay by yourself?
Yeah.
Be careful.
Okay.
Don't stay out too late.
Where's Yuki?
She went back to school today.
Oh, that's good.
What about Ame?
He comes and goes, I guess.
That's fine.
There's something to be said
for a guy who stops
going to school in elementary school.
Edison and I were both like that.
There you go, saying such
irresponsible things again!
Speaking of which,
does anyone live on the mountain?
On the mountain?
Ame said he was going to Sensei's place...
I was sure he was talking
about Grandpa Nirasaki, but...
I don't know about that...
No one would go into the mountains
during the busy farming season.
Sensei knows everything.
He knows everything about the mountain.
I didn't think you'd make friends
with someone older than you.
Bring him over to our house sometime.
I want to thank him, and--
Sensei doesn't meet with humans.
He doesn't come down to the village
like the wild boars and bears.
But it's probably okay if it's you, Mom.
Sensei is the master
of the entire mountain in these parts.
Thank you for always taking care of Ame.
"Hometown Nature"
You can take a bath now.
Yuki, you should have
Sensei teach you, too.
Your hunting will get a lot better.
There's a trick to running
through the forest at full speed.
And to reading the terrain, too.
You'll learn a lot.
How to find water and how
to read the weather,
and marking your territory
and getting along with others--
There's no way I'm going.
Why not?
What about you?
Why won't you come to school?
Because the mountain's interesting.
Because there's a lot I don't know.
I don't need to know.
Why not?
Just come to school already.
I don't want to.
Why not?
Because I'm a wolf.
You're a human.
I'm a wolf.
I've already decided not to become a wolf.
Why not?
Hey, Why not?
Because I'm human! Do you hear me?!
Because I'm human!
But Why?
Stop asking so many questions!
You're a wolf, aren't you?
Why don't you act like one?
Shut up! You don't know anything!
About what?
If you don't come to school tomorrow,
I'll never forgive you!
I'm not going!
Wanna fight?
What is it? What's that sound?
Yuki! Ame!
Stop it, both of you!
Stop it, Yuki! Ame!
Yuki...
Ame...?
Ame...
Yuki and Ame are both
starting to walk their own paths.
Even though that's what I wanted...
Why am I so uneasy?
Why is that?
My last summer in elementary school, there
were a number of record-breaking storms.
Ame started to go
into the mountains all the time.
He seemed to be very worried
about the effects of the heavy rains
on Sensei and the plants
and animals of the mountains.
Ame!
Where have you been all this time?
You're cold. Hang on,
I'll get the bath ready.
Sensei... hurt his leg, and he can't move.
He'll probably die soon.
Someone has to take over all the things
he has been doing on the mountain.
Ame.
You can't go into the mountains anymore.
Do you understand?
You're only ten years old.
You're still a child!
Even if a ten-year-old wolf is an adult,
you're still--
Please.
Please don't go into the mountains anymore.
Please... For me.
C'mon! Over here!
Shoot it! Pass it!
--By the way, did you know?
--Know what?
And?
They said Sohei's mom...
...is getting married!
--What?
--No way!
Why?
Probably because she's beautiful.
Then Sohei will have a new dad?
That's good.
But Sohei doesn't know about this yet.
What?
“No Way!
--Really?
You can't tell anyone about this!
All right! Yes!
How many points do we have now?
Good morning.
Today, it will be sunny during the day,
but heavy rain will start
in the evening and continue overnight.
--It's so humid! --Please use caution
if you go out during this time.
First, the meteorological report.
Yuki--
--Hm? --Today will start mostly sunny with high
atmospheric pressure within the prefecture,
--Stay with Mom. --but the weather
front will extend to the Sea of Japan,
--You'll miss the bus-- --causing stormy
weather from the evening into the night.
--You stay at home with her.
--And now for the regional forecast.
--Take care! --In the northwest region,
it will be sunny followed by rain,
with lightning in some parts.
The southwest region
will be sunny followed by rain.
--Ame? --The northeast region will
be sunny with scattered showers.
--Ame! --The southeast region will
--Don't forget your umbrellas
when you go out today.
So the problem is asking, how far
can the swallow fly in three hours?
First of all, do you know
what seventy km/h means?
If you take seventy km,
km/h means the number
of kilometers traveled per hour.
So in one hour,
the swallow can fly seventy kilometers.
The weather front along
the Sea of Japan is moving south,
and atmospheric conditions
have become extremely unstable.
Because of this,
there will be lightning and sudden gusts
accompanying the heavy rains.
Predicted rainfall is,
depending on the location,
over seventy mm per hour in the flat areas,
and near the mountains,
over one hundred mm per hour.
The weather station has issued
a heavy rain flood warning.
Use extreme caution due to possible landslides,
rises in river level, submersion of buildings,
as well as other damage.
And now, for today's
eleven o'clock weather alerts.
In the northwest region,
heavy rain, lightning, and flood warnings.
Have a seat, everyone. Sit down!
It looks like there will be
severe rainstorms soon,
so afternoon classes have been canceled.
Yay!
Until they come, gather in the gym
according to where you live.
A blackout?
I have to go.
I understand. I'll head over now.
Ame, let's go pick up Yuki together.
Ame?
Where are you?
Ame!
Where are you, Ame?!
Takahiro?
Mommy!
Keiko!
Daddy!
♪ Yankee Doodle came to town-- ♪
My parents sure are late.
Don't worry.
But--
If we have to stay at the school overnight,
we can play cards all night.
Cards?
I wanna play.
Oh, that sounds like fun!
It'll be like camp!
I'll go get the cards from the classroom.
Okay.
Do you even know how to play cards?
I only know how to play Old Maid.
Stupid!
Don't fight, you two.
Shino!
Oh, Dad!
You're so late.
Sorry, sorry. It's a raging storm out there.
Yuki, we can take you home, too.
Oh yeah, let's go, Yuki.
But--
C'mon, hurry up.
Thank you for offering,
but I think my mom will be here soon.
You don't have to hold back.
Yeah.
I don't want to miss my mom when she comes.
That's true. We'll leave first, then.
Bye!
Bye.
Ame!
Where are you? Ame!
Ame...
Where...?
Sou's taking a long time.
Yuki--
What, did Yuki go home already?
Attention everyone!
We'll take everyone that's left
home in the school's car.
Ame!
Wait!
Wait, Ame!
Ame...
Where are you...?
Why are you here?
Because...
...you were being slow.
Oh, no one's here.
Did everyone go home already?
I guess we're the only ones
not getting picked up.
I wonder if something happened to my mom.
It's cold.
Let's walk around.
Yuki.
Oh, wait for me!
What'll we do if no one
comes to pick us up?
We can just live at school.
We can't do that.
We can sleep in the
nurse's office at night.
What about food?
We can eat leftover cafeteria food.
What if no one ever comes to pick us up?
Will you live at school forever?
I just have to get a job.
Delivering newspapers or something.
You're just a kid. No
one's going to hire you.
I'll lie about my age.
I'll tell them that I'm in middle school.
Do I look like a middle schooler?
No.
Really?
I want to grow up faster.
Me too.
Ame...
He's probably shivering somewhere...
He's probably lost... crying...
I have to... protect... him...
I have to... protect...
Is anyone still here?
He's gone.
My heart's still pounding.
Hey, why did we hide?
Hey!
It's like the ocean.
I feel like it's going to suck me in.
Will we really end up living here secretly?
If our parents don't come,
then we have no choice, do we?
Why? Your morn will come for sure.
No, she won't.
Why not? She's...
My mom got married.
And she's having a baby. So once it's
born, I won't be needed anymore.
But she was so worried about you...
I'm fine with that, though.
I'll run away from home
and become a boxer or a wrestler.
I'll live like a lone wolf.
What do you think? Will it work?
You'll be defeated in a second.
You have no muscles.
I'll train.
I'll train and live on my own.
Sou, I want to be like you,
and be able to smile
even when I'm telling the truth.
Sou...
That day,
the wolf that hurt you was me...
It was me.
I kept thinking that I
had to say something.
It hurt to hold it in.
I already knew. I knew the whole time.
I didn't tell anyone your secret.
I won't tell. So...
...don't cry anymore.
I'm not crying, these are drops of rain.
Thank you.
Ame... Where did you go?
Ame?
Ame.
I was looking for you.
Come on, hurry back
so we can go pick up Yuki...
Hana.
I missed you so much!
It's been hard, hasn't it?
I'm sorry.
It's okay.
I was watching you the whole time.
Yeah, I know.
You raised our children well.
No, that's not true. I keep messing up.
It's true.
Yuki and Ame have both grown up fine.
That's not true. Because...
Oh... Ame...
That's right. Ame's gone.
Ame!
Ame's fine.
But...
He's fine.
He's already an adult.
An adult?
He's found his own world.
Ame?
Oh, Ame!
Are you going to leave?
But...
I still haven't been able
to do anything for you.
I still haven't...
But you're still...
Wait!
Ame!
Ame...!
Ame...
Be well...
Live a good life!
Goodbye.
Mother said that she
would never forget that morning.
The freshly washed beech leaves...
The freshly washed spider webs...
The freshly washed sky...
Everything glittering under the sun...
Like the world had been reborn overnight.
That was what Mother thought.
"Municipal Junior High School
Entrance Ceremony"
Looking back on the twelve years
she spent raising us,
Mother smiled, saying that it was
over in a moment, like a fairy tale.
"Junior High"
Mother is living quietly
in that mountain house even now.
"Ame"
"The Forest is Alive"
"I hope to meet you soon,"
I always prayed as I rubbed my belly
(Ooh ooh) What will you look like?
(Ooh ooh) What will you sound like?
I see my reflection in your big eyes
As teardrops spill onto your cheeks
(Num nums) Come here, the food's ready!
(Pitter patter) Come on,
let's go for a walk!
Your eyes swollen, you sit
with your arms around your knees
Tell me why you're crying,
tell me everything
Don't worry, I'm not going anywhere
No matter what happens, we'll be together
I love your smiling face
It makes me feel better, even when I'm down
(Lalala lalala) Come here, let's sing!
(Aroo aroo) Come on,
let's raise our voices together!
I want you to grow up brightly and freely
Running in the snow, counting clouds
Playing in the rain,
being blown by the wind
Buried under flowers, playing grass kazoos
On four feet, on two feet
A new morning
A new wind
Prepared just for you
A new morning
A new light
The world is yours for the taking
A new morning
A new rainbow
The world is full of mystery
Choosing one of two paths,
eyes fixed on a point far away
Is there nothing else I can do for you?
Whenever you decide to leave,
I will see you off with a smile
(Ooh ooh) But I'll still be a little sad
(Aroo aroo) Please, live a good life