ｩ
ｩ P
ｩ P@
ｩ P@r
ｩ P@rM
ｩ P@rM!
ｩ P@rM!N
ｩ P@rM!Nd
ｩ P@rM!Nde
ｩ P@rM!NdeR
ｩ P@rM!NdeR M
ｩ P@rM!NdeR M@
ｩ P@rM!NdeR M@n
ｩ P@rM!NdeR M@nk
ｩ P@rM!NdeR M@nkﾖ
ｩ P@rM!NdeR M@nkﾖﾖ
ｩ P@rM!NdeR M@nkﾖﾖ ・
Mobile - +919815899536
EMail - parminder222536@hotmail.com
You know, Paan Singh killed...
nine Gujjars in broad daylight.
He was avenging his brother's death.
And the cops are completely helpless now.
What can the cops do anyway?
If the cops are east...
then Paan Singh is west.
They say that he used to be in the Army.
Hey, give me a cigarette...
The entire packet.
Here's, your money.
There's some hanky-panky going on!
You look pretty pleased.
You ain't seen nothing yet!
Look out for my photo on the first page of the newspaper.
If it is not printed...
then I'll eat the food you feed your dogs.
Why?
Have you joined Paan Singh's gang?
How do you know this?
Keep it to yourself!
- The guy wearing the blue shirt?
- Yes.
Yes?
Greetings.
Is he the journalist?
Yes.
I hope he won't squeal.
Not at all.
He's an army man.
He is very particular about punctuality.
Absolutely.
Till the task is completed the girl stays with us.
My dear...
stay here with uncle...
just for a little while.
He'll give you sweets.
You'll get your favourite sweet!
He'll also show you your favourite movie.
Is that okay?
Please look after her.
Excuse me...
hold on...
Please keep this with you and take care of her.
Let's go?
Is my sister safe here?
That depends on you.
Come on.
Come...
The journalist is here, Subedaar.
I've frisked him.
Listen, brother...
How do I address him?
Does 'sir' sound fine?
Or...
S... S... S...
Subedaar?
Thank you, Subedaar...
for consenting to meet me.
This interview...
is very important to me.
Hey...
- What are you doing?
- What the...
My n... n...
I was just taking out my notebook.
The way you moved your hands...
I thought you had a bomb in there.
Let it be.
Sir, I'm downstairs.
Sit down.
Any difficulty in sitting on the floor?
You are way younger than I am!
You are Major Chauhan's nephew?
Yes sir, he's my uncle.
Why aren't you in the army?
Sir, I...
I'm passionate about writing.
With your blessings I hope to become a well known writer.
You work at leisure and it shows on your body!
Get rid of it.
From tomorrow, start running four kilometres, everyday.
Huh?
Say, 'from tomorrow'.
From t... t... tomorrow.
- Say properly, 'from tomorrow'.
- From tomorrow.
Shall we begin, sir?
How did you become a dacoit?
Are you a qualified journalist or still training?
Don't you know the customs of this locality?
In the ravines we're called rebels.
Dacoits are found in the parliament.
P... p... p...
Forget it. The session's over.
- N... no...
- Take your stuff and leave.
- Subedaar, I... I... I'm sorry...
- I said it's over.
It's over.
What I meant was...
your c... career...
I mean...
When did you pick up the gun for the first time?
That's the question.
The British fled...
and then...
Pandit Nehru became the Prime Minister.
With a new beginning for India...
I too started a new chapter in my life.
Ramcharan, look who's coming this way?
Daughter-in-law come here.
Who is that?
Who is he?
Look who's coming!
My son is home.
He is an army man now!
Look what I brought for you.
If not us at least think about your wife.
I'm sorry, forgive me.
Apologise to your wife!
Now, can I get something to eat?
Let me help you.
Don't bother!
I'm used to staying alone.
Don't spoil me.
If you are so used to it then I'll go back tomorrow.
Fine...
you leave, and I'll jump into the well.
You've been hiding here.
You're a good runner.
Just like a rooster.
Okay... swift as a cat!
I've organised a village discourse...
everyone is busy out there.
Look at me.
Did you also think I had died?
Don't say that.
I had shown your horoscope to the priest.
He said, you were a born wanderer.
But I knew...
no matter what...
you would come back to me.
This is the army, not a government office...
where you can do as you please.
Why are you late by two days?
Sir, my mother was ill.
Sir, I was getting married.
The Army comes first, and family later.
And you?
Sir, I had to harvest the standing crop.
Soon you won't be standing either!
Run ten rounds with luggage on your head.
Left, right, left.
Attention!
Ten...
I did ten rounds, sir.
You think I'm an idiot?
I'm a fast runner.
I have no problem with running.
Great, then run another ten rounds.
With or without my luggage, sir?
Rakesh...
Who is this guy?
He's a new recruit, Paan Singh Tomar.
For the first time I've seen someone enjoying his punishment.
That's 37 rupees.
How will you manage with just two rupees?
The military takes care of my needs.
My wife has just
delivered a baby girl.
Congratulations!
I need to take care of their needs now.
Do you eat to live?
Or live to eat?
This is the bread for living...
and this is the bread for eating.
Take some?
Take it.
Paan Singh...
this is a battalion, not a bachelor's party.
We're short on supplies and you will starve us to death.
I have a large appetite.
Get into sports, there is no dearth of food there.
Bye, ma'am.
Have a great time in Gwalior.
The British left behind two great things, sir.
First is discipline...
and the second is ice-cream.
I've got some for you.
Take some home, ma'am will love it.
No, no...
By the time I get home...
it will become a milkshake!
Sir...
Take me into sports.
There is no restriction on food there.
Sports?
Which sport?
Anything, sir.
I even run very fast.
Oh really?
Yes, I love to run.
Fine, if you deliver this ice-cream to the Major's house...
before it melts!
Then you are a sportsman.
The address, sir?
The Major has sent this.
You can check it's not melted.
What is the time now?
It's nine o'clock.
Why?
Tell him I was here in four minutes.
What?
Paan Singh... run!!
You're supposed to run at the signal...
not recite a prayer, you idiot!
Now run!
He is one who delivered the ice cream in four minutes!
Congratulations, Paan Singh!
You're the runner-up.
Sir, are these for the athletes?
Paan Singh has potential.
But he wants to be a sportsman to satisfy his hunger!
Don't think he is interested in sports.
Hit it hard.
Harder, now.
Load them up.
My father fought against the British...
and he sent me here...
to serve the country.
I can't do this.
I can't operate a gun.
You are an idiot.
Say, 'yes'.
Say 'yes'.
Yes, sir.
It's easy.
Strap on the gun...
shut one eye...
aim at your target and pull the trigger.
It's as simple as that.
What's going on here?
He's new here.
I'm teaching him to shoot.
He's new here...
and you were born with a gun?
The gun and I share a long relationship.
My uncle owns four Mark-3 guns.
Is that so?
Then show me your skills.
Nobody else fires!
On your feet!
Sir.
Where are you from?
From Bhidosa, in Morena district.
I see, the Chambal Valley.
Dacoit area!
Not dacoits. They are rebels.
My uncle was a rebel too, and a respected one.
The cops have not been able to nab him.
Recruit Paan Singh...
was your uncle a dacoit?
Not a dacoit.
He was a rebel.
He was a good man.
Stick to the question.
There are no records...
but have you ever been to jail?
Not even my uncle.
The police cannot catch us.
I asked you to stick to the question.
Do you trust the government?
No, sir, the government is a crook.
That's why, I'm in the Army and not a government servant.
Except the army, everyone is a swindler.
Can you give your life for your country?
Yes, and I can take lives too.
This country is our motherland...
If anyone dares harm my mother, how can I bear it?
The Army means discipline.
You need to obey the orders of your officer.
Will you obey every order?
Sir, I'm a fourth grade drop out.
I've learnt more from experience than books.
If an officer like you gives me an order...
I'd give up my life.
But, sir, a few officers here are just for namesake.
They are good for nothing.
I'm not too sure about their orders.
Sir, let me talk to him.
Major Masand, this is the man you were recommending.
Have you heard what he is saying?
He shouldn't even be here.
I still have my doubts.
I'm trying to understand.
Sir, what he is trying to say is something different...
Did I say something wrong, sir?
Paan Singh, it's okay.
You may wait outside.
Check out his attitude.
He's got a rebel for an uncle.
Great!
- Army officers are useless.
- Sir...
He is the best recipe for a mutiny!
We have to do something about him.
I have an idea...
we should send him to the Army Physical Training Centre.
He can run as much as he wants to.
That will cool his temper.
We should use him to our advantage.
You haven't seen him run yet.
Good morning...
Looks like you stepped out of bed and onto the ground!
- Good morning, sir.
- Good morning...
Greetings Gurveer, everything okay?
Greetings to you too.
Done with the warm up?
It makes no difference to me.
I'm always ready.
All of you here, for the 5000 metre race.
Everyone on your feet!
Let's begin the race!
- Jai Hind, coach.
- Jai Hind!
Aren't you from Bengal Engineers?
Yes, sir.
You want to run the 5000 metre?
Let's go.
What's your name?
My name is Paan Singh Tomar, sir.
Athletes... on your mark!
- Jai Hind, sir.
- Jai Hind!
Hold on, Paan Singh.
I need to talk to you.
About what?
I need to discuss something very important.
Come along.
Don't mind my words.
- Greetings, coach.
- Greetings.
I suggest you don't run the 5000 metres race.
Don't run?!
Not take part in the 5000 metre race?
But I've been sent here for this race.
I have other plans for you.
You are a good runner, with a good stamina.
You should run a different race.
All these months that's what I've been practicing for.
The Defence Meet is in two months...
where I have to win a medal.
Why are you stuck on the Defence Meet?
I want to make you a national champion.
So why not in 5000 metres?
Listen to me.
If you run the 5000 metre, Gurveer will lose...
How does this concern me?
Listen...
My daughter is married to Gurveer's brother.
My daughter is already suffering.
If Gurveer loses, his brother will...
take it out on my daughter.
I get it, coach.
Since this concerns my teacher's daughter...
I can run on hot coals now.
Bless you, my son.
Not fire, you will run on water.
On water?
You will run the steeplechase!
Steeplechase.
Yes, sir.
I will run.
Earlier, the steeplechase was a race meant for horses.
Later, this was introduced into athletics.
Watch carefully...
There are 28 hurdles.
And 7 water pits, which you have to cross to finish the race.
If horses and donkeys can do it
then you are way better than them!
Praise the Lord!
Very good.
Remember you're training for the National Games.
Now, the last track and field event.
The 3000 metre steeplechase.
Athletes on your mark!
Use your stamina wisely.
Why do you keep looking behind you?
Do you think you're in a wedding procession?
What's wrong?
Sir, I'm thirsty.
I'd like some water.
Have you lost it?
It's a race, not a pissing competition!
Paan Singh, if you lose this race, you motherfucccr...
I will bury you right here in this ground.
What are you doing?!
- The time?
- It's 9:12:04.
You clocked 9:12:04.
A new national record.
Congratulations...
this is unbelievable!
You're the national champion.
You broke the record.
I knew you were champion material!
What's the matter?
Aren't you happy?
Coach, the thing is...
you are my teacher.
But next time you shout at me...
don't abuse my mother!
You know it's a habit, Paan Singh.
I also have a habit.
I pull the trigger when I hear abuses.
I love my mother a lot.
Hanumanta, go get some lemon toffees.
The shop here is no good.
You get better ones near the bus stop.
Take your sister along.
I didn't get anything for you.
Can you make something sweet?
I have some good news to share.
Tell me the good news, then I'll make the sweets.
What if I don't like the news?
I have been promoted.
You are now the wife of a Subedaar.
I broke the National record.
What have you broken this time?
Every time you go out, you break something.
Idiot! When will you learn?
I haven't broken anything. It means...
I've set a new time record.
Really?
How would I know that?
Let me go... no don't!
Let me go...
I said no!
They're sending me abroad.
Tokyo, Japan.
Major athletes from Asia will be present.
What do you want from Tokyo?
Come.
- Going abroad?
- Yes.
What do you want?
I don't like the way you run in shorts.
The women stare at you.
Should I run in my pajamas?
What if I bring home a Japanese wife?
Which well will you jump into?
I'll lie down on the rail tracks.
Let me just kill you then.
Shall I?
The kids will be here.
No...
No... don't...
Let go!
Water... drinking water?
Coach...
do I need to wear these?
Of course, it's necessary.
Coach, with these nails, the shoes will dig into the earth.
- They are called spikes.
- What?
Spikes! Come on...
Indian athletes will participate without spikes?
Why didn't you give these for practice?
I've been running wearing canvas shoes.
Now, you're giving these to me and that too, at the competition.
So, the world should mock Indian athletes?
Look at the other athletes.
Why should I?
They get good food and all the facilities.
You expect us to win a medal on two egg yolks?!
What's your point?
Whatever you want to make of it!
Don't act smart!
Get it?
Wear the shoes and take your position.
Come on... you will definitely win!
Move it!
That day I lost the race.
I regret it to this day.
And I always will.
Don't be upset.
I had to take my shoes off.
It's okay.
They don't give us facilities.
They just keep asking for medals.
You know English?
I don't understand what they are saying.
You handle it.
Sir, could you please tell us your name?
Oh?!
Paan Singh Tomar.
Paan Singh Tomar, India.
India.
Paan Singh I love you.
She is in love with you.
All he's brought back is dirty clothes!
How is she?
She's nice.
Just nice?
He has me to clean up after him.
Did he go there for a medal or a new wife!
I'd almost decided on settling there.
What stopped you?
Your cooking!
The food there is terrible!
No difference between a dog and a duck.
All you remembered, was my cooking!
Hanu, get some lemon toffee.
They are not going anywhere.
Sit right here.
Here is the money.
I said, you will not go.
Let the kids go.
They aren't going!
- Let them eat the toffee
- I said, you will not go.
Didn't you hear me?
You won't go!
Lemon toffees, my foot!
They aren't going anywhere!
Hanu, time you took a break from studying.
Go out for a while and get my clothes from the tailor.
Take your sister along.
She needs a new dress.
Don't hurry with the measurements.
So, you put the kids to work?!
Were you really going to bring that Japanese woman here?
Absolutely.
You don't even like me running, and she is crazy about it.
Look at this.
Look at me.
One second...
What are you doing?
This is how it's done abroad.
Stupid girl!
Abroad, what they do is...
here... right here and then...
This is the moment...
to show your valour...
and die for your country which is every soldier's dream.
Soldiers...
you have undergone rigorous training...
and now it's time to show your strength.
They have started the war but we will end it!
Promise your motherland that...
before you become a martyr, you will kill ten of the enemy!
- 51...
- Victory!
- The code will be Bravo.
- Yes, sir.
- G. S reservation.
The Battalion moves at 1500 hours.
- Any doubt?
- No, sir.
Move.
Victory to India.
Sir.
Paan Singh... at ease.
Yes?
Sir, why can't I go to the battlefront?
It's an Army rule.
Athletes are not sent to the front.
I have a point...
I won't be able to face my people in the village...
Sir, please!
The army can take all my medals...
I'm ready to forego sports.
I cannot lose this opportunity.
Let me go there once, please.
You will stay right here.
Move.
What happened, Paan Singh?
Not coming to the front?
On sick leave?
- 51...
- Victory!
The war of 1965 took place and they said...
athletes are the nation's precious treasure.
And they won't be sent to war.
I desperately wished I could do away with the rule.
My wish of defeating the enemy did not die out...
and I got my chance.
In the year 1967.
At the International Defence Meet.
He's lost it.
Sir, explain it to him.
There are athletes half his age.
He'll definitely lose.
It's impossible to explain this to him.
He wasn't able to fight in the war...
so now, this is his battlefield.
Sir, this is the International Defence Athletic Meet...
not a battlefield.
For him it is!
So, Paan Singh?
You are participating in an international meet.
You've grown older.
What if you lose?
You didn't send me to the battlefield...
To put my life at stake
Now with my self respect at stake,
the playground will be my battleground.
That was the most important race of my life.
There was no record involved...
- but that race...
- Excuse me?
- Will you help me with this?
- Sure.
The biggest race.
Will you eat something?
The mutton looks delicious.
Why did he eat it first?
This is how my life is.
I need to be alert 24 hours.
If it is poisoned, the person who eats first, dies.
Okay.
The meat is absolutely delicious.
Don't be shy, have some.
Okay.
Now I can proclaim that I have dined with you.
Let it be.
Meat is not good for you.
Start running, lose some weight.
- Then you can eat it.
- Right.
Go on.
I can continue talking.
Okay.
When did you leave the Army?
In the recently concluded International Defence Games...
Subedaar Paan Singh Tomar, broke his own record...
in the 3000 metre steeplechase race,
to establish a brand new record.
It means, he broke his own record.
Oh, okay.
What's going on here?
Now what is that no-good brother of yours up to?
What do you mean, Bhanwar Singh?
He's your cousin as well.
So what has he done?
Paan is the national champion again.
He's got a gold medal.
A coward's job is to keep running.
What's the big deal?
What are you saying?
Why?
He left his responsibilities, and ran to the army.
Let him come back.
I'll present him...
with a gold medal.
Stupid coward.
Let's go.
Father...
father, uncle is here.
He has grabbed the land next to the well.
They let animals loose on standing crops.
And when we protest this is what happens.
He has four licensed guns...
what can we do?
Let's shoot Bhanwar Singh.
End of story.
Shut up!
You aren't even as heavy as the gun...
I can't handle this on my own.
We have to do something.
You are still the same.
I'll be back in six months.
Fix yourjumping.
Don't ever let your regiment down.
We will break the record of your record-breaker.
That's the spirit!
- Victory to India.
- Subedaar...
Colonel Masand is on line from Gwalior.
Sir, I've taken premature retirement.
Are you going to quit the game?
Household duties and farming, are more dangerous sports.
The coaching offer remains open for you.
Sorry?
You can be a coach with the Army.
Yes, sir.
I want to give you something.
You've helped my son become an Army man.
What else can I ask for?
Colonel Masand has sent this for you.
It's ice cream.
Rings a bell?
Let's see, if it melts...
by the time you reach home.
This is my biggest medal, sir.
Brother...
- Let's go...
- What's the matter?
Our fields have been...
Lets go.
What happened...
I was there last evening.
Everything was fine.
Are you sure they are responsible?
See here it is...
Brother...
What's the problem?
What is it?
Why are you barking early in the morning?
What is this?
We own the farm, worked hard on this crop.
How can you cut it?
This is stealing.
Who made you the constable?
Answer me!
The field and crops belong to us.
It's ours to burn at the festival in two weeks.
You can approach the court, if you want to.
Go!
The courts are a pain and no one benefits.
This is our crop, please give it back.
But the documents show this is our land.
I have paid Matadin for it.
Yes, he sold his share.
Yes, he sold his share but this is from my share.
The land was divided equally by the village council.
That's funny!
Listen, little boy...
go and look at the land records for yourself.
Go to the council, or the court, don't bother me.
If I get angry, Your fate will be decided right here
What will you do?
- Tell me...
- Paan Singh... let's go.
What will you do?
Let's go. Goodbye brother.
Don't scare me with these guns...
I've seen bigger ones.
Colonel Masand?
Jai Hind, sir.
Subedaar Paan Singh speaking.
I'm in trouble.
Things aren't good.
My relatives have seized my farm and land.
It's been two years now.
Can your brother...
request the Collector of Morena to solve our case?
He's lying, sir.
We own the land.
They only till the land.
This document will prove who is lying.
My brother has sold his land, I've have not sold mine.
They've bribed their way to register the land in their name.
This is our land.
Aren't you related?
Yes, we are cousins...
that's why he is alive.
That is why you're alive, uncle...
I wish I could celebrate your death anniversary.
Shut up!
Not in front of the collector.
Look...
Hanumanta is here.
He got leave.
Greetings, father.
The Bhanwar Singh dispute is still on?
The Collector is here to sort it out.
Calm down, Hanumanta.
The country needs you.
Don't die for such petty issues.
Shut up, will you!
Respect the Collector.
Bhanwar Singh...
the papers prove Paan Singh's ownership
on the land.
You own enough land...
stop fighting over such small issues.
Solve this amicably.
Sir...
Sir, their family owns seven licensed guns...
which they threaten us with.
Please confiscate them till this problem is solved.
I came here on Masand's request...
but you have to resolve it amongst yourselves.
You have the authority.
They keep threatening us with their guns.
An army man petrified by a gun!
Let's fight without weapons then.
This is the aggression of Chambal Valley.
Solve it yourselves!
Following your father's footsteps... are you?
Your father never fought in a war.
Since you're spoiling for a fight, listen to this.
We have such a huge family that...
we can drown you in our urine.
Mind your language, uncle.
Let's leave, Paan.
Burn it all...
It's Paan Singh's crop.
Burn it.
Yes, keep burning.
I won't spare anything, damnit.
Not a single grain
You bastard!
Where are you going?
Why are we exerting ourselves.
Just shoot him!
Let him go.
Let him go?
And what about his father?
He can do nothing.
But run to the police.
That's all he can do.
Run.
If he had any guts...
he'd have used the gun by now.
Tomorrow, we shall get them all.
Let the whole village know who's boss.
Who is that?
Over there... who is that?
Don't stop me today, father.
Let me go.
You don't have the courage...
to resolve this farce.
I will settle this with Bhanwar Singh.
Put down your guns.
Violence won't solve anything.
It will not heal my son's wounds...
What about our honour?
Our pride?
What about it?
We won't shed more blood.
My son is an Army man.
The Army considers me a national treasure.
Won't the police listen to me?
What's the proof that this is you?
And what is this...
Steeple... chase.
- Chase?
- Yes, sir.
So, who chases whom?
There is no chase here, sir.
This is a hurdle race, 3000 metres long.
One has to jump across barriers...
It is the most grueling race.
How do we know it's you?
Here is the proof, sir.
This is me.
This is also me.
You were young then.
Why do people abroad wear such skimpy clothes?
Well...
You must have feast your eyes!
How did you travel?
By air, or by ship?
This is no time for discussion.
My son's life is in danger.
I've won medals for the country.
I've been the national champion.
I've been in the forces, just like you.
Neither the council nor the registrar is hearing my case.
Where do I go now?
Listen, this is a land and family dispute.
Without a few dead bodies, how can we intervene?
What I'm trying to say...
This is Morena district...
the police is revered here.
I'm saying...
What will people say if we meddle in petty issues?
I'm not asking you to solve the land dispute.
But they thrashed my son mercilessly...
within an inch of his life.
He can't move...
But he's breathing, isn't he?
He isn't dead yet.
Should I wait till he dies?
I have run for my country in vain!
But you got your medals.
Now get out of here.
Get lost.
ｩ P@rM!NdeR M@nkﾖﾖ ・
ｩ P@rM!NdeR M@nkﾖﾖ ・/font>
Your duty is to protect people.
So?
Not to feast on their blood.
What... what did you say?
You heard it.
Don't act like you can't hear me.
You've got corruption written all over you!
A pimp would do yourjob better.
You bloody two-cent of a soldier.
Son of a bcccc!
Stop your crap... and get out.
Do you want to be beaten up?
I'll beat the life out of you!
I'll rip that uniform off you.
Bloody pimp!
Get lost!
Where is he?
Tell him to come with the guns.
There will be a river of blood today.
You are relaxing here and Paan Singh's gone to file a complaint.
He's a stubborn man.
We have to get rid of him.
If he were a real man, he wouldn't keep running to the police.
Beware, there'll be violence today.
Bhanwar Singh is coming...
Run...
Bhanwar Singh is here.
With his cronies...
and they have guns.
These bastards need...
to be taught a lesson.
Do we have no pride that anyone
can walk in when father is out?
Please don't go there.
Wait, don't go.
- What's wrong?
Where are you going with that gun?
Mother... mother... hide.
They are coming!
Why did you have to shoot?
Run to the roof.
Break the door!
Mother... hurry...
You go, Bhanwar Singh won't hurt me.
Come on, Bhanwar Singh!
I'll teach you!
Break it down before they run!
Break it!
Jump!
Mother, this way...
Run!
What do you think you're doing?
Have some respect.
Get out of my house now!
Old woman, where's your son now?!
Help... help...
It's a bad time.
We need ward off the evil eye.
We need to make offerings.
And arrange a prayer in the village.
Subedaar, don't go home.
Bhanwar Singh and his family have attacked the house.
There are bullets all over.
The house is destroyed!
They did not even spare mother.
They are on the look out for you.
Where is my son?
Your wife has taken the kids to her mother's village.
Is there anyone at home?
No one.
Mother asked me to give these bangles to you.
Mother, till things cool down...
we'll live here.
Jairaj...
Where are you going with the gun?
I'm not going anywhere!
Come back, I say!
I'll be here.
Look father is here.
What do we do now?
If we go back to the village we'll be killed.
The police don't care.
Will you lead the rest of your life at your in-laws'?
We have to get back to the village...
and the police better care.
Hanumanta, you get back to duty tomorrow.
I will not go back.
Shut up!
Your life has just started, son.
I've lived mine already.
You will join your unit tomorrow.
Say 'yes'.
Yes.
What about our unit, uncle?
Our unit?
Our unit leaves tomorrow morning.
Take care of yourself.
Move it...
Mother's calling you, she is not well.
Alright.
They shot my son...
Run...
- Where is Jigesh?
- He has gone to his parent's place.
I've been telling him...
The cops will make your life hell!
Listen everyone!
- Let's go, brother.
- This is Paan Singh Tomar's gang.
I haven't settled my scores yet...
and I won't rest till I do.
I will be back.
Bhanwar Singh, now the game has started.
Why are you talking like this?
Surrender!
Serve your sentence and start coaching.
I'm ready to come back but if I leave...
my family and relatives...
no one will be spared.
God and you know how much the game means to me.
These cops and village council...
what do they know?!
They have created another rebel to run in the ravines.
These are my nephews...
they're innocent, sir.
Would you enlist them in the army...
Why don't you enlist them in your gang?
No one is a rebel by choice.
You and I will never meet again.
My news will keep reaching you.
Matadin is a pious fellow...
he can't kill a fly let alone commit a murder.
Bloody bastards...
Sir, listen to me...
I wasn't there at all.
It's a lie.
- Look.
- Inspector, please hear me out.
I'll let you go...
on one condition.
Tell me where I can find Paan Singh.
I swear, I have no idea.
They're lying!
They will not answer easily.
Make them sit on the stick
and they will start to sing
Take them away!
I'm asking for the last time.
Where is Paan Singh?
Don't spare them!
What can we say...
things are very difficult.
Bhanwar Singh has made our lives miserable.
The cops are questioning everyone about your whereabouts.
Where do we go now?
I've arranged for some police uniforms.
When Subedaar was looking for you, you were holidaying...
now that the cops have beaten you up you come whining.
Why should he take you into his gang?
- Let us join your gang.
- Please...
If you become a rebel you die.
We're not living in any case.
Have you tried this with ice cream?
No, I haven't tasted anything like that.
Tastes like heaven!
Here, have some.
Come on!
The bowl is for you.
I've had ice cream in many foreign countries...
but the best is the German one.
One in six different colours.
And another one... you press a button
and the ice cream flows out like honey!
Softy.
You get it in Gwalior as well.
Don't talk rubbish!
No, no.
You've come to the city after a long time.
You wouldn't know.
Did all your relatives join the gang?
Bhanwar Singh filed complaints...
against all of them there was no other option.
- How much is it for?
- What?
- Softy.
- Two rupees fifty paise.
How much?
Two rupees fifty paise.
Two...
Where did you get your weapons from?
We bought them, obviously.
Your eyes are like a double barrel gun...
Your words are like a double barrel gun...
You give me a shock like a rifle...
You're an expensive weapon my darling...
Come here...
Happy Birthday to you...
Is singing all that she can do?
Depends on how much money you have!
Don't bother with this.
It's not nearly enough.
Go on...
Keep it going, I'll be back with the money.
One move and I'll give you a bullet for your birthday!
Oh my, a garland of notes.
Hey Balram, drop it.
You're a rebel.
Stop acting like a fool.
What will you do with that cheap garland?
Ramcharan, come here...
Inform the boy's family...
and ask them for a ransom of 125,000 rupees.
And if they inform the cops...
he will lose his life.
Do you understand?
Say, 'understood'.
Brother...
Ask Govardhan, the barber to inform the boy's family.
- Right now?
- Yes...
You sit here, with me.
What are you doing?
Making sure he doesn't run away.
You think he can outrun me?
Get him to work.
There is no free lunch here he will have to cook for the gang.
So, tell me...
I dealt the cards.
It's your turn to play.
You call these cards?
I just taught you how to deal.
I have a hand.
You dealt a wrong hand.
Have you arranged the ransom?
I have 75,000 rupees.
It's 125,000 to free the boy.
But this is all I have.
You better shed tears worth 50,000!
If the Subedaar gets emotional, your son might be freed.
Everything depends on you.
That's not good.
You need to cry a river!
Make sure that the Subedaar doesn't get annoyed...
otherwise we aren't responsible for your life.
There he is.
Subedaar...
I couldn't arrange 125,000 rupees.
I sold everything and managed 75,000.
You can check, if you want to.
He is bargaining for his own son.
Don't believe a word...
he is trying to dupe us.
We are rebels, not businessmen...
give us what you have and leave.
We'll release him in a week.
In a week?
Well, what if you turn informer?
I don't have the grit to inform the police.
Count the money, before taking it.
Get away.
Shall I tell him, where we found you?
He was busy with a nautch girl.
We caught him then.
Superb! So you enjoy dancing girls...
while I go bankrupt trying to save you.
Should I tell the Subedaar
about your misdeeds?
What about your mistress who you send...
10,000 rupees to every month!
Shall I tell him...
Subedaar, kill the bugger.
You want to argue with me!
You didn't even bring the entire ransom!
I'm your bloody father.
Bad excuse for a father.
Come here, boy.
Your tears won't help!
Wish you weren't my son!
Bring him here.
Subedaar, kill him.
- Move it!
- You can kill him.
You're playing games with me!
Your son is following in your footsteps.
What an interesting family!
Now, pay up 75,000 for your son and another 75,000 for your self.
Give me 150,000 and you can go.
But Subedaar...
If I decide to make you dance you'll be damned!
Tie both of them up!
This rubbish is spoiling the peace of the ravines.
We had an understanding with the border police.
As long as we didn't mess in their area...
they didn't trouble us.
We carried out so many kidnappings in collusion with the police.
On their instructions!
Om Prakash, the cloth merchant had lent me four thousand rupees.
But the interest exceeded the loan.
Sir, he's a big fish.
We should get hold of him.
My loan will get waived, and you will also benefit.
Is this a plan or an invitation from Death?
Sir, all I want is revenge.
Great! Your rivalry and our funeral pyre!
Don't listen to him.
He's made plans to get us killed in UP.
Our corpses will float in the Ganges.
Don't give us this nonsense.
Where is the full house you were mentioning?
Here's my last card.
It's my set!
We need to get past the police of three states.
Madhya Pradesh, Uttar Pradesh and Rajasthan.
Exactly! He's got plans to get us killed.
Leave Rajasthan to me.
You think the cops of UP and MP will welcome us?
Arrange for a police jeep.
Done.
Who can drive well?
I can.
We are at the MP and Rajasthan border.
Hurry up and change.
Let them pass.
There are cops up ahead.
So what!
We're officers.
Keep driving.
We've got a report, you're sheltering rebels.
Inspector, someone's misinformed you.
You aren't the police.
Correct, better late than never.
My name is Subedaar Paan Singh Tomar
and you have been kidnapped.
Say 'yes'.
You tricked the police of three states.
Must have created quite a scandal.
That's the pity!
I crossed 28 barriers and 7 water pits
to become the national champion...
Nobody cared.
But when I became a kidnapper and fooled the police...
everybody started chanting, Paan Singh... Paan Singh
I agree.
Sportspersons are not treated well.
Stop shedding crocodile tears.
If I was just an athlete...
would you have risked so much to interview me?
You are right.
Is it true you got 400,000 rupees...
for the Om Prakash kidnapping?
And then we became a complete gang.
Look at this one, brother.
I'm buying you a gun...
put this there.
Not this... it's for my prayers.
- Go, keep this there.
- Where?
There on the hillock.
If I need something else?
You'll get everything.
Guns, rifles, grenades, LMG, everything.
Put it there and move away.
There, I've kept it.
Okay, now move away!
Why are these guns numbered?
What's in a serial number?!
You have to keep track of the material.
It's good, isn't it?
There are no criminals in the army.
This perhaps belonged to a policeman.
It doesn't matter where it comes from.
I just sell it.
Subedaar...
You are all over the radio.
Turn it off!
When I brought laurels for the country nobody cared.
Now that I'm a rebel I'm famous!
Let me make this clear.
The bigger the gang...
the more the enemies.
Only two things can save us.
The first is...
our loyalty to each other.
And second, the support of our body.
Loyalty is our tradition.
And I'll train your bodies.
From tomorrow your military training begins.
- Say, 'yes'.
- Yes.
Yes.
I can't tell the difference between your yes and no.
Keep your head close to the ground.
A tortoise can easily win a gold medal against you.
You resemble a bunch of goats in a slaughter house.
Lift your gun higher!
Lmagine there is constant fire from here. You have to clear through.
So we need to learn the scout formation.
In this formation the first guy remains ahead...
while the second and fourth guys are at an equal distance.
Nobody will come in each others way.
Keep sitting.
I can't do this, Paan.
Forgive me.
I'm not cut out for this.
If I keep at it I'll die too soon.
Fine, come and sit here.
Uncle, what is the meaning of this parade?
While the enemy sleeps peacefully.
It's a temporary slumber...
What do you mean?
Very soon they will be sleeping permanently.
How much more time?
We have our own gang, our weapons.
All you say is, There is time...
It's not easy to attack them.
There are machine guns everywhere.
The house resembles a fort now with constant patrolling.
The soil's getting damp.
Sowing begins in a few days...
and crops don't grow inside the house.
They'll all come to the fields.
Isn't there any alcohol here?
All bars are closed.
All across the district?
I could have bought it from the market
but there'd be a rampage.
One shouldn't drink in the day.
I don't need your lecture!
What was that?!
It's an attack.
Paan Singh is back.
Come on...
Run... run!
Who's gang is this?
This is Paan Singh's gang, Inspector.
All of you, stand in a line.
No... No...
Why not?
He filed the wrong reports.
That's because...
He protects Bhanwar Singh!
He filed a complaint and I was only investigating it.
Inspector, you forgot your duty.
But I'm a rebel...
and I remember my duties.
You stand by justice, Subedaar.
I have two kids...
Kids?
Look...
This is your uniform...
and look at you.
You dare wear this uniform again...
and you'll die a dog's death.
You are not worthy of this uniform.
Apologize... to your uniform.
Now!
Please forgive me.
Not me... the uniform.
Dear uniform...
please forgive me.
You are not worthy of an apology either.
Now stand straight... stand up!
Run as fast as you can.
Where is Bhanwar Singh?
Here he is!
Where will you run to, Bhanwar Singh?
Where are you running off to?
Did you think you could out run me.
Tell me!
Where are your bodyguards?
And your licensed guns?
So, tell me...
all we had was a small piece of land...
and you had to go and occupy it?
Please forgive me.
Now how will you till the land?
You can take your land, take mine too...
Just let me go.
You thrashed my son...
till he was almost dead.
He was beaten to pulp!
What was my mother's fault?
That you hit her with the butt of a gun?
You beat my mother with the butt of the gun!
Forgive me, please.
I won't die with this bullet.
Please have some mercy.
You think I don't have enough bullets...
Or you think I can't aim?
You were my brother...
brother... my elder brother...
I was an international athlete...
Forgive me...
Tell me where I went wrong...
that you snatched my playing field from me?
You forced this gun into my hands.
And now I'm running laps in the ravines.
How will we settle this score?
I want my answers.
Please forgive me, Paan.
You are my brother.
Keep the gun away.
Please forgive me.
As a brother, forgive me.
I can run...
I've been running my whole life.
If that's fate, so be it.
Answer me before you go.
Answer me!
Why are you always in a hurry?
We were discussing something important...
and you had to intervene.
Drop your gun... now.
I'll get my answers...
when we meet in the afterlife.
My questions are still unanswered.
I had my revenge.
But in the ravines, enmity runs deep.
And then one day something happened...
because of which I am telling you my story.
Shut up!
Stop your ridiculous song.
The food better be spicy or off with your tongue!
Then you will be miming the song forever
Your trust is a great honour.
The arrangements here are fantastic.
We have a big gang.
Whenever we pass by, we will come here.
Keep this.
- I cannot keep it.
- Keep it.
We have a big gang.
I don't want to become a burden on you.
What if you stopped respecting us!?
The word is that the Morena and Gwalior police is on the move.
It's dangerous.
We shall stay here until things settle down.
Come and get your lunch.
The women folk are coming here for their bath.
Would appreciate if you could all step outside.
You too, please step outside.
Try it, it's very sweet.
Don't pray so hard...
lest the almighty himself come down.
And asks you to accompany him back to heaven.
We've been betrayed.
Everybody take your position!
Give me cover.
What's wrong?
Balram, let the cattle loose.
Are you hurt, brother?
Where have you been shot?
My time is up.
You leave now.
I won't let you die.
My story is up.
I'll get you out of here.
Hold my hand.
Pull it, quick!
Quick, the cops won't swim across.
Mark my words!
Don't come any closer or you will be killed!
Three of our men have died.
Their bodies are with the police.
Inform their families and send them money.
Tell them, I'll come to meet them.
We have to do something now.
What!?
Uncle...
Till I don't burn down that village...
I will get no solace.
Come here, son...
He was a father figure to me too.
Save your anger for the last round.
We'll teach them such a lesson,
nobody in Chambal will dare betray us.
This is the gang of Paan Singh Tomar from Bhidosa.
We do not harm children and women.
But rest assured, the informer cannot escape.
You bloody bastard, come outside.
What are you doing?!
Don't stop me, Subedaar uncle.
I won't spare anybody in the village.
Stop talking nonsense!
Give me the gun.
Get back now.
Go and get the headman and his relatives...
Where do you think you're going?
Listen carefully.
This is the rule of Paan Singh's gang.
We don't spare the police and their informers.
But the poor and the innocent have
our complete protection.
Remember...
betraying us is an invitation to death.
Forgive me, sir.
What do you have to say now?
- Forgive us.
- Forgive?
Like a dog you betrayed us to the cops.
Say 'yes'.
- Say 'yes'.
- Yes.
You squealed and my pious brother...
paid with his life.
My mistake, forgive me.
How can I forgive you?
It was a mistake.
Satpal...
Satpal!
Yes, Sir!
Is this going to play all night?
Stop this blaring music!
Stop the music!
Just a minute.
Is your interview over?
- Yes, I'm done.
- Then go.
And one more thing...
Listen...
understand this...
it was necessary to kill...
those nine villagers.
If I didn't kill them...
They were unarmed but they were not innocent...
Yes.
Paan Singh is not a murderer.
I agree.
Will you be promoted for writing this story?
Yes.
Buy some sweets for your sister.
Go now.
There are so many journalists trying...
and you say you managed it
Did you really meet Paan Singh?
Or did you just cook this up?
Small town mentality!
We had dinner together.
See how this shakes the government.
What are you doing?
Move them aside.
You know these animals...
they'll move on their own.
What's the hurry?
Why are you peeping inside?
Move on... move on...
I'm checking if one round will be enough.
The killer of nine innocent villagers...
dacoit Paan Singh Tomar was sitting
in Gwalior, calmly giving interviews.
The opposition has slammed the government.
You didn't give us a chance to fire.
In this part of the world...
you shoot when you're in the mood.
I was in the mood today.
Open up the boot.
Inform his family.
Okay.
You can come out now.
Don't be scared, These are real cops in real uniforms
Step out!
Back here again?
Get your act together...
- Sir!
- Yes
Paan Singh rules the Bhind area...
but his family and gang members...
hail from Morena.
I want Paan Singh to surrender.
After all, he's been a national champion.
He used to win awards for the country...
now there's a reward on his head.
Some people are in the mood for
an encounter, not surrender.
How did this happen, sir?
What's there to say!?
We were on the lookout for Paan Singh's gang...
but got hold of another gang
now there is one less gang in the area
Greetings, Subedaar.
Ghesu and Pehelwan, come with me.
Paan Singh...
the cops are getting too close for comfort.
They killed ten members of the Setu Mallah gang.
The nine villagers you killed...
and that interview...
has aggravated the matter.
What is it that you want?
You are the cause of these problems.
If you surrender...
things will be fine.
I'm not afraid...
If you are, go surrender yourselves.
Don't be naive.
Surrender yourself and things will be fine.
Sir...
Have you ever run a race?
There is a rule in racing.
Once the race begins...
regardless of whether you win or lose...
you have to complete the race.
Over there on the horizon...
is the finish line.
You have to finish it.
Whether I win or lose...
I have to finish my race.
You think of yours.
What's the urgency?
I just feel like meeting them.
I don't want you to go alone.
The police is looking for me in the ravines...
but I'm going to town.
The police is looking for a whole gang...
so we cannot stick together.
We'll all disperse in groups of three or four.
Go far away from here.
We will meet a month from now at the Goraiyya river bank.
A month from now.
Beware...
don't trust anyone but your gang members.
Isn't this too high?
Paan Singh used to practice at this height.
Stay right there...
Your colleagues shouldn't get suspicious.
But, father...
Because now, I'm not just a father...
You look smart.
Like an army man.
You've become weak.
I've grown old.
I got word of your marriage.
The girl is from Jalaun.
Mother has approved of her.
She has four brothers.
I hope my reputation is not causing trouble.
They have agreed because of you.
No one in their family has had their pictures in the papers.
My disrepute is of some use then...
How is your mother?
She worries about you.
Tell her I'll be coming to meet her.
Okay.
Go now.
Go...
Will you get into trouble if you meet me?
If you are scared, I'll leave.
Who the hell is scared, damnit?!
- Why don't you do one thing?
- Yes.
Surrender yourself.
There's no other way out for you.
So I should accept that...
I made a mistake and seek forgiveness?
And be known as a surrendered rebel for the rest of my life.
Why don't you ask this of the people who make us rebels?!
Ask them to surrender first.
Then I will.
I am leaving now.
Don't mind me taking these.
I'm also taking this photograph.
So, why did you come here?
I missed your abuses.
Not sure if I will get another chance.
I missed you a lot.
Here he is.
Go ahead, eat some.
Janki...
this is for you.
What else has your astrologer predicted about my future?
He said you will surrender.
That's all he can say...
Surrender... surrender.
Do you know what it means to surrender?
He is just trying to please you.
Don't you worry.
This will settle down pretty soon.
When will you come again, father?
Whenever I happen to pass by.
Will you surrender yourself?
Your astrologer's definition of surrender is different.
We all have to surrender some day.
No, no... it's alright.
Get me some water.
We are a lowly caste, sir.
Caste and creed are not important.
We should help each other.
Customs which create such discrimination...
should be done away with.
Don't you agree!?
When have you been wrong?!
Tell me...
this boy Gopi from Paan Singh's gang, is this his wife's village?
Yes.
He comes here often?
Yes, he does.
He comes for social functions.
His wife lives here.
Get us to meet next time.
Would benefit both of you.
Will you enlist my son in the police?
Then it will benefit me.
Your wish is my command.
Won't need it now, son.
We'll celebrate your induction now.
It's important.
Should get sorted soon.
Sure. Will be done.
Goodbye, sir.
You are suddenly concerned about me.
Why?
And how would you do that?
I suggest we go to Rajasthan.
What's with Rajasthan?
Got a mistress out there?
We are not staying here.
We cross the border tonight and go to U.P.
What's the harm in staying a little longer.
Are you tired?
I've got some sweets for you.
We'll leave after eating it.
Hold on!
You eat it first.
Not this one, take this other one.
This can be easily eaten while walking.
Your mother-in-law made this for us?
No, there was a wedding in the village.
I got it from there.
Subedaar...
there is a rich party staying in the village.
It's a good opportunity.
We need to lie low for a few days.
What happened, sir?
People shouldn't think Paan Singh's gang is afraid of the police.
This news has reached the papers.
Gopi, is the party really loaded?
The wedding is next Saturday.
We can kidnap at least four or five people.
Sir, trust me, we should go to Rajasthan.
We'll take our catch and go to Rajasthan.
I refuse to be subdued by the police.
Gopi, can we trust your wife's family?
They gave me their daughter.
- Subedaar, lets stop right here.
- But why?
Looks like the Grim Repear.
- Gopi...
- Yes
Check if the coast is clear...
and bring the host here.
Okay.
Uncle...
I'm coming.
The gang's outside the village.
Subedaar's called for you.
Son, go inform the inspector.
I'll go get him.
This way.
You guys go ahead.
Govindram...
Are all the arrangements done?
I did my best to organize what I could.
The fellows are tired.
We'll stay here for the night and
leave early morning with our catch.
Okay.
Where is Gopi?
I'm right here.
Leave early for the catch.
Get them out on some pretext
Okay.
- You got the booze?
- Yes.
The food is ready.
You will have to eat it first.
What do we do about this?
I'll say that I've quit.
Or I'll find some excuse.
Have you checked the sedatives?
Yes I have.
Subedaar shouldn't get suspicious.
Or we're dead
You quit!
- Sir. I quit.
- Why?
I had TB last year.
- That's enough for me.
- That's it?
That's my rule.
Alcohol is good in small amounts.
After that it is poison.
Give some to everyone.
Pass around the alcohol.
Tell them to have some.
They'll sleep well.
Will you have some?
No, no.
Life was a barren land.
Filled with loneliness and sorrow...
Till I met you
- Then?
- The rest of my life got screwed
Uncle...
- What happened?!
- I told you!
That death is in the air.
The bloody cops have surrounded the entire village.
- The cops are here?
- Yes.
Give me my gun.
- Govindram!
- Yes, sir.
Who informed the cops?
Tell me who.
I don't know sir.
Not me sir.
Tell me who.
I didn't do it.
Trust me, I didn't inform on you.
I don't want to go to hell.
I was...
I am obliged to you.
Where is the police?
At the canal.
Let the cattle loose!
The cop manning the LMG won't hesitate to shoot them.
Call Gopi.
The bag of bullets is with him.
He has the bullets?
He ran away in the nick of time.
How many cops are there?
About 500.
There's only one way out of the village and that's where the cops are.
We have to escape from there.
Get the megaphone.
It's ready!
We leave this way.
Where's my gun?!
Everyone go towards the canal.
Stay together.
We move ahead in a scout formation.
Keep moving in this formation.
He's been shot.
Get down!
Don't shoot me.
I'm the informer Gopi!
Bloody traitor
Don't shoot.
Hold your fire!
Somebody man the LMG.
- Who got shot?
- Govind.
- Where?
- He's dead.
There's only one way out.
We have to cross the canal.
That's my route.
They will attack me...
Try running away through the fields!
Subedaar...
What's the matter, Subedaar?
I think the bastard poisoned the drinks.
Subedaar...
Are you feeling drugged, Jigesh?
Where are you going?
Subedaar...
Inform the CM that the operation is a success.
Go and count the bodies.
We are yet to find Paan Singh's body.
Go and find him...
Subedaar, it's all over.
Everyone's dead.
- You are still alive Ramcharan.
- Yes.
There lies the finish line.
The canal is the final hurdle.
Tell people my story.
That Paan Singh finished his race.
He did not surrender.
We shall meet again.
Ramcharan!
Listen here, corrupt inspector...
This gang isn't finished yet.
Paan Singh is alive.
And he will never surrender!
Many before you tried to catch me but failed miserably.
And you think you will?!
Bring in some more battalions to help you...
try and capture Paan Singh!
ｩ
ｩ P
ｩ P@
ｩ P@r
ｩ P@rM
ｩ P@rM!
ｩ P@rM!N
ｩ P@rM!Nd
ｩ P@rM!Nde
ｩ P@rM!NdeR
ｩ P@rM!NdeR M
ｩ P@rM!NdeR M@
ｩ P@rM!NdeR M@n
ｩ P@rM!NdeR M@nk
ｩ P@rM!NdeR M@nkﾖ
ｩ P@rM!NdeR M@nkﾖﾖ
ｩ P@rM!NdeR M@nkﾖﾖ ・
Mobile - +919815899536
EMail - parminder222536@hotmail.com