How many stars
sparkle in the sky?
Ever tried counting them?
lt would take 6,000 years to
count those in our galaxy alone
How many such galaxies exist?
Scientists reckon
two billion more
lsn't it possible that amongst
these billions of celestial bodies
a planet with people
like us exists?
As we explore space
looking for them,
couldn't they be coming here,
looking for us?
Hindi pop song
What the thief stole was the
gadget to recall his spaceship
Without this remote
he could not return home
He neither knew our language,
nor had a friend here
Alone, anguished,
his only thought was...
.. how will l return home?
On the pathway of Time
Life is but a brief flame
ln its luminous mist
We wish, we dream, we exist
But on a beautiful bend
A stranger may we meet
Life after life
Whose memory may persist
Extra ticket.
Anyone extra ticket?
- Yes sir...
- I'II take it!
Sorry, I raised my hand first
But I caIIed out first
I'm a big fan of
Mr Bachchan, the poet
I'm a bigger fan of his son,
the actor
From age ten, I know aII his poems.
FuIIy memorized
From age five, I know his son's
diaIogues - without memorizing
HeIIo, who wants it?
Give me.
Poetry's not his cup of tea
€100
€100 for a €40 ticket?
BIack market of poetry!
Queued up
six Iong hours for this
Time is money
- Go for the diaIogues.
- AII yours. Ladies first
Just a sec!
Why not spIit the ticket?
1st haIf you enjoy the poetry.
2nd haIf I'II savor the acting
That's a damn good idea!
10, 20, 30, 40
50 more
- 96
€96. How about a discount?
We're from the same country
HaiI India, bro!
Long Iive motherIand!
€100
Extra ticket.
Anyone extra ticket?
Sir!
Can I borrow €4?
PIease!
Keep my watch tiII I repay
PIease, Sir,
it's the Iast ticket
Show is soId out, chiId.
No tickets Ieft
There is one Ieft
with that bIack marketer
ScoundreI!
Giving India a bad name
So true!
Wait here.
I'II get you that ticket
OK, Sir
Thank you
Yes!
- Sir!
- Do I know you?
Where's my ticket?
Ticket?
Yours for € 100
You bIoody cheat!
Decaying dacoit!
SeniIe snake! CapitaIist!
Mind your Ianguage!
Mind your coat first!
- Now enjoy the show!
- Security!
- WrinkIed wreck!
Let's get outta here
I'II get you for this!
Don't chase me...
catch him!
OIdies these days!
It's a spoiIt generation!
Forget it
How can I?
That bandit basks in poetry
and here I am
Drop it
Why pine for the party
that shuns us?
Follow the moment
that beckons us
I too dabbIe in poetry
It's nice. Go on
No. If I go on,
you'II propose to me
- You crazy?
- I mean it!
Your favorite poet,
senior Mr Bachchan
met a Iady one morning,
wooed her with verse
By dusk they were married.
So I've read
ReaIIy?
And boy!
Look what they produced -
Amitabh Bachchan -
the great actor
Jaggu
Jaggu?
My name
Papa named me Jagat Janani:
world's mother
I got mocked at schooI
so I shortened it - Jaggu
- From Mumbai?
- No. DeIhi
I'm studying TV production
And you?
Sarfaraz. I study architecture
and work part time
at the Pakistan Embassy
Pakistan Embassy? Why?
WeII, I'm from Pakistan
UnIikeIy the Indian Embassy
wiII empIoy me!
What's wrong?
Nothing
My being from Pakistan
perturbs you?
AIright then
Goodbye
Ask not my name,
nor my country
From bondage of
borders break free
A few steps
on this brief journey
Come,
just walk with me
Ask not my name,
nor my country
From bondage of
borders break free
A few steps
on this brief journey
Come,
just walk with me
Past the realms of
word and speech
Hand in hand,
nowhere to reach
A few steps
on this brief journey
Come,
just walk with me
Past the realms of
word and speech
Hand in hand,
nowhere to reach
A few steps
on this brief journey
Come,
just walk with me
lf the sun scorches
the pathway
A carpet of shade
will l lay
lf darkness
fills you with dismay
l'll conjure up
a moon in the sky
lf dejection fills up
your day
With laughter
l'll shoo it away
Laughing, frolicking,
humming a song
Together we shall
walk along
With you,
my fellow traveler
Nothing in this world l fear
Why a few steps,
a whole lifelong
With you l'll walk along
Past the realms of
word and speech
Hand in hand,
nowhere to reach
A few steps
on this brief journey
Come,
just walk with me
- Thank you
Mom!
Papa!
She's faIIen in Iove!
FaIIen in Iove?
He's so cute!
More photos pIease!
What's his job?
What's his famiIy Iike?
CaIm down Mom.
I'II teII you
First, the name
Sarfaraz
MusIim?
Yes. Studies architecture.
FamiIy is in Pakistan
Pakistan!
Which Pakistan?
There's just
one Pakistan, Mom
You'II wear burkhas?
Read the Quran?
Have you gone mad?
Don't you disconnect.
Stay put
Start the car
AII's doomed, Your HoIiness.
HeIp!
l knew exactly
where Papa was headed
Since childhood one face had
surrounded us.: His Holiness
Bye Mom
From bags to bathroom walls,
he was omnipresent
Even for a root canal
he would set the auspicious time
He had gifted Papa a God box
with a deity for every task
Goddess of Wealth
for the stock market
God of Health for workouts
Web-based worship and
sacred sweets by courier
were his innovations
HaiI, Your HoIiness
Touch his feet Jaggu
Why this fataI infatuation?
Pick up a pen and write
God
EnIighten me
Yes...
Your wish is our command
Write down the prophecy
This Pakistani boy,
Sarfaraz,
wiII betray you
I know he won't
History stands witness:
these peopIe scheme and betray
He wiII pursue
carnaI pIeasures
But wiII never marry you.
He'II vanish
Come home now! One more
night there, and you're dead to us
Mr Sahni,
I'II taIk to her
ChiId, hit the deIete button
Banish him
from your system
HeIIo!
What happened?
Do you Iove me?
Of course I do. Why?
- WiII you marry me?
- What's the matter?
Yes or no, Sarfaraz?
- Yes, but...
- Tomorrow
Tomorrow?
Tomorrow we get married
His prophecy is wrong.
I'II prove it
Mr James Herrick and
Miss Oprah Brown, you're next
- James isn't here, yet.
- Oh, taIk to the registrar
CouId you just
hoId this pIease?
- Yes of course.
- Thank you
HeIIo...
This is for you
- For me?
- Yeah
Thank you
lt was from Sarfaraz
He said.: marriage isn't just
between individuals, but families
Our faiths, countries,
cultures are different
We can never be happy
if our families are unhappy
Don't try to contact me
l'm sorry
Where to go young Iady?
New DeIhi
l came back to my city, but
my parents refused to see me
l joined a news channel
as a reporter
Today's story:
a depressed dog
That's our breaking news!
Some days we had news,
some days we fabricated it
Missing: God
If found, contact Tipsy
There's a story in this man.
I'II see you at office
Don't be Iate!
Excuse me?
Why are you
handing these out?
I have a case
pending with Him
He neither soIves it,
nor meets me
My Iife is kaput
He's gone into hiding
Have you seen Him around?
No
Hail Goddess,
Hail Holy Mother
By the way,
what's with the heImet?
Got the idea from taxi-tops
YeIIow yeIIs out from miIes
Taxis are spotted
easiIy in traffic
- So?
- So God can spot me easy!
How eIse wiII he spot me
in this crowd?
A bit to your Ieft - perfect!
Ok, background?
Cue Jaggu
They say
animaIs are not suicidaI
Here's Nikku.
Mr Sweetie Singh's dog
Nikku has attempted
suicide thrice
Jumping off a roof, Iicking sIeeping
piIIs, hopping onto a gas burner
What's wrong with Nikku?
Is Nikku prey to a
mentaI probIem?
Is Nikku...
What's wrong Jaggu?
What is this shit, Mitu?
Our chat with famed industriaIist
Mr Ratan continues
right after this break
Going weII, Ratan?
Some coffee?
Get him some coffee
- Cherry...
- Oh no!
What's your guess? This dog has
depression, anxiety disorder,
schizophrenia, or ADHD?
Whatever,
why wouId I care?
ExactIy
Why wouId anyone care?
Then why do we air such buII?
What wouId you rather air?
HoId him pIease
See this?
I met a guy distributing
these pamphIets
- He is searching for God.
- Found Him?
No... but
Searching for God - that's reIigion.
Finding God - that's news
If he finds God, get him.
I'II put him on air
You know the Company poIicy
No news on reIigion,
no news on God. Finished
Man, you've changed!
Where's the fighter,
Cherry Bajwa?
You wanna see the fighter?
Take a good Iook
There are three marks here
These aren't birthmarks
I ran a show against His HoIiness,
your Dad's Guru
His devotees shoved a trident
right here in my bum
Anchor coming to you
in 10 seconds
That day I swore -
if you want to Iive in this country
don't mess with reIigion.
That's it
- l've got a show to run now.
- 5... 4...
3...
2...
1...
WeIcome back from the break
We were chatting with
famed industriaIist Mr Ratan...
The boss killed my story
But it came back to life
two weeks later
[ DONATION BOX ]
Stop! Thief!
He's steaIing
from the donation box!
Don't Iet him go!
Lifting from the
donation box, you fooI?
Yes
He's no thief!
WhiIe donating
my waIIet feII in the box
He was getting it out for me
Trust me
Check for yourseIf.
It has Rs 5,000 in it
- That's mine!
- It was
Once in the box,
it's donated
Now, it's God's.
Let them go
Dude, what the heII
were you up to?
CIaiming my refund
God took His fee
but didn't deIiver
Hang on...
I saw you fish out some money,
then put some back in
I took back what I'd paid
at this branch. Returned the rest
You used to wear
beads and amuIets?
Rejected. Gone for good
Why the stickers then?
SeIf-defense!
God pics on waIIs - prevent peeing
on face - prevent punches
Mitu, where are you?
Pick me up.
I've no money to get home
I'II fiII you in Iater
I'm at Mudrika,
outside the tempIe
Hurry.
Thanks, bye
Here you go
- For what?
- For the ride home
When someone can't
get home, I feeI sad
- Wait.
- That's aII I had
I can't accept this
- Why?
- Won't you need it to get home?
Money can't get me home
Why? Where do you Iive?
In the step-well ruins
But in this rainy season,
I check into a Iock-up
Lock-up!
As in poIice Iock-up?
There are 122 in the city.
I yo-yo between them
And they Iet you check in,
Iike a hoteI?
Come.
I'II give you a demo
[ Sign: DO NOT URINATE HERE ]
Just watch!
Hey, copper -
Iook here proper!
I'II show you proper!
Jaggu!
We have to
foIIow that van
- Who are we chasing?
- A story
Gimme your waIIet.
I need cash
Hurry!
Thanks. Bye
Excuse me?
Yes?
I want to go
inside the Iock-up
Why?
To meet that guy
You think this is the
IocaI coffee joint, huh?
Saunter in and chiIIax
with your buddies?
This is a Iock-up, get it?
OnIy offenders get in
Bribing is an offence!
That's why I'm committing it!
I can Iock you in
PIease do... ASAP!
- Thank you, Mr Pandey.
- One hour, that's it
Hi
I want your story.
WiII you share it?
Why?
I'm a TV reporter.
It's my job
- Go on, ask.
- Awesome!
Your name?
Don't have a name
They caII me Tipsy here.
Beats me why
And what do you do?
I'm an astronaut
Astronaut!
Those who shoot off
to the moon?
Been there once.
lt's kaput
Sure!
So what's your
favorite pIanet?
- My own.
- I meant besides Earth?
Earth is mega-kaput
I meant my own pIanet
It'II show up there at night
We went bananas,
when we found another pIanet
with peopIe Iike us
I was sent here
on a research mission
Boy, what a weIcome I got!
My remote got robbed
Without it,
I can't signaI my peopIe
and without a signaI
they won't come for me
They'II think
it's a periIous pIanet
That I'm dead as a dodo
HeIIo!
- Listen...
- What?
Let me out.
I want to go home
Your Highness, convicts
don't decide that. Cops do
I'm not a thief
So say aII the thieves
Where's officer Pandey?
Out on his rounds
Officer Pandey!
Shut up, or you get
a knuckIe sandwich
You think
I'm taIking baIoney?
ObviousIy!
Is Hindi the officiaI Ianguage
of your pIanet?
On our pIanet...
.. there's no Ianguage!
We read minds.
There's no confusion
Here, you utter something
and mean something eIse
A two-Ietter word can have
four different meanings
When you nod and say ''oh'',
it means ''Oh, that's cooI''
When your eyes pop out,
''oh!'' means bad news
''Your mother-in-Iaw
is moving in.'' ''Oh!''
When angry, you thunder
''Oh! You'II pay
for that bIunder!''
And when your thought is deep,
your ''oh'' is Iong!
''Ohhhhhhh! I see!''
As you hear the words,
you gotta watch the expression
to get the reaI meaning
It's torture!
Took fuII 6 hours to Iearn Hindi
A whoIe Ianguage in 6 hours?
No one Iet me hoId hands
FinaIIy, a nice Iady
Ient her hand
I heId it and transferred
her Ianguage into my system
Man, there's no Iimit
to your whoppers!
Is your hand a USB cabIe,
that transfers fiIes
between computers?
And your cIothes? Are faded jeans
the rage on your pIanet too?
Noooo!
On our pIanet...
.. no one wears cIothes.
There we go bare
Here, at first I thought
your skins were
different from ours
Some had sparkly hides,
some jet black
Some hides were colorful,
some white
Some hides sticky-tight,
some baggy
Then one day
l found a car
A dancing car
That day l realized
our skins were the same
but yours are covered
with a thing called fashion
Radio CommerciaI
Now l could mingle
Yet l was mocked
Look here -
haIf man, haIf woman!
Slowly l got it
There's man - fashion
and woman - fashion
There was day fashion...
.. and night fashion
Sporting fashion...
.. and serving fashion
With the clothes,
l found some photos
lt hit me - these photos
meant survival
You could
swap them for food
So l built a portfolio
of this old man's photos
What's this?
What are these for?
Why are you giving me
this junk?
Right! Now we're taIking!
Here you go
l got it.: this photo had value
on just one kind of paper
On any other paper,
it was worthless
For cash and clothes,
dancing cars were widely available
They were my bank,
they were my tailor!
Once, l got
such magnetic attire
that no photos
were needed
Food was pulled to me
For you, Sir
Now, to find my remote, l had to
learn this planet's language
Without it,
every task was a trial
Like telling this gentleman
there was a defect
in his fashion
l felt l had spoilt his fashion
So l put it back
where it was
[Radio Announcement]
Found him on the road
Some scumbag
hit him and boIted
Seems pretty okay,
but isn't responding
Has his eardrum
caIIed it a day?
Are you deaf?
Can hear aIright,
but isn't taIking
Seems in a state of shock
Memory Ioss, I'm afraid
Remember the scumbag
who hit you?
Remember the Iicense pIate?
Remember anything at aII?
Come my friend.
Come with me
Be my guest tiII you
get your memory back
Keep sIamming your head
One knock took your memory away,
another might bring it back
Seen it in the movies
To figure what he was
yapping about,
l had to hold his hand
and transfer his language
Hey!
With memory Ioss your gender
sense went for a toss?
Wait a moment...
See this - my Iicense
Sex: MALE
Man...
rogue, rascaI, scumbag
To return home
l had to hold someone's hand
Here comes my zany guest
Can't tell guy from gal
Happily hits on all
Here comes my zany guest
Can't tell guy from gal
Happily hits on all
Your frantic antics if not stilled,
will surely get me killed!
Don't be a scourge
Do curb your urge
Here comes the lusty lad
My guest with this crazy fad
Tourist in tacky gear
are you from near or far
From Mumbai, Madrid
or Madagascar
Tourist in tacky gear
are you from near or far
From Mumbai, Madrid
or Madagascar
What was your name at school
Was it nerdy or was it cool?
What's the zip code
Of your abode
Did you alight from a cloud
Or sprout from underground
Your frantic antics if not stilled,
will surely get me killed!
Don't be a scourge
Do curb your urge
Here comes the lusty lad
My guest with this crazy fad
This memory loss is a blessing
Feuds forgotten
lenders left guessing
Lovable lad
lnnocent cad
Don't be a scourge
Do curb your urge
Here comes the lusty lad
My guest with this crazy fad
Here comes the lusty lad!
Here comes the lusty lad
My guest with this crazy fad
I feeI your pain, bro
But don't go grabbing hands
You may end up in bed,
but most IikeIy a hospitaI bed
Don't give up,
I know pIace for you
Hand, foot -
hoId whatever
No one wiII bash you here
Come
What a neighborhood!
Virtuous, welcoming women
All reaching for my hand,
inviting me home
Here l met a serene and
gentle woman, Pepper
Pepper, take him
to the honeymoon suite
Pepper sat patiently all night
For full 6 hours,
l transferred her language files
ABC - XYZ,
l drew in everything
First time?... Kaput before you kicked off?
Y...y... yes!
Where are you from?
Far, far away
From an unheard of viIIage
But you speak my Iingo!
Because I Iearnt it from you,
Sister
Sister! You think
this is a convent? Out!
Bro!
Bro, wake up!
You're taIking!
Bro, I need your heIp
Pepper cIeared up your throat!
Bro, come with me quick
Memory and making out
have a direct connection!
Update the docs:
get Iaid, get weII!
It's urgent, bro!
Okay, Iet's go
Stop... stop!
Stop, bro!
The jerk robbed me
right here
I need my chain, bro.
I must get it back
- Precious?
- It's priceIess!
The thief must be a IocaI
But he'II seII
the Ioot in DeIhi
If he soId pricey stuff here,
he'd get caught
Then I must go
Where?
DeIhi
- Officer!
- Yeah?
- My remote controI is stoIen.
- Are you tipsy?
Expect the poIice force
to track your TV remote?
- It's not a TV remote!
- Then?
Can't teII you.
But it's Iike a chain
ReaIIy precious
- Where was it stoIen?
- In Mandawa
And you're searching
in DeIhi, you idiot?
The thief came to DeIhi
- So?
- So where's the thief?
BIockhead!
It's a city of 15 miIIion
PoIice are human,
not God
OnIy God can heIp you
Surrender to God,
you'II succeed
OnIy God knows
Ask God, not me!
Trust in God, my chiId
Who was this God chap?
All said only He could help
What l saw blew my mind
Earthlings had figured out
who had manufactured them!
Their creator lived with them.
He had millions of houses
Earthlings took their problems to Him,
which He solved for a small fee
My planet had no such facility
l could not believe it!
So decided to test it
One take-away God
Which one?
Rs 20, 100, 500?
Any difference?
In the Rs 20 and Rs 500 ones?
Just the size.
Otherwise ditto
Rs 20 God is
equaIIy efficient?
OK, gimme Rs15!
Nothing Iess
God, I am famished.
Get me some food pIease
l went bananas
God actually worked!
Now l could go home
God, my remote is stoIen
PIease find it.
I want to go home
God's battery died.
Worked once, then kaput
What do you mean?
Stick a new battery in.
Where does it go?
- It needs no battery.
- Then why is it off?
- Manufacturing defect?
- I make no defective stuff
- You made this God?
- Of course! With my own hands
You made God,
or God made you?
He made us aII -
I onIy make His statues
Why the statues?
To worship Him.
To voice our probIems
Is there a transmitter inside?
How can He hear us?
God needs no transmitter.
He hears directIy
DirectIy?
Then why the statue?
What's with him?
Want to bust my business?
What's your probIem?
My remote is stoIen, Sir
I'm requesting God.
But He doesn't repIy
- Are you tipsy?
- Meaning?
You're overIoading
this pint-sized God
His itty-bitty feet
can't chase the thief
Bother the big God
inside the tempIe
He'II run fast
Offer Him coconut and money -
He'II deIiver
That'II be Rs 200
Earthlings waited with fees
to get their work done
Full 2 hours later
l got the appointment
God,
pIease get my remote back
- Where is it?
- Move!
Wait,
He didn't deIiver my stuff
He didn't deIiver!
See, I paid His fee
- Your work wiII be done.
- But when?
Can't say when,
but it wiII be done
- Move on.
- But when wiII I get it?
Don't bIock the Iine, scram!
If I scram,
someone eIse may get it
Are you tipsy?
Lady, pIease!
Where wiII I get my stuff?
At the mentaI hospitaI!
What? Cash here,
deIivery at mentaI hospitaI!
- Throw him out!
- OK, give me a receipt
Out!
Without a receipt
how do I cIaim my deIivery?
Get out!
But my remote?
Leave!
I can't find my shoes
Someone's taken them.
Now you take your pick
Rotation is routine
at tempIes
He took the payment,
didn't deIiver
What's his name?
- They caII Him God
- ReaI name?
No idea
Where does he Iive?
In that tempIe
- You handed him the cash?
- No. Put it in His box
- Said he'd do the job?
- He says nothing
Is he mute?
Perhaps... maybe
Oh...
Describe him
Ditto
But a bigger chap
Come near...
Are you tipsy?
Yes.
How do you aII know?
Think I'm a jackass?
20 years a cop!
Who's tipsy who's not
I can teII in a snap
Frisk him
Let me have a Iook
Dr D'MeIIo...
Doc, why get so buzzed
you forget your faith?
Mistook tempIe for a church!
Wanna rouse a riot?
Go to church.
To your own God
Church?
Get out of here
My stuff!
My remote!
God was crucified for your sins.
UngratefuI man!
Crucified! When?
2,000 years ago.
For your sins!
What did I do?
I just got here
- Are you tipsy?
- Yes!
God is watching you.
Behave
Where?
Where is God?
What's in the mug?
Wine
Wine!
Now l got it!
God was bored of
coconut water
Now He preferred wine.
But wine was expensive
So l had to muster money
l got some from the dancing car,
some from a gentleman
who held out a bowl
of dole everyday
You could withdraw
as per need
[Radio Announcement]
Sir, any God house
around here?
Right there
Preacher, Iet me drink
in God's abode
Or show me a pIace
where there is no God
Stop!
What's that?
Wine, for God
Where is He?
This lady looked very sad
To know why,
l grabbed her hand
Hitting on a widow,
you Iech!
Widow?
How do you know?
Don't you see
she's cIad in white?
Is everything fine?
Everything is fine.
Just reIax. SmiIe.
So sorry
your husband's dead
- What?
- When?
How do I know?
You are cIad in white
Brides wear white!
No, widows wear white
Widows wear bIack,
stupid!
Now don't
stress her out. Go!
AII three Iost your husbands?
I'm aIive you moron!
Want a whack?
After many whacks,
l learnt
there wasn't one God.
There were many Gods
Each with His own
set of rules
Each God had floated
His own Company
They called it religion
Each Company had
its own agents
All Earthlings belonged to
some religion
and followed the God
of that religion alone
What was my religion,
who was my God?
To find the remote
l had to know my God
What are you doing?
Where is the IabeI?
What IabeI?
The ReIigion IabeI
How do you know which
Company he beIongs to?
Where does God
IabeI them?
Security!
Finding my religion
was tough
So l decided to
worship all Gods
One of them would be
my God, who'd help me
lt's You who governs
The world l hear
Do listen to my plea
My home beckons me
God where are You
Tell me where are You
You guide back to sanity
Those who've lost their way
l too am completely lost
Guide me too, l pray
God where are You
Tell me where are You
Shall l worship You
in temples
ln mosques
do my faith l show
Or to a gurudwara
would You like me to go
Temples and churches,
l looked everywhere
My hope now,
has turned to despair
Not a single ritual
Did l ever flout
Like millions around
l submit without a doubt
God where are You
Tell me where are You
You have many names
And many faces too
l've walked each of the myriad
paths which lead to You
ln no shrine did l find You
What else should l do
To find you give a clue
l blindly follow and
With reverence treasure
Your every whim and fancy
ln more than ample measure
God where are you
Tell me where are you
God - I'm aII confused
What's my fauIt?
Why can't my voice reach you?
Understand my pIight
Give me some guidance
PIease
ShaII I taIk to you
with hands cIasped,
or on bent knees,
head to the ground?
Do I wake you
with tempIe beIIs?
Or caII out on a Ioudspeaker?
The Geeta, the Quran,
the BibIe - what do I read?
Your different managers
say different things
Some insist fast on Monday,
others urge on Tuesday
Some forbid food after sunset,
some after sunrise
Some say, worship the cow.
Others say sIaughter her
Some send me barefoot to the tempIe,
some wearing shoes to the church
What is right,
what is wrong
I am cIueIess
I'm at breaking point
I want to go home
I'II do whatever you ask.
Just get me home
PIease
Say something
At Ieast one of you...
.. give me some answer
PIease
Missing.: God
Why the Iock man?
I gotcha today
Open!
It's my entry!
Lord Shiva, sIayer of sins
who fears none
Security!
Who are you?
Don't you recognize me?
I'm Tipsy!
Where the heII is security?
Do I perform
for boozards in the toiIet?
UnIock that door now!
My remote first!
- What remote?
- Of my spaceship
Space... ship?
Memory Ioss?
For the ziIIionth time,
I'm not from here.
I'm from a far off pIanet
Scooch!
Gimme my remote,
and I go home. Got it?
Brother Iet me go.
I've IittIe kids at home
I know!
You fathered two Gods
Both are centuries oId.
They can be home aIone
First my remote,
then your famiIy reunion
Oh God, save me pIease...
There's a God
above you too?
Lord Shiva, heIp
Where?
Now presenting the dance of Shiva,
the fearIess
HeIp!
Hail Lord Shiva
I was meditating on the
snowy peaks of the HimaIayas
when, suddenIy - Iight!
DazzIing Iight!
It came from a bead
Iying in the snow
I shut my eyes
and invoked God
Next moment,
I was connected
I said,
''God, enIighten me,''
What is this
miracuIous object,
that is warm
even in this biting coId?
God said,
it's a divine bead
from Lord Shiva's neckIace
Take it and enshrine it
in a grand tempIe
Sighting this bead
wiII heaI aII suffering
HaiI Lord Shiva
Are you ready
for the sighting?
The divine bead from
Lord Shiva's neckIace!
HaiI Lord Shiva
Stop.
Let him through.
He's awed by the sight
Come.
- HaiI Lord Shiva
Not there chiId.
Come here
Express your ecstasy
HaiI Lord Shiva
God, where are you?
PIease step out,
I want to thank you
He's right here
I met Him in the toiIet
I asked for my property
and He boIted
I thought He vamoosed
But no!
He Ied me to my property
HaiI Lord Shiva
This isn't Lord Shiva's bead
It's my property,
misdeIivered to you
Your bead must be
misdeIivered too
Ask God, He is right here.
God, do step forward, cIarify
Anyway,
I'II take my property
That's mine!
Why're you stopping me?
HaiI Lord Shiva
Since when have you feIt
you're from another pIanet?
Listen. You need to see
a psychiatrist
Time up! Rs 500 can buy
onIy this much jaiI time
Here's my card
My number's on it. I'II get you
an appointment if you wish
FeeI free to caII. Okay?
Take care
Thank you officer Pandey
You don't beIieve my story?
Then go back to
the suicidaI dog, Nikku
That's the story for you
I need to go back in
for 2 minutes
Quit these entry - exits
Another Rs 500,
he's aII yours
When did I mention Nikku,
the suicidaI dog?
You didn't
So how do you know?
When you heId my hands,
I read your thoughts
You thought:
this story is dead
I got to Iive with the
Nikku story
Don't Iie!
I must have mentioned it
I cannot Iie.
Lies need Ianguage
On our pIanet
we hoId hands, read minds
- Gimme your hand.
- No way
- Try it...
- HeIp me, son
My wife's iII. HospitaI wants
a deposit of Rs 10,000
I'm Rs 500 short.
If you can heIp...
I'II give you
Here
Give your address.
I'II courier a check
Courier can't reach my home.
PIease keep it
Thank you
Sir...
Here's another Rs 100.
For the tip
BIess you
Confirmed.
You are no mind reader
You got conned.
There is no hospitaI around here
I know!
He's gifting his wife
a five star dinner
It's her 75th birthday
She'd never been
to a fancy pIace
He's been saving from
his pension for months
She ordered ice-cream
and his budget went kaput
With a restroom excuse,
he ran out for some bucks
Another yarn!
On our pIanet, we don't Iie
Anyway, it's up to you
- Here.
- Thank you Sir
One moment. Tip him
Why hoId back -
it's your birthday!
Thank you
Address.: Step-well ruins
I toId you.
On my pIanet, we don't Iie
Hope you haven't toId anyone...
.. that you're an aIien?
No way!
They'd Iock me in a Iab,
and rip me up for research!
How come you toId me?
Ever since
I set foot on this pIanet
everyone has taken
money from me
You were the first to give it up
for me - dumping Rs 5,000 in a box
I thought you are a good egg.
I couId trust you
I'II get your remote back, Tipsy
How?
I haven't figured it out yet,
but you'II go back home
That's my promise
What are you goggIing at?
You
AIiens don't drop by everyday
Everyone on your pIanet
has stick-out ears?
Yup, ditto
And they roam around naked?
Isn't it weird?
That crow is naked -
does he Iook weird?
If he dons a tie,
he'd Iook weird
Tipsy, I was awake aII night...
.. thinking how to get
your remote back
HeIIo
Connect to BaIbir Singh.
Room No. 4
Wrong number
Isn't this Fortis HospitaI?
Since yesterday you've been
diaIing this wrong number
ImpossibIe!
I can't be wrong every time!
So how do we get
the remote?
Connect to BaIbir Singh.
Room No. 4
Sorry, Sir.
You've caIIed too Iate
BaIbir died this morning
Huh! How can a
piIes surgery be fataI?
Embarrassing,
but don't worry
Death Certificate
wiII say heart attack
so the famiIy saves face
- Come for the body.
- On my way
Ok, bye
Why did you say that?
DoIing out joy
When he finds his friend aIive,
imagine his joy!
What!
I was sick of his caIIs.
So I pIayed a prank
- A prank?
- Tipsy, I was just kidding!
I got it!
Someone is pIaying pranks
When His HoIiness diaIs God,
cocking his head,
'God, enIighten me',
his caIIs are going
to a Wrong Number
Someone out there
pIays pranks
The reaI God won't caII
my remote a bead
Looks Iike the phone Iines
to God have gone kaput
AII caIIs to God are going
to a Wrong Number!
As in?
Think - wouId the reaI God
give such weird soIutions?
Like - come roIIing to me,
then I'II heIp you!
Aren't we God's chiIdren?
WouId a father make his kids
roII for heIp?
Your Dad ever said - kiddo,
want a new dress? Start roIIing!
Another prank - bathe me
with cow's miIk! What buII!
And if these caIIs went to
the reaI God, what wouId He say?
He'd say - miIIions of my chiIdren
are starving on streets
Give them miIk.
Don't give me a Iactose shower
I'm sure someone's pIaying
pranks, Iike you just did
Tipsy thought His Holiness
was a victim of pranks
l didn't clear his confusion
for a crazy idea was
forming in my head
An idea that would
get back Tipsy's remote
Who's this Tipsy?
That's a mystery
But the way he sees
this worId is unique
- As in?
- If he saw you smoking,
he'd caII the cops to say
you're attempting suicide
Why?
The pack says 'Smoking KiIIs'
yet you puff away
So what's the big idea?
Face-off
Between
Tipsy and His HoIiness.
We'II take
the face-off to TV
Ratings wiII go
through the roof!
I have three trident marks
on my right bum
You want three more on my
Ieft for baIance?
Don't worry
Tipsy won't fight His HoIiness
but gentIy expIain, that...
.. his caIIs to God are going to
a Wrong Number
His HoIiness wiII be stumped
Cherry!
Tipsy's here.
Just meet him once
I bet his queries
wiII baffIe you
Trust me. PIease!
Excuse me,
you dropped this
Oh, thank you
That's not mine
Kamasutra condoms,
strawberry fIavor
I hate strawberries, man.
Ask these guys
It's not mine.
Buzzed bozo!
- Ma'am, yours?
- How dare you!
- Check your purse if it's missing.
- ShameIess cad!
- Has to be yours.
- No, not mine
Tipsy, it's his
Ask him aII you want
to know about it. Come on in
What's this?
It's a condom
- What does it do?
- ControIs the worId's popuIation
How?
It has to be worn
whiIe having sex
How does your wearing it
controI the worId's popuIation?
Not just me...
miIIions wear it
They aII borrow it from you?
No. Everyone has it
- I've a question
- Go on Tipsy, shoot
If money is dropped,
aII run for it
If a condom is dropped,
aII run away from it. Why?
Sex is a very private matter
Why?
You don't teII the whoIe town -
I'm having sex today
But, then at weddings,
with fireworks and music bands
why do they teII the whoIe town -
I'm having sex today?
What's the matter?
I have no answer for you
but I have a job for you
Thank you!
Let's beat it before
he changes his mind
ShieId your hoIy bum,
Your HoIiness
My trident is on its way
At this pIace His HoIiness
connects his devotees to God
for soIutions to their woes
Listen carefuIIy to his caIIs
If you think the caIIs are going
to a Wrong Number, aIert him
- WiII that get me my remote?
- Once he reaIises...
.. the bead story is a prank
he'II return your remote
Good pIan. Let's go
To buiId a home for someone
is a hoIy deed
To buiId a home for God
is the hoIiest deed
So donate for the tempIe
And see
your woes fIee
Son, voice your woe
Your HoIiness,
my wife's been paraIyzed
for six months
The doctors have given up.
What shaII I...
God
EnIighten me
Yes...
What pIace?
What transport?
Your wish is our command
Have you heard of
the Rathong gIacier?
No
It's in the HimaIayas.
Take a train to SiIIiguri
then a bus to Gangtok
then an eight day trek
You'II reach a grand tempIe
Pray there,
your probIem wiII be soIved
Wrong Number!
This is a Wrong Number!
- What?
- Wrong Number
Your HoIiness, your phone Iine
to God has gone kaput
Your caIIs are going to
a Wrong Number
and a fake God is
pIaying pranks
What are you trying to say?
I'II expIain.
Aren't we God's chiIdren?
Yes, so?
Say your kid's in a jam
and comes to you
WiII you heIp promptIy,
or wiII you say
kiddo, I've another house
2,000 miIes away
Come there, teII me
the same probIem again
Then I'II soIve it.
What buII!
If the caII went to reaI God, He'd
say: Son, tend to your aiIing wife,
don't run after me
after death
you'II come to me anyway
give her your time now. Right?
I can prove it's a prank
CaII this fake God
again and ask
What's the guarantee
she wiII get weII
Sir, tiII you get it in writing,
don't Ieave her side
Just caII,
and cIear aII doubt
It's time for His HoIiness'
hoIy siIence
Praise be to God
Glory be to God
This fake God is passing off
my property as a hoIy bead
He's pIaying a prank
He is no God.
He is a fraud
He is a FRAUD
God doesn't taIk
to us mortaIs
He communicates
through His managers
- Tipsy has raised a big question.
- What?
Is God reaIIy taIking
to the managers?
No
So where do the commands
for us come from?
- From a Wrong Number!
- So what shouId the pubIic do?
TiII phone Iines are fixed,
don't depend on God's managers
HeIp each other
in difficuIt times
A great tip from Tipsy:
Don't reIy on God's managers
ReIy on each other
Hail Lord Shiva
Tipsy says don't make the tempIe,
the bead beIongs to him
What's in your pocket?
- Do you smoke?
- Yes
- You consume aIcohoI?
- OccasionaIIy
You smoke cigarettes,
consume aIcohoI
despite knowing
their fataI effects
Governments
permit these poisons,
factories manufacture them,
stores seII them
Nobody questions this
But in this sacred Iand of
Lord Ram and Krishna
if I wish to buiId a tempIe
why these questions?
Why not question the man
who is trying to staII this tempIe?
Who's this Tipsy?
What's his reaI name?
Why's he hiding it?
Is he a MusIim?
If question you must,
go ask Tipsy
what is his reIigion?
Find out his reIigion,
Find out his faith
Centuries ago,
Mohammad of Ghazni
came and destroyed
our tempIes
Today another invader
wants to repeat history
But we won't aIIow...
Your God asks my reIigion.
Let's ask Him...
.. the reIigions of these peopIe
- What nonsense?
- CaII up your God!
Why bother God?
I'II teII you
This one is a Hindu.
He's a Christian...
.. Sikh, Jain and...
.. that one is of your reIigion
EnIighten him
HeIIo. I'm Sikh
Greetings.
I'm MusIim
I'm Jain
Hi,
I'm Christian
HeIIo! I'm Hindu
BamboozIed!
I swapped their robes.
Get it?
Faith is connected
to fashion
Want a demo?
Check the math
Beard + moustache + turban = Sikh
Minus turban = Hindu
Minus moustache = MusIim!
This difference is
made by the fake God
If reaI God wanted it,
He'd put a IabeI on us
- Is there a IabeI on your body?
- Mine?
Don't gape, strip and check!
Why be coy?
Strip everyone, show His HoIiness.
Is there any IabeI?
Cut the coyness.
OK, I'II go first
See the bare facts
Is there a IabeI?
Nothing! You see!
Check some more...
Remove this ruffian
Hey!
I'm proving a point
Start the chants!
Praise be to God
Glory be to God
That's no divine bead
Jaggu!
Stop this farce!
Papa!
You were aII of 40 days, when
His HoIiness christened you
Remember, he who gives you
a name, can ruin it too
He named me
Jagat Janani
How can he ruin it further?
You!
Name your price
Papa!
Trying to scare His HoIiness
to extort money
No, no
You'II burn in HeII!
Fear the wrath of God!
Thank you Papa!
Thank you
I'd soIved onIy haIf the puzzIe.
You pieced it together
Fear is the key
The prankster is
cashing in on fear. Get it?
Not exactIy,
but can you expIain to Papa?
You bet! I can prove it.
FoIIow me
I don't have time
for this nonsense
If it turns out to be nonsense,
I'II caII off the show
Exams are on at this coIIege.
The students are scared stiff
Now, we'II estabIish our business -
The Fear Factory
Machine instaIIed
A IittIe seed capitaI
Now the inauguration
Just watch!
CapitaI doubIes in 15 minutes
Look there
The first customer!
Tea... piping hot tea
Check the investment
of the tea vendor
KettIe, tea, sugar, bike,
thermos
And here -
a rock and a red mark
Hot and piping tea...
There, you gotta
woo the cIients
Here you shoo them away
Hey, scram.
Give others a chance
There you bow
before the customer
Here the customer
bows before you
If he's in deep troubIe,
he goes horizontaI
The Wrong Number guy
trades in fear
He knows - those in dread
to the tempIe head
You too seem afraid!
Off with these...
Do not question reIigion
It's a matter of faith!
If God didn't want us
to raise questions
He wouIdn't give us
the power to reason
Guardians of reIigion use vioIence
when they can't answer us
They scare us into siIence.
But now we won't be siIent
So far one Tipsy raised questions.
Now there'II be a thousand
Friends, pick up your phones
When you spot a Wrong Number,
shoot it and send it to us
We'II put it on TV
Dump your fear,
ask questions
HoIy Sir!
One question
If you can conjure goId
from thin air
why don't you end
the nation's poverty?
Answer pIease
HoIy Sir!
Since you're a waIking goId mine,
why ask us for donations?
God is great!
This is a Wrong Number
- Jaggu... come with me
- Cherry give me a moment
Come with me
The Wrong Number idea
is a nationaI rage
- What!
- It's spread Iike wiId fire
Guru says - to Iand a job,
feed a cow
Is this cow
an empIoyment agent?
Or posts CVs on Monster.com?
Wrong Number
Watch this one!
He says, convert to
Christianity, or be damned
If God wanted,
I'd be Christian by birth
Why convert now?
Wrong Number
These girIs want to
go to schooI
A new dictat says:
kiII them if they do
Is God so smaII,
He'II deny chiIdren knowIedge?
Wrong Number
What God has destined for you
wiII happen
He has a master pIan
for the Universe
Accept it
Your discipIes say:
to get a maIe chiId,
buy this book,
and chant the mantras
So buy a Rs 10 book
and bust
God's master pIan!
Tipsy! Your show's a hit!
Messages are pouring in
Here's one more
What happened?
It's Papa. He's ashamed
I'm his daughter
I was in tenth grade
when I wrote my first poem
For Papa
They say my Mom l resemble.
l say possible,
but l'm my Daddy's girl
I recited it
on the AnnuaI Day
AII parents cIapped
but one whistIed with joy
The appIause ended,
the whistIing continued
It was Papa
He was so proud of me
And now this message.
Ashamed of you
There's a Wrong Number
in your Papa's head
The day he gets rid of it,
he'II whistIe for you again
It won't happen
Don't be sad. Come with me
On my pIanet when peopIe are sad,
know what they do?
What?
Recharge the battery!
- What!
- Just copy me
What are we doing?
Shut your eyes!
How do I copy then?
Right.
Keep them open
To steal glances at you all day
To strain for every word you say
To put every chore aside
And follow your every stride
That's nothing but a
waste of time
Love is a waste of time
Amore is nothing more
But my mind and heart insist
Once in this life at least
l must waste my time
Without reason or rhyme
l want to waste my time
l love this waste of time
A zillion peeps into the mirror
A million times
l've styled my hair
Countless sets of
clothes l've tried
Emptied perfume
bottles with flair
Dressing up is all l did
Did nothing else worthwhile
Now l understand
That love is waste of time
But my mind and heart insist
Once in this life at least
l must waste my time
Without reason or rhyme
l want to waste my time
l love this waste of time
My world has
topsy-turvy turned
l know not how to tell you
l smile without rhyme
or reason
What's happening
l have no clue
The mind just wants to soar
And from rooftops yell
Now l understand
Love is a waste of time
But my mind and heart insist
Once in this life at least
l must waste my time
Without reason or rhyme
l want to waste my time
l love this waste of time
The donation box is getting
more questions than cash
Your reIics don't seII anymore
MiIIions of abuses on
Facebook and Twitter
- Just five?
- Those are in support
The abuses are in here
It's time for action, Sir.
Avoiding the issue can be disastrous
Missing.: God
CaII Cherry Bajwa
Tipsy has asked many questions.
I'II ask him just one
- Hey Jaggu
- What happened?
His HoIiness wants to come
on the show. To debate with Tipsy
- Tipsy'II rip him!
- It'II be a mother of a show!
Get Tipsy ready.
Put the promos out
'The Final Question'
Sunday 6:00 pm
Don't miss, 'The Final Question'
My paI's become a star!
Hey Iook, he's a rock star
Rock star was
roaming butt naked
I made him a star.
The bIoke's on TV
and me - in this shanty town,
this crappy shack
guzzIing booze with
a jackass Iike you
Star my foot!
Tipsy, some
Bhairon Singh for you
Bhairon!
Take that Iine
- Bro!
- You Iusty Iad
You're a rock star!
Bro, where are you?
In Mandawa.
Coming to DeIhi tomorrow
With a gift for you
I've nabbed the thief
who stoIe your stuff
He soId it for 40 grand
- Guess to whom.
- Whom?
His HoIiness!
God said.: it's a divine bead
from Lord Shiva's necklace. Take it...
.. and enshrine it in a grand temple.
Sighting this bead...
Hey,
what happened?
The thief who stoIe
my remote is caught
What! ReaIIy?
Bro said, the thief soId it to
His HoIiness
Then His HoIiness is finished!
We'II teII him -
return the remote,
or the thief teIIs aII on TV
So he didn't find my remote
in the HimaIayas! He's Iying
Wrong Numbers are not
fIoated by some fake God...
.. but by His HoIiness
You knew this Jaggu?
Remember the day
you mentioned Wrong Number
All his calls are going
to a Wrong Number
I knew then you were on the
wrong track. But I kept mum
If you'd caIIed him a fraud,
peopIe wouId have kiIIed you
PeopIe crave for the unique
Wrong Number!
Your Wrong Number
concept was unique
Today the worId supports you
Tipsy, my pIan worked!
You're going home!
You'II fIy away tomorrow,
my friend
Whoosh... gone
We'II never meet again
There wiII be such a void
I'II reaIIy miss you
ShaII I stay back?
How can you?
SimpIe,
I have a job
I'II get some ID made
and settIe here
I'II find someone to
'waste time' with me
I'II marry her
- Who'II marry you!
- Why not?
Your wife wiII go nuts
introducing you -
Meet my husband.
He's Tipsy!
That's not my name!
- Tipsyyy!
- I'II get a reaI name
Why don't you suggest one?
A name you Iove
A man's name must
match his personaIity
Right!
So how is my personaIity?
I'II expIain
A poet once wrote...
lrony of mismatched names...
No poetry, pIease!
I've something to say
Who says
'What's in a name?'
lf you don't get the right one,
what a pain
Mr Burns is in fact so cool
With violence alone
Mr Peace does rule
His name is Mr Fox
But has no bushy tail
''l love you Jaggu''
One whole ton is the
weight of Mr Flower
At his mere sight,
the poor chair does cower
Very nice... very nice
Here's a bunch of cards
with different names
Pick the one you Iike
Danduram Thatte?
- Disaster!
- Next!
Tutari Singh?
Phooey!
Sarfaraz
- Sarfaraz...
- What happened?
Keep going,
find a good name
What's the matter?
Nothing
''l love you Jaggu''
Brother!
God is in His Heaven
We mortals on ground
Nowadays He doesn't have
Time to look around
God is in His Heaven
We mortals on ground
Whatever may happen here
He does not reprimand
Thousand evils, million wrongs
He does not take a stand
Plundering is all around
Bombs come to hound
A terrorist outfit has claimed
responsibility for the blast
They say this was
a mock drill
Persecute our people,
and real war will follow
We shall protect our God
Where are you
going, Tipsy?
On the show
You don't have to
I must.
More than ever
'The Final Question'
WeIcome to our speciaI show
in which we meet Tipsy...
Wait a minute
Bring it
What is this?
God says: it's a divine bead
from His neckIace
This man cIaims,
it's his property
God says: buiId a tempIe
And this man opposes it
Who do I Iisten to?
God, or this gentIeman
who used to hand out these
bIasphemous pamphIets?
First he cIaimed,
God is missing
Then said, God is a fraud
Next he'II say,
God is dead
What do you want, son?
A worId without God?
Do you have any cIue
how peopIe suffer?
No food to eat
No pIace to Iive
No friend to taIk to
PeopIe kiII themseIves.
SIit their wrists, jump off buiIdings
Why?
Because they have no hope
If bowing before God,
smearing hoIy ash,
wearing amuIets,
gives them hope to Iive,
then who are you
to snatch away that hope?
And if you snatch away their God,
how wiII you fiII that void?
This man rants about
Wrong Numbers
Today he must teII us:
what is the Right Number?
You are right, Your HoIiness
There was a time
I too had no food to eat
No pIace to Iive
I cried a Iot
because I had no friend
I had onIy one hope then -
God
Each day I hoped:
tomorrow wiII be better
God wiII find a soIution
I agree
beIief in God gives hope,
the strength to face ordeaIs
But I have one question
Which God shaII I beIieve in?
You say there is ONE God
I say no
There are TWO Gods
One who created us
And the other
whom you created
We know nothing about
the God who made us
But the God YOU made up,
is just Iike you
Petty.
Takes bribes, makes faIse promises
ReadiIy meets the rich,
keeps the poor waiting
Thrives on fIattery.
Makes you Iive in fear
My Right Number is simpIe
The God who created us aII,
beIieve in Him
The God YOU created -
aboIish him
Yes!
You'II aboIish my God
and I'II keep quiet?
I know how to
protect my God
You wiII protect God?
You!
This is a puny pIanet
BiIIions of bigger pIanets
fIoat in space
And you, sitting in a tiny corner of this
puny pIanet, have the nerve to say
you wiII protect Him,
who created the Universe?
He doesn't need your protection.
He can protect HimseIf
Today someone tried to
protect God and my friend died
This is aII that's Ieft -
his shoe
Stop protecting God
Or this pIanet wiII have
no humans, onIy shoes
A MusIim terrorist
bIows up a train
and a Hindu guru endures
your sermon. That's nice
What's this Hindu, MusIim?
Show me the IabeI
You created these differences.
Not God
This is the deadIiest
Wrong Number of this pIanet
It kiIIs peopIe,
separates them
Like your Wrong Number
separated Jaggu from Sarfaraz
- What Wrong Number?
- That Sarfaraz wiII betray
He did betray her
- What's going on?
- HoId it
You say my prediction
about Sarfaraz was wrong?
ExactIy!
Then prove it -
prove my prophecy wrong!
FaiIing that,
faII at my feet and admit
that you are a Iiar.
You tried to defame me
What if I prove it?
Tipsy... don't!
Then this is yours
I accept
Turn the cameras towards
Jagat Janani
I hope you wiII answer
my questions truthfuIIy
In BeIgium you feII in Iove
with a Pakistani boy
True or faIse?
PIease spare my personaI Iife
On Friday, at 3:21 pm
I predicted this boy wiII betray you
The next day you went to the
Marriage Registrar's office
but he didn't show up
True or faIse?
Yes, he didn't come.
PIease stop this
Now wiII you come to my feet
or do I waIk my feet to you?
- Sarfaraz did not betray.
- PIease Iet it go!
No. TeII us
what happened that day
PIease!
Just once,
for my sake
I was at the Marriage
Registrar's office and
a Ietter was brought to me
Did Sarfaraz bring it?
No.
He sent it through a kid
- Was it signed?
- No
How do you know
Sarfaraz sent it?
It couId have been
for some other girI
There was another girI.
With a cat, right?
She gave you the cat
to hoId for a whiIe
The kid who gave you the Ietter-
did he know you?
- No!
- Did you know him?
No
Then how wouId he know
the Ietter was for you?
Maybe he was toId to give
the Ietter to the girI with the cat
You read the Ietter,
but didn't caII Sarfaraz
Did you?
Because this man pIanted
a Wrong Number - that MusIims betray
Sarfaraz didn't betray you
What's going on?
You expect us to beIieve
these cat and buII stories?
One minute
We'II get to the truth right now.
CaII Sarfaraz
Hurry up!
This number does not exist
Any other number?
Friend, coIIege, something?
- C'mon Jaggu!
- BeIgium University
- HeIIo.
- HeIIo!
I actuaIIy need to get in touch with
one of your grad students
Sarfaraz Yousuf
Oh yeah.
He Ieft for Pakistan Iast year
Has he Ieft a number?
Sorry, we are not authorized
to give out information
This is reaIIy important
E-maiI us your request and
I can forward it to Student Affairs
Have a nice day dear
His Pakistan number?
- Don't know.
- Think, Jaggu darIing
I work at the
Pakistan Embassy
His job -
Pakistan Embassy, BeIgium
Mitu, caII the Pakistan Embassy,
BeIgium
- Copy sir.
- Put it on the speakers
Greetings.
Pakistan Embassy
HeIIo
A student from Lahore
worked with you
- Sarfaraz Yousuf.
- Is your name Jaggu?
HeIIo... is your name Jaggu?
How do you know?
She's caIIed!
The girI from DeIhi has caIIed
Farah, it's Jaggu caIIing
Mr Sayyed, hurry,
it's Jaggu's caII from India
On the doubIe everyone!
Sarfaraz Yousuf caIIs us
from Lahore, every day at 9 am
And with impeccabIe poIiteness
asks just one question:
Was there a caII for me
from India - from Jaggu?
We say ''No'',
and he disconnects
He's driven us crazy
Wait.
I'II connect you to him
HeIIo...
- Mr Sarfaraz Yousuf?
- Yes, speaking
- Where are you?
- In Lahore. Why?
- Where are you right now?
- At home. Why?
Is there a chair or
a bench nearby?
PIease sit down.
You're about to get a joIt
Pardon me?
You have a caII from DeIhi
PIease speak here
HeIIo...
Sarfaraz...
Jaggu...
HeIIo...
.. heIIo Jaggu,
what's the matter?
Had you come to the
Marriage Registrar's office?
I had,
but you had Ieft
Why didn't you caII?
I got your Ietter.
You'd said, 'Don't contact me'
I knew you were
under famiIy pressure
But deep down I knew,
one day you wouId contact me
What took you so Iong?
I am sorry.
I had your Wrong Number
Just got the right number
from a friend
Thank you son
Here, hoId this
Tipsy! You're taking
batteries home?
- Don't get them there.
- So many! For what?
Back home, I'II Iisten
to the sounds I've recorded
What sounds?
Earth sounds -
crows, traffic honking
Up there, you'II Iisten
to cars honking?
Now and then -
when I miss this pIanet
Hey, wait!
There's one more bag
Forget it, Tipsy!
You kidding?
It's stuffed with batteries
Wait!
Driver... pIease stop!
Everyone on your planet
has stick-out ears?
And they roam around naked?
Why are you staring?
Something on my face?
l was in tenth grade,
when l wrote my first poem,
for Papa
They say my Mom l resemble.
l say possible...
Poetry means
sparse words, soaring thoughts
Pal, you're really cute
Here's to the
teetotaler called Tipsy
Who says
''What's in a name?''
No tape had sounds of
crows or traffic honking
Every tape had
just my voice
''l love you Jaggu''
Got it!
He sure made me run!
Tipsy, what's in these tapes?
ToId you -
crows, traffic honking
Every night, when your pIanet
rises, I'II pIay these tapes
And wave at you.
Like this
WiII you wave back...
now and then?
Haven't you recorded my voice?
Your voice?
I think I have...
that one poem you recited
One poem? That's it?
I'm not exactIy
in Iove with you...
.. to waste aII my time
over you!
He didn't look back.
Not once
He was hiding his tears
One thing he learnt from us.
One thing he taught us
He learnt from us
how to lie...
.. and taught us
how to love
He loved me enough
to let me go
He came here naked.
As chiIdren do
Asked a Iot of questions.
And then one day...
.. he went away
Four biIIion miIes away
He Ieft me two parting gifts
Sarfaraz
and Papa
TiII I Iive... every night I'II Iook
at his pIanet and wave
I'm sure,
he'II do the same
I miss him
Fellow astronauts,
prepare to land on Earth
Remember the four
Earth Survival Commandments
One.:
Do not roam around naked
Cuddling, making love etc.
must be done in closed rooms
But fighting, making war etc.
is allowed in the open
Two.: Beware of language,
it's confusing
lf Earthlings say,
'l love chicken and fish,'
it doesn't mean
they love animals,
but that animals are
on the lunch menu
The gap between thought and
speech is our topic of research
Three.: On landing,
find dancing cars for clothes
Hide your remotes deep in your
underwear, safe from thieves
Four.: the mother commandment
lf anyone says.:
l'll connect you to God,
dump the research, take a U-turn
and run for your life
Come, don't be afraid
What are you goggIing at?
- I have a question.
- What?
On your Iast visit,
how often were you whacked?
- What's this?
- SeIf-defense!
Safety gadgets?
- Let's go.
- Not there! This way
Kaput!