PRISONERS
Our Father, Who art in heaven,
Hallowed be Thy Name,
Thy kingdom come,
Thy will be done,
on earth as it is in heaven.
Give us this day our daily bread,
and forgive us our trespasses,
as we forgive those
who trespass against us;
lead us not into temptation,
but deliver us from evil.
For the kingdom, the power,
and the glory is yours,
now and forever.
Amen.
You know the most important thing
your Grandpa ever taught me. Mm?
Be ready.
Hurricane, flood,
whatever it ends up being.
No more food gets delivered
to the grocery store,
gas stations dry up…
People just turn on
each another and uh…
all of a sudden all that stands
between you and being dead is you.
I'm proud of you son.
That was a nice shot.
Okay. Come on, hon.
Oh, wait, wait, wait.
I forgot something.
Hold on a second, Anna.
Are we taking the truck?
We're going across the street you dope.
— Come on.
— Hey, wait for your mother, please!
— Give me a ride.
— Here.
Oh, you're getting heavy.
Um… Danny's Dad said
he'd sell me their old car.
I got half of what I need
saved from the summer,
I thought maybe—
— Forget it.
I'm barely getting enough carpentry work
to keep up with the mortgage.
Well, why don't you rent out
Grandpa's old apartment house?
Like I keep telling your
mother, it's an old building.
It would cost a fortune to fix it up.
Ok, ok…
They're here!
Hello!
— Happy Thanksgiving!
Oh, for God's sake!
Keller, get the hell in here!
Keller, you bring that poor deer you shot?
This one's Ralph's.
Well, you killed it,
you take it into the kitchen.
Alright, join.
Join.
You are missing the game!
Anna, come here…
Alright, you're in charge of this.
Us veterinarians make lousy butchers.
No problem.
Can I go outside with Joy?
Uh… convince your brother
to go with you and you can.
And wear a hat, please.
You're just getting over a cold.
Joy, you wear a hat too.
Did you feel bad for that deer
when you shot it?
Do you feel bad for cows
when you go to McDonald's?
That's what my Dad says.
And the deer, if they have too many
babies and the babies starve anyway.
You gotta keep the population down.
— Right.
Did your Dad say that too?
Hey, get away from that thing!
Come on, let's go.
— No.
— I said, let's go.
— Hey, hey, hey. Come on, let's go.
— No. Let me…
— Let's go. Come on,
come on, come on.
Wait. Did you hear that?
Somebody's in there.
Alright, I don't feel like
getting yelled at. Let's go.
Now the school board's telling me
there's no money
for the marching band uniforms.
These kids are wearing the same uniforms
they had when we went there,
and they were old then.
They're marching right out of 1979.
Why isn't he speaking to me?
He doesn't speak.
Cutie pie.
Oh, my gosh!
He's fast. Woh.
He's so quick. Is that a slide?
Thank y'all. Thank y'all.
I got a surprise.
— Yes!
— No.
You gotta listen out for it,
cause this is not easy.
Mom. Mommy, can I take
Joy to our house?
Why?
My red whistle.
She's gonna help me look for it.
Oh, sweetheart, I think
that whistle is long gone.
What whistle?
The emergency whistle Daddy gave me.
I lost it…
A hundred and thirty-three days ago.
Well, if you wanna find a whistle,
you have to whistle for it.
So we'll do Jingle Bells to find it.
Jingle bells, Batman smells,
Robin laid an egg!
The Batmobile lost a wheel
and the Joker got away! Yay!
— Okay! Okay!
— You can go, alright?
Just make sure you ask Ralph
to go with you, please.
No looking in the basement.
— I won't.
— Stay out of the basement.
But I am taking requests from you, Keller.
— From me?
— Your day, your request.
Oh. Uh… the piano.
No! No, no, no.
You all set?
Wait, listen. He used to love this,
but he used to dress like Springsteen.
— Really?
— I loved Springsteen, yeah.
Do you remember 'Jersey Girl'?
— Well, I ain't white…
— Yeah!
And I like him too much.
But I'm too drunk to cover The Boss.
Thank you.
— Honey, what else?
— Um… nothing comes to mind, nothing.
— Oh, oh. I know.
— What?
He actually loves the
Star Spangled Banner.
I know, I know.
Sings it in the shower, so.
— I do not!
— Yes, you do!
Where are your sisters?
I can't find them.
Did you uh… did you go
to the house with them?
No, what are you talking about?
— Really?
— No.
What? They were supposed
to come down earlier and get you.
They didn't come get you?
— No, we haven't since we ate.
— It's alright.
Don't worry, they're
probably at our house.
Anna? Joy?
Girls?
Girls!
Put these dishes in here.
They weren't outside,
it started raining.
Did you check over by the rear swing?
Yeah.
Well, they're getting
whooped when they get here.
Sorry, Grace. I whoop kids.
Wait, you said they
weren't there either.
Are they here?
— No, they're not here!
— They weren't there?
No, they're not at the house.
— Were they there?
— No, they're not there.
But I checked the entire house,
they're not here.
— The… the RV.
— What RV?
Dad, there's this RV and
they were playing on it.
There's… we thought that
there was someone inside.
Where? Where was it? Show me.
Go that way,
we'll meet you at the other side.
— Anna?
— Paul, seen my daughter walk by here?
No. You got a problem?
Anna?
Here! Dad, it was
parked right here!
Anna? Anna?
Hello? Hello?
— Do you see 'em?
— No. Hello!
I couldn't find them!
— Were you messing around in this house?
— No!
I told you not to come here.
We weren't! They were just on the RV,
we go 'em off of it.
Tell me everything you can
remember about that RV.
— Uh… there was a ladder on the back.
Wait.
Police, please.
Happy Thanksgiving.
Thanks.
Do you have any of those um…
fortune cookie things?
My boss told me cops
don't like fortune cookies.
What year were you born in?
Were you a dragon,
or a snake, or a horse…
— I am a monkey.
— Oh, you're a monkey.
You're very intelligent,
and you have an ability
to influence people.
Maybe you could influence your boss
to lower the check a little bit.
No, I cannot. My boss is a rooster.
So he's selfish and eccentric. That's…
All units, all units, an RV was
reported matching the description.
The vehicle was parked at
a rest stop off of Route 26,
northbound, past exit 17.
Any available units?
This is 12-12, responding.
10-80 responding.
This is 13-40, I'm five minutes out.
Call in all respond units.
Hey! Don't move! Hey!
Don't shoot! Don't shoot! Don't shoot!
I got this side, take the right.
Clear!
Alright. Wait, wait, wait,
wait, wait! I got this.
Hey. Hey. I see you in there.
Show me both your hands, right now.
Hey! I see you in there.
Show me your hands!
Both hands, right now!
That's it, slow. Slow. Slow!
Slow. Slowly, both hands.
Both fucking hands!
Walk! Walk!
Get up! Get up!
Get up!
Show me those girls!
Where are those girls?
Where are those girls?!
Hey, give me a flashlight.
Show me those girls.
Are they in the woods?
You took them into the woods?
Where did you put those girls?
Did you hear me?
What the fuck is this guy on?
— No, he's hiding something.
— He's fucking walking to the car.
Get in the car.
Get in the fucking car!
Walk!
Hey, call PSP.
Tell 'em to send their sniff dogs
and seal off the whole area!
— Yeah.
— The entrance, all of it.
— Alright.
— You, follow me.
— No? They weren't playing on your RV?
— No.
Okay, take a look at them again.
You don't recognize these girls?
I didn't see them. May I sit down?
What do you do in the RV?
Answer my question.
— I sleep there.
— You sleep in there.
You were sleeping out there, in the day?
Why was the RV parked outside the house?
I went for a drive.
You went for a drive?
You weren't driving.
I know for a fact those girls
were playing outside your RV.
You weren't driving, it was parked.
Was it a special day?
Were you planning on
taking little girls?
— No.
— Have you done it before?
No.
— Did you ask them to come inside?
— No.
Did you ask them to come inside the RV
and then you take them away?
— No.
— Did you put those girls somewhere?
— May I sit down?
— Please don't touch me.
— I know you put those girls somewhere.
— Did you hide 'em?
— No.
Where did you hide 'em?
Did you tie 'em up?
— Mmm…
Huh?
Hey. Hey.
Look, I know you're a good guy, alright?
I know you're a decent guy.
I'm not trying to tell you that
you're doing anything bad.
I'm just trying to get to
the right answers out of you, okay?
The real ones.
That's all I want.
Where do you usually park your RV, Alex?
— My aunt's house.
— Your aunt's house.
She lets me park it in the back yard.
The grass don't grow back there anyway.
It was my husband's.
It's for sale if you want it.
No, thanks.
Well, would you tell me what
you're doing on my property then?
I'm just glad to know where he is.
He's always home before dark.
And I just don't understand,
that boy has never been in trouble,
not a day in his life.
Uh… in the summer time he sleeps out
in the camper some, but
this time of year
he sleeps in here on a sofa bed.
That's my husband.
We had a fight,jeez… five years ago.
He walked out, didn't come back.
Alex loved him like a father.
Where are Alex's real parents?
My husband's brother and his girlfriend,
they died in a car accident
when Alex was six.
Sorry to hear that.
He doesn't have much.
What do you got?
Well, this thing's clean.
I mean, it's filthy as shit,
but we didn't find anything.
We didn't find any uh… wool fibers,
anything like that?
The girls could be wearing some wool
gloves or wool hats, no cotton fibers?
Well, if he was just using this thing
to transport them I might buy that,
but if there had been struggle,
I would have found something.
I'd start looking the woods,
by the rest stop.
Yeah, half the uniformed cops
in the state are doing that right now.
Hey, when you're done with this thing,
can you send the crew
over to the aunt's house?
Anna!
Please, come in. I'm Franklin Birch.
My wife's in here.
Honey. This is Nancy.
Detective Loki is… honey?
These photos are better than
the ones my husband gave you.
You can see her eyes more clearly.
So did we pass?
I'm sorry, what did you say?
The poly-thing… the like detector
we took this morning, did we pass?
Oh, yeah. Yes, sorry.
Yes, we appreciate your cooperation.
It's embarrassing, all the…
all this fuss.
Everyone's gonna think we're crazy
when those two come out of hiding,
wherever they are.
Do you have some reason
to believe they ran away?
No. They're happy.
But they must have run away.
I think they must have run away, right?
Um… your police captain told me
that you've solved every case
that you've ever
been assigned, is that right?
Sorry.
I'm so sorry. Do you…
do you have children, Detective?
I'm gonna find your daughter.
We believe they came back here after
they left you at the Birch's yesterday.
They were looking for
Anna's red whistle.
Right.
I read your statement.
I'm Detective Loki.
I'm heading up the investigation
into your daughter's disappearance.
Please, sit down.
Uh… my… my son already
told you that the guy
was inside the RV just watching them.
Right?
We haven't found any
physical evidence in the RV,
or his aunt's house where he lives.
Nothing?
Alex Jones unfortunately
has the IQ of a ten year-old.
There's no way that someone with the IQ
of a ten year-old could abduct two girls
in broad daylight and then…
somehow make them disappear.
Uh… well, how can he drive an RV?
I mean, if he can't
answer a question?
Well, he has a legal
Pennsylvania license.
And he ran, right?
They said he tried to run away.
Why wo— uh… why…
Why would…
why would he run?
I just spent ten hours
questioning this boy, okay?
I hear what you're saying.
Did-did you give him
a lie detector?
You gave us a lie detector,
did you give him one?
Sir, I understand what you're asking me.
Yes, we did.
— And?
We gave him a lie detector,
and there's no way…
A lie detector doesn't work
if you don't understand the questions.
Well, maybe he wasn't on his own.
How can he drive an RV
if he has an IQ of a ten year-old?
Sir, sir, hey,
we are considering all possibilities.
I don't think you are
considering all possibilities.
I hear… I hear what you're saying.
Sir, sir…
No, you listen to me! Just shut
the fuck up for a fucking second!
This is what I'm gonna
need you to do for me.
I need you to calm down.
I'm sorry. I'm sorry.
Please listen to me for a second.
Mr. Dover, I understand that
this is an incredibly hard time,
but I have every uniformed police
officer in this state looking for Anna.
I don't understand what any
of this means. They said he ran.
They said he tried to get away.
I don't understand why
he would try to run away.
We're considering all
possibilities, Mr. Dover.
I hear what you're saying.
I'm not crossing anybody off my list.
Just… let me do my job.
— Hey! Detective!
— Shit.
Hey! He stays in custody until
my daughter is found, right?
Right?
We have a forty-eight hour hold on him
until tomorrow unless we bring charges.
Then charge him with something.
Charge him.
— Mr. Dover, I understand what you're suf—
— Detective… Detective,
two little girls have gotta be worth
whatever little rule you gotta break
to keep that asshole in custody.
Now I know you can't promise me
anything, I understand that.
But I'm asking you to be sure,
be one hundred percent sure.
Thank you.
I appreciate it.
Now, you're positive he's innocent,
but you wanna keep hold of him.
Anna Dover's father was most…
Hey, I get it, I understand.
But it's not gonna happen.
You know, I'm just asking
for one more day.
Fuck you. You find his daughter,
he'll forgive you,
you don't, he's gonna hate you anyway.
So what's next?
I'm knocking on doors all night.
Yeah, well, you're coming up on 24 hours
missing and you have exactly shit.
Well, I've got nine
level 3 sex offenders
living within a ten mile
radius of Fairmont Circle.
So, if you'll—
— Go.
— Yeah.
It's right here.
Right, I'm thinking straight, okay?
It's— oh, I ain't— look.
Look, I know you—
Alright. You enjoy some German porn, uh?
Father! Open up, it's the police!
Father…
Father.
Do you mind if I take look around?
Fucking drunk.
What the fuck?
Wow.
Fuck. Oh, fuck.
No! Please, don't! Oh, God!
What's the name of your buddy
down there, huh? What's the name?
— I don't know his name!
— You don't know his name?
I don't know his name!
Hey, you know I spent six years
in the Huntington Boys Home, Father.
You know the Huntington
Boys Home, right? Huh?
Finding a real fuck like you
is a real treat for me.
— Now you tell me a fucking name.
— He didn't tell me his name!
He came to me for confession.
He said he'd killed sixteen children.
He bragged about it!
I convinced him to come back here.
He said he'd kill more.
Sixteen children, huh?
Let's go, you fucking shit!
— Hey.
— They're letting him go.
What?
The police said they're
letting him go today.
Okay. I'll take care of it.
— Dad?
— Keep searching.
Where are you going?!
You have to write your whole name.
That's better.
Mm-hmm. Good job,
now give it to the man.
Come on.
I just wanna talk.
He's a free man, I'm a free man!
Tell me what you did with them!
— Tell me!
— They didn't cry until I left them.
What did you say? What did you say?!
No, no! No, no, no!
Now, I know your Dad
was a guard at Graterford,
and I've got a daughter of my own, so
we're gonna pretend this never happened.
Okay? And as for Alex Jones, he has
orders not to leave the commonwealth.
What?
— Sir, I need you to go home.
— What?
Alright? I need you to go home—
What about what I just fucking told you?
Why aren't you sending someone
to go arrest this guy?!
Tell Detective Loki what you just told
me and he'll definitely look into it.
Go ahead.
That asshole you promised me
you'd keep in custody, right?
And you didn't.
And right now when I grabbed him
in the parking lot,
he said right to my fucking face,
they didn't cry until I'd left them.
Right to my fucking face!
He said… he said that to you
in the parking lot just now?
Right now, yeah! What did I just say?
In the parking lot!
Before you grabbed me off.
Did anyone else hear besides you?
I don't know. He was quiet,
he… he said it to me.
He wanted me to know.
— Are you sure he said that?
— What?
— Are you sure that's what he said?
Jesus Christ, you think
I'm making this up?
— No.
— Why would I make this up?
— Hey, hey, hey.
— No, no, no! Why would I make this up?
I'm not saying that to you,
I'm just asking you a couple questions.
— I will talk to him. Okay?
— No, don't talk to him!
— Mr. Dover—
— Arrest him!
What did I fucking tell you?
What did I tell you? One more day.
You're sure you didn't say anything to
Mr. Dover in the parking lot today?
Anything he could have misinterpreted.
I was right there,
they didn't say anything to each other,
the man just attacked the boy.
Nothing, like, get away from me,
or help? Or anything like that?
No.
Can I speak to Alex alone for a minute?
It's alright, sweetie.
I'll be right in the next room.
You love your aunt, don't you, Alex?
Yes.
You know if you know something
you're not telling us
that she can go to jail
for a very long time.
Do you want that for her?
After everything she's done for you?
No.
Mr. Dover, this is Detective Loki.
Have you arrested him?
Yeah look, I've just come from Alex Jones,
now he said he didn't say anything
to you in the parking lot.
Now, I pushed him pretty hard
and he didn't budge.
So look, we can't waste any more
time on this guy. Alright?
You're gonna have to trust me,
I'll let you know if I have anything
new, alright, Mr. Dover? For—
Fuckin' A.
The zipper on her coat was broken,
and I told her it didn't matter
cause we were just gonna
go right down the street.
— Ralph, Ralph.
— Why hasn't she come home?
It's been three days.
Why can't you make her come home?
I don't understand.
I don't understand!
It's been too long!
Please make her come home!
Please bring her.
— How many of these…
how many of these… ?
— I don't know!
Ssh. Okay, it's alright. Just take one.
No. I don't wanna sleep!
I don't wanna go to sleep.
You… you made me feel so safe.
You told us that you could
protect us from everything.
I'm gonna go out now and help the police,
just keep an eye on your mother.
Your sister needs us
to be brave for her.
Be brave for her, be a grown-up for me,
okay? Can you do that?
Can you do that?
I know you're scared. Look at me.
Come here.
I know you're scared.
It's gonna be okay.
The former is the reason why
we should be very patient,
the latter why we should be very
penitent when we are afflicted.
He reminds him that
trouble and affliction
are what we have all reason
to expect in this world.
Man is brought to trouble,
not as man but as sinful man,
who was in the transgression.
Man is born in sin,
and therefore born to trouble.
Come on. Com'on, Tucker.
Jingle bells, Batman
smells, Robin laid an egg!
The Batmobile lost a wheel
and the Joker got away…
Alex.
That song, where did you
hear those words? Hm?
Did you bring a change
of clothes like I told you?
Yeah. You gonna tell me why?
It's better if I just show you.
Show me what?
— Didn't you use to live here?
— Mm-hmm.
Close the door, lock it.
Welcome home.
Oh, my God. What did you do?
Keller, what in the hell—
— I heard him sing
the same song they were
singing on Thanksgiving.
I swear to God, Franklin,
the same fucking song.
And I told you what he
said in the parking lot.
— Then we take him to the police.
— No, no, no. Police won't do shit,
he'll just clam up and
act crazy like he did last time.
Someone has to make him talk. Someone!
Shit, man, this— this ain't right!
What if you're wrong?
— Come on, Franklin.
— No, no, wait! What if you're wrong?
What if you only heard what you wanted
to hear? What if… what if…
Man, I want my daughter back
as much as you do,
— Franklin! Franklin!
— but this isn't right!
We hurt him until he talks
or they're gonna die.
— This ain't— This ain't—
— No! No!
We hurt him until he talks
or they're gonna die.
That's the choice.
That's the choice you have to make.
I've made my choice.
I know what I heard.
He's not a person anymore.
No, he stopped being a person
when he took our daughters.
I need your help.
This is your last chance.
I know you're scared,
and I know you wanna go home.
Alright, I don't… I don't
wanna hurt you, I don't.
I'm gonna take the tape off, then
I want you to tell me where they are.
Hey, come on.
Did you see my glasses?
— What?
— I can't see.
If you aren't gonna talk, Alex,
I'm gonna have to hurt you.
Tell me where they are?
Where are they?
Tell me where they are!
Yeah, I'm out here at the house
on Fairmont Circle,
the house the RV
was parked in front of.
It's only been on the market
a couple of months.
I'm gonna track the owners down
and see if they know anything.
You got any new info on that corpse
we found at the priest's basement?
No DNA, dental or fingerprint matches.
Nothing?
The priest is sticking
to the story too.
Alright.
Same person who took him
took those girls. I'm sure of it.
I'm wearing out the tape I guess.
I watch it everyday after breakfast,
it's the only video I have of him.
It was before your time,
twenty-six years
ago, August 19th.
I took a nap in the afternoon, and
when I woke up, Barry was gone.
No one could ever tell me
what happened to him.
He was playing in the front yard, just
a few feet from where
they say that RV was parked.
What do you think that means?
I'm more interested in
what you think that means.
I don't think we'll ever know.
It's just like Barry.
No one took them.
Nothing happened.
They're just gone.
How are you doin', Father?
I've… been better.
So Detective Chemelinksi tells me that
you have some specifics about the crime
you claim that guy committed.
The abductor.
He was… waging a war against God.
Great. That's great.
I thought you said he had
something specific? I… I…
Tell him how he took the kids.
He said…
he took them in daylight.
Sometimes more than
one child at a time.
— He said that?
— Yes.
Did he say if he was with anybody?
He did it alone?
He… he said he had a family.
— That's it?
— Yes.
Alright.
Informative.
You said they cried when you left them.
Look at me, you said they cried
when you left them!
You said they cried when you left them!
Tell me! Where is she?
Tell me where they are!
Just tell me. Just tell me and I'll stop.
I'll stop as soon as you tell me.
Just… Just tell me where they are.
Why won't you tell me?
Uh?
Why won't you just fucking tell us?
He knows.
I can see in his eyes.
He fucking knows.
I know you know, why
aren't you fucking telling me?
Why?
Come on. Get him up.
Up. Get up.
Get up!
You're gonna make me use this?
You're gonna tell us, if you don't I'm gonna use this.
You're doing this to yourself.
Just tell us.
Tell me…
Tell me!
Tell me! Tell me! Tell me!
Where is my daughter?
Where's — my — daughter?
Four days have passed since Anna Dover and
Joy Birch were last seen by their families…
Where have you been?
I was searching for her in the woods.
Franklin, what is it?
Huh! Hey, what the fuck!
And this is who the police are saying
is a person of interest,
in the investigation of
the two missing girls.
Now this unidentified man who was
last seen at last night's candlelight vigil,
fled on foot when the investigating
detective attempted to question him.
The police caution the public
not to approach this man
but to call the police immediately
if they do see him.
Look, Keller.
Let me just think about it, why would
the police be looking for this man,
if they didn't think
he did it in the first place?
They did it together,
they know each other.
I fucking told you. Right?
He just looked me in the eyes,
he said they only cried when I left them.
Somebody who knows where the guy is.
Alex Jones' dog.
Got it on Southern street.
Apparently Alex Jones
took the dog for a walk,
the night before last,
he never came home.
and his aunt didn't want
to tell us about the dog
when we called about it
this morning, she said
that she thought we'd get him
into trouble or some shit.
I thought you said we would
keep him under surveillance.
And I thought you said
the guy was innocent.
And I thought the guy
from last night you said was our guy.
Look, I don't have money in the budget
for watching innocent people.
You said to me that you'd
put him under surveillance.
— What d'you want me to say?
— Did you keep your word?
You could have just given me a call,
cause I would have been there all night,
I would have stayed up all night,
I would know where he was now.
I need to know where everybody is.
Alright, point made.
Alright? Point made.
You'll be clear with me,
and I'll be clear with you.
I need to know where everybody is.
You can something different,
please tell me.
Tell me about the RV.
What were you doing in the RV?
It's where I go…
to be alone.
What music do you listen to
in the RV when you're alone?
Radio… Tape…
The RV was parked over
on Fairmont for a reason?
No. Just I am coming. I am— I— I—
— Have you seen these girls?
— No.
Just take a look at them.
Have you seen these girls?
No.
Did you participate in any way
in the abduction of these girls?
No.
Loki, you got a call.
I called as soon as I saw the sketch on TV.
He comes in here every week almost
to buy some kids clothes, but
he's always buying stuff
in different sizes,
I caught him messing around
with the mannequins once.
— What'd he pay with?
— Cash.
Uh, you give me a call
if you hear anything.
Okay.
It's been five days.
Five days since he had a drink of water.
And this could be
your last night that matters.
Look, I call you after
Nancy goes to sleep, alright?
I promise.
Where have you been all this time?
What the hell were you thinking?
Did you tell anyone?
Did you?
I want to see him.
Please help me.
Can you help me find my little girl.
I got a picture.
Here.
This is my baby.
Her name is Joy.
This is… it's a teddy we got her
when she was two
because she was afraid
to sleep by herself,
please tell me where my little girl is,
please tell me where my girl…
Oh, I know you're gonna tell me.
I know you're gonna tell me.
Help me.
Please, help me.
Nancy!
What the fuck are you doing?
Let it down!
Let it go.
Let it go!
You untied him? Huh?
That was close.
What is it, what happened?
Get Franklin.
I need to show you something.
Did he say anything new?
He will soon, you'll see.
No light gets in.
Barely enough room to sit down inside.
The shower still works,
but we control it from that here.
And with the water heater, so
it either comes out scalding or freezing.
And uh… we talk to him through this.
It's to remind us
if we start feeling sorry for him.
My God.
We can't hurt him anymore
without killing him, so
this is the only way.
Have you lost your mind, Keller?
Do you have a better idea, Franklin?
Untie him.
Go ahead, let him out of here,
I'm not gonna stop you.
If that's what you really want,
you go ahead.
You think soon is long
enough for the girls,
the way you're looking out for him?
I hope.
It's been five days now,
and we're really running out of time.
You don't even know it's him.
— I do.
— No, you don't.
— I know you, you don't.
Look,I want my baby back…
as much as you
and despite what you think about me,
I would die for my daughter.
But this ain't right.
This has to stop.
Alright, you'd better get to work.
Let's start with that wall there.
Stop.
Think of July.
I need to get out of this place, Ralph.
Everything in this house just
makes me want to throw up.
Your Dad's building.
No, there is no way I'm standing
in that crack house.
It's not gonna help Keller,
but we won't stop him.
Let him do what he needs to.
We don't know about it anymore.
Lisa…
Elisa.
Elisa, open the door.
Elisa!
Honey?
Right, I'll break it, I'll—
Yeah, fuck you both.
Yeah, somebody explain me
on leaving me here alone
when you could try at least
tell me where you're going.
Mom?
— Anna.
Anna was here.
— Mom, hey Mom!
Mom, come on, sit down. Calm down.
I will close the window.
I am sure I was here.
And then I heard…
a sound from my room, and I…
I came in, and the window was open.
And…
and it wasn't open before.
And then… and then Ralph, he…
he came in.
And he looked, and uh…
And then…
Then, I don't know.
Won't you gonna write this down?
The basement, I didn't check the basement,
we need to check the basement.
Right, I'll show you.
I'll show you.
Kids know they're not
allowed to come here.
They're not supposed to come down here,
but then, you never know.
My husband likes to be
prepared for emergency.
Where is your husband, Mrs. Dover?
I was gonna ask you,
he's been out searching
with the police for Anna.
But you shouldn't be here right now.
Does he always stay out this late?
Yes he stays out this late.
When he is looking for my daughter,
and my daughter would be gone, yes!
Shit.
Hey. Pull around.
Pull around.
Come on, Mr. Dover.
Why are you following me?
Get in the car.
Where were you going just now?
I parked at a liquor store,
I have a bottle of liquor.
You're the shit hot detective,
work it out.
Actually, before that…
You were walking
in the opposite direction.
Across the parking lot.
Towards Campello street.
It's been long. I hadn't been drinking
in nine and a half years.
I fear if I walked
in the parking lot for a while,
by the time they open,
I'd still want in that bad.
and then, uh, then I saw you.
So it helped me make up my mind.
There's a bag of lye in your basement.
It's half-empty.
Your wife thinks you've been
helping us with…
but we both know that's not true.
I used the lye to bury our dog last year.
And "helping a cop" sounds better than
"I've been driving aimlessly in my truck
cause I don't know
what the fuck else to do."
Is that what you were doing
last Saturday night?
Probably. Am I a suspect?
No, I'm only asking.
I'm only asking cause you
assaulted the man who's gone missing.
I heard that. Then what happened?
I thought you had him under surveillance.
I'm— I'm gonna assume you're asking
because you have no idea.
Yeah, I didn't think it was something
I could get away with.
It's not.
Yeah, how convenient. They skip town,
cause this asshole is guilty.
Oh, it could be that, right?
'Cause then it wouldn't
be your fault, right?
Mr. Dover.
— What?
You take care of yourself and your wife.
That's the best thing
you can do right now.
That little girl is gonna need you
when she comes home.
Kids gone for more than a week…
have half as good a chance of being found,
and after a month, almost none
are found alive, alright?
So, forgive me for doing
everything I can to f…
You know what?
It hasn't been a fucking week.
— You're right.
— It hasn't been a week.
Day fucking six! Day six.
And every day, she's wondering
why I'm not there to fucking rescue her!
Do you understand that? Me, not you!
Not you! But ME! EVERY DAY!
So forgive me for not going home
to have a good night's rest!
And why didn't you look
for my fucking daughter?
Mother fucking—
— Hey, hey, hey, hey…
— Don't follow me.
Mr. Dover, Mr. Dover…
Now you think I'm gonna let
you get behind the wheel
after you've been
drinking, do you?
I'm gonna walk.
You look for my daughter.
Daddy.
Daddy, help me.
Who was it?
[ ]
Wait. What'd you say.
What? What?
[ ]
Listen. You don't understand.
Just— just help you.
— Help me.
No no no. No more riddles.
Just fucking tell me.
I'll let you go home tonight…
if you tell me where they are.
I just want… to play…
Don't let me do this again.
Don't let me do it.
Why are you making me do this?
Oh God…
[prays]
And I hope you'll forgive me for my sins.
Damn it.
No— no noise, you shut up.
You make any noise,
and I turn on that tap.
High, rising shine.
I ain't gonna find girls here, am I?
Fuck you.
— What about Alex Jones?
— What about him?
I came to drink here, I didn't wanna
drink in front of my wife.
Look, my father left me
this building, alright?
You're not giving me a tour?
Why didn't you tell me about this place?
— I didn't think it mattered.
— Everything matters.
It's all pretty much like this.
I will renovate soon.
Yeah.
Not as organized as your basement, uh?
What's up with all this
survival gear in there?
Pray for the best,
prepare for the worst.
Yes, we agree there, yeah?
Come on, hurry up.
Ah shit!
Hello?
The guy that you were
looking for was just here.
He saw me watching and then ran.
Did you get a plate?
Yeah…
Yeah.
Go home, Mr. Dover.
'Morning.
Why did you run away
from me the other night, then?
I've never seen you before.
You sure you're at the right house?
You're doing some shopping
in the ValueMore lately?
Yeah. Hm-hmm…
Why? Is it a crime to shop there?
I can't afford to buy suits
from Brooks brothers.
Uh yeah, no…
Ah right, you buy children's cloth.
Did I? Must have been in a hurry.
Do you have— do you have children?
I don't… have…
You move, I put a bullet
into your fucking head.
This is 13-40, I need additional units
for search. 4-2-7 Keller street.
Possible kidnapping victims
on the premises.
Anna. Fucking…
Anna? Joy?
Fuck.
Aah. Fuck.
So we've taken photographs
of the clothes found…
Mr. Dover, is your wife here?
She's not coming.
So if you can make it,
I made these photographs,
I'm gonna need her to come
in and take a look at them.
Have a seat.
So he confessed and he said he killed them.
We're hoping he was lying, but…
we haven't found any bodies,
Mr. Dover, but…
The butcher's partly identified
two pieces of cloth.
So I'm gonna need to— you tell me
if you recognize anything.
No.
Not sure. I don't know.
That's her sock.
You wasted time.
You wasted time following me.
You let this happen.
Don't talk to them.
Elisa told me they're dead.
— Is it true?
— No.
No, she said they found
their body cloth.
Don't tell your mother that,
don't you dare
tell your mother that,
d'you understand me?
Now I need you to listen to me.
I need you to stay with her
in the house a couple of days,
and you make sure
she does not watch the news,
and when the people come,
you just go the fuck away.
Listen!
Do not give up on your sister, do not!
I will find her, and I'll bring her home,
I'm not giving up.
You're gonna bring her home?
She's dead, you can't do anything.
You've been leaving me and mum here,
while you— you were going out
to get fucking drunk,
look, I— I can smell it on you!
— Shut up!
How long has this Bob Taylor
been working on this map?
Three and a half hours.
And you think this gonna leave you to the
bodies? Cause that sure as shit don't.
Yeah, give me a favor, cap,
and go fuck yourself.
We weren't getting anywhere
questioning him.
— It looks more like a maze than a map.
— He's got a thing for mazes.
I'm going home.
Call me if something happens.
Give me that card, Joe. The key card.
Alright, it's done now.
Tell me what you're drawing.
You said you were drawing a map,
it looks like a fucking puzzle,
tell me what you're drawing.
— Tell me what you're drawing.
— I can't…
Yes you can. Yes you can.
Shit!
Yes, you can!
Yes you can!
Yes you can! Yes you can!
Oh, shit!
Gun! Gun!
Come on, don't!
Put ​​the gun down!
Put the gun down!
No, no, no!
Fuck…
You gonna call a fuckin' RE!
[Pray]
He explained this before
he hit the bullet?
I'm sorry.
Fuck yourself.
Save it for the girls parents.
I don't know what to do, Alex.
I don't know what to do anymore.
And what comes pretty fucked-up about all
this is I know you know where they are.
I think we're done.
In the maze…
That's where they put them.
What? What did you say?
It's the maze.
What— what maze, where is it?
Where is the maze? Where do I find it?
Alex?
Alex, Alex, listen to me.
I'm gonna get you outta here,
okay, tell me just where the maze is.
That's it, just tell me, mate.
Where is the maze?
Come on, tell me.
Just tell me where the maze is, okay?
Come on, don't fuck with me.
Don't fuck with me now,
tell me goddammit!
Tell me where they are.
Tell me, tell me! Tell me!
Something's gonna get to you man.
Something's gonna get to you!
Can I help you?
Good morning, Ma'm, uh…
I'm Keller Dover,
my little girl was…
abducted with her friend.
What do you want?
I guess I haven't though this
too well, uhm I…
I've been thinking a lot about
what happened to your nephew,
and I know I scared him
the other day at the police station, and…
What I'm trying to say is I kind of
feel responsible for him running away.
— You wanna come on in?
— Yeah…
My husband and I were…
very devoted one time.
We spent our summers driving around
with that camper with our son.
Handing out pamphlets…
Spreading out God word.
After our son died of cancer…
we started seeing things differently.
Adopting Alex helped.
Howie never got up here.
I'm sorry.
You look very tired.
Yeah, I don't sleep much.
I, uh…
I keep dreaming
I've being lost in a maze.
I'm sorry.
Alex never talks very much, so
people come over here,
I hardly know what to say.
— He doesn't talk much?
Oh he talks, you know,
'good morning' and that sort of things.
Hard to get too much more than that.
He had an accident when he was little.
And after that he started
choosing his words about too carefully.
What, uh— what kind of accident?
My husband kept snakes.
No, it wasn't that bad,
what happened, but…
now with that fear of them…
That's not my favorite memory.
Yeah, I'm sorry,
it's none of my business.
Can I get you a cup of tea, Mr. Dover?
Oh I'm so sorry, I— I thought
you had known about that already.
I say it's better this way,
you know, that awful man,
he would have spent years on death row,
just watching TV and getting fat.
You still have to worry
about losing your PSP.
When forensics have finished
with the guy's place,
we're gonna deploy cadaver dogs.
Look kid, we can't always save the day.
Alright? We're just cops. Janitors.
So we lost this one. alright?
Look, you want a family,
you need to find a girl,
you know, start a family,
have some kids, let it go.
— Yeah?
— Hey, it's Rich.
We found something.
Guys, let's have a look.
Two kid size department store mannequins,
with their heads kicked in.
I was talking to our lab guys,
and they told me that all the blood
that we sampled from the plastic
containers… pig's blood.
Alright you guys, let's get this
covered up, it's supposed to snow soon.
Hurry up, okay?
It's like he's play acting.
I mean, except for the few items
ID'd by the Dovers and the purchases,
all the kids cloth that we found
still had the tags on.
And that maze book that we found,
made.
Photocopies, pictures from this book
that we found in the attic.
Ex-FBI agent wrote that.
— Finding The Invisible Man.
It's about a theoretical
suspect that people believe
is responsible for a bunch
of child abductions.
This totally discredited, I guess but
I read some bits, kind of—
Taylor— Taylor was abducted when he was
a kid, he ran away after three weeks.
And the capturer drugged him on
some sort of LSD ketamine cocktail,
and he never remembered,
we never caught the guy.
And so… he read the book, and decided
he was taken by the Invisible Man.
Now he's doing his best imitation.
Right?
Yeah, he was doing his best imitation,
he killed himself last night.
Man, how did he do that,
I though he was in custody?
Taylor drew this, a map to the bodies.
It's a map to the bodies,
and we found the same
design on a pendant
that we pulled off that
corpse the other day.
— There's a connection. Okay?
— Yeah. Then?
The connection is his
last maze in the book.
I did it, it's unsolved,
but there is no way out.
Your corpse is— is another
wannabe who read the book.
What're you saying to me, Rich?
What're you saying me?
What're you saying,
that this guy's a fake?
You're saying that the girls,
these girls are out there somewhere.
How did Bob Taylor get those clothes?
How did— how did the parents
positively ID those clothes?
That, I can't reconcile.
You can't reconcile?
Just keep knocking on doors,
looking out windows…
Hey. Why is that there?
Tag that—
IN THE HOUSE
WINDOW — OPEN?
Yes.
Uhm… Yeah, this is she.
What?
Oh my God.
Uh, we… Is she… ?
Ralph, Keller!
Keller, we need to go to the hospital,
they found Joy but not Anna,
they find Anna, maybe she'll know
where Anna is, we have to go!
Keller!
Elisa's not picking up.
— Did you text her?
— Yeah.
— Oh, nobody gets behind this point.
— Please, don't touch me!
— Miss! Wait a minute!
— It's okay.
— Nancy.
— Grace.
You'll find Anna,
I know they will.
— I know.
— How is she?
— Is she awake?
Joy, were you far from the street?
How far from the street were you, Joy?
Joy.
— You can't be doing this now.
How long did it take you to get there?
— She's been through a lot.
— Just let me ask a question, please.
Keller!
The detective will be back in
just a minute, you need to wait.
She's been drugged.
Joy… Sweet heart…
Just let us know she's alive, okay?
You need just nod your head,
baby, just nod your head.
Baby… can you give us a nod,
can you nod your head for us, please?
Joy.
FINISH ALL THE MAZES
AND YOU'LL GO HOME
You were there.
What? I wa—
I was where?
They put a tape on her mouth.
It's okay, it's okay honey…
It's okay, it's okay.
Mom and Dad are here, you're okay?
You're alright.
— Excuse me.
You're alright, now.
Yeah, I said nobody is allowed
in that room but her family.
— Hey! Where're you going?
— Keller?
— Hey! Where is he going?
— I don't know.
Call downstairs, don't let him go.
Get him off that car!
Stop him, hey!
Fucker.
I know where you're going.
Hello again.
Hey, I was hoping you'd, uh…
I need to do some penance.
For what?
For scaring you the other day
at the— at the station.
You already apologized for that.
I know, I was thinking
that maybe you, uh…
you could use some, uh… help around—
you know, I know your door
here needs some fixing,
so I brought my tools, and uh…
Ooh… I see.
I burned myself.
Feel a little wacky today.
But I'm glad you wanna talk some more.
No need to make excuses though.
Come on in and make me a cup of tea.
Come on in.
I don't wanna have to hurt you.
I know they were here.
Put ​​your hands on your head
and turn around.
Do it.
I'm just gonna go.
Don't touch that bag.
Put your hands on your head.
Come over here on this counter.
Come on.
Top drawer.
Open it.
Put ​​them on.
You don't know me, Mr. Dover.
But believe me when I tell you
I will not let you go.
You don't have to drink all of it.
About a third should do
for a man of your size.
Something to make you more manageable.
Forget it.
Drink it, Mr. Dover. Or I'll kill you
right here in my kitchen,
bring your daughter in here,
and have her scrub your brains
off that floor.
— Where is she?
Drink.
Just let me see her.
— You wanna see her?
— Yes.
That's your ticket to
your daughter right there.
A little more, Mr. Dover.
A little more.
Good.
This is my dear husband's recipe.
Now we're going out back.
Let me see her.
Take it out of your pocket.
Put it in the sink.
Put it in the disposal.
Put ​​your car keys on the table.
Put ​​the car keys on the table.
Over the TransAm, over here.
The car over there, come on, move it.
The look on your face.
My husband used to have
the very same look.
When we took Alex,
he was the first kid we ever took.
His name was a Jimmy… Ber— Barry.
I can't remember that, he can't either.
So many names.
Forgot all about Bobby Taylor,
until I read about him in the paper.
Get in the driver's seat.
Open the door and get in the car.
Making children disappear is
the war we wage against God.
Makes people lose their faith…
turns them into demons like you.
I had to slow down
since my husband disappeared,
but I do what I can.
Start the car.
Keep trying.
Back up. Slowly.
Come on. Back up.
Come on…
Stop. Turn it off.
Turn it off!
Get out.
I think you should know.
Alex never laid a hand on those girls.
Just wanted to take him
for a ride in the camper.
I was the one who decided
they should stay.
Take a look.
Maybe your daughter is under there.
You never know.
I had the girls down there
when the police came poking around.
I should have left them down there.
I'm so lonely without Alex.
Get in there.
— What?
— Get in.
If you want me to get in there,
you're gonna have to shoot me.
I'm not gonna get in
just 'cause you ask.
Oh! God!
Go on. Get in there.
That's good.
Make yourself a tourniquet.
This might last 24 hours.
I'd love you to still be alive when
I dump your daughter's body down there.
Wait, no, wait wait wait!
Wait!
I need you to go to Holly Jones,
she needs to be notified.
No, I'm gonna find Dover.
No, you're done
with Dover, okay?
— Please.
— Ok, you want me to go to Holly Jones?
I want you to go Holly Jones
as a notifier, please.
Oh God.
Almighty God… Protect my girl…
Mrs. Jones?
Mrs. Jones.
Show me your hands right now.
Don't move and show me
your fucking hands, right now.
Stop, right now!
Show me your fucking hands,
do not move and show me your hands.
Make sure they cremate me, I'm sure
I don't want to be buried in some box.
Both hands, right now!
Right now!
Oh, my God.
Oh God!
Oh shit!
Come on. Come on, uh.
Aah, go!
Stay with me Anna.
You're gonna stay with me, uh?
I need you to— stay with me, Anna!
Stay with me, Anna, it's alright.
It's alright, come on!
Come on, move, move,
move, move!
Don't die. Don't die.
It's okay.
Hey. It's okay.
Hey. Hey!
Hey! Help!
Help!
Help! Help!
Uh, Detective Loki?
I hope we're not intruding.
She's doing real good.
She's gonna be… up and around
in a few days, and she…
She just wanted to come and say
thank you and hi to her hero.
Hello.
Uh… Do you mind giving me a minute?
— Yeah.
— Thank you. Say goodbye Joy.
Say goodbye, Anna.
She found her whistle, yeah?
No. She keeps insisting
that Joy helped her
find it on Thanksgiving
before they were taken.
I think she's just confused though.
I got her a new one.
He hasn't contacted me.
I know you d… I know you probably
don't believe it, but he hasn't.
I b— I believe you.
Do you think you're gonna find him?
Yeah.
And he'll go to jail?
Probably.
Thanks for everything.
Oh, God…
I miss him.
He d-… He did what he had to do
to find Anna, and I thank God for that.
He is a good man.
That's it, let's pack it up.
You're done for tonight?
Yeah, the ground's frozen, so
it's just gonna take a week
to excavate the entire property.
We just found some dead snakes and shit.
Pray for the best,
prepare for the worst, yeah?
G'night.
Captioning: jcdr
V1 — 17.10.2013