Juice by Tappy.
That's got juice.
Oh, Tappy.
Juice by you.
Juice by you. Thank you.
We got a winner.
She's a flight attendant
from Washington, D.C.
Will you please welcome
Mary Kellington.
Juice by Mary!
- Harold, please, not again the TV.
- Come on, ma.
Why make such a big deal of this?
You'll get the set back
in a couple of hours.
Why you gotta make me
feel so guilty, ma?
What are you trying to do?
Get me to break my mother's set?
Or the radiator?
Maybe blow up the house, ma?
Is that it?
Your own flesh and blood, ma?
Is that what you trying to do?
Why do you always play
games with my head?
I wouldn't do that.
The chain isn't for you.
It's for the robbers.
Why won't you come out?
See what I mean? See how
you always gotta upset me?
Ma?
C'mon out, please.
Screw it!
This isn't happening.
And if it were, it
would be alright.
Don't worry Seymour.
It'll all work out.
You'll see.
In the end it's all nice.
Shit, that mother fucker's
looking a little seedy, Jim.
You particular all of a sudden?
Mother fucker could grow a beard,
as long as we get our braid.
Give me a hand, Tyrone.
Hello.
Hi.
Fuck, the table too.
What, you want me to
schlep it on my back?
You got a friend.
I ain't no lepers schlepper.
Such a son. A goniff.
Your mother needs you like
a moose needs a hat rack.
Sheeit, that's some
boss scag baby.
I mean dynamite.
Oh, man, something else.
Know what we need?
Get us a piece of this Brody shit
cut it up, and off it.
We could double our money.
We could buy a couple of pieces
and get some whole
other shit going on.
That would be righteous.
In no time at all, we'd
get a pound of pure...
straight from Sal the Geep.
That's what I'm talking
about, baby, no hassles.
How's it going?
What's up?
The usual?
Yeah, sounds good.
Anything else?
No. Nothing.
I'm alright.
Good afternoon, Mrs. Goldfarb.
Good afternoon, Mr. Rabinowitz.
Although I'm not sure how good.
And you?
What can I say?
You want your TV?
Yes, if you don't mind.
Can I ask you a question?
You won't take it personal?
How many years we know each other?
Who's to count?
Why don't you tell the police?
They talk to Harry, he won't
be stealing no more the TV.
I couldn't do that.
Harold's my child.
He's all I have.
Thank you, Mr. Rabinowitz.
Join us in creating excellence.
More passion for living than
you've ever imagines.
Be excited.
Hello? Who is it?
Now what?
Hello?
Mrs. Sara Goldfarb?
Me. Speaking.
This is Lyle Russel
from Maylin and Block.
I'm not interested.
I'm not selling anything.
I just want to offer you a
chance to be on television.
Maylin and Block...
Television?
That's right, Mrs. Goldfarb.
Television. Congratulations.
I don't have any...
I'm not looking for money.
I'm calling to tell you
you've already won.
We discover contestants...
America's favorite TV shows.
You've been chosen from
a long list of contestants.
Meaning you've already won.
Yes, Mrs. Goldfarb.
I never thought I'd
be on television.
That's right.
You, on television.
We'll send you all the
necessary information.
Goodbye, congratulations
and take care.
I don't get it. Why are you
so hard on your folks?
They give you everything.
They hook you up with
an apartment.
With a croaker shrink.
Which is great. It's just...
money is never what I
really wanted from them.
That's pretty much all I get.
Why don't you get away from them?
How am I going to do that?
What about your clothes?
Your sketches are great.
Open up a store.
I can't.
Why not?
When will I have time
to hang with you?
Where's the party?
You're going to jump
out the window.
I got a great diet book.
Thought I'd catch
a little sun today.
Really? In a box you'll catch it.
Relax and think how gorgeous
you'll be with new red hair.
Today the hair, tomorrow the sun.
Anybody want to waste some time?
Angel says we should do it now.
I'll call Brody tomorrow.
Who's Brody?
My connection. He's
got unbelievable shit.
Shit, righteous.
We got this idea.
What is it?
We cut this stuff up
and double our money.
Get a pound of pure and retire.
Know what that means?
We get off hard knocks
and be on easy street.
What's the catch?
That's red. I mean that's a red.
It's not a red red,
but that's a red.
Red?
Yeah.
You're telling me that's a red?
I'm telling. It's red.
Then what's orange?
I want to know what's orange.
Well, it could be...
it's a little orange too.
You know something?
I always thought you're the most
beautiful girl I've ever seen.
Really?
Ever since I first saw you.
That's nice, Harry.
That makes me feel good.
Others told me that before...
and it was meaningless.
Why? Thought they were
pulling your leg?
No, nothing like that.
I don't know or even
care if they were.
From them it was...
meaningless.
When you say it, I hear it.
I really hear it.
Someone like you could make
things alright for me.
You think?
What is it?
Remember I told you
about the store?
Yeah.
I've been thinking.
I put together some numbers...
and it's not impossible.
You could and should do it.
We could do it together.
What do you think?
Stop already.
I felt better in a red
dress than a cheese Danish.
Three things is all I
did to change my life.
Three things.
No red meat.
Why do they stick in red meat?
I ate red meat to the
point where I'd...
eat it raw.
I loved my meat.
You need to be passionate.
No red meat.
No red meat for 30 days.
Three things is all I
did to change my life.
Ada told us. It's gorgeous.
We'll make it a little
darker tomorrow.
Why darker?
To go with my red dress.
Now it's looking like Madonna.
This is not Madonna.
Neither is this, but
I'm going on a diet.
What diet are you on?
Eggs and grapefruit.
I was on that once. Lots of luck.
It's not so bad.
How long you been on it?
All day.
All day? It's one o'clock.
I'm thinking thin.
She's thinking thin.
My Louise lost 50 lbs.
Just like that.
Like that?
Like what?
Did you put her in a sweat box?
She went to a doctor. With
pills, you don't want to eat.
What's so good about that?
I'm sitting here...
not thinking about chopped
liver and pastrami on rye?
You shouldn't talk like that
when someone's on a diet.
Oh, big deal.
I'll sneak more grapefruit.
I'm thinking thin.
The mailman.
You have something
for Sara Goldfarb?
I'm expecting something.
Goldfarb... Goldfarb...
Sara Goldfarb.
This is it? That's it.
Wait, I got to get my stuff.
Okay, spell out your name.
S-a-r-a G-o-l-d-
f-a-r-b.
Dynamite? Dynamite.
Alright, we're on our way.
Says he got some real fine shit.
Alright, man.
Here we go.
Let's do this right.
Come on, naturally.
Come on, hurry.
I wonder when you'll hear?
They'll send you to
Tavern on the Green...
where they send all the stars.
I'll have eggs and grapefruit
at Tavern on the Green.
I hope they have some.
Hurry up.
Here we are.
Listen.
There it is.
There it is, baby.
Shit.
Shall we try?
Wait, Ty.
This is our chance
to make it big.
We play it right,
we can get a pound of pure...
but if we get wasted,
we'll fuck it up.
I ain't trying to jive you, jim.
I don't want to run the
streets my whole life with...
my nose runnin' down to my chin.
But we should take a taste
so we know how much to cut.
It's business.
Fair enough.
Sheet...
Thank you.
30 days is all it takes.
Number two:
No refined sugar!
Now sugar's everywhere.
Even in bottled water.
I was sick with sugar.
It nurtured my spiraling brain
that I felt I was a loser.
Juice by you.
Rule 2 is no refined sugar.
Don't even think about
sodas anymore.
Sucking candies, very good, sir.
Just stay away from that stuff.
No refined sugar.
For 30 days I'll eat right.
I'll pick up my spirits.
I am going to try.
I found hope. And in that
hope, I found a way.
Stop!
Hello?
Rosie?
Yeah?
Sara.
I need the number of that doctor.
I don't understand why
you got to see him.
Cut the son of a bitch loose
for Christ's sake.
I don't want him telling my
parents I've stopped therapy.
They're already pissed
off at me.
I'm not going to sleep with him.
I'm coming home after the concert.
You're jealous!
Harry, jealous?
You're stubborn, put
your arms around me.
Stop that!
I'll suck your eyeballs out.
I'm disappointed...
that you're indisposed.
Is Anita out of town?
Why do you ask?
I was wondering if
she's "indisposed".
No, she's fine, thank you.
She's in Florida.
Can I ask you something personal?
Of course.
Anything.
You have something over here.
There?
A little bit lower.
Don't worry. It's much better.
Arnold.
How are you, Mrs. Goldfarb?
How am I? Enormous.
That's why I'm here.
I've seen much worse.
Thank you.
How's your hearing and vision?
I have both.
The doctor will be
with you shortly.
You're a little overweight.
A little?
I have 50 lbs. I'm
willing to donate.
We can take care of
that, no problem.
We're on the way, baby.
It was great out there.
Everybody's thirsty.
Come to me.
Purple in the morning.
Blue in the afternoon.
Orange in the evening.
That's my three meals.
And green at night.
Just like that. 1, 2, 3, 4.
Come back to bed, honey.
Come on, got plenty
of time for that.
I'm grooving with these
new mirrors I got.
I told you, ma,
one day I'd make it.
You don't have to make anything.
You just have to love your momma.
What are you doing, baby?
Nothing.
I was thinking about you...
and about the nasty things
I'm about to do to ya.
I'm going to get on you.
You'll scare me to death.
I won't scare you. I don't
want to scare nobody.
All I want is a little
peace and happiness.
You're the finest fox I
ever laid my eyes on.
That's what I'll do.
For my mother.
I've been thinking about
getting something for her.
Like a present, or something.
But I didn't know what
I was going to get.
And?
I finally asked myself,
what's her fix?
Television, right?
If ever there's a TV
junkie, it's the old lady.
I owe her a new set anyway
after...
being schlepped around
to old Abe's.
You really love her.
I guess so.
I just want her to be happy.
Let's go get it.
Let's push-off first.
We shouldn't get going
till tonight.
Number three...
Three!
This drives most people crazy.
This... is... easy... so... far...
Give yourself 30 days...
I guarantee... it will...
change... your... life...
I mean that is thin.
She doesn't look
like the same person.
I can almost zip the dress.
I've almost got the zipper up.
Sara, the mailman.
When I see it,
I'll wave it all over.
- You sure?
- Yeah, I'm sure.
What did he say?
Don't worry, it'll come.
He said it'll come.
I once waited 2 months
for a package.
Two months?
It's Harry!
Look who's here.
Harry!
Easy, you'll crush me,
for Christ's sake.
Come inside.
Hi, Harry.
How are you, Harry?
You look so good.
You want something to eat?
No, ma.
A little nosh or a piece of cake?
I could go out and get some.
I don't have anything in the
house, but Ada will have.
You want something to eat?
No, ma, nothing.
Sit down. You make me dizzy,
for Christ's sake.
Notice anything about me?
Notice I'm slimmer?
Yeah, I guess you are, mom.
25 lbs. I lost.
Can you believe it?
And that's only the beginning.
I'm really happy for you.
But will you sit?
Sorry I haven't been
around in a while.
I've been real busy.
You got a good job?
You're doing well?
Yeah, real good.
What kind of business?
I'm sort of a distributor.
For a big importer.
I'm so happy for you.
Mom, you're killing me.
Have you been lifting weights?
I knew you could do it.
You were right.
Maybe you'll meet a nice
girl and have a baby.
I already met one.
Don't go ape shit, alright?
Who is she?
Who's her parents?
You know her.
Marion Silver. Remember?
Oh, Silver, of course.
Manhattan Beach.
He's got a house on the
esplanade. Garment business.
He's real big in women's undies.
And before you go bouncin'
all over again...
I want to tell you
I got you a present.
I don't want a present,
just have a baby.
Will you let me tell
you what I got ya?
You're something else today.
Look, I know...
well...
I'm sorry for being such a bastard.
I want to make it up.
I know I can't change
anything that's happened.
But I want you to know I
love you and I'm sorry.
And I want you to be happy.
So I got you a brand new TV set.
It'll be delivered in a few days.
It's from Macy's.
Your father would be so happy
to see what you're doing for me.
You see that, Seymour?
See how good your son is?
He knows what it's like for
his mother living all alone.
No one to visit her...
Hey, ma.
You on uppers?
What?
You on diet pills?
I'm going to a specialist.
You're makin' a croaker for speed.
I'm just going to a doctor.
Does he give ya pills?
Of course. He's a doctor.
What kind of pills?
A purple, blue, orange one...
What's in them?
I'm Sara Goldfarb,
not Albert Einstein.
How should I know?
The make you feel good...
and give you pep?
Well, a little.
A little? I can hear you
grinding your teeth from here.
That goes away at night.
At night?
With the green one.
In 30 minutes I'm asleep.
You gotta cut that stuff loose.
It's no good.
What? 25 lbs. I've lost.
Do you want to be a dope fiend?
Am I foaming at the mouth,
or something?
He's a nice doctor.
That croaker's no good.
How come you know so much?
How come you know more
than a doctor?
Believe me, ma, I know.
You'll get strung out.
Come on, I almost
fit in my red dress.
The one I wore to your
high school graduation...
your father liked so much.
I remember how he looked
at me in the red dress.
What's the big deal?
I'm going to wear...
You don't know?
I'm going to be on TV.
I got a call and application...
Whose pullin' ya leg?
I'm going to be a
TV contestant.
I don't know when yet.
You'll be so proud
when you see your mother...
in her red dress
and golden shoes...
What's the big deal?
Those pills will kill
you before you get on.
You drove up in a cab.
Did you see who had the best seat?
I'm somebody now.
Everybody likes me.
Millions of people will
see me and like me.
I'll tell them about
you and your father.
How good he was to us.
Remember?
It's a reason to
get up in the morning.
A reason to lose weight,
to fit in the red dress.
A reason to smile.
It makes tomorrow alright.
What have I got, Harry?
Why should I make the
bed or wash the dishes?
I do but, why should I?
I'm alone.
Your father's gone.
You're gone.
I got no one to care for.
What have I got, Harry?
I'm lonely.
I'm old.
You got friends, ma.
It's not the same.
They don't need me.
I like the way I feel.
I like thinking about
the red dress...
and television... and
you and your father.
When I get the sun, I smile.
I'll come visit, ma.
Now I'm straight, my business
is going good, I'll come.
Me and Marion.
We'll come for dinner.
You bring her. I'll make
you mushroom soup and a roast.
That sounds great, ma.
I'll call ahead of time.
Okay. I'm glad.
I'm glad you have a nice
girl and your own business.
I got to go. I have
an appointment in a bit.
But I'll be back.
You still got your key?
Yeah, I got it, ma.
Goodbye, son.
Brody say you coming up quick.
Thanks, man.
He says you're smart.
You're loyal, and not a junkie.
Brody wants to promote you.
To give you more responsibility.
You interested?
Yeah, yeah.
Brody says you fuck him,
I'll kill you.
I got that.
Remember that.
Shit, you got a white driver.
I love you, Harry.
You make me feel like a person.
Like I'm me and beautiful.
You are beautiful.
The most beautiful
girl in the world.
You're my dream.
No, Mrs. Goldfarb, I'm sure.
I've checked again.
Maybe you got me a weaker
one last time.
That isn't possible.
They're all the same potency.
Something isn't the same.
You're becoming adjusted to them.
It's nothing to worry
about, Mrs. Goldfarb.
We got a winner!
A beautiful woman
with a magical smile.
Straight from Brighton
Beach Brooklyn.
Let's give a juicy welcome
to Mrs. Sara Goldfarb.
Juice by Sara!
Tyrone C. Get your shit
together. You made bail.
How much?
Most of our cash.
You're up for consortin'.
Shit, man.
It's a war between
Italians and blacks.
Sal is keeping the
shit down in Florida...
until guys like Brody
are all knocked off.
Sheeit.
No one's got a thing.
Except Big Tim.
Shit, let's go see him.
He ain't selling.
He only giving up fuzzies.
What?
He's hooked on the thing, man.
I told him I'd give
him all he wants...
but he ain't selling.
Number three!
This drives most people crazy.
You're not going to like it!
This is easy so far.
Give this up for 30 days...
You alright?
Yeah. It was a bad dream.
Want some water?
Maybe we should dip now.
Marion, I already told you.
It's all we have.
Tyrone is going to
score in the morning?
I don't know.
It's a bitch out there.
It'll be okay.
It'll be okay, Harry.
Yeah, I guess so.
I love you, Harry.
What's the problem?
The weight's fine.
The weight's fine. I'm not.
The refrigerator...
Something wrong?
Everything's...
all mixed up...
confused like.
Don't worry, just get this filled.
Make an appointment for a week.
Well?
Tyrone ain't found nothing yet.
What are we going to do?
I don't know.
You have to do something here.
It's your fault we don't
have something.
What are you talking about?
You were hot to
get off last night.
That is bullshit!
We could have had something.
I'm going to sit around and...
watch you push-off alone?
Don't put it all on me.
Don't worry, man.
We'll fill it up again.
Things will get better.
We'll fill the box back up.
You want to hear the news?
What news?
You got good news and bad news.
Shoot.
Good news is, in a couple of
days, they'll be prime back.
Really?
Who told you?
Angel.
Yeah?
Says Sal sent word...
to let go a couple of
keys for Christmas.
Not wanting anybody...
wantin' this glorious season.
You believe it?
I did, until I heard
the bad news.
Yeah?
Price is doubled and you
have to cop for weight.
At least half a piece.
How much?
Two.
Two? That's fucking insane!
What the fuck you gonna do?
He won't lay no nickel
bag on you.
Where we gonna get two?
You mean Arnold?
Your parents won't even
return your call.
I haven't seen him in months.
So what? He's still calling.
I don't know.
I don't know what else to do.
This is our last chance
to get back on track.
We won't have to scuffle
and make that freezing scene.
We need the bread.
Getting the money
is not the problem.
Then what is the problem?
Don't know what I'll
have to do to get it.
Look...
baby...
we'll be back in business
in no time.
We'll start moving again
and saving.
It'll be perfect. Just
like it was. I promise.
You'll see.
I had the flu forever,
it seems like.
Are you depressed?
No, nothing like that.
I've been really busy.
I've been designing non stop.
I'm glad to hear you've
been productive.
To be frank, I was surprised
to hear from you.
Something wrong?
No, why?
That's usually the case
when you get a call...
from someone you haven't
heard from for a while.
Everything's fine.
Actually...
I have a favor to ask.
You smug fuck!
What is it?
I need to borrow some money.
May I ask for what?
Turn the light off.
What for?
Just do it.
You never did before.
Please, Arnold.
Where is everybody?
I don't know, man.
They said meet at Waldbaum's.
Sure this is the right one?
Yeah, man, I'm positive.
You watch my back,
and I'll watch yours.
What the fuck now?
Everyone and their mother.
The truck's going to be here.
Back up.
Back up!
Here we go, guys.
Stupid fucking junkie.
We're fucked!
We're fucked.
That's the last shit for miles.
Muthafuckas going back
to Florida...
while we're ass deep
in motherfucking snow.
What if we went to cop?
You serious?
Why not?
What the fuck are you saying?
We go to a fuckin' room clerk...
and ask him for a connection?
You can't nose out some
dope when it's around?
We got nothin' to lose.
If we get there now...
we name our price...
and be cool.
Have them scufflin' for us.
Last summer was a mother
fucking ball.
Seems like a thousand years ago.
It'll be back like that.
Angel'll get us a short if we
get him some dynamite scag.
Where have you been?
Where the hell do you think?
Where's the score?
We had a bit of a problem.
Everything was going good,
and then...
some dumb ass junkie...
Did what?
Some dumb ass junkie did what?
You fucked it up?
What the fuck is wrong with you?
You promised everything
was going to be okay.
I fucked that sleazebag for you.
I put myself through fucking hell!
There's nothing out there.
I don't give a shit!
You fucking loser!
You want extra stuff?
A guy's holding some extra weight.
But he ain't selling!
Yeah?
Give me that guy's number.
What guy?
The guy who likes broads.
Big Tim?
Give me the fucking number.
Alright. 9, 3, 4...
8, 7, 7, 7.
Here, go fix yourself
up with him.
You won't have to wait so much...
and I won't freeze my ass off
in the fucking streets.
We got a winner.
A beautiful woman with
a winning sense of humor...
and a magical smile.
From Brighton Beach, Brooklyn.
Give a juicy welcome to our
very own Mrs. Sara Goldfarb.
Juice by Sara!
It's a pleasure to be here.
It's a pleasure to have you.
That is one smashing dress.
Thank you, Tappy.
I'd like to say hello...
to my husband Seymour...
and to my beautiful,
successful son Harold.
Harold, I hope you're in love.
Come see me and bring Marion.
He'll be here soon.
Are you ready?
I'm ready, Tappy.
Not to worry.
What are you doing here?
Why are you here?
This place...
What do you want?
Tappy!
Join us in creating excellence.
I thought you'd never ask.
That's disgusting.
What do you expect?
Could you do better?
It's an old building.
It hasn't been painted in years.
I'm old. Alone.
You don't understand.
Please, I'll explain.
I don't want this.
Get away from me!
Ready, Mrs. Goldfarb?
For what?
3... 2...
Feed me, Sara.
Thank you, Angel.
Hope this mutha' fucker works.
Could use some heat.
How long will it take?
We'll make it in a day.
A day.
Shit. California, here we come.
It's Florida.
Either way, your pale ass
getting a tan, right?
This train go to Madison Avenue?
You know Maylin and Block?
I have their address.
They're on Madison Ave.
I'm going to be on TV.
You're whacked!
Hello?
This train go to Madison Avenue?
I'm going to be on TV.
I just have to find out when.
Florida?
When's he back?
A few days!?
What am I supposed to do?
You gotta help me!
I can get you money.
Angel, there's got
to be something.
Help me!
Why aren't you calling me?
I have to know
when I'll be on TV.
I'm Sara Goldfarb and...
you should tell me when
I'll be on TV.
Sit, I'll ring them.
I just want to know when.
Maybe you lost my card.
You'll have a look
and you'll tell me.
It's not the prizes.
I'll give them away.
I just want to be on the show.
I've waited so long...
to be with my Harry
and grandson.
Mrs. Goldfarb, sip this.
Sometimes it takes a
while to get called.
- This her?
- Yes.
Can you walk?
I'm walking across this stage.
You should see my Harry
on television.
We're giving the prizes away.
I just wanted to be on the show!
What's her name?
Sara Goldfarb.
Call Seymour to meet me
at the beauty parlor.
I got the dress I wore
to Harry's graduation...
and the gold shoes.
Okay, Mrs. Goldfarb.
One... two... three...
Take it nice and easy.
Yeah?
Hi.
Rosa, I'm going to be on TV.
Sheet. God damned Jim,
how long you had that?
A few days.
It don't look too good.
I don't feel too good either.
Some stuff'll take care of that.
Don't shoot in there.
I'll blow it if I don't.
Fuck it!
Oh, shit.
Hi, can you hear me?
Yes, Seymour.
Did you take anything?
I took my red dress in.
Take her to psych.
Come on in.
What's your name?
Marion.
What do you know, Maid Marion.
I'm Little John.
Beautiful view...
Know what I like about
patty chicks?
They give good head.
Black broads don't
give good head.
I don't know why.
Maybe it's because of some
ancient tribal customs.
Save some of the energy.
I know it's pretty, baby...
but I didn't take it out for air.
I told you to stay
away from that arm.
I gotta call Marion.
That's a long distance call now.
That's 600 miles.
We're 600 miles
closer to Miami.
And 600 miles further
away from New York.
I know where you could
pick up a nice taste.
It's more like play.
Sunday we're throwing a gathering.
All good people.
I can't, I'm busy.
I'm not really hooked.
I'm tellin' ya',
it's a real nice taste.
See you Sunday, Maid Marion.
Try and answer my questions.
When did you start the pills?
The summer.
Last summer?
I got the best place. In the sun.
Ada fixed my hair.
Everything'll be alright.
We'll get you fixed up in no time.
You're okay.
I can't cut it. I gotta do
something about this arm.
Let's see it.
Oh, damn, Jim.
Oh, man.
That's an ugly mothafucka'.
I gotta call Marion.
Fuck that. We got to
get you to a hospital.
What is that?
I don't want that.
What's the problem?
My arm, it's killing me.
Let's have a look.
Alright.
I'll be back in a minute.
I want to play blackjack
all night.
So I make up this routine.
I tell them I don't feel good.
Have a good time dancing, guys.
They leave the room.
Ready? One... two... three...
As soon as they leave, I
run back down to the casino.
Sit at my blackjack
table the whole night.
Finally I got up big.
I got $500 black chips.
Hours are going by,
I'm laying bets.
Next thing, this guy
is sitting next to me.
A security guard.
Tells me I have to leave.
I'm like "why leave?"
S-w-a-l-l-o-w!
You have to eat.
To get healthy, you have to eat.
Work with the attendants.
I'll try some new medications.
Hello?
Marion?
Harry?
I've been thinking about you.
Are you okay?
When are you coming home?
Soon.
When?
Soon. You holding out alright?
Harry...
can you come today?
I'll come.
I'll come today.
Just wait for me, alright?
Okay, Harry.
I'm coming back.
Yeah.
Marion.
I'm sorry, Marion.
I know.
Mrs. Goldfarb...
are you alright?
we've tried several
medications...
and you don't respond.
We might want to try some...
alternative methods.
We've had excellent results
with ECT in the past.
So if I can just get
your John Hancock...
we'll get underway.
Jesus Christ.
I need a doctor.
My friend is sick.
Can you help?
I can't take it. My arm!
My fucking arm!
Help me!
Somebody fucking help us, please!
Maid Marion.
Welcome.
Can you see me?
Yes, sir.
Okay for work.
Can you hear me?
Can you see me?
Yes, sir.
Okay for work.
Can you hear me?
Can you see me?
- Yes, sir.
- Okay for work.
- Can you see me?
- Yes, sir.
Okay for work.
Can you see me?
- Yes, sir.
- Okay for work.
Meet Marion.
Can you see me?
- Yes, sir.
- Okay for work.
Can you see me?
- Yes, sir.
- Okay for work.
Can you see me?
- Yes, sir.
- Okay for work.
Showtime.
Can you see me?
Say "sir". God damn New Yawk
dope fien niggas.
Learn some manners.
Can you see me?
Yes, sir.
Okay for work.
Can you hear me?
Can you see me?
Something wrong with his arm.
Ma...
You won't be putting
more dope in that arm.
It smells worse than he do.
Get him to the hospital.
He won't live out the week.
One.
That's the trouble with
New York dope fiends.
You got a rotten attitude.
What we do now?
Ass to ass.
Put your spineless back into it.
And...
two.
Okay. Ready? And three.
Cum. Cum, cum, cum,
cum, cum, cum, cum.
Off at the shoulder.
Move or we lose him.
Cum. Cum, cum, cum,
cum, cum, cum, cum.
Marion!
Marion?
It's alright. Don't worry.
Marion.
Who's that?
She'll be sent for.
She'll come.
No.
No?
No, she won't.
She'll come.
We got a winner.
We got a winner!
Our winner is that
delightful personality...
from Brighton Beach, Brooklyn.
Give a juicy welcome to
Mrs. Sara Goldfarb.
I'm delighted that you have
just won the grand prize!
Let me tell you what you've won.
He has a sweet smile
and his own business.
He just got engaged.
And is about to get married
this summer.
Give a warm...
and juicy welcome:
Harry Goldfarb!
Juice by Harry!
Harry's got juice!
I love you, Harry.
I love you too, ma.