Let me tell you what
"Like A Virgin"is about.
It's all about a girl who digs
a guy with a big dick.
The entire song
is a metaphor for big dicks.
No, it ain't.
It's about a girl
who's very vulnerable.
She's been fucked over a few
time and she meets a guy...
who's sensitive.
Timeout. Tell that bullshit
to the tourists.
Toby? Who the fuck is Toby?
Like A Virgin is not about
some sensitive girl...
who meets a nice fella.
That's "True Blue" is about.
No argument about that.
- Which one is "True Blue"?
- It was a big hit for Madonna.
I don't even follow
that top-of-the-pops shit...
and I've heard of "True Blue".
I didn't say I ain't heard it.
All I asked is, how's it go?
Excuse me for not being the
world's biggest Madonna fan.
Personally, I can do
without her.
I used to like her
early stuff, "Borderline"...
but when she got "Papa,
Don't Preach", I tuned out.
Hey, you guys are making me
lose my train of thought here.
I was sayin' something.
What was it?
Oh, Toby's that
little Chinese girl.
- What was her last name?
- What's that?
It's an old address book
I found in a coat...
I haven't worn
in a coon's age.
- What was that name?
- What the fuck I talkin' about?
You said "True Blue"
was about a guy...
a sensitive girl
who meets a nice guy...
"but "Like A Virgin"
was a metaphor for big dicks.
Let me tell you what
Like A Virgin is about.
It's all about this cooze
who's a regular fuck machine.
I'm talkin' morning, day,
night, afternoon...
dick, dick, dick, dick, dick,
dick, dick, dick, dick!
- How many dicks is that?
- A lot.
Then one day, she meets this
John Holmes mother-fucker.
It's like, "Whoa, baby".
He's like Charles Bronson
in "The Great Escape".
He's diggin' tunnels. Now she's
gettin' serious dick action.
She's feelin' somethin'
she ain't felt since forever...
pain, pain.
Chew? Toby Chew?
It hurts. It hurts her.
It shouldn't hurt her.
Her pussy should be
Bubble-Yum by now.
But when this cat
fucks her, it hurts.
It hurts just like it did
the first time.
You see, the pain
is reminding a fuck machine...
what it was once
like to be a virgin.
Hence, "Like A Virgin".
Wong.
- Give me that fuckin' thing.
- What hell do you think...
you're doin'?
I'm sick of hearin' it, Joe.
I'll give it back to you...
when we leave.
What you mean, when we leave?
Give me it back now!
For the past 15 minutes now,
you've been droning...
on about names.
Toby. Toby?
Toby? Toby Wong.
Toby Wong? Toby Wong.
Toby Chung
"fuckin' Charlie Chan".
I've got Madonna's big dick
comin' out of my left ear...
and Toby the Jap
I don't know what...
comin' out of my right.
Give me that book.
Are you gonna put it away?
I'm gonna do whatever fuck
I want with it.
Well, then I'm afraid
I'm gonna have to keep it.
Hey, Joe...
- want me to shoot this guy?
- Shit.
You shoot me in a dream you
better wake up and apologize.
You guys been listenin' to
K-BILLY's Super Sounds...
- of the '70s weekend?
- Yeah. That's fuckin' great.
- Believe the songs they play?
- Know I heard the other day?
Heartbeat, It's a Lovebeat
by little Tony DeFranco.
I haven't heard that song
since I was...
in the fifth fuckin' grade.
When I was comin' down here...
"The Night the Lights
Went Out in Georgia" came on.
I ain't heard that song
since it was big.
But when it was big,
I must've heard it...
a million-trillion
fuckin' times.
But this is the first time
I ever realized...
that the girl
singin' the song...
is the one who shot Andy.
You didn't know
that Vickie Lawrence was...
the one who shot Andy?
I thought
the cheatin' wife shot Andy.
They say that
at the end of the song.
I know, mother-fucker.
I just heard it.
That's what I'm talkin' about.
I must've zoned out
during that part before.
All right,
I'll take care of the check.
You guys can get the tip.
Should be about
a buck apiece.
And you, when I come back
I want my book.
Sorry.
It's my book now.
Hey,
I changed my mind.
Shoot this piece of shit,
will ya?
Everybody cough up some green
for the little lady.
Come on, throw in a buck.
I don't tip.
- You don't tip?
- I don't believe in it.
You don't believe in tipping?
Do you know what these
chicks make? They make shit.
If she don't make enough
money she can quit.
I don't even know
a fuckin' Jew...
who'd have the balls
to say that.
Let me get this straight.
You don't ever tip, huh?
I don't tip because
society says I have to.
If they really put
forth the effort...
I'll give 'em
somethin' extra.
But this tipping
automatically...
it's for the birds.
As far as I'm concerned,
they'rejust doin' theirjob.
- This girl was nice.
- She was okay.
- She wasn't anything special.
- What's special?
Take you in the back
and suck your dick?
I'd go over 12% for that.
I ordered coffee, all right?
She's only filled...
my cup three times.
I want it filled six times.
Six times? Well, what if
she's too fuckin' busy?
"Too fuckin' busy" can't be
in a waitress's vocabulary.
Excuse me, Mr. Pink,
but the last...
fuckin' thing you need
is another cup of coffee.
These ladies aren't
starvin' to death.
They make minimum wage.
I used to work minimum wage,
and when I did...
I wasn't lucky
enough to have ajob...
that society
deemed tip-worthy.
You don't care they count
your tips to live?
You know what this is?
The world's
smallest violin, playin'...
just for the waitresses.
You don't have any idea
what you're talkin' about.
These people bust their ass.
This is a hard job.
So's working at McDonald's,
but you don't feel the need...
to tip them.
They're servin' you food,
but society says...
"Don't tip
these guys over here...
but tip these guys".
That's bullshit.
Waitressing is
the number-one occupation...
for female non-college
graduates in this country.
It's the onejob basically
any woman can get...
and make a living on.
The reason is
because of their tips.
Fuck all that.
I'm very sorry the government
taxes their tips.
That's fucked up.
That ain't my fault.
It would appear that
waitresses are one of the...
many groups the government
fucks on a regular basis.
Show me a paper
that says the government...
shouldn't do that,
I'll sign it.
I'll vote for it. But what
I won't do is play ball.
This non-college bullshit,
I got two words for that...
Learn to fuckin' type.
If you're expectin' me
to help out with the rent...
you're in for a big surprise.
He's convinced me.
Give me my dollar back.
Hey. Leave the dollars there.
All right, ramblers,
let's get ramblin'.
Wait a minute.
Who didn't throw in?
- Mr. Pink.
- Mr. Pink?
- Why not?
- He don't tip.
He don't tip?
- You don't tip?
- He don't believe in it.
Shut up.
What do you mean...
you don't believe in it?
Cough up a buck,
you cheap bastard.
I paid for
your goddamn breakfast.
Since you bought breakfast,
I'll put in.
But normally I would never
do this.
Never mind what you
normally would do.
Just cough in your goddamn
buck like everybody else.
Thank you.
That was
the Partridge Family's...
"Doesn't Somebody
Want To Be Wanted?"...
followed by
Edison Lighthouse's...
"Love Grows Where
My Rosemary Goes"...
as K-BILL Y's
Super Sounds...
of the '70s weekend...
just keeps on truckin'.
I'm gonna die.
I'm gonna die!
Just hold on, buddy boy!
- I'm sorry!
- Give me your hand.
I can't believe
she killed me, man!
Who'd have fuckin'
thought that?
Hey, just cancel that shit
right now!
You're hurt. You're hurt
real fuckin' bad...
but you ain't
dying!
All this blood's scarin'
the shit out of me, Larry!
I'm gonna die!
I know it!
Excuse me, I didn't realize
you had a degree in medicine.
Are you a doctor?
Answer me, please!
No, I'm not.
I'm not.
So you admit you don't know
what you're talkin' about.
If you're through givin' me
your amateur opinion...
lie back and listen.
I'm takin' you back
to the rendezvous...
Joe's gonna get you a doctor...
the doctor's gonna
fix you up and...
you're gonna be okay.
Now say it!
You're gonna be okay!
Say it!
Say the goddamn words!
You're gonna be okay!
Oh, God!
Say the goddamn fuckin' words!
Say it!
Okay, Larry.
Correct! Correct!
I'm okay.
Look where we are.
She had a baby, man.
She had a baby!
We're in a warehouse.
Who's a tough guy?
Come on, who's a tough guy?
You're a tough guy.
You're a fuckin' tough guy.
We're in a warehouse.
Look where we are.
We made it. We made it.
We fuckin' made it.
We have fuckin' made it.
We're in a warehouse.
Look where we are.
Hold on. Hold on.
- Shit!
- Stop bangin' your head.
You're gonna bang a fuckin'
hole in the floor.
You don't wanna hurt
the fuckin' floor, do you?
I can't do anything for you.
But when Joe gets here...
which should be
any time now...
he's gonna help you out,
he's gonna take care of you.
We're gonna sit
and wait for Joe.
- Who are we waitin' for?
- Joe.
Larry,
I'm fucking scared, man.
Would you please hold me?
Yeah, sure.
You go ahead and be scared.
You've been brave enough
for one day.
I just want you
to relax now, okay?
You're not gonna fuckin' die.
You're gonna be fine.
When Joe gets here,
he'll make you 100% again.
Am I hurt?
I'm hurt bad, Larry.
It's not good, no.
Hey, Larry...
God bless your heart
for what you're tryin' to do.
I was panicking
for a minute back there.
But I got my senses back now.
The situation is,
I'm shot in the belly.
Without medical attention,
I'm gonna die.
I can't take you
to a hospital.
Fuck jail, man!
You don't have to take me in.
Just drive me up...
to the front, man.
Just drop me on the sidewalk.
I'll take care of myself.
I won't tell 'em
anything, man.
I won't tell 'em anything.
I swear to fucking God, man.
Just look in my eyes, Larry.
Look in my eyes.
I won't tell them anything.
You'll be safe, man.
You're not gonna fuckin'
die, kid. All right?
Listen to me.
You're gonna be fine.
Along with the kneecap,
the gut...
is the most painful area
a guy can get shot in.
No shit!
But it takes a long time
to die from it.
I'm talkin' days.
You're gonna
wish you were dead, but...
it takes days
to die from your wound.
Time is on your side.
Was that a fucking set up,
for what?
Shit. Orange got tagged?
Gut shot.
Fuck. Where's Brown?
Dead.
How did he die?
How the fuck do you think?
The cops shot him.
This is bad.
This is so fucking bad.
Is it bad?
As opposed to good?
Man, this is fucked up.
This is so fucked up.
Somebody fucked us up
big time, man.
You really think
we were set up?
Do you even doubt it, man?
I don't think we got set up,
I know it.
Where did all those cops
come from, huh?
One minute
they're not there...
and the next minute
they're there.
I didn't hear any sirens.
The alarm went off, okay?
When an alarm goes, you got
a four-minute response time.
Unless a patrol car
is cruising...
that street at that moment...
you got four minutes before
they can realistically respond.
In one minute, here were
17 blue boys out there...
all knowing exactly what
the fuck they were doing...
and they were all there!
Remember that second wave
that showed up in the cars?
Those were the ones
responding to the alarm...
but those first ones...
they were there
and they were waitin' for us.
Haven't you fuckin'
thought about this?
I haven't had a chance to think.
First I wasjust tryin'
to get the fuck outta there.
And after we got away I've
just been dealin' with him.
Better start thinkin'
about it...
'cause that's all
I'm thinkin' about.
I wasn't even
gonna come here...
I wasjust gonna
drive off, man...
because whoever set us up
knows about this place.
There could've
been cops here waitin'!
There could be cops
comin' right now!
Let's go in the other room.
Hey. In there.
Larry, don't leave me.
I'll be right
in the other room, okay?
I'll be right there
lookin' at ya.
I'm right here
lookin' at you, okay?
I'm right over there.
Larry...
I'm gonna fucking die.
Larry.
What the fuck
am I doin' here, man?
I felt funny about thisjob
right off.
As soon as I felt it
I should have said...
No, thank you,
but I never listen.
Every time I ever got
fucked buying weed...
the same thing.
I didn't trust the guy,
but I wanted to believe him.
If he's not lying,
then it's great.
I always said that if I felt
that about ajob, I'd walk.
And I didn't. I didn't
because of the fuckin' money!
What's done is done.
I need you cool.
Are you cool?
I'm cool.
Splash some water
on your face.
Take a breather.
Relax. Have a cigarette.
I quit.
- All right.
- Why, you got one?
Okay, let's go through
what happened.
We're in the place,
everything's going fine.
Then the alarm gets tripped.
I turn around and
all these cops are outside.
You're right.
It was like, bam...
I blinked my eyes
and they're there.
Everybody starts
going ape-shit.
Then Mr. Blonde starts
to shoot all...
- That's not correct.
- What's wrong with it?
Ok. The cops did not show up
after the alarm went off.
Not until Mr. Blonde
started shootin' everybody.
Soon as I heard the alarm,
I saw cops.
It wasn't that soon.
They didn't let
their presence be known...
until after Mr. Blonde
became a madman.
I'm not sayin'
they weren't there.
But they didn't make
a move until after...
Mr. Blonde started
shootin' everybody.
I mean, that's how
I know we were set up.
C'mon Mr. White,
you can see that...
Enough of this
Mr. White shit.
Wait! Don't tell me
you're fuckin' name!
I don't wanna know it!
Jesus Christ,
I ain't gonna tell you mine.
You're right.
This is bad.
- How did you get out?
- I shot my way out.
Everybody started shootin',
so I blasted my way out.
Move it!
Get outta the way!
Get the fuck outta the way!
Move it!
Get outta the way!
Jesus Christ!
What the fuck
is your problem, man?
- You fuckin' asshole!
- Fuck you!
Move!
- Jesus!
- Get outta the car!
Get the fuck outta the car!
Move it!
Move outta the way!
I tagged a couple of cops.
Did you kill anybody?
- A few cops.
- No real people?
Just cops.
Could you believe Mr. Blonde?
That was the most insane
fuckin' thing...
I have ever seen.
Why the fuck would Joe
hire a guy like that?
I don't want to kill anybody.
If I gotta get out that door
and you're standin' in my way...
one way or the other you're
gettin' outta my way.
That's the way I look at it.
The choice between
doin' ten years...
and takin' out
some stupid mother-fucker...
ain't no choice at all.
But I ain't no madman,
either.
What the fuck
was Joe thinkin'?
You can't work
with a guy like that.
We're awful goddamn lucky
he didn't tag us...
when he shot the place up.
I came this close
to takin' his ass out myself.
I mean, everybody panics.
Everybody.
Things get tense.
It's human nature.
I don't care what your name
is, you can't help it.
Fuck, man,
you panic on the inside...
in your head, you know?
You give yourself
a couple of seconds...
get a hold of it
and deal with it.
What you don't do
is start shootin' up...
the place
and start killin' people.
What you're supposed to do
is act like a professional.
A psychopath
ain't a professional.
You can't work
with a psychopath.
You don't know
what those sick assholes...
are gonna do next.
I mean, Jesus Christ,
how old do you think...
that black girl was? Twenty?
- Maybe 21?
- Lf that.
Did you see what happened
to anybody else?
Me and Orange
jumped in the car...
Brown floored it.
After that, I don't know
what went down.
It was every man for himself.
As far as Mr. Blonde
and Mr. Blue are concerned...
I ain't got the foggiest...
'cause once I got out,
I never looked back.
What do you think?
What do I think?
The cops either
caught 'em or killed 'em.
No chance they punched
through? You found a hole.
Yeah, and that was
a fuckin' miracle.
But even if they get away,
then where are they?
If one of'em got a hold
of the diamonds and...
- No, no way.
- How can you be so sure?
I got the diamonds.
That's my boy.
- Where?
- I stashed 'em.
If you wanna come with me,
let's go get 'em...
right now, this second.
'Cause I think
stayin' here, man...
we should have
our fuckin' heads examined.
That was the plan.
We meet here.
Then where the fuck
is everybody?
I say the plan
becomes null and void...
once we found out
we got a rat here.
We ain't got
the slightest idea...
what happened
to Mr. Blonde or Mr. Blue.
They could both be dead
or maybe they're arrested.
The cops could have 'em
right now at the station...
sweatin' 'em down.
They don't know names, but
they know this place.
I swear to God,
I think I'm fuckin' jinxed.
What?
Twojobs back,
it was a four-man job.
We discovered one of the team
was an undercover cop.
No shit?
Thank God
we discovered in time.
We had to forget
the whole thing, just walk...
the fuck away from it.
So who's the rat this time?
Mr. Blue?
Mr. Brown?
Joe? Joe set
this whole thing up.
Maybe he set it up
to set it up.
I don't buy it.
Me and Joe go back
a long time.
I can tell you definitely,
Joe didn't know a thing...
about this bullshit.
I know Joe, and me sayin'
he definitely...
had nothin' to do
with it is ridiculous.
I can say
I definitely didn't do it...
'cause I know
what I did or didn't do.
But I cannot definitely say
that about anybody...
'cause I don't
definitely know.
For all I know, you're the rat.
For all I know,
you're the fuckin' rat!
All right, now you're usin'
your fuckin' head.
For all we know,
he's the rat.
That kid in there is dying
from a fuckin' bullet...
I saw him take...
so don't you be calling
him a rat!
Look, I'm right, okay?
Somebody's a fuckin' rat.
Where's the commode?
I gotta take a squirt.
Go down the hall, make
a left, go up the stairs...
and make a right.
- By the way, how's Alabama?
- Alabama?
I haven't seen Bama
in over a year and a half.
But I thought you two
were a team.
We were for a little while.
Did about
fourjobs together.
Then decided
to call it quits.
Why?
You push that woman-man
thing too long...
and it gets to you
after a while.
What's she doin' now?
She hooked up
with Frank MacGarr.
They've done
a couplejobs together.
Hell of a woman.
Good little thief.
- So explain the telegram.
- Five-man job.
Bustin' in and bustin' out
of a diamond wholesaler's.
Can you move
the ice afterwards?
I don't know nobody
that can move ice.
No problem.
We got guys waitin' for it.
What happened
to Marcellus Spivey?
Didn't he
always move your ice?
He's doin' 20 years
in Susanville.
Twenty years? Holy God.
What for?
Bad luck.
I guess you can say
that again.
What's the exposure like?
Two minutes, tops.
But it's a tough two minutes.
Daylight,
during business hours...
dealing with a crowd.
But you'll have the guys
to deal with the crowd.
- How many employees?
- I'd say around 20.
Security pretty lax.
They most usually
just deal in boxes.
You know, uncut stones
from the diamond syndicate.
But on this day,
they're getting a shipment...
of polished stones
from Israel.
They're like a way station,
you know?
They get picked up
and sent to Vermont.
No, they're not.
What's the cut, poppa?
Juicy, junior.
Real juicy.
Look, man,
you do what you want.
I'm outta here, man.
I'm gonna check...
into a motel
for a few days.
You know, I'll lay low
and I'll call Joe...
Shit.
Did he fuckin' die on us?
Huh?
Is he dead or what?
- He ain't dead.
- What is it?
He scared
the fuckin' shit outta me.
I thought he was dead
for sure.
Without medical attention,
he will die for sure.
What are we gonna do? We
can't take him to a hospital.
Without medical attention,
he might not live...
through the night.
The bullet in his belly
is my fault.
While that might not mean
jack shit to you...
it means a hell
of a lot to me.
First things first, okay?
Stayin' here's goofy.
We gotta book up.
What do you suggest we do?
Go to a hotel?
We got a guy
who's shot in the belly...
who can't walk,
bleeds like a stuck pig.
And when he's awake,
he screams in pain.
You got an idea, spit it out.
Joe could help.
If we could get in touch
with Joe...
Joe could get him
to a doctor.
Joe could get a doctor
to come to see him.
Assuming we can trust Joe,
how we gonna get in touch?
He's supposed to be here,
but he ain't...
which makes me nervous
about bein' here.
Even if he is
on the up and up...
I don't think he's gonna be
too happy with us.
He planned a robbery
and he's got a bloodbath...
on his hands now.
He's got dead cops, dead
robbers, dead civilians.
I tend to doubt he's gonna
have some sympathy for us.
If I was him,
I'd put as much distance...
between me
and this mess as possible.
Before you got here,
Mr. Orange...
was askin' me to take him
to a doctor to a hospital.
I don't like the idea of
turnin' him over to cops...
but if we don't,
he's gonna die.
He begged me to do it.
Well, all right.
Then I guess we take him
to a hospital.
If that's what he said,
let's do it.
Since he don't know
nothin' about us...
I say it's his decision.
He knows a little about me.
What? Wait, wait.
You didn't tell him
your name, did you?
I told him my first name
and where I was from.
Why?
I told him where I was from
a few days ago.
It wasjust
a natural conversation.
You weren't supposed to
tellin' him your name.
He asked.
We had just gotten away
from the cops.
Hejust got shot.
It was my fault
he got shot.
He's a fuckin' bloody mess.
He's screamin'.
I swear to God,
I thought he was gonna die...
right then and there.
I'm tryin' to comfort him...
telling him not to worry...
everything's
going to be okay...
I'm gonna take care of him.
And he asked me
what my name was.
I mean,
the man was dyin' in my arms.
What the fuck
was I supposed to do?
Tell him I'm sorry?
I can't give out
that fuckin' information?
It's against the rules?
I don't trust you enough?
Maybe I should've,
but I couldn't.
Fuck you! Fuck Joe!
I'm sure
it was a beautiful scene.
Don't fuckin' patronize me!
I have one question.
Do they have a sheet on you
where you're from?
- Yeah!
- That's that, then.
I was worried about mug
shot possibility as it was.
He knows A, your name,
B, your face...
C, your hometown
and D, your specialty.
They're gonna show him a few
pictures to pick you out!
You didn't tell him
anything else...
so they could narrow
down the selection?
If I have to tell you again
to back off, we're gonna go...
'round and 'round.
We ain't takin' him
to a hospital.
If we don't,
he's gonna die.
And I'm very sad about that,
but some fellas are lucky...
and some ain't.
What the fuck are you
touchin' me for, man?
I'll show you
who you're fuckin' with!
You wanna shoot me,
you piece of shit?
- Go ahead, take a shot.
- Fuck you, White.
I didn't create
this fucking situation!
You're actin'
like a first-year thief!
I'm actin'
like a professional!
If they get him,
they could get you...
they could get
closer to me...
and that can't happen!
You're lookin' at me
like it's my fault?
I didn't tell him my name!
I didn't tell him
where I was from!
Shit! Fifteen minutes ago
you almost told me your name!
You're gonna get stuck
in a situation you created!
So if you wanna throw bad
looks around use a mirror!
You kids shouldn't play
so rough.
Somebody's gonna
start cryin'.
Mr. Blonde.
Shit.
You're fuckin' kickin' me.
What happened to you?
Figured you were dead.
Hey, you okay?
Did you see
what happened to Blue?
We didn't know
what happened to you.
That's what
we were wonderin' about.
Look, Brown is dead...
Orange got it in the belly.
Enough! Enough!
You better start talkin',
asshole.
'Cause we got shit
we need to talk about.
We're already freaked out.
We need you actin' freak
like we need a fuckin'...
bag on our hip.
Okay, let's talk.
We think we got a rat
in the house.
I guarantee we got a rat
What makes you say that?
Is that supposed to be funny?
Look, we think
this place ain't safe.
This place ain't secure
anymore.
We're leavin'
and you should go with us.
Nobody's goin' anywhere.
Piss on this fuckin' turd.
We're outta here.
2yDon't take another step,
Mr. White.
Fuck you, maniac!
It's your fuckin' fault
we're in this trouble!
What's this guy's problem?
What's my problem?
Yeah,
I got a fuckin' problem!
I got
a big fuckin' problem...
with any trigger-happy madman
who almost gets me shot!
What the fuck
you talkin' about?
That fucking shooting spree!
In the store! Remember?
Oh, fuck 'em.
They set off the alarm.
They deserve what they got.
You almost killed me!
Asshole!
If I knew
what kind of guy you were...
I never would've agreed
to work with you.
Are you gonna bark all day,
little doggie...
or are you gonna bite?
What was that?
I'm sorry, I didn't catch it.
Would you repeat it?
Are you gonna bark all day,
little doggie...
or are you gonna bite?
You two assholes,
calm the fuck down!
Hey, come on!
What, are we on
a playground here?
Am I the only professional?
You're actin' like
a bunch of fuckin' niggers!
Ever work with niggers?
Always sayin' they're
gonna kill each other.
You said yourself you though
about taking him out.
- You fuckin' said that?
- Yeah, I did, okay?
But that was then.
Right now...
this guy is the only one
I completely trust.
He's too fuck homicidal
to be with the cops.
- You takin' his side?
- Fuck sides, man!
What we need here
is solidarity!
Somebody's stickin' a red-hot
poker up our ass...
and I want to know who.
Fuck. Look, I know
I'm no piece of shit.
I'm pretty sure you're okay,
and I'm fuckin' positive...
you're on the level.
So let's try
and figure out...
who the bad guy is,
all right?
Wow.
That was really exciting.
I bet you're a big
Lee Marvin fan, aren't ya?
Yeah, me too.
I love that guy.
My heart's beatin' so fast,
I'm about to have
a heart attack here.
I got
somethin' outside that...
I'd like to show you guys,
so follow me.
Follow you? Where?
To my car.
Did you forget
your French fries...
to go with the soda?
No, I had them already.
I got somethin' I think
you might wanna see, though.
- What?
- It's a big surprise.
I'm sure you'll like it.
Come on.
We still gotta get
outta here, you know.
No. We're gonna stick around
and we're gonna wait.
- What for? The cops?
- No. Nice Guy Eddie.
Nice Guy Eddie?
What makes you think...
he isn't on a plane halfway
to Costa Rica?
Because I spoke to him
on the phone...
and he said
he's on the way down here.
You talked to Nice Guy Eddie?
Why didn't you say
that in the first place?
- 'Cause you never asked me.
- Hardy-fuckin'-har.
- What'd he say?
- He said stay put.
So in the meantime...
I'll show you guys
somethin'.
Jesus Christ.
Maybe our boy
in blue here...
can answer some
of these questions...
about this rat business
you've been talkin' about.
You're a piece of work,
my friend.
Let's get him
the fuck outta here.
Hey, Sid, will you relax?
I've known you a long time.
I'm not worried.
I know you'll pay me back.
Don't tell me
what I already know.
Don't embarrass me.
So you had
a few bad months.
You do
what everybody else does.
I don't care
if it's J.P. Morgan...
or Irving the tailor.
You ride it out.
- Vic Vega's outside.
- Hold on.
- Who?
- Vic Vega.
Tell him to come in.
I gotta go.
- Come on in.
- A friend of mine's outside.
I'll be talkin' to you.
Don't worry.
Hey, welcome home, Vic.
How does freedom feel, huh?
- It's a change.
- Ain't that the sad truth.
Sit down,
take your coat off...
make yourself at home.
- Have a little drink?
- Yeah.
How about
a little Remy Martin?
Sure.
Who's your parole officer?
Seymour Scagnetti.
How is he?
He's a fuckin' asshole.
Won't even let me
leave the halfway house.
It never ceases to amaze me.
A fuckin' jungle bunny
goes out there...
slits a woman's throat
for 25 cents...
he gets Doris Day
for a parole officer.
A good fella like you...
winds up
with a ball-bustin' prick.
I want you to know
I appreciate...
all the packages
you sent me on the inside.
What the hell
was I supposed to do?
Forget about you?
I just want you to know
that it meant a lot to me.
It was the least I could do.
I wish to hell
I could've done a lot more.
Thanks a lot, Joe.
Ah, Vic.
Toothpick Vic.
So tell me your story, kid.
What are your plans?
You son of a bitch.
I see you sittin' there,
but I don't believe it.
- How you doin', Toothpick?
- Hey, Eddie.
Listen, I'm sorry.
I should've
picked you up myself.
I was... My fuckin'...
This week's been crazy.
I've had my head up my ass
the whole time.
Funny you say that,
'cause that's what...
me and your daddy
were talkin' about.
That I should've
picked you up?
No, that you had
your head up your ass.
I walk in the door,
he's like, "Vic, Vic...
I'm so glad somebody's
finally here...
who knows what's goin' on.
My son Eddie's a fuck-up.
He's ruining the business.
I mean,
I love the guy...
but he's flushin'
everything down the toilet".
That's what you said, right?
Tell him yourself.
Eddie, I hate for you
to hear it like this, but...
Vic came in and asked me
how business was.
You don't lie
to a guy who's...
just done four years
in the slammer.
That's very true.
All right,
enough of this shit!
Break it up!
Come on,
this ain't a playground!
You guys wanna
roll around on the floor...
you do it in Eddie's office,
not mine.
- Daddy, did you see that?
- What?
The guy got me
on the ground...
he tried to fuck me.
- You wish.
- You sick bastard, Vic.
You tried to fuck me
in my father's office.
Look, Vic,
whatever you wanna do...
in the privacy
of your own home...
go to it...
but don't try to fuck me.
I don't think of you
that way.
I like you a lot, buddy...
but I don't think of you
that way.
Listen, if I was
a butt cowboy...
I wouldn't even throw you
to the posse.
No, you wouldn't.
You'd keep me for yourself.
Four years fuckin' punks
up the ass...
you'd appreciate
a piece of prime rib.
I might break you in,
Nice Guy...
but I'd make you
my dog's bitch.
Ain't that
a sad sight, Daddy?
A man walks into prison
a white man...
walks out talkin'
like a fuckin' nigger.
You know what?
I think it's all
that black semen...
pumped up your asshole,
now it's backed...
into your fuckin' brain and
it's comin' out your mouth!
Eddie, you keep talkin'
like a bitch...
I'm gonna slap you
like a bitch.
Enough of that shit!
I'm sick of it!
Now both of you, sit down.
Now, Eddie...
when you came in here...
we were talkin'
some serious business.
Vic here's
got a parole problem.
- Who's your P. O?
- Seymour Scagnetti.
Scagnetti. Fuck.
- I hear he's a mother-fucker.
- Oh, he's a fucker.
Won't even let me leave
the halfway house...
unless I get
some shitty job.
You're comin' back
to work for us, right?
Well, I wanna.
But first
I gotta prove to, uh...
ass-head that
I can get...
a regular, you know,
job-typejob...
before I can move out
on my own.
I can't come back
to work for you guys...
if I gotta worry about...
makin' some silly-ass
10 o'clock curfew...
every fuckin' night.
We can work this out,
can't we, Eddie?
This ain't all that bad.
We can get you
a lot of legitimatejobs.
I'll get you down in
Long Beach as a dockworker.
I don't wanna lift
no fuckin' crates, Eddie.
You ain't gonna lift shit.
You don't even work there.
But as far as the records
are concerned, you do.
I call Matthews and tell him
he's got a new guy, boom...
you're on the rotation.
You get a time card.
It's clocked in and out
for you every day.
At the end of the week
you get a nice paycheck.
Dockworkers do very well.
You can move
into a halfway decent place...
without Scagnetti goin'...
"Where the fuck's the money
comin' from?"
And, if he decides
to make a surprise visit...
that's the day
we sent you to Tustin...
to pick up a load of shit.
If he comes back again...
hey, "Sorry, Seymour.
You just missed him.
We send him to the Taft
airstrip five hours away.
We had a load of shit
he had to pick up there...
and bring back here".
Part of yourjob
is goin' different places.
That's the beauty of it.
We got places
all over the place.
See, Vic? Did I tell you
not to worry?
Vic was worried.
I'll take you
to Long Beach tomorrow.
We'll get you fixed up
with Matthews...
I'll tell him what's what.
You know,
I really appreciate...
what you guys are doin'...
but I'd like to know
when I can come back...
you know,
do some real work.
Well, it's hard to say.
It's kind of
a strange time now.
Things are kind of...
They're a little fucked up,
is what they are.
We'rejust gettin' ready...
for a big meetin'
right now in Vegas.
Look, just let Eddie for now
set you up at Long Beach.
Get you ajob...
give you some cash...
and get this Scagnetti
fuck off your back...
and then we'll talk to you,
all right?
Huh?
Dad, I got an idea.
Just hear me out.
I know you don't like usin'
the boys on thesejobs...
but Vic here, I mean...
he's only been nothin'
but good luck for us.
The guy's
a fuckin' rabbit's foot...
for cryin' out loud.
I'd like to have him in.
You know
he can handle himself...
and you damn sure know
you can trust him.
All right, Vic...
how would you feel about
pullin' ajob...
with about five other guys?
I'd feel great about it.
K- BILL Y's "Super Sounds
of the '70s"continues.
If you're the 12th caller...
you'll win
two tickets...
to the monster
truck extravaganza...
being held tonight
at the Carson Fairgrounds...
featuring Big Daddy Don
Bodine's truck...
"The Behemoth."
The 12th caller wins
on the station...
where the '70s survived.
Hey, Dov, we got
a major situation here.
I know you know that.
I gotta talk to Daddy...
and find out
what he wants done.
All I know
is what Vic told me.
The place turned
into a bullet-fest.
He took a cop hostage
just to get outta there.
Get up! Get up!
Do I sound like
I'm fuckin' jokin'?
He's fuckin' drivin' around
with a cop in his trunk!
I don't know who did what!
I don't know
who's got the loot.
if anybody's got the loot.
I don't know who's dead...
who's alive,
who's caught, who's not.
I will know.
I'm practically there now.
But what do I tell
these guys about Daddy?
All right.
You sure
that's what he said?
Okay, that's what
I'll tell 'em.
Huh? Fuck you!
You like bein'
a fuckin' hero?
You're gonna suffer
for nothin', pal.
You hear me? 'Cause you're
gonna fuckin' talk.
- I don't know anything!
- You fuckin' know.
You know. Look at me.
You fuckin' know.
What in the Sam Hill's
goin' on here?
- Nice Guy, we got a cop.
- Where the fuck is Joe?
Holy shit. Orange is dead.
No, he's not dead...
but he will be if we don't
get him taken care of.
We were set up.
The cops were there
waitin' for us.
What? Nobody fuckin'
set anybody up.
The cops were there
waitin' for us.
- Bullshit.
- Fuck you, man!
You weren't there,
we were, and the cops had...
that store staked out.
Okay, Mr. Fuckin' Detective,
you're so fuckin' smart.
- Who did it?
- We've been askin' each other!
What'd you come up with?
You think
I fuckin' set you up?
I don't know,
but somebody did.
Nobody did.
You fuckin' assholes
turned thejewelry store...
Don't you call me
an asshole!
You fuckin' idiot!
Turned thejewelry store
into a wild west show...
and you wonder why
the fuckin' cops show up?
Where's Joseph?
I don't know.
I ain't talked to him.
I talked to Dov.
He says
Daddy's comin' down here...
and he's fuckin' pissed.
He's pissed?
I told you he'd be pissed.
What'd Joe say?
I told you,
I ain't talked to him!
All I know is he's pissed.
What are you gonna do
about him?
Give me a fuckin' chance
to breathe.
I got a few questions
of my own here.
You ain't dying. He is.
All right,
Mr. Fuckin' Compassion...
- I will call somebody-Who?
A fuckin' snake charmer!
Who do you think?
I'll call a doctor.
They'll fix him right up.
What happened
to Brown and Blue?
Brown's dead.
We don't know
what happened to Blue.
Brown's dead?
Are you sure?
I'm sure. I was there.
He took one in the head.
Nobody's got a clue
what happened to Mr. Blue?
Either he's alive
or he's dead...
or the cops got him
or they don't.
I take it, this is the
bastard you told me about.
Why are you beatin'
on him?
Maybe he could tell us
who set us up.
You beat
this prick long enough...
he'll tell you
he started the Chicago Fire.
Now that don't necessarily
make it fuckin' so!
Come on, man, think!
All right...
first things fuckin' last.
Who's got the stones?
Please, somebody tell me
one little fuckin' favor.
I got a bag.
Okay? I stashed it
'til we could be sure...
this place wasn't
a police station.
Good for you.
Now let's go get it.
First we gotta get
rid of those cars.
It looks like
Sam's Hot Car Lot outside.
Okay.
Blondie...
stay here
and baby-sit them two.
White and Pink,
take a car each.
I'll follow you, you ditch
'em. Pick up the stones.
While I'm followin' you...
I'll arrange some sort
of a doctor for our friend.
You can't leave these guys
here with him.
Why not?
Because
he's a fuckin' psycho.
And if you think
Joe's pissed off...
that ain't nothin' compared...
to how pissed off
I am at him...
for puttin' me in the same
room as that bastard.
You see what I've been
puttin' up with, Eddie?
I fuckin' walked in here...
I told these guys
about stayin' put.
Mr. White whips out his gun...
he's stickin' it
in my face...
callin' me a mother-fucker...
sayin' he's gonna
blow me away...
and blah, blah, blah,
blah, blah.
He's the reason...
thejoint turned
into a shootin' spree.
What are you,
a fuckin' silent partner?
Tell him!
He went crazy in the store,
but he seems all right now.
This is what he was doin':
Bam, bam...
bam, bam.
Yeah, bam, bam,
bam, bam, bam.
I told 'em not to touch
the fuckin' alarm, they did.
If they hadn't have done
what I told 'em not to do...
they'd still be alive.
My fuckin' hero.
www.moviesubtitles.org