- Miss Webber.
- Just for two minutes.
No.
Go, it's my camera.
You musician, maybe?
You artist, huh?
Painter?
I know. You model.
- Model, huh?
- Thank you.
It's perfect.
You're nice without long hair.
Now it's cool, huh? Cool.
It's just what I wanted.
Now, why don't you
come dancing tonight with me?
You should see, it's so nice.
It's on a boat, on the Tiber,
the river, by Sant'Angelo.
Moonlight, music, romantic.
It's very, very...
- Please, you come?
- I wish I could.
But your friends,
I don't think they'll recognise you.
No, I don't think they will.
- Thank you very much.
- Thank you.
After nine I'll be there, dancing on
the river. Remember Sant'Angelo.
All my friends... If you come,
you will be most pretty of all girls.
Thank you.
- Goodbye.
A thousand lire.
- No money.
- No?
I'm sorry, I've really no money.
Look.
I'm sorry.
- Well, it's you!
- Yes, Mr Bradley.
Or is it?
- Do you like it?
- Very much.
So that was your
mysterious appointment.
- I have a confession to make.
- A confession?
Yes, I ran away
last night... from school.
Why?
- Trouble with the teacher?
- No, nothing like that.
You wouldn't run away for nothing.
It was only meant to be
for a few hours.
They gave me something
last night to make me sleep.
Oh, I see.
- I'd better get a taxi and go back.
- Look, before you do,
why not take a little time for yourself?
Maybe another hour.
Live dangerously, take the whole day.
I could do some things
I've always wanted to.
Like what?
You can't imagine. I'd like to do
whatever I liked, the whole day long.
Like having your hair cut
and eating gelati?
Yes, and I'd like to
sit at a sidewalk café,
look in shop windows,
walk in the rain.
Have fun, and maybe
some excitement.
It doesn't seem much to you,
does it?
It's great.
Tell you what. Why don't we
do all those things... together?
- Don't you have to work?
- No. Today will be a holiday.
You don't want to do
a lot of silly things.
Don't I? First wish, one sidewalk café.
Coming right up.
I know just the place.
What will they say in school
about your hair?
They'll have a fit.
What would they say if they knew
I'd slept in your room?
Tell you what, you don't tell your folks
and I won't tell mine.
It's a pact.
- Now, what would you like to drink?
- Champagne, please.
Champagne?
Well, champagne,
and cold coffee for me.
Must be quite a school,
champagne for lunch.
- Only on special occasions.
- For instance?
The last time
was my father's anniversary.
- Wedding?
- No.
The fortieth anniversary
of... the day he got his job.
Forty years on the job.
What do you know about that?
What does he do?
Well, mostly you might
call it public relations.
Oh, well that's hard work.
- I wouldn't care for it.
- Does he?
I've heard him complain about it.
Why doesn't he quit?
People in that line of work
almost never do quit,
unless it's actually unhealthy
for them to continue.
Well, here's to his health then.
You know, that's what
everybody says.
- It's all right?
- Yes, thank you.
What is your work?
Oh, I'm in the selling game.
Really? How interesting.
What do you sell?
Fertiliser. Chemicals, stuff like that.
- Irving! Am I glad to see you!
- Why, did you forget your wallet?
- Sit down.
- Aren't you going to introduce me?
Yes. This is a very good friend of
mine, Irving Radovich. Anya, Irving.
- Anya...?
- Smith.
- Oh. Hiya, Smitty.
- Charmed.
Hey, did anybody ever tell you
you're a dead ringer for...
- Well, I guess I'll be going.
- No, don't do that, join us.
Well, just till Francesca gets here.
Tell me Mr Radovich,
what is a ringer?
- Oh, waiter!
- It's an American term.
It means anyone who has
a great deal of charm.
Oh, thank you.
You're welcome.
Cousins.
Mr Bradley's just been telling me
all about his work.
- I'd like to have heard that.
- What do you do?
I'm in the same racket as Joe,
only I'm a...
I'm awfully sorry, Irving.
- What are you...?
- I'm sorry.
I can take a hint. I'll see you around.
- But your drink's just here.
- Yeah, Irving, take it easy.
I'm sorry about that.
Sit down, that's a good fellow.
That's the boy.
You're... You're twisting
my arm, you know.
Just be a little more careful not to spill.
- Spill? Who's been spilling?
- You.
- Me?
- Yeah.
Where did you find this loony?
You're OK. Here's to you, huh?
Here's hoping for the best.
If it wasn't for that hair,
I'd swear that you...
Thanks.
You slipped, you almost hurt yourself.
- I slipped?
- Yes, you did.
- I didn't slip.
- A bad sprain...
- Never mind!
- You'd better get it fixed up.
- Would you excuse us?
- Of course, I'm so sorry.
Joe, what are you trying to do?
Take your hands off me.
- Got your lighter?
- What?
- Have you?
- Yeah.
Listen, what would you do
for five grand?
- Five grand?
- Look...
She doesn't know who I am.
This is my story, I gotta protect it.
She's really the...
Your pictures
will make this twice as valuable.
- The princess goes slumming.
- You're in for 25°%.
- Of 5,000?
- Minimum, Hennessy shook on it.
- That's $1,500!
- It's $1,250.
- Now you shake.
- OK, now lend me 30,000.
That's $50! Are you gonna buy
the crown jewels?
She's drinking champagne.
We gotta entertain her.
We can't go running around
with a hot princess!
Do you want in
on this deal or don't you?
- This I want back Saturday.
- OK. Now where's your lighter?
Let's go to work.
- Better now?
- Huh?
- Your ear.
- My ear?
Oh, yeah, Joe fixed it.
- Would you like a cigarette?
- Yes, please.
You won't believe it,
but it's my very first.
Your very first?
- No smoking in school?
- Your first cigarette.
There, the gismo works.
Well, what's the verdict, OK?
- Nothing to it.
- That's right, nothing to it.
I'll stretch my legs a little.
- I'll pick this one up, Irving.
- You can afford it.
What next?
Shall we make a little schedule?
Oh, not that word, please.
I didn't mean a work schedule...
a school schedule,
- I meant a fun schedule.
- Let's just go, huh?
How about you, Irving, are you ready?
- Yeah.
- Let's go.
Francesca. Oh, this is...
- Smitty.
- She's a grand girl, Irving.
Five grand.
- Joe.
- Where are you going now?
Honey, I gotta work.
I'll call you tonight.
Look at those men! They were
supposed to be inconspicuous.
You asked for plain clothes.
Hey, stop, come back.
I'm going straight from now on.
News Service? What did he mean?
Oh, you say you're with the press
and you can get away with anything.
Going to church to get married
on a scooter! Joe's a wonderful liar.
Congratulations!
Don't look so worried,
I won't hold you to it.
Thank you very much.
Don't be too grateful.
OK, I won't.
I'm a good liar too, aren't I?
- The best I ever met.
- Thank you very much.
Say... Come with me.
The Mouth of Truth.
The legend is, if you're a liar
and you put your hand in there,
it'll be bitten off.
- What a horrid idea.
- Let's see you do it.
Let's see you do it.
Sure.
Hello!
- You beast, you're all right!
- I'm sorry. It was just a joke.
- You never hurt your hand.
- I'm sorry.
- OK?
- Yes.
All right, let's go. Look out!
I'll park at the corner.
What do they mean,
all these inscriptions?
Each one represents a wish fulfilled.
It started during the war, in an air raid.
A man with his four children
was caught in the street.
He ran to that wall for shelter
and prayed.
Bombs fell very close
but no one was hurt.
Later, he came back
and put up the first tablet.
Now it's a sort of shrine.
People come,
and when their wishes are granted,
they put up another plaque.
Lovely story.
Read some of the inscriptions.
Make a wish? Tell the doctor?
Anyway, the chances of it
being granted are very slight.
Well, what now?
- I've heard you can dance on a boat.
- You mean Sant'Angelo.
- Couldn't we go tonight?
- Why not?
Anything you wish.
At midnight I'll turn into a pumpkin
and drive away in my glass slipper.
That'll be the end of the fairytale.
- I guess Irving has to go now.
- I do?
Yes, you know, that big business
development you have to attend to?
- That development.
- Can't afford not to.
Yeah. See you later, Smitty.
- Good luck with the big development.
- Thanks.
Hello.
Mr Bradley, if you don't mind my
saying so, I think you're a ringer.
A what? Oh, thanks very much.
You've spent the whole day doing
things I've always wanted to. Why?
It seemed the thing to do.
I've never heard of anybody so kind.
It wasn't any trouble.
Or so completely unselfish.
Let's have a drink at the bar.
There you are.
I look for you a long time.
I think maybe you not come.
- Off, all off!
- It's nice without, isn't it? Cool.
- Oh, very good.
- This is Mr Bradley.
I Mario Delani.
- Old friends?
- Yes, he cut my hair.
He invited me here tonight.
- What was your name?
- Mario Delani.
Mario Delani.
I'm very glad to know you.
Me too.
Oh, may I enjoy myself the pleasure?
- You mind?
- Go right ahead.
I thank you.
- Did I miss anything?
- You're just in time.
- Who's Smitty dancing with?
- Her barber.
He cut her hair this afternoon,
made a date for tonight.
The princess and the barber?
- What is it?
- Momento.
August!
Thank you.
Bye.
Your Highness.
Dance quietly towards the entrance.
A car is waiting.
- No.
- Your Highness!
You've made a mistake. Let me go!
Will you let me go? Mr Bradley!
Let me go, will you! Mr Bradley!
Hit him again, Smitty!
- Here are my car keys.
- Police!
The other side of the bridge.
- All right?
- Fine, you?
Oh, fine.
You were great back there.
You weren't so bad yourself.
I...
I guess we'd better get out of here.
This is the American Hour,
continuing our programme
of musical selections.
- Everything ruined?
- No. They'll be dry in a minute.
Suits you. You should
always wear my clothes.
Seems I do.
I thought a little wine might be good.
- Shall I cook something?
- No kitchen.
- I always eat out.
- Do you like that?
Well, life isn't always what one likes.
- Is it?
- No, it isn't.
- Tired?
- A little.
- You've had quite a day.
- A wonderful day.
This is the American Hour
with a special news bulletin.
There is no further word
from the bedside of Princess Ann,
who was taken ill yesterday
on the last leg of her European tour.
Rumours suggest
her condition may be serious,
causing alarm and anxiety
among the people in her country.
- The news can wait.
- Yes.
May I have a little more wine?
I'm sorry I couldn't
cook us some dinner.
Did you learn how in school?
I'm a good cook.
I could earn my living at it.
I can sew too, clean a house, iron.
I learned to do all those things,
I just haven't had the chance
to do it for anyone.
Well, looks like I'll have to move
and get a place with a kitchen.
Yes.
I shall have to go now.
Anya...
...there's something I want to tell you.
No, please.
Nothing.
I must go and get dressed.
Stop at the next corner, please.
OK.
- Here?
- Yes.
I have to leave you now.
I'm going to that
corner there and turning.
You stay in the car and drive away.
Promise not to watch me
go beyond the corner.
Just drive away and leave me.
As I leave you.
All right.
I don't know how to say goodbye.
I can't think of any words.
Don't try.
Your Royal Highness,
twenty-four hours,
they can't all be blank.
They are not.
What explanation am I
to offer Their Majesties?
I was indisposed. I am better.
Ma'am, you must appreciate
that I have my duty to perform,
just as Your Royal
Highness has her duty.
Your Excellency,
I trust you will not find it necessary
to use that word again.
Were I not completely aware of
my duty to my family and my country,
I would not have come back tonight.
Or indeed, ever again.
And now, since I understand
we have a very full schedule today,
you have my permission to withdraw.
No milk and crackers.
That will be all thank you, Countess.
- Did you really get it?
- What?
The princess exclusive.
Did you get it?
- No, I didn't.
- What? That's impossible.
- Coffee?
- Don't hold out on me.
- Who's holding out?
- You are. I know too much.
First you ask about an exclusive
on the princess, next you disappear.
Then I hear a rumour from the
embassy that she's out on the town.
Do you believe every rumour
that comes your way?
There's a lot of other rumours.
About a shindig down by the river,
and the arrest of eight secret
service men from a certain country.
Then she makes
a miraculous recovery. It all adds up.
Don't think you'll raise the price,
a deal's a deal. Now come on.
- Where is that story?
- I have no story.
- Now what was the idea...
- Joe.
- Wait till you see these.
- Irving.
Hi, Mr Hennessy.
Irving!
- What's the idea?
- You charge in, spilling things!
- Me?
- I warned you before.
- Remember?
- Look at my pants.
- Come and dry them off.
- Nuts to that.
- Did you tell him about Smitty?
- Who?
- Wait till you...
- Irving!
There you go again, Irving.
- Joe...
- Save that till later.
- Why don't you go home and shave?
- Shave?
Or else keep quiet
till we're finished talking.
What kind of routine is that?
What are you up to? Who's Smitty?
- A guy we met.
- What is there to look at?
Just some of Irving's dames.
You wouldn't like them.
- Maybe you would.
- Don't change the subject.
- Yesterday you said...
- I had a good lead.
But I was wrong, that's all
there is to it. There is no story.
OK.
She's holding the press interview
today. Maybe you can get that story.
And you owe me $500.
- Take it from my salary, $50 a week.
- Don't think I won't.
What gives?
Have we had a better offer?
Irving...
I don't know just how
to tell you this, but...
Wait till I sit down.
Well, in regard to the story
that goes with these,
there is no story.
Why not?
I mean, not as far as I'm concerned.
The pictures came out pretty well.
Want to have a look at them?
How about a blow-up
from a negative that size?
- Her first cigarette!
- Yeah.
The Mouth of Truth.
I had a caption in mind:
"Barber cuts in. "
Here's the key shot
for the whole layout.
"The Wall Where
Wishes Come True. "
Joe, that's good.
Lead off with that,
then follow up with the wishes?
I got that from the file.
"Princess Inspects Police. "
Yeah...
"Police Inspects Princess. "
- How about that?
- Pretty good.
I got a topper for you.
- Wow!
- Is that a shot?
- What a picture!
"Bodyguard Gets Body Blow. "
No, how about this?
"Crowned Head?" Huh?
Oh, I get it. Joe, you got...
She's fair game, Joe.
It's always open season
on princesses.
- You must be out of your mind.
- I know, but...
Look, I can't prevent you from
selling the pictures, if you want to.
- You'll get a good price for them.
- Yeah.
- Are you going to the interview?
- Are you?
Yeah. It's an assignment, isn't it?
Yeah.
I'll see you.
It ain't much, but it's home.
Ladies and gentlemen,
please approach.
Her Royal Highness.
Your Royal Highness,
the ladies and gentlemen
of the press.
Ladies and gentlemen,
Her Royal Highness
will now answer your questions.
I believe at the outset,
Your Highness,
that I should express
the pleasure of all of us,
at your recovery
from the recent illness.
Thank you.
Does Your Highness believe
that federation could be a solution
to Europe's economic problems?
I am in favour of any measure
which would lead
to closer cooperation in Europe.
And what, in the opinion
of Your Highness,
is the outlook for
friendship among nations?
I have every faith in it...
...as I have faith
in relations between people.
May I say, speaking for
my own press service...
...we believe that Your Highness's
faith will not be unjustified.
I am so glad to hear you say it.
Which of the cities visited
did Your Highness enjoy the most?
Each in its own way
was unforgettable.
It would be difficult to...
Rome! By all means, Rome.
I will cherish my visit here
in memory, as long as I live.
Despite your indisposition,
Your Highness?
Despite that.
Photographs may now be taken.
Thank you, ladies and gentlemen.
Thank you very much.
I would now like to meet some of
the ladies and gentlemen of the press.
Hitchcock, "Chicago Daily News".
- I'm so happy to see you here.
- Thank you.
Scanziani, "La Suisse".
Klinger, Deutsche Presse Agentur.
Maurice Montabré, "Le Figaro".
Sytske Galema,
"De Linie", Amsterdam.
Jacques Ferrier, "Ici Paris".
Gross, "Davar Tel Aviv".
Cortes Cavanillas, "ABC Madrid".
Lampe, "New York Herald Tribune".
- Good afternoon.
Irving Radovich, CR Photo Service.
How do you do?
May I present Your Highness
with some commemorative photos
of your visit to Rome?
Thank you so very much.
Joe Bradley, American News Service.
So happy, Mr Bradley.
Moriones, "La Vanguardia", Barcelona.
Stephen House, of the
"London Exchange Telegraph".
Good afternoon.
De Aldisio, Agence Press.