Name.
Good evening-
Welcome to
Who Wants to Be a Millionaire?
Are you
ready?
-  Please give
a big round of applause-
-  Good luck, kid.
to our very first
contestant of the night...
Jamal Malik, from our very own...
amchi Mumbai!
Chalo, let's play.
Smile. You'll be fine.
Name.
- Name.
- Jamal... Malik.
You have a name. Good.
Stop crying.
Thank you. Thank you.
Thank you very much.
So, Jamal...
tell me something about yourself.
I work in a call center.
In Juhu.
Good.
A phone basher.
And what type of call center
would that be?
XL 5 mobile phones.
Oh. So you're the one who calls
me up every single day of my
life with special offers, huh?
No. Actually, I'm an assistant.
An assistant phone basher?
And what does a assistant
phone basher do exactly?
I get tea for people and-
Chai wallah.
A chai wallah!
Well, ladies and gentlemen...
Jamal Malik-
...from Mumbai, let's play
Who Wants to Be a Millionaire?
So, has he confessed yet?
Except his name, I could not get
anything out of the runt.
You have been here a whole bloody night,
Srinivas. What have you been doing?
He's a tough guy.
A little electricity will loosen his tongue.
Give him.
Yes, sir.
Okay. So, were you wired up?
Mobile or a pager?
A coughing accomplice
in the audience...
or a microchip under the skin?
Huh?
- The chip is not here.
- Not here?
- No.
- Okay. Leave the chip.
Leave the chip. Leave the chip.
It's hot...
and my wife is giving me hell...
and I've got a desk full of
murderers, rapists...
extortionists, bum bandits and you.
So why don't you save us
both a lot of time...
and tell me how you cheated.
Hmm.
I'm done, sir.
Now, listen.
Hello.
He's unconscious, Juti.
What good is that?
How many times
have I told you, Srinivas?
I'm sorry, sir.
Srinivas. Now we'll have...
Amnesty International here next,
peeing in their pants about human rights.
Sir, I was thinking, um-
- Get him down, tidy him up,
please, for God's sake!
- Sir...
what if he did know the answers?
Professors, doctors, lawyers,
general knowledge wallahs...
never get beyond 16,000 rupees.
He's on 10 million.
What the hell can a...
slumdog possibly know?
The answers.
I knew the answers.
# They can't touch me
We break off, run so fast
they can't even catch me #
# Been that gypsy
Touch me, I show you tricks
with my sticks that quickly #
# Pick up their packs
on my journey #
# Dogs run
They start to follow me
I have my luck #
# Some days they suck
when we live for the buck
we get for the family #
# One day I wanna be a star
so I get to hang in a bar#
# I'll go to Vegas if they pay us
just to forget my scars #
Sorry.
Sorry. Sorry.
Sorry!
# They can't touch me
We break off#
- # Run so fast
they can't even catch me #
# Been that gypsy Touch me #
# I show you tricks
with my sticks that quickly ##
-  Athos!
-  Cried the two musketeers.
-  Musketeers.
-  Athos!
Repeat it.
"You have sent for me, sir,"said Athos.
- "You have sent for me, sir."
- Ah.
Huh?
So...
Mr. Malik...
the man who knows all the answers.
Talk.
So, Jamal...
are you ready for the first question
for 1,000 rupees?
Yes.
Not bad money to sit on a chair
and answer a question.
Better than making tea, no?
No. Yes. No.
No? Yes? No?
Is that your final answer?
So, remember, you have
three lifelines.
Ask the audience, fifty-fifty...
phone a friend.
So the first question for 1,000 rupees.
Here we go.
Who was the star in
the 1973 hit film Zanjeer?
Amitabh?
Amitabh Bachchan!
Salim!
Amitabh!
Yea!
Amitabh-
"A."Amitabh Bachchan.
Guess what. You're right.
You just won 1,000 rupees.
You don't have to be a genius.
I knew it was Amitabh Bachchan.
- Hmm?
- Mmm.
Like I said, don't have to be
a genius.
He's the most famous man in India.
A picture of three lions...
is seen in the national
emblem of India.
What is written underneath?
"A," the truth alone triumphs...
"B," lies alone triumph...
"C,"fashion alone triumphs...
"D," money alone triumphs?
What do you think, Jamal?
The most famous phrase
of our country.
Would you like to phone a friend?
Ask the audience.
Put the poor man out of his misery,
ladies and gentlemen.
My five-year-old daughter can answer
that question, but you couldn't.
That's strange for
a millionaire genius.
What happened?
Your accomplice nip out for a piss?
The inspector is asking something.
How much is pani puri
at Harish's stall on Chowpatty?
What?
Pani puri. One plate, how much?
- Ten rupees.
- Wrong.
Fifteen since Divali.
Who stole
Constable Vermaas's bicycle...
outside Santa Cruz
station last Thursday?
You know who that was?
Everyone in Juhu knows that.
Even five-year-olds.
Congratulations, Jamal.
You just won 4,000 rupees.
For 16,000 rupees.
Religion.
Interesting.
In depictions of God Rama...
he is famously holding what
in his right hand?
Hey, Jamal.
Jamal-
I wake up every morning wishing I didn't
know the answer to that question.
If it wasn't for Rama and Allah...
I would still have a mother.
A bow and arrow.
Final answer?
Final answer.
Hmm. Ah. Computer-ji,
"D"lock kiya-jaye.
You've just won 16,000 rupees.
Well done, my friend.
Time for a commercial break.
Don't go away now.
You got lucky, huh?
If I were you,
I would take the money and run.
You're not gonna get the next one.
Everybody back in 90, please.
Okay?
Can you come and do
the controls, please?
Salim.
Welcome back to Who Wants
to Be a Millionaire?
Our contestant, Jamal Malik,
call center assistant from Mumbai...
is on 16,000 rupees
and has already used one lifeline-
ask the audience.
So, my friend,
you're into serious money.
Yes.
The song "Darshan do Ghanshyam" was
written by which famous Indian poet?
"A,"Surdas, "B," Tulsidas...
"C,"Mira Bai...
"D,"Kabir?
Hello.
It's hot, huh?
Yea!
Arvind.
# Darshan do Ghanshyam #
Salim.
#Darshan do Ghanshyam #
Huh?
Hey.
# Darshan do Ghanshyam #
Salim.
Huh?
Jamal.
Punnoose.
# Darshan do #
#Darshan do Ghanshyam #
# Darshan do Ghanshyam ##
Salim!
Jamal!
Latika.
Latika!
Salim!
Surdas.
Surdas?
Surdas...
apka final answer?
Yes.
Guess what.
You're right!
What happened to the girl?
They blinded her too?
They had other plans.
It took me a long time to find out.
# I fly like paper
get high like planes #
# If you catch me at the border#
- # I got visas in my name
If you come around here #
# I make 'em all day
I get one done
in a second if you wait #
# I fly like paper
get high like planes #
# If you catch me at the border
I've got visas in my name #
# If you come around here
I make 'em all day #
- # I get one done
in a second if you wait #
- Bye! Bye!
# Sometimes I think
sittin' on trains #
# Every stop I get to
I'm clockin' that game #
- # Everyone's a winner
We're makin' our fame #
# Bona fide hustler
I'm makin' my name #
# Sometimes I think sittin' on trains #
- # Every stop I get to
I'm clockin' that game #
- Yea!
# Everyone's a winner
We're makin' our fame #
- # Bona fide hustler
I'm makin' my name #
Hey.
# Pirate skulls and bones #
# Sticks and stones
and weed and bombs #
# Running when we hit 'em #
# Lethal poison
through their system #
# Pirate skulls and bones #
# Sticks and stones
and weed and bombs #
# Running when we hit 'em #
# Lethal poison
through their system #
# No one on the corner
has swagger like us #
# Hit me on my banner
prepaid wireless #
# We pack and deliver
like U.P.S. trucks #
# Already going hell
just pumping that gas #
# No one on the corner
has swagger like us ##
Salim! Salim!
Is this heaven?
You're not dead, Jamal.
What is it?
Some hotel, huh?
The Taj Mahal is considered the finest
example of Mogul architecture.
... who died on June 17, 1631-
during the birth
of their 14th child.
The Taj Mahal was completed around, uh,
1648, using a labor force of 20,000 workers-
In 1980 it became a UNESCO
World Heritage Site and was cited as the-
If you would like to follow me...
I will show you 99 names of Allah
on Mumtaz's tomb.
Please take off your shoes.
Please. Please.
What time is the next tour?
We are on a very tight
schedule, you see.
Have to see the Red Fort
this afternoon.
- No, I-
- Please, would it be possible...
to show us around now?
Obviously we understand
that it costs more for just the two of us.
But of course, madam.
Please follow me.
The Taj Mahal was built
by Emperor Khurram...
for his wife Mumtaz.
Was the maximum beautiful
woman in the world.
So, when she died, the emperor decided
to build this...
five-star hotel...
for everyone
who'd like to visit her too.
But he died in 1587...
before any of the rooms
were built or any of the lifts.
But the swimming pool,
as you can see...
was completed on schedule,
in top-class fashion.
There's nothing of this
in the guidebook.
The guidebook was written by a bunch of
lazy, good-for-nothing Indian beggars.
Oh.
And this, lady and gentleman,
is the burial place of Mumtaz.
How did she die?
- A road traffic accident.
- Really?
Maximum pileup.
I thought she died in childbirth.
Exactly, sir. She was on the way
to hospital when it happened.
Ready?
Don't move an inch.
Smile.
Unbreakable Thailand wood.
You take. Shoes!
American brands! Shoes!
# All I wanna do
And a-#
# Then take your money
'Cause all I wanna do #
# And a-
Then take your money #
# All I wanna do
And a-#
# Then take your money #
# And a-#
- # All I wanna do #
- Smile!
# And a-
And take your money #
# All I wanna do
And a-#
# Then take your money #
This, Mr. David, is the biggest dhobi ghat
in the whole of India.
That's amazing.
Come on.
Take a real good look at this.
They say that every man
in Uttar Pradesh...
is wearing a kurta that has been
at least washed once out here.
Formula One! Formula One!
Pit stop ka speed!
Schumacher ka style!
The-The cows, the-the buffaloes.
What are those over there?