Part Two
STALKER
Where are you?
Come here!
Are you tired?
Oh, God!
Judging by his tone, he's going to
start sermonizing again.
Let everything that's been planned
come true.
Let them believe.
And let them have a laugh
at their passions.
Because what they call passion
actually is not some emotional energy,
but just the friction between
their souls and the outside world.
And most important,
let them believe in themselves
let them be helpless like children,
because weakness is a great thing,
and strength is nothing.
When a man is just born,
he is weak and flexible,
when he dies,
he is hard and insensitive.
When a tree is growing,
it's tender and pliant,
but when it's dry and hard,
it dies.
Hardness and strength
are death's companions.
Pliancy and weakness are
expressions of the freshness of being.
Because what has hardened
will never win.
Come here!
We're progressing well.
Soon we'll come to a dry tunnel,
after that it will get easier.
Knock on wood.
- Are we on our way already?
- Of course. Why?
l thoughtyou just wanted
to show us something.
- What about my knapsack?
- What about it?
l left it there.
l didn't know we were going.
- There's nothing we can do about it.
- No, we have to go back.
- lt's impossible!
- l can't do without my knapsack!
Can'tyou understand that no one here
has ever come back the same way?
Forget aboutyour knapsack.
What have you got there, diamonds?
The room will give you
anything you want.
Really. lt will drown you
in knapsacks.
Howfar is it, this room?
lf you go straight, about 200 meters,
but there's no going straight here.
Let's go.
Give up your empiricism, Professor.
Miracles are outside empiricism.
Remember how St. Peter
was nearly drowned?
Go, Writer.
Go where?
Up these stairs.
Professor, where are you?
Here is the dry tunnel!
You call it dry?
This is a local joke.
Normally one has to swim here.
Wait, where's Professor?
- What?
- Professor has disappeared!
How could it happen?
He was following you all the way.
He probably lagged behind and
lost his way.
No, he didn't lose his way!
He must've gone for the knapsack!
He won't be able to make it now.
Shall we wait for him?
We can't. Things change here
every minute. We'll have to go.
Look! What is it? How could it be?
- l already explained.
- What did you explain?
lt's the Zone, don'tyou understand?
Let's go, quick. lt's...
There he is!
l'm certainly grateful to you
thatyou... but...
How did you get here?
Mostly l had to crawl up here
on my fours.
lncredible.
How did you manage to overtake us?
What do you mean, ''overtake''?
l came back here for the knapsack.
And how has our nut gotten here?
Oh, my God, that's...
the trap!
Porcupine put this nut here
on purpose.
How could the Zone let us through?
Oh God, l'm not going
to take one more step until...
l don't like it.
That's it! We rest!
But keep off this nut,
just in case.
Sorry, but l thought that
Professor won't be able to make it.
You see, l...
l never know beforehand what kind
of people l'm taking with me.
Everything gets clear only here,
when it's too late.
What's important is that Professor's
bag with his underwear is safe.
Don't stick your nose in someone's
underwear if you don't understand it.
What is there to understand?
Binomial theorem?
Some psychological abysses!
You have a bad reputation
atyour institute.
They don't give you money
for an expedition.
So you decide to pack a knapsack
full of manometers and other shit...
penetrate the Zone illegally...
and put all these miracles
to an algebra test.
No one in the world
has ever heard of the Zone.
So we'll work a sure sensation!
The television, fans raving
and bringing laurel wreaths.
Here our Professor appears,
all in white,
and declares:
''Mene-mene, tekel, uprasin.''
Everyone gaping
and shouting:
''He deserves a Nobel Prize!''
You lousy scribbler,
a homespun psychoanalyst.
You're only good for painting walls
in public toilets, you blabbermouth.
No good. Too sluggish.
You don't know howto do it.
All right. l'm going to get
a Nobel Prize.
And what are you after?
Want to bless mankind
with the pearls
of your purchased inspiration?
l don't care a damn about mankind.
Of all your mankind
l'm interested
only in one man - myself.
Whether l'm worth anything
or l'm just shit like others.
And if you find out
thatyou're really...
You know, Mr. Einstein,
l have no wish to argue with you.
Truth is born of argument,
damn it!
Listen, Chingachgook...
You've brought here
many people.
Not as many as l would like.
That's not the point. Why did they
come here? What did they want?
Happiness, l guess.
Yes, but what kind of happiness?
People don't like to speak about
their innermost feelings.
And it's neither yours
nor mine business.
ln any case, you've been lucky.
As for me, l haven't seen
one happy man in my life.
Me neither.
They return from the room
and l lead them back,
and we never see each other again.
lt's not that wishes come true
immediately.
Have you ever wished
to use this room yourself?
l'm fine as l am.
Listen, Professor.
Speaking of the purchased inspiration.
Let's imagine that l enter this room
and return to our God-forsaken
town a genius.
A man writes because he's tormented,
because he doubts.
He needs to constantly prove
to himself and the others
that he's worth something.
And if l knowfor sure
that l'm a genius?
Why write then?
What the hell for?
Well, l must say
that we exist for...
Will you be so kind
and leave me alone?
Let me get a wink,
l haven't slept all night.
Keep your complexes to yourself.
ln any case,
all this technology of yours...
all those blast furnaces, wheels...
and other bullshit
are only designed in order
to work less and eat more.
They are all just crutches,
artificial limbs.
And mankind exists
in order to create...
works of art.
Unlike all other human activities,
this one is unselfish.
Great illusions!
lmages of the absolute truth!
Are you listening to me, Professor?
What unselfishness are you talking
about?
People still die of hunger.
Have you fallen from the moon?
And they are considered to be
our brainy aristocracy!
You're not even capable of thinking
in abstractions.
Are you going to teach me
about the meaning of life?
And also howto think?
lt's useless. You might be
a professor, but an ignorant one.
And there was
a great earthquake.
And the sun became black
as sackcloth made of hair.
And the moon became like blood...
And the stars of the sky
fell to the earth,
as a fig tree casts
its unripe figs
when shaken by a great wind.
And the sky was split apart
like a scroll when it is rolled up.
And every mountain and island
were moved out of their places.
And the kings of the earth and
the great men
and the rich and the chiliarchs
and the strong and every free man,
hid themselves in the caves
and among the rocks of the mountains;
and they said to the mountains and
to the rocks, ''Fall on us
and hide us from the presence of
Him who sits on the throne,
and from the wrath of the Lamb,
for the great day of His wrath
has come,
and who is able to stand?''
And that very day two...
two of them...
were going to a village
which was about 60 stadia from...
named...
and they were conversing with each
other about all these things.
And while they were conversing
and discussing...
He Himself approached,
and began travelling with them.
But their eyes were prevented
from recognizing Him.
And He said to them:
''What are these words...
you are exchanging with one another,
and why are you sad?''
And one of them, named...
Are you awake?
You were speaking of the meaning...
of our... life...
of the unselfishness of art...
Take music, for instance.
Less than anything else,
it is connected to reality,
or if connected at all, it's done
mechanically, not by way of ideas,
just by a sheer sound, devoid of...
any associations.
And yet, music, as if by some miracle,
gets through to our heart.
What is it that resonates in us in
response to noise brought to harmony,
making it the source
of the greatest delight
which stuns us and brings us
together?
What's all this needed for?
And most important, who needs it?
You would say,
''No one. And for no reason.''
Unselfishly.
No.
l don't think so.
After all,
everything has some sense.
Sense and reason.
Do we have to go there?
Unfortunately, yes.
There's no other way.
lt looks morbid, don'tyou think,
Professor?
l don't feel like going there first.
And Chingachgooks
can never be volunteers.
l think we'll have to draw lots.
Do you mind?
For this, l would rather have
a volunteer.
Have you got matches?
Thanks.
The long one will go.
Pull it.
The long one.
No luck this time.
Why don'tyou throw one of your nuts
at least?
Sure. As you wish.
One more?
All right... l'll go.
Hurry up, Professor!
There's... There's a door here!
Go that way!
Open the door and go in!
Me again?
Do l have to go in first again?
You've drawn the lot.
Go! People don't wait here.
What have you got there?
No guns here!
You'll have yourself killed,
and us too!
Don'tyou remember the tanks?
Drop it, l beg you.
Don'tyou understand?
lf something happens,
l can save you, but not this way...
l beg you!
Who are you going to fire at?
Go, we haven't got much time!
There's water here!
Hold on to the handrail and go down.
But don't go anywhere!
Wait for us outside!
l hope you haven't got anything
like that?
- Like what?
- Like a gun.
No. As a last resort
l've got an ampule.
- What ampule?
- lmplanted ampule. Poison!
Oh, God! Did you come here to die?
No, it's just in case.
Writer! Come back!
Come back! You want to getyourself
killed?
l told you to wait by the exit!
Stop! Don't move!
That's all your pipe.
- Why?
- You should've gone in there first.
He was so scared that he went
the wrong way.
One more experiment.
Experiments, facts,
truth of the highest instance.
There's no such thing as facts.
Especially here.
All this is someone's
idiotic invention.
Don'tyou feel it?
Butyou, of course, must find out
whose invention it is.
And why.
What good can your knowledge do?
Who is going to get guilty conscience
because of it? Me?
l've got no conscience.
l just got nerves.
Some bastard would criticize me,
l get wounded.
Another would loud me,
l get wounded again.
l would put my heart and soul in it,
they gobble up both my heart and soul.
l would relieve my soul of filth,
they gobble it up too.
They're all so literate.
They all got sensory deficiency.
And they're all swarming around,
journalists,
editors, critics,
some endless broads.
And they all demand:
more, more!
What hell of a writer am l
if l hate writing?
lf it's constant torment for me,
a painful, shameful occupation,
sort of squeezing out a hemorrhoids.
l used to think that someone would
get better because of my books.
No, nobody needs me!
ln two days after l die they'll start
gobbling up someone else.
l wanted to change them,
but it's they who've changed me.
Making me in their own image.
The future used to be just
a continuation of the present,
with all the changes looming far
behind the horizon.
Nowthe future and the present
are one.
Are they ready for it?
They don't want to know anything!
All they know is howto gobble!
Gosh, how lucky you are!
My goodness, now...
You're going to live a hundred years!
Yes. But why not forever?
Like the eternal Jew.
You are probably a fine man.
l almost didn't doubt it.
l can imagine what torture it was
for you being in there.
This pipe is a horrible place!
The most horrible in the Zone!
lt's called ''the meat mincer'',
but it's much worse than any mincer.
So many people perished there!
Porcupine sent his brother
to die there.
The boy was so delicate,
very talented.
Here, listen to this.
So summer is gone,
Leaving no epitaph.
lt's still warm in the sun,
Only that's not enough.
All that true could have come,
Like a five-fingered fluff,
Folded into my palm,
Only that's not enough.
No evil was slighted
ln the good aftermath,
World was festively lighted,
Only that's not enough.
Life forever was tucking,
Caring, making me laugh.
l was really lucky,
Only that's not enough.
No leaves ever seared,
No limbs broken rough.
Day, like glass, washed all clear,
Only that's not enough.
Good, aren't they?
That's his verses.
Why do you fidget?
Fussing all the time?
- l'm just...
- l get sick just looking atyou!
l'm so happy! lt's not often that
everyone who goes makes it.
You did everything right.
You're good, kind, honest people.
l'm proud that l was right aboutyou.
Look at him! He's happy
that everything ended well!
Fate! Zone!
l'm a fine man, he says!
You think l didn't see how you
shoved the two long matches at me?
- No, you don't understand...
- Of course, how could l?
l'm sorry, Professor,
no offense meant,
but this jerk has chosen you
to be his favorite.
Come on, it's unfair!
And me, a second-rate creature,
he shoves into that pipe!
Meat mincer! To think of such
a word!
What right have you got to decide
who is to live and
who is to go into the meat mincer?
You've chosen ityourself!
What? One long match out of the two
long ones?
The matches are nothing.
The Zone had letyou through
earlier, under the nut,
so it became clear that only you
could go through the meat mincer.
And we just followed you.
Well, it's too much...
You can't even imagine how dangerous
it is to make a mistake here.
But someone had to be first!
Yes? No, it's not a clinic!
You see, someone has to go first!
Don't touch it!
Laboratory nine, please.
Just a minute.
- Hello?
- l hope l'm not disturbing you.
- What do you want?
- Just a few words with you.
You've hidden it. l've found it.
The old building. Bunker four.
Do you hear me?
l'm alerting the security
immediately.
You may do it.
You may inform on me,
you may set my colleagues against me,
but it's too late.
l'm now at a stone's throw
from that place.
Do you realize that's the end of you
as a scientist?
Well, you may rejoice!
Do you realize what will happen
if you dare?
Trying to scare me again?
All my life l've been afraid of
something. Even of you.
But now l'm not afraid of anything,
l assure you.
Oh God, you are not even
a Herostratos.
lt's just thatyou've always wanted
to make my life unbearable
because twenty years ago
l slept with your wife.
And now you're delighted
thatyou've made even with me.
Well, go and do your...
vile thing.
Don'tyou dare hang up on me!
Prison is not the worst thing
expecting you.
The worst is thatyou'll never be
able to forgive yourself for this.
l already see you hanging from your
suspenders in your prison cell.
What are you up to, Professor?
Do you realize what will happen
when everybody believes in the room?
And all come rushing here?
lt's only a question of time.
lf not today, then tomorrow!
And not just tens of them, thousands!
Unfulfilled emperors,
great inquisitors, fuhrers,
self-appointed benefactors
of the human race!
And they'll come not for money or
inspiration, but to change the world!
l never take here people like that.
You think l don't understand it?
What on earth can you understand?
You're not the only stalker
on Earth.
No stalker can know
what those you lead bring with them
and what they take from here.
And the number of unmotivated
crimes is on the rise!
lsn't thatyour doing?
Take coups d'etat by the military,
or the mafia penetrating governments,
aren't they all your clients?
Or lasers and all those
super-bacteria,
all that filth, kept for the time being
in safes?
Will you please stop this
sociological diarrhea?
Can you really believe
in all those fairy tales?
Not in the good ones, no!
But in the bad ones, certainly!
Come on!
A human being is not capable
of such hatred or love...
that would extend over
the whole of mankind.
Well, money, a woman,
maybe a desire for revenge,
let my boss be overrun by a car,
that l can understand.
But ruling over the world!
A just society!
God's kingdom on earth!
These are not just wishes,
this is ideology, action, concepts.
Unconscious compassion
is not ready for realization yet.
As a regular
instinctive impulse.
There cannot be happiness
at someone else's expense.
l can see quite clearly now
thatyou plan to overwhelm
mankind with good deeds.
As for me, l'm not a bit worried
aboutyou or myself,
and least of all about mankind.
Because you're not going
to achieve anything.
At bestyou'll getyour Nobel Prize.
Or rather you'll get something
absolutely incongruous,
something you don't even think about.
Something like this telephone...
You dream of one thing,
butyou get quite another.
Why did you do that?
Telephone... electricity...
Look, very good sleeping pills.
They don't make ones like that any
longer. Why so many of them here?
Maybe we'd better be going?
lt will be dark soon,
difficult to come back.
By the way, it's absolutely clear
to me
that all this poem reciting
and making detours
is just a form of apologizing.
l can understand you.
Difficult childhood, bad environment...
But don't have any illusions,
l'm not going to forgive you.
Will you please stop it,
do me a favor.
Professor, come here, please.
Wait a minute.
Don't be in a hurry.
l'm in no hurry whatsoever.
l know, you're going to get mad.
Anyway, l must tell you...
We are now...
on the threshold...
This is the most important moment
in your life.
You must knowthat...
Your innermost wishes
will be made real here.
Your most sincere wish!
Born of suffering!
No need to say anything.
You just have to...
concentrate
and try to recall your whole life.
When a man thinks of the past,
he becomes kinder.
And most important...
Most important...
You have to believe!
Now you can go.
Who wants to be the first?
Maybe, you?
Me? No, l don't want to.
l understand, it's not easy,
but it will pass.
l doubt...
that it will pass.
lf l begin recalling my life,
it's very unlikely l'll get any kinder.
Besides, don'tyou feel
how shameful the whole thing is?
Humiliating yourself,
sniveling, praying?
What's so bad in praying?
lt's justyour pride speaking.
Calm down, you're not ready yet.
lt happens quite often.
Maybe, you first?
Yes, me.
We see before us
Professor's new invention!
An appliance exploring human souls!
Soulmeter!
lt's only a bomb.
What?
You must be kidding.
No, it's just a bomb.
Twenty kilotons.
What for?
We had it assembled with my friends.
With my former colleagues.
This place will never bring any
happiness to anyone.
But if this thing gets into the wrong
hands...
Though, l'm not sure any more.
We came to the conclusion then...
that we shouldn't destroy the Zone
after all.
Even if it's some miracle,
it's still part of nature,
and therefore, a hope in a sense.
They had hidden that bomb,
and l've found it.
The old building, bunker four.
l guess there must be a principle...
Never do anything
that can't be undone.
l understand everything, l'm not some
maniac.
But as long as this plague lies
in the open, accessible to any scum,
l can get no peace, no sleep.
Or maybe, my innermost
won't let me do it?
Poor man, some problem
he's invented for himself.
Give it to me!
You're a civilized man, aren'tyou?
- Why? What's the matter with you?
- You, lousy hypocrite...
Why?
What have l done... to you?
He wants to destroy your hope!
That's all people have got left
on this earth!
lt's the only place
they can come to,
if there's no hope left for them.
You yourself have come here!
Why destroy hope then?
Shut up!
l can see through you!
You don't give a damn about people!
You just make money,
using our... anguish!
lt's not even the money.
You're enjoying yourself here.
You're like God Almighty here.
You, a hypocritical louse, decide
who is to live and who is to die.
He deliberates!
Now l see why you stalkers
never enter the room yourselves.
You revel in all that power,
that mystery, your authority!
What else is there to wish for?
lt's not true!
You... you're mistaken.
A stalker must not enter the room.
A stalker must not even enter
the Zone with an ulterior motive.
Remember Porcupine?
Yes, you're right, l'm a louse.
l haven't done any good in this world,
and l can't do any.
l couldn't give anything
even to my wife.
l can't have any friends either.
But don't take mine from me!
They'd already taken everything from
me back there, behind the barbed wire.
So all that's mine is here.
You understand? Here! ln the Zone!
My happiness, my freedom,
my self-respect, it's all here!
l bring here people like me,
desperate and tormented.
People who have nothing else
to hope for.
And l can help them!
No one else can help them,
only l, the louse, can!
l'm so happy to be able to help them
that l want to cry.
And that's all.
l don't want anything more.
l don't know. Maybe.
Anyway, excuse me, but...
You're just a God's fool.
You have no idea
what's going on here.
Why do you think Porcupine
hanged himself?
He came to the Zone
with a mercenary motive.
He made his brother die
in the meat mincer because of money.
l know.
But why did he hang himself?
Why didn't he come here again,
not for money, but for his brother?
ln way of repenting.
He wanted to... l don't know.
He hanged himself a week later.
Because he realized that
not just any wish comes true here,
but only your innermost wish.
Not what would you holler
at the top of your voice...
Coming true here is
only what's in line with your nature,
with your essence,
of which you know nothing.
But it's there, in you,
directing you all your life.
You didn't understand anything,
Leather Stocking.
lt wasn't greed that had done
Porcupine in.
He was crawling in this puddle,
begging to bring his brother back.
But what he got was only money,
and he couldn't get anything else,
because render unto Porcupine
the things that are Porcupine's!
And things like conscience, anguish,
they are just inventions.
He realized that and hanged himself.
l'm not going to your room.
l have no wish to pour my filth
over somebody's head.
Even yours.
And then to put my neck into
the noose, like Porcupine.
l'd rather drink myself to death
in my mansion, in peace and quiet.
You don't understand anything
about human beings, Chingachgook,
if you take to the Zone
people like me.
And something else...
Why do you think that this miracle
really exists?
Who told you that wishes
actually come true here?
Have you seen a single man
who's been made happy here?
Was it Porcupine?
As a matter of fact,
who told you about the Zone,
about Porcupine, about that room?
He did.
Then it makes no sense to me at all.
What's the use coming here?
lt's so quiet...
Can you feel it?
What the heck... Why not chuck it all,
take my wife, Monkey,
and move over here.
For good.
There's no one here.
No one can hurt them here.
So you're back.
Where did you get this?
He got attached to me.
l couldn't leave him there.
Well, shall we go?
Monkey is waiting.
Are you coming?
Does any one of you need a dog?
l've got five of them at home.
So you love dogs, don'tyou?
What?
That's very good.
All right, let's go.
You can't even imagine
howtired l am!
God only knows!
Calling themselves intellectuals,
those writers and scientists!
Don't get so excited.
They don't believe in anything!
They've got the organ with which one
believes atrophied for lack of use.
Stop it. Come on.
Go to bed. Don't lie here...
lt's too damp here for you...
You shouldn't lie here.
Take it off.
Oh God, what people...
Calm down, it's not their fault.
You ought to pity them,
not to be angry with them.
Haven'tyou seen them? They've
got empty eyes.
The only thing
they can think about
is howto sell themselves
not too cheap!
Howto get as much as possible
for their every emotional movement!
They knowthey were ''born for
a purpose'', ''called upon''!
After all, they live ''only once''!
Can people like that
believe in anything?
Stop it, calm down.
Try to sleep, will you?
Go to sleep.
And nobody believes.
Not only those two. Nobody!
Who am l going to take there?
Oh, God...
And what's most awful...
is that no one needs it.
No one needs that room.
And all my efforts are just in vain.
Why do you say that?
Stop it.
l'm not going there with anybody
again.
Do you want me to go with you?
Where?
You think l've got nothing
to ask for?
No...
You can't go there.
Why not?
No, no.
What if it wouldn't work
with you, either?
You know, my mother was against it.
You've probably noticed already
that he's not of this world.
All our neighborhood laughed at him.
He was such a bungler,
he looked so pitiful.
My mother used to say:
''He's a stalker,
he's doomed,
he's an eternal prisoner!
Don'tyou know what kind of
children the stalkers have?''
And l... l didn't even argue with her.
l knew it all myself,
that he was doomed,
that he was an eternal prisoner,
and about the children.
Only what could l do?
l was sure
l would be happy with him.
Of course, l knew l'd have a lot of
sorrow, too.
But it's better to have
a bitter happiness than...
a gray, dull life.
Perhaps,
l thought it all up later.
But then he approached me and said:
''Come with me.''
And l did,
and never regretted it.
Never.
We had a lot of sorrow,
a lot of fear, and a lot of shame.
But l never regretted it,
and l never envied anyone.
lt's just our fate, our life,
that's how we are.
And if we haven't had our misfortunes,
we wouldn't have been better off.
lt would have been worse.
Because in that case, there wouldn't
have been any happiness.
And there wouldn't have been
any hope.
l love your eyes, my darling friend,
Their play, so passionate and
bright'ning,
When a sudden stare up you send,
And like a heaven-blown lightning,
lt'd take in all from end to end.
But there's more that l admire:
Your eyes when they're downcast
ln bursts of love-inspired fire,
And through the eyelash goes fast
A somber, dull call of desire...
The End