Have it, this is yours, this
is yours and that's yours.
Draw, paint and do
whatever you want to do.
Till now I be back by dropping this.
But what we paint sir there
is nothing on the table.
This table.
This table is very too small sweetheart
that it can't bare your beautiful thoughts.
Look in to your mind and draw
an amazing Technicolor photo.
and drop it on the paper.
Steal, steal the joy.
Nobody is here to stop you.
Where were you been lost friend?
Are you looking for
something in thoughts?
Nothing to worry and rush.
What happen kid?
Don't you like painting?
What is your name son?
Sir his name is Ishaan Awasthi.
Thanks.
Where did you go? Where did you go?
Your mother called.
Go and stand by the phone,
she's going to call again.
Go.
- Hello.
- Is Ishaan Awasthi around?
- Yes, Yes... Just a minute.
- Yes.
- Talk with him.
- Have it.
Hello Enoo... Hello
Enoo... Say hello son.
Look Enoo, we can't come
on Saturday, son. Dada's
...interschool tennis finals is
held on Sunday. Isn't it son?
I know you are very angry with Mama.
Mama is very bad.
I'm very sorry Enoo
but what can Mama do?
Dada is also having the
tension of finals. Isn't it?
Would you like to talk to Dada?
Now talk to Dada. And wish him all
the best, one minute... one minute.
Hello Enoo. Hello Enoo are you there?
Enoo, I'll miss a lot in the finals.
- Hello.
- Hello Enoo.
Enoo.
Son talk to Mama.
Hello... Enoo... Hello.
- Hello.
- Hello Madam he left.
- Left.
- Yes Madam.
Sorry.
- What happen?
- He hadn't talked?
Don't worry we'll go next Sunday.
- Err! Why are you putting it there?
- This is the class work of the kids.
Then what happened? Holkar didn't put
it there. That place is for the books.
Then where do I put them.
Return them to the kids.
By the way are they for any use?
What the wreckage they are
making in your class Nikumbh?
They are the kids,
the have to make noise.
And if the kids wouldn't
show there emotions in
...the art class then
where else they would show them.
That's alright. Just that Headmaster
wants discipline in the school. Discipline.
I heard that you were
singing the class yesterday.
And playing the flute.
Yes I was singing and playing the flute.
Kids happy so I'm happy.
But the children of this school isn't
like the children of that school.
What kind of children?
You are teaching in tulips school.
Mentally retorted abnormal kids.
Teach the way you like in
that kind of school, it doesn't
...makes any difference. No future
wouldn't be made of that kids.
No serious teaching. This
is a formal school, your
...singing, dancing style
wouldn't be appreciated over here.
We prepare kids for the race of life.
They must compete, succeed. Make a future.
Three rules of our school.
Unity, faith and discipline.
Three rules of success, the
way of complete education.
Hail Hitler.
Tevari-ji now you have to learn German.
What happen Ishaan?
Okay... Okay... Okay... Okay...
It's okay.
Err! Listen, where is your friend?
Sir, don't know sir. He was
here by now, suddenly he ran off.
He saw his new boring art teacher.
No... No sir, he went to the
dinning hall for the lunch.
What is your name friend?
Rajan Dhamodhran sir.
Rajan tell me one thing,
what is the matter of Ishaan?
- Sir.
- Is he having some problem?
He's afraid all the time.
- He wants to go home.
- Why?
- He's a new boy sir.
- In the middle of the year.
He's having a problem.
As much he can try but he
...can't read and write. He
has been punished all the time.
Red marks all over the book. What to do?
You play here, I'll be right back.
Ok?
Are you coming from somewhere
after cutting onions?
The human is...
- worse then animals.
I know that.
And blind too.
Away from the inner beauty.
Who you're confronting these days?
Myself.
After so long, I'm seeing
myself in the mirror.
So is there someone to
show you the mirror?
That's what I always ask you to.
You have a nice face.
Jabeen, he's in danger.
Who?
There's a boy in the school
He's 8-9 years old.
He doesn't do or speak anything,
always seems scared.
His eyes are like...
screaming for help.
I'm afraid he'll fall.
Let's go, it's time for the lesson.
Ok, lets go.
Hey, Sail, come. Do you know
what's the time of the show?
After two days.
Yes.
Excellent, let's go.
Yes?
Hello.
My name's Ram Shankar Nikum.
I teach at New Era School.
Come in.
Are these his 3rd standard books?
- Yes.
Who made this?
Ishaan did.
Ishaan did?
Does he paint?
Yes, he loves to paint.
Can I have some water please?
Why did you send him?
Why?
There was no choice.
Last year he failed in 3rd standard.
Can you believe?
In 3rd standard.
And there's no sign of
improvement.
This, my elder son, he comes 1st
in every class every subject.
And that other one...
What do you think, what
his problem is?
Problem? His attitude. What else?
Towards studies, towards everything.
Always stubborn, always attitude.
He never listens to anyone.
I'm asking about his problem,
but you're telling me the symptoms.
You're telling me he has the fever,
that's I know already.
I'm asking why is he having fever.
What's the reason of the fever?
Then you tell me.
Tell me.
Have you noticed any pattern
in his mistakes in his lessons?
Pattern. What pattern?
They all are mistakes.
Then you couldn't notice
the patterns.
Look here.
Here "b" is in place of "d"
and "d" in place of "b"
Confusion among similar
looking alphabets.
Here, he wrote "s" and "r"
in reverse. Even more...
Look here.
This small "h" and small "t"
Mirror imaging.
Animal, animal, animal. Three different
spellings on the same page.
It means, it's not the case that
he remembers one wrong spelling.
He mixes similar looking words.
This "t-o-p" becomes "p-o-t"
This "s-o-I-i-d" become "s-o-i-I-d".
Why does he do that?
Is he stupid, or lazy?
No
I think, he's having difficulty
in recognizing words.
When you read "a-p-p-I-e" apple,
you imagine a red apple in your head.
Maybe he can't read "apple"
That's why he can't
get the meaning as well.
To learn, one has to know the sounds,
visual and meanings of words.
Ishaan is lacking this
very important need.
There's nothing like that.
He only makes excuses.
To skip the studies.
Read this please.
How can I read it?
It's in Chinese.
Try it.
Come on. Concentrate.
What's this rubbish?
You're not behaving.
You're being rascal.
That's how Ishaan must be feeling.
He couldn't understand
the words.
This problem in studies
is called as "Dyslexia".
Sometimes child has some more
problems other then Dyslexia.
Like difficulty in understanding
multiple instructions.
Turn to page 65, chapter 9,
Para 4, line 2
Oonfusion...
Or Poor Final Gross Motus Skills.
Does Ishaan feel problems in
buttoning his shirt or tying his shoelace?
Yes
Can he catch the ball
when you throw it to him?
He can never judge the ball.
Because he can't understand the size,
distance and speed all together.
A ball, how big, from how far and
at what speed coming towards him.
Until he analyze all this...
It's too late.
Think about it.
A child
Just 8-9 years old.
Can't read, can't write.
Can't do day to day normal things.
Can't do what other children
can do very easily.
What could he go through then?
His self-confidence must have
been shattered.
He must have been fighting by hiding
his inabilities under stubbornness.
He must have been making a
hell out here.
Thinking, that why should he tell the
world that he can't do things.
Why shouldn't he get all that ignored
by just saying that he doesn't want to do.
That's what children learn from the elders.
And now he can't even
continue to fight that.
I'm sorry to say that
he has stopped painting.
It's very sad.
Why only Ishaan?
There's no answer to that.
It's a Neurological Disorder.
It can happen to anyone.
Sometimes it can be genetic.
To make it simple, there's just
some wiring problems in his brain.
So you're saying that my son
isn't normal, he's mentally retarded.
What kind of a person you are?
Look this, Mr. Awasti?
This fast brain is playing with
thousands of thoughts with colors.
Way more then yours and mine abilities.
But what's the use of that?
What are you looking into it?
Then what should I look?
What will he become when
he'll grow up?
How will he compete with
the world?
Will I keep on feeding
him for whole of his life?
I know this.
There's a cold world out there.
Everyone wants to grow toppers
and rankers in their homes.
Everyone wants No. 1
Doctor, engineer, management,
less then that is unacceptable.
95.5%, 95.6%, 95.7%
less then that is uncountable.
Isn't it?
Think about this.
Every child has his own quality,
own expertise, own desire.
But no,
Everyone is busy stretching the
finger to make it long.
Keep on doing that.
No matter you break the very finger.
What's are the options?
- No options.
There's no way.
If you like horse to race, then
breed race horses, damn it.
Why do you give birth to children?
Putting the weight of your ambitions
on your child, is worse then child labor.
And when the child can't
what if he can't carry the weight?
When they will understand?
That every child has his own
capacity to lift the weight.
He learns eventually.
Every child has own pace.
Five fingers make a fist.
Why are we dreaming to settle
these little ones in to the mainstream?
Friends, I'm going to tell
a story today.
A story about a boy.
There was a boy, don't ask where.
He couldn't read and write.
Even after so many tries.
He couldn't remember that "y"
comes after "x".
Words were his enemies,
used to dance in front of his eyes.
They used to tease him by
dancing and moving around.
Studies used to make him tired.
Who he could have told his problem to?
His mind was full, he was a starter bull,
and the alphabets were disco to him.
He failed in the exams.
He was a victim of the burden
of the studies.
People called him an ass
and stupid.
Boy took everything bravely.
And one day, he did something genius.
Everyone was shocked when
heard his theory.
Tell me, who's that boy?
Elbert Einstein.
Correct Rajan,
Albert Einstein.
Genius and great scientist.
Who shocked the world with his
theory of relativity.
Now tell me what's this?
No, no.
It's not an ordinary helicopter.
The great artist inventor,
Leonardo DaVinci
Who?
- Leonardo DaVinci
Yes,
he made this picture.
A working sketch of a helicopter.
But when?
In the 15th century.
400 years before the first
airplane could fly.
Do you know, Leonardo DaVinci used
to have difficulties to read and write.
He used to write like this.
Can you make anything out of it?
Now read it.
My name is Ram Shankar Nikum.
Ishaan, turn on the light please.
Who was the great person,
who lit the world with electricity?
Edison.
Thomas Edison.
Correct Ishaan.
He too was a victim of "abcd".
Sit down Ishaan.
No leave the light on.
Let Edison's light come on us.
Everyone must know him.
- Abhishek Bachchan.
He too used to have difficulties
in studies during childhood.
Now see, he is a blast.
There are more examples.
Pablo Picasso, famous painter.
He never understood
the number "7"
He used to say, "It looks
like my uncle's nose in reverse."
Who's the father of Mickey Mouse?
- Walt Disney.
Correct.
Walt Disney.
He was too confused about words,
so he put his art into cartoons.
Neil Diamond, popular singer.
He used to write songs out of the
shame about his red report card.
Agatha Christy, famous mystery book writer.
Can you believe a writer, who was
unable to read in her childhood.
But, why am I telling you all
this suddenly today?
To show you that, there were gems
in the world who changed it.
They were able to see
the world from their eyes.
Their minds were a bit different.
People came in their ways.
But still they won.
And they won like that the whole
world saw it in an awe.
Out today's art class will be
dedicated to all those geniuses.
We will step out remembering them.
And we'll make something different.
Anything.
Pick anything you like,
rock, wood, junk, anything.
Come on, move towards the door.
Ishaan, one minute.
Rajan, you can go.
Do you know there was another name
among all those I mentioned?
Because that name is not that great.
But he too had the same problem.
That name is Ram Shankar Nikum.
I too had difficulties in
reading and writing.
My father never understood me.
He thought I was being naughty,
and wasn't paying attention.
He thought I would not succeed
in my future.
What a duffer and idiot could become?
Whatever I am today,
I'm in front of you Ishaan.
Shall we go?
Did you go to my home?
Hey, it's moving.
Can it fly?
Will it?
Who made it?
Is Principal present?
Yes sir.
- Ok, stay seated.
I wanted to talk about a student.
Ishaan Awasti, 3rd "D"
He's a new student.
Some other teachers are
also complaining about him.
I don't think he could
even complete a year.
No sir, he's a smart boy.
He has just come problem
in reading and writing.
You know about "Dyslexia".
You've made our job easy.
I was confused what to tell his father.
He came through our trustees.
Good, good.
Then Special School is perfect for him.
Isn't it?
No sir,
He's a child with above
average intelligence.
He has full right to study
in a normal school.
He just needs a little help from us.
All children around the world having
any problem study in normal school.
And these children have right
to study in any normal school.
I'm sorry sir, it's not me who say
this. It's the law of our country.
Under the law of rights of
education, every child gets this right.
It's another thing that there are less
schools who don't follow this law.
Nikum, tell me one thing.
How will this boy manage here?
There's math, history, geography,
science, language...
He will.
Only if teachers help him a bit.
Where's the time that teachers have?
To attend one child
among 40 children?
Impossible.
Sir, it won't take as much time
as you think.
2-3 hours a week.
I will show you.
And he has to just pass all these
subjects,
his real destination is something else.
So, all the subjects that we teach
are useless but yours isn't.
No, sir, I didn't mean that.
every child has his art.
Please sir, look at his painting.
It's a battlefield, soldier digs a mine
and turned the page and
escaped while digging.
What an idea? Confident brush
strokes, such bold use of colors.
Very bold.
Look at this sir, a flip book,
story about getting away from home.
What an idea?
From just an 8 years old boy.
Sir, there are a few who
could think out of the way.
Sir, just one chance.
He needs this chance.
Or he'll loose his faith.
What do you want from me?
For some time, his spellings and
writing should be ignored.
We should take his tests orally.
Education is real be it
oral or written.
By the time, I'll also work
on his reading and writing.
That will be improved gradually.
I don't know, if I'm doing a permanent
damage by following a temporary teacher.
Now add 3
Very good, now add 5
What did you get?
Very good, now subtract 1 1
There's a question. Have you ever
painted after you finished your school.
What?
What is this sir?
Painting competition.
For students, teachers, everyone.
Seriously, what's the meaning of art.
It's meant to release your
emotions.
If you're happy, your hand will
reach all bright colors.
Lunch was bad, you'll end up
filling with all dark and dull colors.
I'll be back in two minutes, friends.
Sorry, there's a little space.
How come you're here?
I was passing by.
Have you met Ishaan?
- No, not yet, I will meet him.
First I needed to talk to you.
Go ahead.
My wife has been surfing internet
for a few days.
She has read all the information
about "Dyslexia"
We just wanted to you tell you that.
Why did you want to tell me?
So you don't mistake us as parents
who don't care about their children.
To care.
It necessary Mr. Awasti.
It has the power to cure.
It's a medicine that relieves pain.
It's a security that child thinks
someone cares about him.
One hug, or one lovely kiss.
To show that you care.
To tell him, "Son I love you".
"If you have any worries,
you can come to me".
"It's ok if you made a mistake,
I'm there for you."
To care.
Isn't it what's called "to care"?
I'm happy to hear that you
think you care.
I'll leave now.
Mr. Awasti,
Has your wife read about
Solomon Islands on internet?
I don't know.
In Solomon Island, when people
wanted to clean a part of woods
for farming, they don't cut the trees.
Instead, they stand around the tree
and start shouting at him,
cursing at him.
In some days,
the tree gets weak.
And dies by itself.
There has been great gems
in the world who changed it.
because..
They were able to see
the world from their eyes.
Their minds were a bit different.
People didn't like that and
they came in their ways.
But still they won.
And they won like that the whole
world saw it in an awe.
What a fair they have arranged?
Look, I have arrived.
Where's your Ishaan?
I've been dying to meet him.
I don't know,
I can't see him.
Rajan, where's Ishaan?
I don't know sir,
he left hostel before everyone.
Really?
Hey Nikum, you've pulled
me into this too.
You should try this,
it's fun.
No way, I can't do this
painting thing.
I will put so many alphabets
and fill it will alphabets.
I've come here only for headmaster
to see my presence.
I will be here for 5-10 minutes only.
I will not make my Sunday waste
It's an honor for us that
you've come.
Where I have to sit?
Children will show your sitting place.
Children, come here.
Show to sir his sitting place.
My special guest Madam Lalita
Teacher, painter, my guru.
Hello
- Hello
Have you seen Ishaan?
No sir, he must be with Rajan.
Where's he?
I don't know sir, as I said earlier
he left before everyone.
Where had you been?
Come here, sit.
Do you have colors?
Sir, haven't you left yet?
You were leaving in 5 minutes.
What are you painting?
It's a frog, duck and a banana.
Is it a frog?
How's my painting?
Look at it.
Absolutely beautiful sir.
First prize sir.
Amazing!
What a wonderful morning.
Going through the colored
glasses of windows we reached
our childhood.
Praise to be God's.
I saw other's childhoods too.
We made Joy sir to promise
He will take compulsory
lessons from Nikum Sir.
Isn't it Joy Sir?
But not only me, Sen and Tiwari
Sir will too,
these two had bad paintings as well.
All right.
By Nikum, I just remember.
That we won't have to look
for a new art teacher.
Nikum sir, along with Tulip School,
will also teach in our school.
Now, what you have been waiting for...
I'm going to announce that.
Let me come to the results
of the Art Fair.
Our special guest Madam Lalita
was in a fix.
She was in a confusion. she was
confused between two paintings
It was a tie. She wanted to award
both paintings to be the best.
That wasn't possible.
Because the winner painting
I thought that painting will become the
front cover of the school's yearbook.
Now, there can't be two
front covers.
So what to do now?
Madam was in deep confusion.
After thinking a lot she
came to a conclusion.
She selected the student
leaving the teacher.
Yes children.
Your Nikum sir has been defeated.
And the student who defeated him
Little, 9 years old,
Ishaan Nandkishore Awasti.
Applause.
Here's your Ishaan
and here's his painting.
Just look at it, what
a masterpiece.
He's a very talented boy.
I'm really happy to have him.
Have you met his teachers?
No sir.
Please go ahead and meet them,
they'll give the progress report.
First we thought something was
wrong, he won't be staying here.
But what improvement he made.
What a pace to pick-up he has.
Wonderful. Here's his progress report.
Your Son is very talented.
I can't believe all this.
Thank you.
What?
What happened?
I can't find words to
thank you.
He's lovely boy.
Just look after him.
Come back early
after holidays.