A TOHO PRODUCTION
PRINCESS FROM THE MOON
Make way!
Make way for the high priest!
Hurry!
Anyone in the way...
grind them into the ground!
Vermin!
Hurry!
Taketori.
It's Uda, the merchant.
I'm here to buy your goods.
Hey! Anybody home?
Unlocked?
Hello, Taketori's wife.
Go home.
As you can see, I've got nothing to sell.
But I...
So you're here.
What's wrong?
Your wife sent me away.
What happened?
We lost our daughter yesterday.
What? Your pretty daughter, Kaya?
She fell sick and died quickly.
How old?
Five.
You must be discouraged.
But I hope you'll work again soon.
Your bamboo ware and her cloth...
They both sell well in town.
Then pay us more.
I'll be back.
What are you doing?
Why?
Why did Kaya die?
Because we have little money?
Forget it.
Blaming poverty won't console us.
We couldn't afford a doctor.
How can I forget it?
I had her when I most gave up.
I wish I died with her.
Eat something.
You haven't eaten since yesterday.
Why couldn't it have been me instead?
Still grieving!
It won't bring her back alive.
Give it up.
Get out of here!
It's the bamboo forest.
Something's burning.
Kaya's grave is there.
I can't let it be burned.
Wait. You can't go now.
And I can't lose the bamboo woods.
I'd lose my livelihood.
Kaya.
You've saved the bamboo.
Thanks.
A baby?
But it's strange.
Can I leave it here?
Hard luck.
Anyway, I'll take you home.
The village master will rear you.
We're too poor to do it.
What? It's warm!
Stop squirming!
Where is it?
Kaya!
So many trees burned down!
Was this the reason?
How was this made?
Something's been burning.
How strange.
Kaya?
Kaya!
My daughter! You're back!
Wait.
Listen.
I found a baby in the woods.
It was in this cradle.
I was shocked.
It grew quickly into a girl.
Here she is.
Are you listening?
Isn't it strange?
But she's none other than Kaya.
You're wrong.
Her eyes...
Blue eyes.
Kaya's were dark.
You see?
She has a ball.
A crystal ball.
She keeps it.
Look.
She must be heaven's gift
to console our deep sorrow.
So you brought her here.
Let's adopt her.
We don't know her.
Kaya!
Blue eyes!
A ghost!
Kaya's ghost!
Blue eyes!
You're laughing at us.
Take that!
She hurt my son's head.
She let go of my game.
I'm sorry. Please forgive her.
Some evil spirit got into her.
Her eyes turned blue.
Maybe she set fire to the shrine.
You must keep your eyes on her.
One more incidents will finish you.
That's right!
Right.
Day in day out I say I'm sorry.
They believe she's our real child.
We're doing alright, aren't we?
They blame Kaya for everything.
Why, you think so, too?
I'm glad.
Your father knows you're innocent.
Father? Me?
No. I didn't adopt her.
Only you think she's your child.
Nonsense!
Your affection for her is unusual.
Maybe so it is, as you say.
But I want to believe she's mine.
Please let me.
Trash, isn't it?
A bamboo maker found it.
It's part of a container.
He wants to sell it, but...
I don't think it's of any value.
Look.
See the sun.
What colour?
It's green.
It proves it's gold.
Not for cheap chasers like me.
It's pure gold.
Sold?
Hands.
Your hands.
Both of them.
Careful.
Listen.
This is just between you and me.
A secret.
Do you have anymore?
Give me that!
Where is it? Give it to me!
Where is what?
The cradle I found Kaya in.
You threw it away with the trash.
Here it is!
I've got it.
Listen. This is gold. Pure gold!
With this,we'll be poor no more.
I don't understand.
It's Kaya's.
Ours!
We're rearing the girl heaven sent.
So this is heaven's gift for us.
Your majesty.
I took my time to check something...
before I discuss it here today.
So I'm late.
Let's discuss it later.
I understand, Councillor Otomo.
Take your seat.
We've been hearing the report
about the strange incident...
that happened the other night.
Resume your report.
Continue.
The ground around the big hollow...
was scorched as if hundreds of...
thunderboIts hit it all at once.
A moment before the disaster...
a big fireball was seen...
flying across the sky to the hill...
at an amazing speed.
Some villagers saw it.
The report was made by a spy
who is working for the court.
He's there.
Prince as chief of the library...
you're learned.
Does any book of yours tell us...
about such a disaster?
No. Well...
I'II have it checked.
You don't know?.
You seem to prefer girls to books.
No wonder.
Abe, you take things for granted.
I'm modest.
I don't like to brag.
What do you say, Reverend?
This incident is serious.
So is the matter I'm checking.
I found some unknown gold in town.
Gold?
Raise the curtain.
Tell me more.
Yes.
I took the gold to our mint...
for close examination.
And they found this:
It's extremely pure gold.
No mine in our country can...
produce gold of such quality.
I don't think we can overlook it.
Reverend Doson?
Somebody came from
a foreign land in secret.
I don't hunger for gold.
But it determines a nation's fate.
Sometimes it disturbs the reign.
We must find where it came from...
and confiscate all of it.
Weaving threads of various colours...
is a new trick to me.
I've brought blue cloth today.
Very good.
A certain nobleman ordered it.
Well, then...
there you go.
Thank you for giving me the job.
You're great. I admire you.
Your man either idles or drinks.
We must work as long as we live.
By the way...
Tell me something.
About the thing...
how much do you have?
He gives me only a little at a time.
I know nothing about it.
So you're in here?
You sold your cloth?
I told you not to.
We don't have to work anymore.
No more shady deals with Uda.
But you wanted money.
If it's clean.
Oh, I'm sorry!
The wrong place.
Come on, let's go.
Excuse us.
Strange.
It looks like our house.
Still drunk?
I'm Kaya.
What?
Are you Kaya?
So it's Kaya!
Yes.
Nonsense!
Now you're speaking!
Your eyes are dark.
She has the image of little Kaya.
It's Kaya.
How can you be so simple?
As I thought, she isn't normal.
She's growing up fast, that's all.
I like that.
She was a baby when I found her.
Now she's...
She doesn't know why.
Do you, Kaya?
No.
Nor where you came from?
I don't understand.
How could she grow up so fast?
I believe this is divine grace.
Heaven gave us a girl.
Now she's big and beautiful.
I'm so happy to have her.
Thank you so much.
Aren't you going to work?
How long must you spy on others?
Ask for a transfer.
Why?
No promotions.
This time I'll get one.
I'll be a courtier at the palace.
You won't have to work like that.
Hey!
If it isn't Fujiwara! WeIcome!
I've been so busy I couldn't come.
You're to blame.
You exaggerate things.
Abig hollow was made.
And you reported it as a disaster.
But it was extraordinary.
It has some connection with...
the gold discussed at the court.
-What?
- Listen.
I found a seemingly humble man...
spending a lot at the market.
I followed him.
He lived near the big hollow.
Coincidence.
Good spies like me know better.
He had a graceful, pretty daughter,
a rare asset of the village.
Her beauty was even mysterious.
Then...
During the period I watched his house...
all his family suddenly moved away.
I don't know where to.
They bother me.
Who?
Those men who want to see Kaya.
I can't sleep.
They're all around this house.
Neither Kaya or I mind them.
You don't have to work anymore.
Why do you think we came here...
far from the village?
Kaya grew up fast; we grew rich.
We must divert suspicion from us.
There's another reason.
The noblemen and rich men in town...
have their country houses here.
So what?
Can't you see?
Kaya is beautiful.
We must find her a nice groom.
A groom?!
Of course!
If she marries a nobleman...
we'll be respected as her parents.
Kaya's not an ordinary girl.
It's our duty to make her happy.
That's a very selfish idea.
But if you think of her happiness...
you must notice how she behaves.
Huh?
What do you mean?
She always has that crystal ball.
Wha...?
She gazes into it all day long.
It's quite unusual.
I'm not here on business today.
We have a poor harvest this year.
Please reduce the tax.
I said I'm not here on business.
It's about the girl.
Yes,yes. I hear she's beautiful.
They say her beauty is heavenly.
She looks so to peasants.
How will she look to me?
Take me to her house.
Who is that girl?
She works here nursing the baby.
Akeno, excuse yourself.
I'll take some flowers to her.
Hey, woman. Pick some flowers for me.
Three red and two yellow.
Minister, she's blind.
Eh? Blind?
Can she work?
The baby seems to love her.
She's an orphan. No relatives.
How can you tell?
By the smell.
Simple water.
Oh, I didn't expect you here.
Have you come to check some books?
What are you checking, minister?
Please wait a while.
You're trying to outwit me.
I knew you'd come here, too.
Have you seen the girl?
Not yet.
She's said to look beautiful.
If she is, what will you do?
You're a married man.
What will you do?
Our parents chose our wives...
for their own reasons.
We can divorce them.
But a rumour is a rumour.
Maybe she's a homely country girl.
This is Kaya, my daughter.
Watch out!
Get back!
Wait!
What are you doing?
Looking for my stick.
This?
Thank you...
Your hands! They're cold!
Why not pick it up?
I'm blind.
Blind? What do you mean?
You don't know what 'blind'' means?
Your name?
Kaya.
So you're the new girl here.
Where are you from?
Where were you born?
I don't know.
Very funny!
I mean it.
That's what I want to know.
You have parents?
Yes.
You're strange.
You're not an ordinary girl.
There's an old Chinese book...
about a girl who worked miracles.
I know well about books.
My father was a doctor.
What are your parents like?
They passed away.
Dead.
I must be going. I'm on an errand.
Can we meet again?
My name is Akeno.
It means ''a field at dawn.''
Empress, here's my poem.
Your poem?
A hymn to the feminine charm?
Read it.
It's all about a very beautiful girl.
Her celestial beauty deserves
The name of Kaguya, a shining lady.
Please listen to mine.
The spring breeze brings me
Melancholy, because of Kaguya.
Similar poems.
A coincidence!
Who's Kaguya?
A girl called Kaya.
I call her Kaguya, meaning shining lady.
So you both are in love with her?
She must be very special.
And she's rich.
Men are talking about her.
A humble girl.
No good.
I formally asked her to marry me.
Not only you.
I proposed to her,too.
You sound serious this time.
So she infatuates all men.
Make way for us!
We were turning the corner!
Get a move on!
What's happened?
-That cart has us blocked.
-Your fault!
Who do you think our master  is?
We're stuckhere.
Wait.
I'm in a hurry.
Pull your cart aside.
Then make your servants help us.
Mother!
The ball shone.
What? Shone?
It isn't shining.
Only for a moment.
Did it happen before?
No.
You imagined it.
No. It really shone.
Kaya.
You care about the ball because...
you think...
it can tell you where you come from.
Right?
Have you found out who you are?
No.
We're now parents and daughter.
We're living together.
Please forget about your birth.
Please do.
She worries about you so much.
You'd better forget the ball.
I know you come here often.
This is not where you were found...
but I understand how you feel.
I'm sorry about the crystal ball.
That's alright.
You consider me your real child.
I'm really grateful.
But I want to know what I am.
You are my child.
What else?
You mustn't say you're not my real child.
Excuse me, but do you remember me?
You can't forget me...
because you were so angry.
I helped you get your cart going again...
but you left without a word.
it was easy to find your house.
I went to your gate...
but I dared not enter.
I can no longer hold myself back.
So I have taken a chance.
I'm Kaya's mother.
Oh, I didn't see you.
I'm Otomo.
You didn't tell me you met him.
Why?
I'd like to marry her.
I decided when I first met her.
I know there are other suitors, but...
I propose to you.
Excuse me.
Will you tell me what to do?
About getting married?
I must accept one of the suitors.
They say men prosper by marriage.
But I...
I see.
You're not an ordinary girl.
Still a girl is a girl.
People marry for love, don't they?
You want the love of one of them?
I can't see if he really loves me.
Nobody can. There's no way.
But you can test their sincerity.
You want to know more about them?
Then put them to a test.
How?.
It is an honour to have you here.
I highly appreciate your kindness.
I told my daughter to choose one...
of the three men who proposed.
She said it was difficult to say...
who was better than whom.
She'll marry the one...
who gives her what she wants.
That's a good idea.
Whatever she wants, just ask.
I'll be delighted to bring it.
There's nothing I can't get.
Name it, and you'll receive it.
Now, Kaya, tell them.
There are three objects.
One is a tree that yields diamonds...
with a gold trunk and...
silver roots, on Paradise Island.
Another is the Fire Rat Fleece...
of the golden rats that live...
in a volcano in China.
The other is on the head of
a dragon in the Indian Ocean:
The Dragon's Jewel.
Choose one for each, please.
They're all known as unreachable.
They're described in books.
But nobody has actually seen them.
A difficult task!
Thousands of powerful men have...
sought these treasures in vain.
Anyone who has even one of them...
will become immortal, so they say.
That's what I heard.
Immortality is man's eternal wish.
I don't think I deserve them.
You can refuse.
No, no, no! I'm not saying I refuse.
I already chose the Treasure Tree.
You're sly.
Why?
You've chosen the easiest.
The first to choose gets the best.
But I must go to the China Sea.
Then I'll search China...
for the Fire Rat Fleece.
Councillor.
You haven't spoken of your choice.
Is it too much for you?
The Dragon's Jewel is for me?
Then I'll go to India.
I never thought she'd ask you...
to do such difficult tasks.
None can accomplish them.
You must refuse for your own good.
She spoke out, and we accepted.
A real man won't back out.
This is a map of Paradise Island.
I have a plan.
Fusamori.
I have an idea.
Here's the money for the fleece, and...
To the south!
Where is the councillor's ship?
That's what I'm thinking.
I opposed your marriage at first.
But not now.
The councillor is brave enough.
I trust he'll make you happy.
Yes.
Mother, I'm so happy at this moment.
So am I.
I know this is folly!
There aren't any dragons!
They're visions yielded by fear!