'After weeks of campaigning
'Tony Blair and his family
'strolled to the polling station
'this election day morning.
'The Labor faithful feel pride
'in Mr. Blair's achievements
'as he is about to become
the youngest PM this century.'
- Have you voted yet, Mr. Crawford?
- Yes, Ma'am.
I was there when they opened.
First in line, seven o'clock.
I don't mind telling you,
it wasn't for Mr. Blair.
- You're not a modernizer?
- Certainly not.
We're in danger of losing too much
that is good about this country.
There is a growing sense
of excitement.
I envy you, being able to vote.
Not the actual ticking of the box,
although it would be nice
to experience that once...
...but the sheer joy of being partial.
Yes. Of course, one forgets that as
sovereign, you're not entitled to vote.
- No.
- Still, I don't feel sorry for you.
You might not be allowed to vote,
ma'am...
...but it is your government.
Yes.
I suppose that is some consolation.
Good morning.
- Shall I draw the curtains?
- Yes, please.
So, did you stay up all night?
Yes, ma'am.
And was it as expected?
Yes, ma'am. Mr. Blair.
By a landslide.
Oh, I see.
'They've stopped the traffic
completely
'for Tony Blair's first day of power
in London.
'You've got the ceremonial,
the official
'and you've got a lovely summer's day.
'Tony Blair waving to the crowds,
people waving to them there.
'I guess they know it's
the Prime Minister on the streets.'
The Prime Minister is on his way,
ma'am.
To be, Robin. The Prime Minister to be.
I haven't asked him yet.
He's a hard one to read, isn't he?
Yes. On the one hand,
his background is quite establishment -
father a Conservative,
educated at Fettes.
He had the same tutor
as the Prince of Wales.
We'll try not to hold that against him.
On the other, his manifesto promises
the most radical shake-up
of the constitution in 300 years.
- Think he'll try to modernize us?
- I wouldn't put it past him.
His wife has
anti-monarchist sympathies.
You may remember her curtsy
the first time you met.
It could best be described as shallow.
I don't measure
the depth of a curtsy, Robin.
I leave that to my sister.
Downing Street
is expected to be informal -
everyone on first-name terms,
at the Prime Minister's insistence.
- What, "Call me Tony"?
- Yes, ma'am.
Oh, I don't like that.
Have we sent him a protocol sheet?
- Funny, I'm actually rather nervous.
- Why? You've met her before.
I know, but never one to one,
and never as Prime Minister.
Well, remember, you're a man
that's just been elected by the nation.
But she's still, you know, the Queen.
The audience room is upstairs.
When we reach the audience room,
I will knock.
We shall go straight inside.
Standing by the door, we bow,
from the neck.
I will introduce you.
The Queen will extend her hand.
You go to her, bow again,
then shake her hand.
A couple of other things -
it's ma'am as in ham,
not ma'am as in farm.
When you're in the presence,
at no point must you show your back.
- The presence?
- Yes, sir.
That's what it's called
when you're in Her Majesty's company.
Would you like to sit there, Mrs. Blair?
How nice to see you again, Mr. Blair.
- And congratulations.
- Thank you.
- Your children must be proud.
- I hope so.
- You've three, haven't you?
- That's right.
Such a blessing, children.
Do sit down.
Thank you.
Have we shown you
how to start a nuclear war yet?
- Er... no.
- Oh. First thing we do, apparently.
Then we take away your passport
and send you round the world.
You obviously know my job
better than I do.
Yes, well, you are
my tenth prime minister, Mr. Blair.
My first was Winston Churchill.
He sat in your chair
in a frock coat and top hat.
He was kind enough to give a young girl
like me quite an education.
I can imagine.
With time, one has hopefully added
experience and wisdom,
better enabling us to execute
our constitutional responsibility,
to advise, guide and warn
the government of the day.
Advice which I...
look forward to receiving.
Yes. We'll save that
for our weekly meetings.
If there's nothing else, I believe
we have some business to attend to.
Of course.
Your Majesty,
my party has won the election,
and so I ask your permission
to form a...
No, Mr. Blair. I ask the question.
The duty falls upon me, as sovereign,
to invite you to become Prime Minister
and to form a government in my name.
And if you agree,
the custom is to say yes.
Yes.
Mrs. Blair, lovely to see you again.
And congratulations.
You must be very proud.
- Yes.
- And exhausted, I imagine.
- Where will you spend the summer?
- France.
- Lovely.
- You'll be in Balmoral?
Yes. Wonderful place.
My great, great grandmother,
Victoria said,
"In Balmoral, all seems to breathe
freedom and peace
"and make one forget the world
and its sad turmoils."
- Your Majesty...
- Oh, excuse me.
No. Really?
Oh. Yes, of course.
I'm so sorry.
We're going to have to leave it there.
Not too short, was it, 15 minutes?
- One doesn't want to be rude.
- No, ma'am.
Morning.
- "Thanks for coming. Now, fuck off."
- What was that about?
God knows.
It'll be something to do with Diana.
'Princess Diana
embroiled in controversy
'as she pulls out of a meeting
with MPs.'
Princess Diana moved to mend relations
with the former nanny...
Princess Diana attended
a memorial service
for the fashion designer
Gianni Versace.
'...where another
royal controversy sparkles.'
...was embroiled
in a second controversy this week.
I am not a political figure.
Princess Diana sailed
out into the Mediterranean
in one of Mr. Mohamed AI Fayed's
yachts today.
- With his son.
- ...quarter of a million pounds
for photographs which appear
to show the couple embracing.
Once again,
her judgment's under scrutiny.
Earlier today, they visited the...
Robin Janvrin.
What?
Tell Sir Guy I want everyone in ASAP.
Ma'am? Ma'am?
- Yes?
- Ma'am, Mr. Janvrin is here to see you.
What?
Oh.
Good evening ma'am.
I'm sorry to disturb, but I've just had
a call from our embassy in Paris.
- It's the Princess of Wales.
- Why? What's she done now?
I see. Er...
Who are we speaking to there?
Right, well, keep me updated.
It's Diana.
She's been in a car accident in Paris.
Is it serious?
Apparently Dodi Fayed is dead.
'Let's recap on the details
of those injuries, Maxine.'
'They're saying the Princess is in
the intensive care unit
'of a southeast Paris hospital.
- 'She has concussion, a broken arm...'
- Why was she in Paris?
- I thought she was in London.
- You know what she's like.
Charles, isn't this awful?
- What will you do about the boys?
- Let them sleep until we know more.
- Yes, that's sensible.
- I should go to Paris.
I told my people to organize a jet.
- What, a private one?
- Yes.
Isn't that the sort of extravagance
they attack us for?
How else can I get to Paris
at this time of night?
Charles, dear, use the royal flight.
They keep one plane
on permanent standby
in case I should kick the bucket.
No, Mummy, he can't.
This isn't a matter of state.
What are you talking about?
Diana is not one of the royal family.
She's not an HRH.
- It's a private matter.
- She's mother to your grandchildren.
What is happening now?
I don't know. I can't hear.
Everyone's shouting.
- Thanks for coming in.
- The ambassador from Paris.
Good evening, sir.
Yes?
I've just spoken
to our ambassador in Paris, ma'am.
I'm afraid it's not good news.
No!
No...
No. No. No.
No.
Diana, Princess of Wales, has died
after a car crash in Paris.
The French government announced
her death this morning.
- What have I got on this week?
- Writing your conference speeches.
Well, let's cancel everything else.
This is going to be massive.
'Her death was confirmed
by the French...'
- I'll make a statement in the morning.
- I've started coming up with ideas.
- She's only been dead an hour.
- Would you prefer I didn't?
Try and be very brave.
It's Mummy. She's dead.
They're going to go back to sleep.
Try, anyway.
My private secretary's office have
found a travel agency in New York
that will sell me a flight to Paris
with an hour's stopover in Manchester.
Perhaps you might consider
if it's an extravagance
to bring back the mother of the future
king of England in one of our planes.
All right. Of course.
John, I don't want the boys
to see the news and get upset.
Take the radio from the bedroom
and the TV from the nursery.
Yes, ma'am.
- Well, well, well.
- Yes.
Are you all right?
Your sister called, from Tuscany.
I hope you told her
to cut her holiday short.
- I did.
- I can't imagine she was pleased.
- That's putting it mildly.
- What did she say?
Something about Diana being more
annoying dead than alive.
Never let the boys hear you talk
like that.
Of course.
Something to help you go down?
No, I think I'll write my diary
a little longer.
Fine. I'm going to bed.
'We've heard nothing official
from the palace.
'We don't know when we'll get
any statements from the palace
'or when the royal family are due.'
That's how she will remain,
in our minds, our hearts, forever.
- OK? Got it.
- 'Where will you do it?'
- At the church, on the way in.
- I'll organize it.
'Viscount Althorp, Diana's brother...'
Hang on. I want to watch this.
'This is not a time
for recriminations, but for sadness.
'However, I would say I always believed
the press would kill her in the end.
'Not even I imagined they would take
such a direct hand in her death
'as seems to be the case.
'It would appear that every proprietor
and editor of every publication
'that paid for intrusive photographs
of her has blood on his hands today.'
Not the press, mate.
You've got the wrong villain.
Tony...
- Oh. Got to go.
- You about to speak to the Queen?
- Yeah.
- Ask her if she greased the brakes.
Now, now.
Thanks.
- Hello?
- 'Putting you through.'
Oh... Right, OK.
- Is the Prince of Wales with the boys?
- Yes, ma'am.
- Good. And he's going to Paris?
- Yes.
I'm sorry to disturb, ma'am...
Ma'am...
...but I have the Prime Minister
for you, from his constituency.
Lucky you.
Thank you, Robin.
I'll take it in the study.
- 'Your Majesty.'
- Prime Minister.
May I say how very sorry I am.
The thoughts and prayers of my family
are with you at this terrible time,
and with the princes in particular.
Thank you.
'Is it your intention to make
some kind of appearance or statement?'
No. No, certainly not.
No-one in the royal family will speak
publicly. This is a private matter.
We would appreciate it
if it could be respected as such.
I see.
I don't suppose
anyone's thought about the funeral.
We've spoken with the Spencer family,
and it is their express wish
that this should be a private funeral
with a memorial service to follow.
Right.
As Diana was no longer
a member of the royal family,
we must respect their wishes.
I see.
'You don't feel that in view
of her high profile and popularity,'
it might be an idea to pay tribute
to her life and achievements,
or even just to her as a mother?
Well, as I said,
it's her family's wish.
And the public, ma'am,
the British people?
'You don't think
that might be denying them a chance...'
A chance to what?
'To share in the grief?'
This is a family funeral, Mr. Blair,
not a fairground attraction.
I think the Princess has already paid
a high enough price
for exposure to the press, don't you?
If there's nothing else,
the children have to be looked after.
Of course. Goodbye, Your Maj...
Her instinct is to do nothing,
say nothing,
and give her a private funeral.
Are you surprised? She hated her guts.
I think it's a mistake.
They screwed up her life.
I hope they don't screw up her death.
Where can I get a black tie?
Oh, the chaplain called.
He asked if he should make
any changes in the service,
any special mention of Diana.
What did you say?
- I told him not to change a thing.
- Quite right.
The less attention drawn to it,
the better, for the boys.
Yes.
We should find some company
for them, some young people.
I'll take them for a long walk
up Craggy Head.
Yes, but no guns, Philip. It is Sunday.
We're going, I believe, to Sedgefield,
the Prime Minister's constituency,
where he is about to make a statement.
'Yes, the Prime Minister coming now
with his wife, Cherie.'
Yeah, well, apart from that?
He's on. Alastair, he's on! Come on!
'Though her own life
was often sadly touched by tragedy,
'she touched the lives of so many others'
in Britain and throughout the world...
...with joy and with comfort.
'The people everywhere,
not just here in Britain, everywhere,
'they kept faith with Princess Diana.
'They liked her. They loved her.
'They regarded her as one of the people.
'She was the people's princess...
'...and that's how she will... stay,
'how she will remain...
'...in our hearts
and in our memories... forever.'
A bit over the top, don't you think?
'The Prime Minister, paying
his tribute to the Princess of Wales.'
The people of Britain, he said,
kept faith with Princess Diana.
They loved her.
She was the people's princess.
- Do we have the Royal Standard?
- Yes, sir.
- And flowers?
If we left it to the royal undertakers,
they'd bring her back in a crate.
Hello?
'This is Lord Airlie.
May I speak to the Prime Minister?'
One moment, please.
Lord Airlie.
The Lord Chamberlain
in charge of the funeral.
You're meeting him at the airport.
- Lord Airlie.
- Good afternoon, Prime Minister.
It's my job to organize
all the ceremonial events.
There's no precedent
for the funeral of an ex-HRH.
Perhaps we should plan
for any contingency.
I propose a meeting tomorrow morning
at Buckingham Palace,
'officials from all three palaces,
representatives of the Spencer family,'
the emergency services
and your people.
Absolutely. Of course.
Precedent?
Where do they find these people?
Thank you.
Brigadier Sir Charles Wood.
Air Commodore Wessex.
- Prime Minister.
- I'm so sorry, sir.
If there's anything
I or my government can do...
They stood up as we drove past,
in cafés, in restaurants,
removed their hats.
This was Paris,
and you could hear a pin drop.
- I imagine it will be the same here.
- The palace prefers a private funeral.
- What are your feelings on that?
- I...
I think that'll present us
with difficulties.
So do I.
My mother... The Queen comes
from a generation not best equipped.
She grew up in the war.
I think what we need,
what this country needs,
is a more modern perspective,
if you follow.
- Balmoral is...
- I think I understand.
'An aircraft of the Queen's Flight
brought the Princess's body home,
'where the Prime Minister gathered
with members of his government.
'A black hearse crossed the Tarmac
'and a Royal Air Force guard of honor
moved forward.'
Has anyone heard from the Spencers?
Did they say when the funeral will be?
Hmm? I don't know.
Nobody tells me anything.
'President Clinton
heard the news last night.'
'We liked her very much.
'We admired her work for children,
for people with AIDS
'for ending the scourge
of land mines...'
On our walk today, one of the gillies
said he'd seen a stag up Craggy Head.
- He reckoned 14 points.
- Oh.
We haven't had one
as big as that on the estate for years.
No. Quite.
'...and I was tremendously impressed...'
Anyway, I thought
it might be a good distraction.
- For the boys.
- What, stalking?
- You don't think it's too soon?
- Anything that gets them out is good.
'...as their relationship
deteriorated,
'she became increasingly unhappy.
'The couple divorced
in August of last year.
'Their love story
brought crowds into the streets.
'They came to see the Queen
and the Prince,
'but most of all,
they came to see Diana.'
- I'm going to bed.
- 'But the fairytale was destined...'
I'll ring the Lord Chamberlain's office
to say we'll send representatives
to the meeting.
Thank you, Stephen.
She gave us so much.
Why couldn't we have given her
something and left her alone?
It just... hurts me so much.
I've never experienced
anything like this.
I wait to wake up,
like it's a bad dream.
Right, it's ten o'clock.
Let's get started.
Thank you all for coming
at such short notice.
I think we all agree that this is
a sensitive occasion,
which presents us
with tremendous challenges -
logistically, constitutionally,
practically,
diplomatically and procedurally.
Oh, Christ.
After 18 years of opposition,
I am proud to stand before you
as the new Prime Minister...
Labor Prime Minister.
I want to set an ambitious course
to modernize this country,
to breathe new life
into old institutions,
to make privilege
something for the many, not the few.
You think the royals are nutters?
You should meet their flunkies.
Two and a half hours to choose
between a hearse or a gun carriage.
You got raves in the press. This calls
you "The nation's mourner in chief."
This lot says you correctly judged
the country's mood.
- Hello?
- Even The Mail was impressed.
People's princess, mate. You owe me.
- Gordon for you.
- Tell him to hang on.
Alastair...
- Is it going to be a public funeral?
- Yeah. Saturday.
- It's a whopper. The Abbey, the works.
- Great.
- Has anyone told the Queen?
- I don't know.
No doubt some flunky will be
dispatched, groveling on all fours.
Do you think it's wise
for the boys to go stalking?
Anything
that gets them out is good.
Maybe they shouldn't take guns.
If a photographer saw them,
it might send the wrong signal.
If there is a photographer out there,
he could be the first kill of the day.
I see Mr. Fayed was buried last night.
At midnight. No cameras, no fuss.
Very dignified.
Why do they do that? Why do they bury
the bodies so soon after death?
Islamic tradition.
- Something to do with the heat.
- Mmm.
It stops the body decomposing.
Come in.
Good morning, ma'am. Ma'am.
Yes, Robin? What can we do for you?
Er... ma'am, there was a meeting
at the palace this morning.
About the funeral arrangements. Yes.
The Lord Chamberlain faxed these plans
for you to consider.
There is now general agreement, ma'am,
that a public funeral
would be more appropriate.
I see.
And what form will this funeral take?
At the moment, they're suggesting...
and, of course, these are early days,
basing it on Tay Bridge.
- Tay Bridge?
- What?
Tay Bridge is the code name
for my funeral.
Indeed, ma'am,
but it would be
for practical reasons only.
It's the only one
which has been rehearsed,
the only one
that could be put together in time.
But I supervised those plans myself.
Indeed, and the Lord Chamberlain
was at pains to stress
that the spirit of the occasion
will be quite different.
For example, the suggestion is
that instead of 400 soldiers,
400 representatives of the Princess's
charities march behind the coffin.
And, instead of foreign heads of state
and crowned heads of Europe,
the guests would include a sprinkling
of actors of stage and screen,
fashion designers
and other... celebrities.
Celebrities?
Oh.
Er... was there anything else?
No, ma'am.
Oh, yes, one other thing.
The police commissioner was keen
that you consider
the idea of a condolence book.
It would give the growing crowds
something to do,
make marshaling them easier.
Oh, yes. Yes, of course.
- Oh, and the flowers.
- What flowers?
The flowers outside Buckingham Palace.
They're blocking the main gate,
and making things difficult
for the changing of the guard.
Fine. Just move them away.
The Lord Chamberlain was wondering
whether we shouldn't leave the flowers
and send the guards
through the north gate.
Oh, yes. Yes, of course.
Yes, quite right.
Stephen Lamport on One.
- Who?
- Prince of Wales's private secretary.
- Balmoral.
- He says it's urgent.
It's all right.
- Good morning.
- Good morning, Prime Minister.
The Prince of Wales has asked me
to thank you for your kind words.
Not at all.
The Prince feels that you and he
are both modern men
of similar mind,
who could work well together
at this difficult time.
Er... well, please thank His Highness,
and assure him
he can count on my full support...
...at all times.
- Was that it?
- Er... yes.
Goodbye.
Bizarre.
- Why is Charles doing this?
- What?
Creeping up to me like this,
banging on about being modern.
He did it at the airport.
He knows that if the Queen
gets it wrong over Diana,
the royals will become
public enemy Number One.
- He's terrified of being shot.
- Who, Charles?
His people have asked
for extra protection.
He thinks if he's seen
to be on our side,
that will leave the Queen
in the firing line.
So it's OK for his mother
to take the bullet and not him?
What a family!
- Wait. Where are they?
- Up at Craggy Head.
- I'll come with you.
- In you go.
- Do you want me to drive?
- No. Certainly not.
- I thought you were getting a new one?
- What for? It's perfectly all right.
I was thinking
what Diana might have done
had it been me that died
in the tunnel in Paris.
She would have taken the boys
to Paris. I regret not doing that.
What, and expose them to the media?
That would have been dreadful.
They're better off here.
It's private. They're protected.
Whatever you thought of Diana,
she was a wonderful mother.
She adored those boys,
and never let them forget it.
Always warm, physical,
never afraid to show her feelings.
Especially if a photographer
was in sight.
She may have encouraged all that,
but still...
that was the extraordinary thing
about her -
her weaknesses and transgressions
only made the public love her more.
Yet ours only make them hate us.
Why do they hate us?
- Not us, dear.
- What?
Yesterday,
when we brought the coffin back,
there was a noise, a bang,
and I thought it was a gun.
I thought
someone had taken a shot at me.,
I think I'm going to walk back.
- I don't feel like stalking.
- Are you sure?
I'll take the dogs.
Walkies? Yes!
Who knows the way home? Come on.
'Do you think
you will ever be queen?'
No, I don't. No.
Why do you think that?
I'd like to be a queen
of people's hearts, in people's hearts,
'but I don't see myself
being queen of this country.
'I don't think many people
want me to be queen.
'By many people, I mean
the establishment I married into,
'because they've decided
that I'm a non-starter.'
Charles and I had a talk
in the car today.
He was good enough
to share his thoughts on motherhood.
- What did he say?
- How wonderful Diana was.
That's changing his tune.
He thought her natural.
'They see me as a threat
of some kind.'
Oh, for God's sake!
Maybe he's got a point.
Maybe we are partly to blame.
Oh, I can't watch this.
No, no. Wait. Please, no, leave it.
'I don't go by a rule book.
I lead from the heart, not the head,
'and it's got me into trouble
in my work.'
We encouraged the match.
We signed off on it, both of us.
You were very enthusiastic, remember?
She was a nice girl. Then.
And I was sure
he'd give the other one up,
or at least make sure
his wife toed the line.
- Isn't that what everyone does?
- Is it?
'Was Mrs. Parker Bowles a factor
in the breakdown of your marriage?'
'There were three of us in this
marriage, so it was a bit crowded.'
I can't bear it. If you're watching,
I'll sleep next door.
- Early start tomorrow.
- Any luck with your stag?
No. But close,
a couple of hundred yards at one point.
One of the boys even got a shot off.
We'll get him tomorrow.
See you in the morning.
Not to worry. Night-night.
'...and with her obsession
with the belief
'that Charles loved a woman he'd fallen
for years before, Camilla...'
The good news is the palace
agreed to video screens.
- And the bad news?
- Crash barriers.
- What about them?
- They expect over two million people.
There aren't enough barriers,
so we've gone cap in hand
to the French for theirs.
There's something else
I think you should see.
Can we run that piece again?
- Of course.
- You'll love this.
- '...find their behavior disgraceful.'
- 'What do you think?'
'I think it's disgusting that they've
not said a word relating to all this.'
- Look, I know all this.
- Wait for it.
'...not to have a flag up. I think
it's a disgrace on the royal family.'
'OK, the Queen's not in residence,
but where is the flag?
'Do you see what I'm saying
about the establishment?'
Don't tell me there isn't a flag
at half mast over Buckingham Palace.
'Dodi, when them two were together,
it was a fairy tale come true.'
Will someone please save these people
from themselves?
- Fine, I'll call Balmoral.
- Planet Zog?
I've really got nothing better to do.
Come on, dogs. Come on.
Those fire lighters all right?
A bit damp?
Oh, well,
I brought some stew just in case.
- It's lamb. We can have that cold.
- No, we'll be all right.
Stay.
Robin had a call from the Prime
Minister, who expressed his concern.
- About what?
- The flag above Buckingham Palace.
He thinks it should be flying
at half mast.
I hope Robin said there isn't a flag
above Buckingham Palace.
There's the Royal Standard, which flies
to denote the presence of the monarch.
Since you're here, the flagpole is bare,
just as it should be.
Isn't it possible that for some people,
the Royal Standard is just a flag,
and the flagpole being bare
sends out the wrong signal?
- No, that's not the point.
- The point is it's over 400 years old.
It's never been lowered for anyone.
Your grandfather didn't get
the flat at half mast when he died,
and if your mother died tomorrow,
she wouldn't either.
Yes, Granny, but in a situation
like this, one has to be flexible.
It is just a flag.
"What about the Union Jack?"
was Mr. Blair's next suggestion.
For heaven's sake!
Next, he'll suggest you
change your name to Hilda.
Who does the think he's talking to?
You're the sovereign.
You don't get dictated to. You conceded
the idea of a public funeral.
You've opened the parks.
That's enough.
Ssh. The boys.
You wait. In 48 hours,
this will all have calmed down.
In one sense, it's comforting.
Now, my parents can see
what it's been like for me,
being up against her popularity.
They're still making the mistake
of thinking the Diana they knew
will eventually be the one
seen by the public, but it won't.
The two Dianas, the public's and ours,
bear no relation to one another at all.
The flag of St. George,
it is at half mast over Highgrove?
- Yes, sir.
- Get a picture of that in the papers.
I'll get onto it,
call in a few favors.
What about a statement of gratitude
to the crowds?
Something heartfelt
from myself and the boys,
thanking people for the flowers
and so on.
Right.
'Di was wonderful, because
she stood up to the establishment.
'She said, "You're elitist people
we are paying to be better than us,
"'and you have to get out
among the people."
'We have a wonderful Prime Minister,
Tony Blair,
'a compassionate young man, who, after
18 years of establishment Tory rule
'is such a breath of fresh air,
'and I feel he will do something...'
- Is this the stirrings of...
- What?
I don't know.
Something more interesting.
Maybe people will see them
for what they are.
Which is?
A bunch of freeloading,
emotionally retarded nutters.
- That's just absurd.
- Why?
They live in a cocoon of wealth
and they don't pay tax.
- Yes, they do.
- The Queen costs us 40 million a year.
If you want a serious conversation
about the constitution.
We don't have one.
About ways in which we could phase out
hereditary privileges, then fine.
- If you're leaving, take the plates.
- Forget the 'off with their heads' bit.
- Why?
- It insults your intelligence.
'The Queen cannot be expected
to change.'
It's unimaginable,
this country being a republic.
- Certainly in her lifetime.
- Why?
Because no-one would wear it.
No-one wants it.
It's just... daft.
- It's not a mother thing, is it?
- What?
Well, if she were alive now,
your mother would be the same age.
You always say how stoical she was -
old-fashioned, uncomplaining,
lived through the war.
- Who does that sound like?
- I'm going to do the washing up.
That's the stalking party off.
Right, we'd better have a look
at those papers.
"Show us there's a heart in the house
of Windsor," says The Sun.
"It's proof the royals
are not like us," The Mirror.
"Time to change the old guard
at Buckingham Palace," Express.
"One can't help wondering
whose advice they are taking,
"for it's clearly the wrong advice."
I'll try not to take that personally.
People have yearned for change
in this country.
The result is a quiet revolution
led by the real modernizers,
the British people.
Revolution? Who wrote this?
- Where does this come from?
- Where does it come from?
- You've won a huge majority.
- People want a change.
Why? What did you think it meant?
Hurry, dear. Your tea's getting cold.
- Is that it?
- Yes, ma'am.
Just the letter of condolence to the
widow of the ambassador to Brazil.
Thank you.
Tea.
Mr. Janvrin, the Prime
Minister wishes to speak to Her Majesty.
Ma'am,
apparently the Prime Minister
is on the phone.
Tell him to call back.
No, no. It's all right. I'll take it.
- Prime Minister.
- Good morning, Your Majesty.
Sorry to disturb, but I was wondering
if you'd seen today's papers?
We've managed to look
at one or two, yes.
'In which case, my next question
would be whether you felt
'some kind of response
'might be necessary?'
No. I believe a few over-eager editors
are doing their best
to sell newspapers.
It would be a mistake
to dance to their tune.
'Under normal circumstances,
I would agree,
'but...
Well, my advisors have been'
taking the temperature
among people on the streets,
and... well, the information I'm getting
is that the mood
'is quite delicate.'
So, what would you suggest,
Prime Minister?
- Some kind of a statement?
- No, ma'am.
I believe
the moment for statements has passed.
'I would suggest flying the flag
at half mast above Buckingham Palace...
...and coming down to London
at the earliest opportunity.
'It would be of great comfort
to your people.'
And would help them with their grief.
"Their grief"?
If you imagine
I'm going to come to London,
before I attend to my grandchildren,
who've just lost their mother...
then you're mistaken.
I doubt there is anyone who knows
the British people more than I do,
nor who has greater faith
in their wisdom and judgment.
And it is my belief that they will,
at any moment, reject this... this mood,
which is being stirred up by the press
in favor
of a period of restrained grief
and sober, private mourning.
That's the way we do things
in this country -
quietly, with dignity.
It's what the rest of the world
admires us for.
If that's your decision, ma'am,
the government will support it.
- Let's keep in touch.
- Yes, let's.
Bloody fool!
And now your tea's gone cold.
Tony, Robin Janvrin on One.
He was listening in.
Robin?
I understand how difficult
her behavior must seem to you,
but try and see it
from her perspective.
She's been brought up
to believe it's God's will.
'She is who she is.'
I think we should leave God out of it.
It's just not helpful.
She hasn't seen anything like this
since the abdication,
and I cannot emphasize
the effect that had.
Unexpectedly becoming king
as good as killed her father.
'I'm afraid she's in a state of shock.
'This public reaction
has completely thrown her.'
All right, but first, we have to deal
with these terrible headlines.
- I'll do what I can with the press.
- I'm grateful, Prime Minister.
I can't promise anything.
It's not me they want to see.
Ask Alastair to come and see me.
Cancel what I'm doing tonight.
- Good morning.
- Your Majesty.
Thomas, where have they gone?
- Up to Abergannie Ridge, ma'am.
- All that way?
- Remind me, that's right at the fork?
- That's right, ma'am.
You follow the track for about a mile,
and you come to...
The river.
- One of the lads will drive you.
- No, I'll manage. Thank you.
Bugger it!
Oh, how stupid!
- 'Hello, Thomas.'
- Hello, ma'am.
I've done something foolish.
I've broken the prop shaft.
- Are you sure, ma'am.
- Yes, of course I'm sure.
It's the front one.
Lost the four-wheel drive.
Don't forget,
I was a mechanic during the war.
- Are you all right?
- I'm fine.
- We'll come out straight away.
- Thank you very much.
I'll wait by the car. You are kind.
Bye.
Oh, you're a beauty.
Shoo! Shoo! Go on!
Go on.
Go on!
There are news crews outside waiting
for you to speak to the people.
- Yes.
- What's all that about?
I told the Queen's private secretary
I'd try to help with the press.
Why? Don't you think she deserves it,
sitting up there on her 40,000 acres?
Yes, but allowing her to hang herself
might not be in our best interests either.
Besides, I think there's something ugly
about the way
everyone's started to bully her.
The first thing that you obviously
think about...
is the rest of your family, and I...
When's she coming to London, Mr. Blair?
- 'She's our figurehead.'
- 'She is.'
'She wanted me to pass on
to the people crowding around...'
'In a spare moment, the Prime
Minister went down Downing Street...'
- How are the boys?
- Not so good tonight.
A lot of slamming doors.
- I think they saw the papers.
- Oh, no!
I'll take them out
early again tomorrow morning.
Perhaps they'll take it out
on the stag.
'What do you think
of the royal family?'
'They've made a mistake.'
- Pardon?
- They've made a mistake.
- 'Why? What do you mean?'
- 'Well, they should've came.
'The family should have come down
to Buckingham Palace on Sunday,
'all of them.
'That girl's been left on her own.
'She's on her own
and the place is empty.'
Oh, please!
Sleeping in the streets
and pulling out their hair?
For someone they never knew?
And they think we're mad?
- Have you seen the funeral guest list?
- No.
I suggest you keep it that way.
A chorus line of soap stars
and homosexuals.
Apparently,
Elton John is going to be singing.
That'll be a first
for Westminster Abbey.
Condolence books are being signed
in embassies all over the world,
and in London alone,
the number has reached 40.
It reminds me of one of those films -
a few of us in a fort,
hordes of Zulus outside.
So, it's vital you hold firm.
Stick to your guns.
You wait.
They will come to their senses soon.
They have to.
Come on, move over, Cabbage.
'It's six o'clock
'on Thursday 4th September.'
'As people start camping out on the route
of Princess Diana's funeral cortège,
'people are asking why the Queen
hasn't addressed her subjects?'
'This is what the newspapers
are saying,
"'Where is our Queen?
Where is her flag?"'
The Express, "Show us you care."
A picture of a grumpy Queen.
The Mail,
"Let the flag fly at half mast,"
and inside, "The Queen should be here
to show her respects."
But the flip side is "Blair more
popular now than Churchill."
Did they pick up
on our statement of support?
Just the one.
Statements of support don't sell papers.
Right.
Ma'am! Ma'am!
The Prime minister for you, ma'am.
I'm afraid he's rather insisting.
I'll take it in the kitchen.
Good morning. Sorry to disturb you.
I'm expecting a phone call
to be put through. Out!
Oh, there it is.
Thank you, Peter.
- Good morning, Prime Minister.
- Good morning, ma'am.
You've seen today's headlines?
Yes, I have.
Then I'm sure you'll agree
the situation has become
quite critical.
'Ma'am?'
A poll that's to be published
in tomorrow's papers
suggests that 70% of people
believe your actions
have damaged the monarchy...
...and that one in four are now in favor
of abolishing the monarchy altogether.
As your Prime Minister,
I believe
it is my constitutional responsibility
to advise the following...
Is Queen Elizabeth up yet?
Mummy?
One, fly the flag at half mast
above Buckingham Palace
and all other royal residences.
Two, leave Balmoral and fly to London
at the earliest opportunity.
Three, pay our respects in person
at Diana's coffin.
And four, make a statement, via live
television, to my people and the world.
Swift prosecution of these matters
might, he felt,
just might, avert disaster.
You will have to talk
to the Lord Chamberlain.
I have, and to Robert Fellowes.
They both agree with Mr. Blair.
- Oh, I see.
- Something's happened.
There's been a change,
some... shift in values.
When you no longer understand your
people, maybe it is time to hand over.
Oh, don't be ridiculous.
Remember the vow you took?
I declare that my whole life,
whether it be long or short,
shall be devoted to your service.
Your whole life. That is a commitment
to God as well as your people.
What if my actions
are damaging the Crown?
Damaging it? You're the greatest asset
this institution has,
one of the greatest it has ever had.
No. The problem will come
when you leave,
but you mustn't think about that now,
not today.
Oh, Mummy.
You must show your strength,
reassert your authority.
You sit
on the most powerful throne in Europe,
head of an unbroken line that goes back
more than a thousand years.
Do you think any of your predecessors
would have dropped everything
and gone to London because
a bunch of hysterics carrying candles
needed help with their grief?
As for that silly Mr. Blair,
with his Cheshire cat grin...
Mr. Janvrin on the phone for you, sir.
Yes?
What?
I can't hear!
Well, that's madness!
The whole thing. Bloody madness!
I've just been told
you've decided we're to follow
the Prime Minister's advice.
I just want to say I...
admire...
I think it's the right decision.
Let's hope we haven't left it too late.
'These are historic shots
of the Windsors.
'The Queen has had a change of heart.
'She's clearly responding to the need
'to feel that the royal family is
somehow engaged.
'These flowers have been brought
to Balmoral
'so she can see some token
of what's been expressed in London.'
Fish fingers. Do you want any?
- I'll be right there.
Thank God for that!
I'm afraid they're a bit burnt.
'From CNN International,
this is World News
'with Ralitsa Vassileva
from CNN Center.'
Queen Elizabeth will deliver
a televised address, Friday.
The royal family has been accused
of showing little grief
over the Princess's death.
- Where are the boys? Have they left?
- Yes.
They left for London
after breakfast with Charles.
It's not right, you know.
No, but further discussion
is no longer helpful either.
Oh, well.
It gives the gillies time
to find another stag for the boys,
now theirs has been shot.
- What?
- Haven't you heard?
He wandered over
to a neighboring estate,
where one of the commercial guests
got him.
Oh.
Really?
Which estate?
Here's your box. There's some
policy unit stuff that's important.
- Have you seen the papers?
- I thought I'd skip them.
- Of course I've seen them.
- Not bad, eh?
"Your Majesty, come to London."
"Who says so?" "Tony Blair."
Mr. Father of the Nation.
Ma'am? Good morning, ma'am.
- Good morning.
- Is it his lordship you came to see?
No, please don't disturb him. I came on
another matter. I hope you don't mind.
There he is.
He's a beauty, isn't he?
An imperial, ma'am.
Fourteen-pointer.
- He was wounded.
- Yes.
We got our guests in very close,
had him lined up perfect...
...and still...
An investment banker, ma'am,
from London.
I'm afraid the stalkers had to follow
him for miles to finish him off.
Let's hope he didn't suffer too much.
Pass my congratulations to your guest.
I will, ma'am.
- God bless you, ma'am.
- Thank you.
- Ma'am...
- Yes, Robin?
I've done a draft
of your television address.
Thank you.
Was there anything else?
No, ma'am.
Landing in 15 minutes.
I've got the Queen's speech.
- Shall I give Tony a copy?
- Let me look at it first.
He's next door.
'...and the anger,
as somebody said earlier,
'perhaps was that people grieving
need to target their anger at somebody,
'and royal protocol
might have got in the way,
'but royal protocol
is being swept aside en masse today.'
Come back, Diana!
'...very serious,
'Her Majesty and the Duke.
'Normally, it is a happy occasion
when they arrive here,
'and normally,
when they're out the front,
'on days like Trooping the Color,
VE Day or VJ Day.
'This is a tragic occasion.'
'The Queen is getting out
to talk to people.'
'It's very unusual.
This is unprecedented.
'I think, perhaps the last time
the Queen was among her people
'outside the palace was the day
the war in Europe ended.'
'It's really as if the public
and the royal family, the monarchy,
'have had a bit of a quarrel and now
it's being healed in some measure.'
'Like a family spat, not unlike
the spats they acknowledged with Diana.
'Jenny is quite right to say that whatever
the professional ups and downs
'between the Queen and the Princess...'
They sent a copy of the Queen's
speech.
You might want
to scrape the frost off it first.
'I think the queen was generous
in recognizing
'that her oldest son wasn't
the easiest chap to be married to.'
I sent some suggestions to make it
seem like it came from a human.
Yeah, all right, Alastair.
At least the old bat agreed
to visit Diana's coffin.
When you get it wrong,
you really get it wrong.
That woman has given her whole life
in service to her people,
50 years doing a job she never wanted,
a job she watched kill her father.
She's executed it with honor, dignity,
and without a single blemish,
and now,
we're all baying for her blood!
She's leading the world in mourning
for someone who threw all she offered
in her face,
and who, for years, seemed committed
to destroying
everything she holds most dear!
Hello. Would you like me
to place those for you?
- No.
- Oh.
These are for you.
For me?
Thank you.
Thank you very much.
Ma'am, there's been a last-minute
addition from Downing Street.
They're suggesting adding,
"and as a grandmother" here.
Right.
"So, what I say to you now,
as your Queen, and as a grandmother,
"I say from my heart."
Do you think you can say it?
- Do I have a choice?
- They're ready for you, Your Majesty.
- Just to confirm, this is live.
- Fine.
You'll be at the front of the six o'clock
news on all channels.
Yes.
Thank you.
- OK, nice and quiet.
- Ten seconds.
'We cross, now, live,
to Buckingham Palace
'for the Queen's tribute
to Princess Diana.'
Since last Sunday's dreadful news,
we have seen, throughout Britain
and around the world,
an overwhelming expression of sadness
at Diana's death.
We have all been trying,
in our different ways, to cope.
It is not easy
to express a sense of loss,
'since the initial shock
is often succeeded by other feelings,
'disbelief, incomprehension, anger
and concern for those who remain.
'We have all felt those emotions
in these last few days,'
so what I say to you now,
as your Queen, and as a grandmother,
I say from my heart.
Heart? What heart?
She doesn't mean a word of this.
That's not the point.
What she's doing is extraordinary.
'In good times and bad...'
- That's how to survive.
- Listen to you.
A week ago,
you were the great modernizer,
making speeches
about the people's princess.
- Now you've gone weak at the knees.
- Ssh.
'...and for her devotion
to her two boys.'
I don't know why I'm so surprised.
At the end of the day, all Labor prime
ministers go gaga for the Queen.
What?
'Millions who never met her,
but felt they knew her, will remember her.
'I, for one, believe there are lessons
to be drawn from her life,
'and from the extraordinary
and moving reaction to her death.
'I share in your determination
to cherish her memory.'
I hope that, tomorrow, we can all,
wherever we are,
join in expressing our grief
at Diana's loss
and gratitude
for her all-too-short life.
May those who died rest in peace,
and may we, each and every one of us,
thank God for someone
who made many, many people happy.
'Diana's coffin, now on the move
'the short distance
from St. James's Palace,
'to her home at Kensington Palace
before her burial tomorrow.
'It's incredible. Less than a week.
'Who could have imagined
such scenes?'
Diana was the very essence
of compassion, of duty,
of style, of beauty,
a very British girl,
who transcended nationality,
someone with a natural nobility,
who was classless,
and who proved
that she needed no royal title
to continue to generate
her brand of magic.
I would like to end by thanking God
for the mercies he's shown us
at this dreadful time,
for taking Diana
at her most beautiful and radiant,
and when she had joy in her life.
Above all,
we give thanks for the life of a woman
I'm so proud
to be able to call my sister,
the unique, the complex,
the extraordinary
and irreplaceable Diana,
whose beauty,
both internal and external,
will never be extinguished
from our minds.
So, off to see your girlfriend?
Now, now...
I hope she shows you
some respect this time.
It's quite a debt of gratitude
she owes you,
Mr. Savior of the Monarchy.
I doubt she'll see it that way.
- Robin.
- Prime Minister.
Tony, please.
The Prime Minister, Your Majesty.
Do sit down.
Thank you.
It's good to see you again,
after what's been... quite a summer.
I'm referring to your visit
to India and Pakistan...
where your comments on ending historic
disagreements went down well.
At the Commonwealth
Heads of Government Meeting,
I spoke to the prime minister of Malawi.
He said how much he appreciated
your tough stance on Nigeria.
I meant to tell you at the time,
but, er...
...you were being monopolized rather.
I imagine those occasions
must be quite difficult,
24 heads of government, each
clamoring for a private audience.
Also, we haven't had a chance to speak
since... that week.
- I wanted to offer my apologies.
- Whatever for?
In case you felt manhandled
or managed in any way.
No, not at all.
I don't think I shall ever understand
what happened this summer.
Well, the circumstances
were exceptional, ma'am...
...and in the end, you showed
great strength, courage and humility.
- You mistake humility for humiliation.
- That's not true.
You didn't read the cards
on the flowers outside the palace.
I think history will show
it was a good week for you.
And an even better one for you,
Mr. Blair.
But there are 52 weeks
in the year, ma'am,
and two and a half thousand
in the time since you've been Queen.
When people assess your legacy,
they won't remember those days.
Oh, really?
You don't think that what affection
people once had for...
for this institution
has been diminished?
No. Not at all.
You're more respected now than ever.
I gather some of your advisors
were less fulsome in their support.
One or two,
but, as a leader, I could never add
my voice to that chorus.
You saw the headlines and thought,
"One day, it might be me."
And it will, Mr. Blair, quite suddenly,
and without warning.
So, shall we get on
with the business in hand?
Oh, look...
Oh, I do love this time of day.
Shall we walk while there's light?
The clocks go back next week.
It'll be dark before five.
- I do hope you're a walker.
- I am.
Good. I think meetings have
a greater chance of success
if the Prime Minister is a walker.
It's how I think best, on my feet.
I've never been one for sitting around.
A good walk in fresh air
sorts everything out.
One in four, you said,
wanted to get rid of me?
For about half an hour,
but then you came down to London,
and all that went away.
I've never been hated like that before.
It must have been difficult.
Yes. Very.
Nowadays, people want glamour
and tears, the grand performance.
I'm not very good at that.
I never have been.
I prefer to keep my feelings to myself,
and, foolishly, I believed that was
what people wanted from their Queen -
not to make a fuss,
nor wear one's heart on one's sleeve.
Duty first, self second.
That's how I was brought up.
That's all I've ever known.
You were so young
when you became Queen.
Yes.
Yes, a girl.
But I can see
that the world has changed,
and one must... modernize.
Well, perhaps that's where I can help.
Don't get ahead of yourself,
Prime Minister.
I'm the one
supposed to be advising you.
Come, dogs!
Tell me, Mr. Blair, what might we expect
from our first parliament?
Er... well, ma'am,
top of the list is education.
We want to reduce classroom sizes.
Yes.
And create a lower teacher-pupil ratio.
Subtitles by International
Broadcast Facilities