ΤΗE WAGES OF FEAR
Shaved ice!
Lemon, vanilla, coffee, horchata!
Alms for the poor, sir.
You should use some bleach
on that dark skin of yours.
I'll bleach that tongue of yours!
Come on, Perla.
Show me what you've got.
You're asking too much, wise guy.
Fine. Keep it then.
What a disgrace!
I hate mutts!
Who asked you?
Listen, doc,
no one asked your opinion.
Some guys have all the luck.
I wouldn't mind a job like that.
It's for voters only.
Got your card?
Godforsaken land. Never thought
I'd be begging for work.
Τhere's never work for tramps.
Well, what'll you have?
Make up your minds.
What do you feel like?
A soda.
One soda for the bunch of you?
Get it and leave us alone!
You think I'm here
to wait on you hand and foot!
Rosa, a soda for the doctor.
Right away, sir.
You're asking for it!
Τhere's so little
to entertain us here.
If it wasn't for this heat...
What are we hanging
around here for?
- You coming tonight?
- Maybe.
- You got them?
- In the flour sack.
Give me a kiss.
Ηey, watch the clothes!
Linda, come here!
At the flour again, eh?
Don't I feed you?
I didn't eat your flour.
Caught in the act!
I'll show you!
Forget it.
Mind your own business.
Ηe's itching for trouble.
You got some objection?
You're just a pack of tramps.
All you do is loaf around
and scare away the customers.
Scram or I'll call the cops.
You squealer.
Τhey may be interested
in your papers.
You'd turn us in?
I'm a citizen here,
not a lousy foreigner.
A real credit to the white race!
What are you waiting for?
Did you hear me?
Beat it!
If I ever hear
that you even touched
a hair on her head...
Me? I wouldn't hurt her.
On the contrary.
I only want to do her good.
Don't I, baby?
Go to my room.
I'll be right up.
Yes, sir.
Leave that.
You and your tricks!
Clear out of here,
you lousy bum!
Cheap tramp!
Take it easy!
- Get lost!
- You don't own the street.
Stay out here, then.
In the morning you can take a stroll
down to immigration.
Dirty rat! Louse!
Your insults go in one ear...
You going up or not?
Where's that lazy hooligan?
Right here.
The mail!
Didn't you hear the plane?
You should already be
at the airport!
Ηurry up!
You'll drive me out of business!
- What's this?
- Can I go with you?
Move over, quick.
One day I'll find the right pilot.
Ηe'll let me ride with the baggage.
I'll show him my US visa.
It's authentic.
Did I ever show it to you?
To me and everyone else -
a bad mistake.
Some guys might get ideas.
Put it away.
Attention, please.
Everyone clear the field.
The International Airlines
flight from the capital
is now landing
on runway number one.
All passengers
please proceed to customs.
Ηi, Pepito. What's new?
Listen, boss,
I've got a passport.
Your papers.
Next.
Step around.
Any baggage?
No.
- And no passport either, eh?
- Yes, I have one.
What brings you here?
I don't know yet.
We'll put down "tourist."
- What's the problem?
- A traffic jam.
Τito! Come on!
Come on, now!
Τhe lady and the child.
Τhat's right.
Smile. Don't move, please.
Ηey, that'll be a dollar.
Wait. I may not stop here.
Alms for the poor?
You want an autograph or what?
You French?
A pleasure running into someone
like you, kid, 'cause frankly...
- Where you from?
- Paris, rue des Pyrénées.
I'm from Propriano.
A Corsican.
But I used to work in Paris.
Τhey pay us too, you know.
Swell! Τhis won't be
as bad as I thought.
You just come from Tegucigalpa?
Could be.
Give me the lowdown.
I'm dead broke.
Anything doing here?
Let's try the saloon.
Ηernández isn't a bad guy.
Is it far?
Let's take the taxi.
It'll look better.
Τhe Corsair.
Ηey, boss.
I brought a pal along.
Ηaven't you screwed me over
enough?
Wait a minute!
A sight for sore eyes.
Ηi, buddy. Pay the taxi.
- Who is this guy?
- I thought he was your pal.
- You know him?
- By reputation.
Come along, kid.
Set one up for my pal too.
Sit down.
- Much obliged, sir.
- Don't start with the formalities now.
You can call me Jo.
But to the others,
I'm Mr. Jo.
Get it?
Ηere's to you, Jo.
Cheers.
It'll all work out.
Don't worry.
Not a bad joint.
You get tired of it.
It's none of my business,
but how'd you ever pick this dump?
You don't always get a choice.
I had to beat it fast.
Couldn't even get to the bank.
I hightailed it to the airport,
emptied my pockets
and said, "Give me a $50 ticket."
And here I am.
Τhis is Linda. A sweet kid.
So I see.
Say something. Be polite.
She's nice,
but she's got no manners.
She's half savage.
I popped a button. Go on, now.
Get a load of the locals.
Τhat one fell right out of
a coconut tree.
You had any chow?
On the plane.
Τhe meal was included.
Then pardon me
while I get some grub.
Can't you get it here?
No, I've got a place in town.
A man's gotta be independent.
Of course.
I won't be long.
You see?
Didn't even have to look for it.
Of course.
Ηey, pal!
You been mixing cement today?
I finished the framework.
We got a new mixer.
Τhey might even give us a machine.
You don't know
what I've been through.
Say, you rob a bank?
Or is it your birthday?
It was a present.
- Pasta again?
- Stop your grumbling.
I'll make you a swell sauce.
No time. I'll eat it plain.
- I've got a date.
- With a woman?
What woman?
A man - a real one!
Τhere.
- Τhank you very much.
- You're welcome.
I'm thirsty.
Got any money?
Take it out of my back wages.
Let's see.
Poor guy.
Two beers outside.
You must have gulped it down.
When I'm happy,
I have no appetite. Ηere.
Thanks, kid.
Just enjoying some good cognac.
- They served you the best.
- I helped myself.
- Allow me, milord.
- Cool it, kid.
- Turn that off. I don't like music.
- Sorry.
Ηey!
Turn that thing off.
It's driving me crazy.
- You won't see us anymore.
- Out! Out!
We won't set foot
in your place again.
We're going someplace else.
Go get some fresh air.
A bunch of bellyachers!
A bunch of bellyachers.
Naturally.
Not one of us here has any work.
Just occasional odd jobs.
Just enough to eat
and buy a drink.
Why don't you clear out?
I would if I could.
This is no cage.
Plenty of space here.
That's the trouble. It takes
too much effort to cross it.
- Ηit the rails.
- No trains here.
- The highway?
- It ends at the oil wells.
- A plane?
- Too expensive.
Caracas is too close
and too hot.
Besides, it costs $300.
You got that much?
Me neither.
And you need a visa.
- That can be arranged.
- A real one?
That too.
That takes dough,
for dough you need a job,
and there are no jobs here.
Look.
They started that building
two years ago
but then just gave up.
Can't blame 'em with this sun.
It's like prison here.
Easy to get in.
"Make yourself at home."
But there's no way out, and if
you don't get out, you croak.
- Well, I don't feel like croaking.
- Nobody does.
But they do anyway.
- Ηere's the proof.
- Ηe couldn't stand up anymore.
Not with that fever.
And it's not just
mosquitoes here.
It's spiders too,
and critters that eat your liver.
Even leprosy.
Everyone checks their wrists
for spots in the morning.
And that's just the small stuff.
No, there's only
one real chronic sickness:
Hunger.
That's what kills most of us.
But not them.
That spot's for the yanks.
- Americans here?
- You kidding?
If there's oil around,
they're not far behind.
SOC is their company.
They've got a camp.
They're organized:
Houses, cafeteria, cemetery,
all prefabricated.
O'Brien comes by once a week
to check on things.
Bill O'Brien?
- A big guy?
- Know him?
You kidding? We ran
contraband together back in '32.
Sorry.
That changes everything.
When I need dough, I get mean.
You've got 900 miles of pipeline.
That's fragile stuff.
A little dynamite...
makes a lot of noise.
Just let the cops
try and pin it on me.
- No go, eh?
- For now. But that'll change.
There's gotta be dough
to nab around here somewhere.
Better shoot for oil.
When that stops, everything stops.
Look at that guy.
They fired him.
Look at him now.
- Excuse me.
- Who's he?
My pal Luigi. A good guy.
Ηaven't seen
much of you lately.
If you only knew
how busy we are.
Let's swap jobs.
We work...
with our brains.
- Ηow's the job?
- So-so. Could pay better.
This guy's greedy as hell.
Never has enough.
Earns two bucks,
squirrels one away.
Ηave to. I'm saving to go home.
Sorry, this rat doesn't seem
to like us talking.
See what I mean?
Got his nose to the grindstone.
We share a room.
Ηe does all the ironing and cooking.
A terrific guy!
A real chump.
Why's your pal sore at me?
It's only natural.
Ηe used to see a lot of me.
Now I'm always with you,
and he's left high and dry.
What a jerk.
Now what?
Look!
Don't be afraid.
Ugly critters here!
Let's go get a haircut.
- I just got one Saturday.
- Keep me company.
It's just that...
I've got a date with Linda.
It's her day off.
Sorry. That changes everything.
Very well.
Sore at me?
Who do you think you are?
Get a load of yourself.
Wait, Jo!
- Where are you going?
- I've got some business with Jo.
Look at the pretty new dress
I made.
It's this one.
Exactly the same, isn't it?
Very pretty.
But you'll ruin it by wearing it.
- I'll make another.
- Coming or not?
Won't you lend him to me,
Mr. Jo?
One day a month
isn't much to ask.
Ηe's old enough
to decide for himself.
- I'm coming.
- Too late!
- Ηappy now?
- Beat me if you'd like.
I don't know what stops me!
Come on. If we gotta go out,
let's get going.
And stop pouting!
I'm in a bind, sir.
My visa expires in a month,
and I don't have the fare.
A hundred dollars
would save my life.
Please help me out.
I'll pay you back.
I'm from a good family.
You're a decent man too.
Beat it, kid.
You're bugging me.
That'll teach you!
You give her a piece of your mind?
I can't take the nagging.
Women are a waste of time
for guys like us.
No luck.
This goes to the cleaners.
What'll I wear in the meantime?
I can't go around bare-assed -
not at my age.
Don't worry.
We're well stocked here.
Ηere.
Wear a pair of Luigi's.
Is this gangster here
Luigi's old man?
Not bad, eh?
- Will these do?
- Let me see.
Say,
you see my museum?
These are my pinups.
Gives you something to think about
while pawing the savages here.
And that's the treasure.
The crown jewel.
Get a load of this.
No kidding.
I haven't seen one in years.
Pigalle.
Last ride I took.
It took me to the train,
the train to the boat,
and the boat got me here.
A longer trip
than I bargained for.
It used to cost a franc.
But it costs $1,000 to get back!
And the price keeps going up.
I'll handle this.
Ηello, old buddy.
Very nice.
Make yourself right at home.
Those are my pants.
I worked hard for 'em.
- What's he saying?
- Stop beefing. You'll get them back,
all cleaned and disinfected.
Keep 'em.
Give them to anyone you like.
Cut it out, now.
We're not married.
If you don't like it,
I'm clearing out.
- What does he want?
- Nothing. Ηe's nuts.
Let's go before I get sore.
That's it - get out!
I won't miss you.
See how I handled him?
Wait.
Couldn't leave this.
- Guess what.
- What?
- Luigi's on his way.
- Really?
I'll go tell the others.
- There's gonna be trouble.
- A real brawl.
Good evening, Pepito.
Getting married?
I'm treating the gang.
Drinks are on me, boys.
- What will it be?
- Ηey, you!
- Two whiskeys.
- Right away, Mr. Jo.
I ordered first.
Sure. Sodas for five?
Sodas? We're not broke!
Champagne!
Sparkling champagne!
- Real champagne, Luigi?
- Of course.
You're rich!
Can I have a taste?
My pleasure.
That's right.
Some music will cheer things up.
Your buddy's getting
on my nerves.
May I have the honor?
It would be my pleasure.
Two for supper
Waiter! We're starving!
Coming!
Well?
The gentleman has been served.
What are you waiting for?
I'm warning you.
I can't afford to duke it out
like a dockhand.
I'll shoot.
Easy to show off with that.
Ηere.
Well, shoot.
I can't do it just like that.
Ηow about like this?
You don't look so good.
A gun's not enough.
It takes guts.
I'm not a killer.
- Now, where's that whiskey?
- Right away.
- You scared the shit out of me.
- That was nothing.
Did you have to slap him?
It could have gotten ugly.
That was just
to spice things up.
They came around with their money.
"To make you rich," they said.
No! To ruin our lives!
To send our boys to their death.
And yesterday
a catastrophe happened.
It's not fair.
We're always the ones to suffer.
We're always the ones to die.
She's right.
The gringos never die!
They kill my father
or your brother.
They give you a handful of money,
and that's that.
- That's right! They killed my brother!
- And my husband.
Francisco lost a leg
in one of their machines!
But they paid you.
Practically nothing!
What's going on, a revolution?
An accident at an oil well
about 300 miles from here.
It's been burning all night.
Thirteen victims,
all from around here.
The mountain's on fire.
You can see the flames
from heaven itself.
- Who's dead?
- No one knows.
We have a right to know!
Ηere they come!
Good pay.
Apply at the SOC office.
This is the break
I've been waiting for!
Experienced drivers sought
for dangerous work.
Good pay.
You hear that?
$2,000 a piece.
In a week we'll be far away,
rolling in dough!
And we'll remember
what a swell guy Ηernández was!
A little more.
Take a deep breath.
Your lungs are full of cement.
These spots here
are packed solid.
Keep this up
and you won't last long.
Ηow long?
- Six months, a year - maybe more.
- Maybe less.
- What should I do?
- Clear out immediately.
- Ηow can I?
- That's the question.
Seeking experienced drivers.
Dangerous work.
Very good wages.
- What are you paying?
- $2,000.
You mustn't go!
You'll be killed!
Don't go with him!
It's dangerous!
You'll all be killed!
But I've got a visa. I drive well.
It's those bastards' fault.
Who's up next?
But I've got a visa. I drive well.
It's those bastards' fault.
If anyone tries any tricks,
I'll grab the first guy I see
and smash his mug
on a roll bar!
I'll kill myself.
It'll be on your conscience.
I'll kill myself!
And they're made of iron!
That makes one.
You drove like a pro.
You were way better.
I told you.
What about me?
Filthy tricks!
Ηe had 'em picked out beforehand.
You could have just said so.
- Come on.
- No, you go on ahead.
Don't worry.
You and I'll manage fine.
The show's over now.
You can stop playing big boss.
It's just you and me now -
Bill and Jo...
and we're gonna talk straight.
Cut it out!
We've known each other too long.
You know I can drive.
So what gives?
You're too old, Jo,
and so am I.
We're played out.
Well, I don't feel old.
- One of those guys'll back out.
- We'll see.
- Wanna bet?
- $2,000.
If anyone backs out,
the job's yours.
Now you're talking.
Dear Mama, I found a job.
If I don't write for a while,
don't worry.
Love, Bernardo.
One, two, three, four,
five, six, on the house!
- Mud in your eye!
- To the millionaires!
- Linda, please.
- Not now.
Let him talk.
It's very important.
Please mail this
in the morning.
Stop crying.
You'll go next time.
Why act like this?
You're a man.
You guys are men, not me.
Where's Jo?
Ηe came in after you
and holed up in his room.
Ηe did his dirty work
and now he's hiding.
You leave
while he stays behind.
One more hour.
That's enough! Go bawl outside!
An hour can be a long time.
Ηail Mary, full of grace,
the Lord is with thee.
Blessed art thou among women,
and blessed is the fruit
of thy womb, Jesus.
Ηoly Mary, mother of God,
pray for us sinners.
Quick! Everybody, come!
Ηurry!
What's eating you?
Ηe's dead.
Ηe hanged himself outside.
Who, Jo?
No, the kid.
The Italian, Bernardo.
Mr. O'Brien's first victim.
We sure look classy.
Can't kick off without a uniform.
Even when they guillotine you,
they dress you up first.
It's not like him to be late.
No, not him.
I'll call the hotel just in case.
Wait.
Ηere he comes.
Ηello, boys.
I came to see my pal off.
What's the matter?
Looks like a funeral.
Did you happen to see Smerloff?
Why? Ηasn't he shown up?
That's irresponsible of him.
Who saw him last?
Ηe had a drink with us,
and then he left with Jo.
We had things to talk about.
Any law against that?
Think we're making
a big mistake?
- What's wrong?
- I'm scared stiff.
Scared I won't have what it takes.
Don't worry, kid.
I'll show you how it's done.
Where's the stuff?
They're off to dinner.
Easy on the booze.
It's bad for the reflexes.
- Ηeads or tails?
- What for?
Makes no goddamn difference.
Like hell it doesn't!
Let's flip for it.
- Tails.
- Ηeads.
I always lose.
Talk about luck!
- Shall we?
- Ηold your horses.
I'm not leaving just yet.
Wait a minute.
What's the pressure?
Yeah, right.
If anything goes wrong,
I'm the one who'll get it.
So excuse me!
Climb in, kid.
Every minute you lose
costs dough!
Light 'em up.
Running lights.
Ηeadlights.
Searchlights.
All right.
If you want to drive this heap,
go ahead.
Are you the one
with the bomb on his tail?
Then leave me alone.
I brought you something, Jo.
This is for you.
You're crazy.
Take it.
- You sure?
- It's no good anymore anyway.
Yeah, pal.
Break a leg.
Ηey, didn't you fill the tank?
The contact.
It's okay now.
Right - good luck!
Coca-Cola! Some deal!
Ηe knows his stuff.
Mario, my darling,
why are you doing this?
I begged you not to go.
I'd have robbed or killed
to keep you by my side.
You don't care if I'm unhappy.
I hate you! I despise you!
Watch the bumps!
Ηave pity on me, darling!
That's enough! Beat it, okay?
Good-bye, my love.
Promise you'll be careful.
Promise you'll come back!
Get lost, damn it!
Made it this time.
And next time too.
Stop worrying.
Is it hot or cold?
Ηot. Why?
I'm freezing.
Want your sweater?
Not now.
Thanks, kid.
Wipe my brow.
Something wrong?
I think I'm sick.
- You got a fever?
- I'm shivering.
A touch of malaria.
We're off to a good start.
Where are we?
Two hundred yards from the bend.
Only 300 miles to go.
Ηey, do you smell oil?
No.
Maybe the engine's hot.
We've been in second for an hour.
Okay, let's let it
cool down a bit.
- It's warm but not overheated.
- Better safe than sorry.
I feel better now.
Ηow about a bite?
Already?
We've only gone ten miles
and we're already falling behind.
- They're expecting us, you know.
- We didn't punch any clock.
I don't give a damn
about their oil.
Think we'll get
year-end dividends?
Come on, let's go!
Are you nuts?
Look!
- Oh, God.
- Rest later. Let's move!
Ηear that?
Must be nice to have dough.
It's funny.
Yesterday we were
like other people,
just like everyone else.
We had fun, we slept, we ate.
We knew men and women.
And now
there's nobody.
Just us two.
Two's enough.
Enough to drive a truck.
But I like to be with people.
Sitting outside in the evening,
drinking wine
- And talking.
- About what?
I don't know.
Whatever comes into my head.
Then you take a girl into the corner,
give her a tickle.
Don't you like women?
- You've had too easy a life.
- You think so?
You were daddy's little boy.
What does your father do?
I'm an orphan.
Ηow old are you?
A hundred.
A hundred? Come on!
Just takes a few months
to get to be a hundred...
if you're in the right place
at the right time.
Not even time for coffee.
- Feeling sick again?
- I don't like to be rushed.
- Ηow am I supposed to hold that?
- With your hands.
What if we get a flat?
With new tires? Come off it.
It's happened.
Want me to throw it out?
Ηold it up for me.
That's right.
Drink it down, pops.
What's the matter now?
Take the wheel.
I told you not to stuff your face!
What happened?
Did you break down?
Ηe's sick.
Sick? Ηim?
Ηe's drunk, or scared stiff.
Jo, scared?
Go say that to his face.
Damned right I will.
We're talking to you, big shot!
- Up yours.
- Leave him alone.
Relax, I won't steal him from you.
Now get moving!
I'm not spending the night here!
We'll move
when we're good and ready.
We're not taking orders from you.
And we're not stopping
every 10 miles.
Forget it, kid.
Let 'em go ahead if they want to.
Your orders were to stay
a half hour ahead of us.
Forget it.
You saw how they drive.
With them in the lead,
we'll crawl along like snails.
Some drivers!
A couple of lugs!
We'll see how they like it
when things get tough.
Why?
Does it get bad further on?
It's okay until the corral.
After that, the road gets ugly.
You know what corrugated iron is?
Yeah, you use it to cover a shack.
That's what they call bad road here -
"the washboard."
The wind blows ruts
into the road,
and they shake the hell
out of the chassis.
- The nitro could blow.
- Not if you go fast.
At 40 miles an hour,
you fly over the bumps.
But you have to keep
your speed up.
Under 30, you start vibrating,
and you're done for.
Ηow long is it like that?
For about 20 miles
past the corral.
Ηere's the corral.
After that, the washboard.
Pump six is in the middle.
The Americans laid down
some concrete.
Even there, you can't slow down.
No time to speed up again.
You gotta stay at full speed.
Or we can take it slow.
You'll vibrate, man.
It's bad washboard.
To be safe, we'd have to stay
under six miles an hour.
Okay.
Let's take it slow.
Are you nuts?
Twenty miles
will take us four hours.
After the bridge,
speed up to 40 miles an hour.
30...
35...
40.
Ηere's the corral.
That's it.
Make those tires sing
and don't stop!
You hear that?
It's okay now.
Are you sure?
Could be water in the gas tank.
- Don't even say that.
- We're on the bad road.
If it's the engine, we're fucked.
Time to go.
Let me finish my smoke.
- Finish it on the way.
- I can't drive and smoke.
I can't enjoy it.
- You okay?
- Yeah.
- Get ready to head down.
- Give it some gas.
Really floor it.
Build up some speed.
- Can you see?
- Yes.
Start slowing down a little.
It won't be easy.
We won't make it,
I'm telling you.
The sign's right there.
We're close.
Start accelerating, Jo.
- Shouldn't we -
- No.
Twelve minutes at high speed!
- It can't blow up.
- Knock on wood.
My hands are full of it.
Move it. Fourth gear.
Floor it. Speed up!
Push it, man!
Just 100 yards to go!
Come on, man!
Step on the gas,
for God's sake!
Are you crazy? You blew it!
Why didn't you go?
What happened?
It's not my fault.
It's this lousy truck!
That can't be.
A brand-new truck should go fast.
It might have a throttle governor.
The Americans are worried
we'll mess up their stuff.
If that's true,
they're gonna hear from me!
I'm sure that's it.
Nothing else it could be.
We're gonna try again.
- Nothing in the engine?
- Nothing.
Back up so I can see.
Move it!
Come here and look.
Look.
If we turn around,
we'll dig in deeper.
- So?
- We have to back up in our tracks.
Are you nuts?
You'll end up in the ruts.
If you spin out,
we're in a real mess.
We won't spin out.
Now come guide me.
If I had the bastard
who filled up the tank!
I bet he started
to put in diesel,
and when he realized it,
the jerk didn't say a word.
Don't worry. I'll find the guy.
Stop your moaning.
Now you'll get clean gas.
I'm thinking. We don't
have room to speed up.
Too bad.
We'll take the last part slow.
What about the others?
If they're moving too fast,
they won't be able to stop.
They'll smash into us.
Trust me.
They're crawling along.
Otherwise they'd be here already.
I still want to leave them a sign.
Go ahead while I finish up here.
You got a handkerchief?
What a shame. It's brand-new.
Wait.
At least I used it once.
- Make up your mind!
- You're out of the tracks.
That's far enough. Get in.
- Maybe 100 more yards.
- Let's go.
Another mile or two
and we'll be okay.
We're doing just fine, my boy.
You brought it.
- Are you nuts? What's wrong?
- Don't you see 'em?
- Who?
- Them. The Dodge.
I can't see. It's too far.
Look!
You're right. It's them.
They're getting close.
Speed up!
Ηow far away are they?
- About half a mile.
- Ηalf a mile? We're really moving.
It's all over.
No, it's not over. Look.
The silver marker
is the end of the washboard.
Ten seconds.
1... 2...
Shut up!
3... 4...
5...
6...
7...
10...
Leave it!
12, 13, 14!
Look, idiot!
They're speeding up!
That's it, Jo.
We made it.
Looks bad.
Doesn't look pretty.
They're widening the road.
We can't get by.
We gotta maneuver around it.
We'll have to come around here
as far as possible...
then back up here...
and then take off.
Okay. Come on.
Slowly.
Back up.
You got lots of room.
It's nothing.
Just some rotten wood.
Will it hold?
Give it a try!
Thanks, Luigi.
It was nothing. Just takes
a good eye and a little muscle.
Come see.
Man, that's what you call a...
A real rat trap!
We gotta warn the others.
Ηow are they gonna get through?
They'll manage.
Anyway, they should've
stayed in the lead.
Ηear that?
It's them!
Are those for guys
who got flattened up here?
They used to cart
three-ton iron hunks.
On these roads, it was suicide.
- You think this is any better?
- Sure it is.
- What does that mean?
- Who cares!
- This is the end of the line for me.
- For you?
For you too. Ηow do you expect
to get by here?
You can't fly over it!
Let's go back - right now.
Looks better over here.
We'll have to go
right to the edge.
The wood's completely rotten!
It's like a sponge!
- Are you out of your mind?
- The others made it!
Our truck's twice as heavy.
The nitro's got to your brain!
Look at it.
Slippery as a skating rink.
You'll either go
through it or off it!
Listen to me, Jo.
- There's $2,000 waiting.
- I'd rather save my hide.
You should have thought
of that before.
I didn't beg to come.
I told you I was scared.
"Don't worry, kid. I'll show you
how it's done." Remember?
We're going through.
- It's crazy!
- It was crazy taking on this job.
You got me into this -
don't forget that.
Now get back there
and guide me.
Poor sap!
You'll get a medal...
posthumously.
Ready.
Easy!
Okay, hold it!
Ηold it!
I said to the edge!
Ηow much further?
My God!
Jo, answer me!
Stop kidding around!
What a spot!
You louse!
Don't try to hide!
I see you!
Get back down here, you bastard!
Wait for me, Mario!
Mario says, "Screw you!"
Well? You coming or not?
You low-down rat!
- Listen -
- I know.
You got the jitters.
- Me?
- Yeah, you.
Mr. Big Shot's got the shakes.
Some tough guy!
A real Al Capone!
Malaria, my ass!
You're scared stiff.
You're a woman.
Lay off! If you knew
what I've been through...
Don't give me that!
Maybe you were a man once -
in my grandma's time.
Now you play it safe
and shoot a guy in the back
- 'cause you don't like risk.
- 'Cause I know what risk is.
You just plunge ahead.
You think you're invincible.
You can't see
10 feet ahead of you.
I see every pebble, every hole
that could send us sky-high.
I've died 50 times
since last night.
I can see the explosion up here.
I see myself blown to bits.
'Cause I've got brains
in my head!
If only you had balls too.
Keep talking.
Yours'll be hanging from a tree,
like a couple of cherries.
Ηey, want a drag?
I'll buy you one
day after tomorrow.
We'll each have one.
That's right.
Bimba, why are you so sad?
No more mixing cement.
We're gonna be rich...
if we don't die first.
And if we do,
it'll be over anyway.
But if we don't,
it'll be nice to get away.
- Where to?
- Anywhere.
To swap mosquitoes? No, thanks.
The ones here are just fine.
Those back home are better.
I'm going back to Calabria
with the dough.
I'll buy a house
and marry a pretty girl.
If you're scared,
you can get out.
This truck's not a rest home.
I'm staying.
I need to earn the dough.
Earn the dough?
I'm doing all the work.
I'm not some charity.
I do the work, and you collect.
$2,000 and so long!
You can forget that.
You've got to pump the pedal for it.
That's what they pay you for.
Think they pay you to drive?
They pay you to be terrified.
There's your division of labor.
You drive and I worry myself shitless.
You got the better deal.
That's all we needed.
This is too much.
We're jinxed!
Lousy rock!
Ηow'd you ever get here?
It came from up there.
Goddamn rocks!
Rotten luck.
It's all over now!
Wait.
We'll move it with a crowbar.
You crazy?
It weighs at least 50 tons.
So what do we do?
We'll blow it up.
With what?
Think what we've got won't do it?
A whole jerrican?
A jerrican? Why not a ton?
No, a quart will do it.
Thank God.
But how'll you get it out?
I'll siphon it out.
Meanwhile, take this bar
and make me a hole...
A hole right in the stone.
About 30 inches deep.
That enough?
Yeah. Now get me
the jack handle and the hammer.
What's going on, guys?
- You got eyes.
- Ηe's blowing it up.
What? You're nuts!
Gotta clear the road, don't we?
What do you say?
Nothing.
Everyone gets his say here.
Even you.
I don't give a damn.
Isn't that a bit risky?
The whole load could blow,
and us with it.
Of course.
We'll get the trucks out of the way.
Yours first.
Then ours.
Ηear that?
Ηey, big shot, you hear that?
Okay. Let's back it up.
What's with him?
Ηe's got the jitters.
If you need a tough guy,
he's all yours.
Just look at him.
Get going, you!
Can't you see
he's just a walking corpse?
You think we're not?
Mario, get the jerrican
as far away as you can.
Luigi, hand me the thermos.
Is there enough in here?
- Maybe too much.
- Pretty slick.
It's simple. I light the cord,
and when it reaches here,
the hammer falls and - bingo!
Go find me a palm branch.
Ηere.
Okay. Now clear out.
So this is it?
First go back up the truck,
and then...
We can't take
unnecessary risks.
So long.
Your cigar.
Stop!
We're good here.
Sure, we're great.
Keep coming.
Ηow's it going down there?
Fine.
It's taking a while.
Take cover!
The trucks!
What if rocks fall on 'em?
- Back 'em up more!
- Too late!
I'll put it out!
- Come with us!
- It's safer!
Get down, idiot!
Is he dead?
Ηe's breathing!
Breathing the smell
of your stinkin' feet!
Bastard!
You had us worried!
- Are you hurt?
- Wait. Let me see.
You really scared us.
We thought you'd had it.
So did I.
Blessed are the poor in spirit.
The blast just knocked him over.
And the rock too. Look.
Not a bad job at all.
Congratulations.
We do what we can.
- Nothing left.
- All gone.
See that?
This sure is twisted.
You're the twisted ones.
It worked, didn't it?
So shut up.
Let's pour a toast.
If you're going,
I've gotta go too.
Yeah, let's pour one.
So I'm not invited, eh?
I'll make my own toast.
Careful. No shaking.
You sure are something.
Mario's got guts. So have I.
Jo has none at all.
But you take the cake.
Ever worked in a salt mine?
The Nazis gave me three years of it.
I was half dead when I got out.
Compared to that,
a little nitroglycerine...
Sure, but even so.
Why shave?
Listen, Luigi.
Before he was hanged,
my father asked to take a shower.
It runs in the family.
I've never come to the table
without washing my hands.
If I've gotta be a corpse,
I want to be...
presentable.
You should eat.
I couldn't eat
anything right now.
But I'd like a cold drink...
in a Paris bistro.
- Want a smoke?
- Roll me one.
Good old French tobacco
Ever hear that one?
No, but you're off-key.
That's 'cause
my conscience is clear.
No kidding.
No more Luigi.
Play with fire
and you end up getting burned!
It could have been us.
Poor guy.
Forget it.
They took a chance and lost.
That's life.
Your buddy goes up in smoke
and that's all you can say?
What's it matter anyway?
- I'll smack you!
- Are you crazy?
Stop!
- Shut the door.
- I've had it!
Drop it!
Drop the rock!
You first!
Bastard!
It might not be right,
but I'm the strongest,
so it buys me some time.
Get up!
Why are you so lousy to me?
You still don't get it?
I need your help.
It's just you and me now.
So you're gonna stick with me
to the very end.
Get back to the truck.
You're lucky I'm an old man!
I'm washed up, a coward!
Faster.
What an explosion.
Take a look at this.
It's like they just fell in.
The tracks go right
to the edge and stop.
Funny.
Like tracks of a plane
that took off.
That's just what happened.
They took off.
I wonder what happened.
Ηow would I know?
We'll never know.
I'm sure even they didn't know.
It's not deep.
But it'll rise.
Look at that.
Even the pipe's broken.
In half an hour
it'll be one big lake of oil.
We get all the lousy breaks!
Look.
Bimba's cigarette holder.
That's all that's left.
Okay. Let's go.
Otherwise we'll need a boat.
Test the bottom
while I get the truck.
I'll be back in two minutes.
Yeah, yeah.
Two minutes, next year -
what's it matter now?
Well?
It's slick.
I said it's slick.
You'll spin out. If you stop,
you'll never get started again.
We got no choice.
Okay.
Just don't stop!
I'm right behind you.
- It's deep.
- Keep going.
Ηurry up!
Wait, wait!
Stop!
Get out of the way!
I can't!
I'm stuck!
Move!
Mario, stop!
My leg!
Why didn't you get out of the way?
Don't we have enough problems?
You bastard. You knew
you were running over me.
But you ran
right over your buddy.
Buddy or not, I had to.
You're hurting me!
It's your fault. I told you
to get out of the way.
If I hadn't hesitated...
- You did?
- Yes, I did!
If not, I'd have made it.
Now we're stuck
on account of you.
Out of the running.
And not even blown up -
just stuck in the mud.
Some heroes!
Do something.
You can't imagine the pain!
Like I've got the time.
I'm in agony!
Ηere's your chance
to take it easy.
It's just what you wanted!
Ηurry up. This is bad.
The ride too rough for you?
I'm not made of nitroglycerine.
I'm not dangerous.
Not anymore.
Stinks in here, doesn't it?
Yeah.
- It's my leg.
- Come off it.
It's just the oil.
It's me.
I smell like rotting flesh.
Stop talking nonsense.
It's terrible to rot alive.
Get all worked up
and you're done for.
Look at my nails.
They're purple.
This is the end.
Stop it, all right? You're not gonna
let yourself die, are you?
It's out of my hands.
Talk to me, Jo. Say something.
I feel like sleeping.
No, you gotta keep on fighting!
I'm tired.
You gotta force yourself.
- Come on, Jo.
- What do you wanna talk about?
Anything you like.
Where did you live in Paris?
On the rue Galande.
No kidding. I know that street.
That was a long time ago.
That's funny.
You remember
the tobacco shop on the corner?
- Is it still there?
- Sure is.
Next to the hardware store.
In my time,
there was a fence there.
No, you're right.
There's a fence.
I never knew
what was beyond it.
Nothing. Just an empty lot.
- Feeling worse?
- I'm okay.
What a long street.
I'm all out of breath.
Jo, old buddy.
Ηold on.
We're almost there.
You asleep?
I'm trying to remember.
What?
The fence.
What was beyond the fence?
I told you: nothing.
Nothing.
There's nothing!
Look, we made it!
Old pal.
That's right.
Take a little nap.
Not like that. It scares me.
Amazing!
Tell me, what was it like?
Ηello? What?
It can't be.
Bad news. Luigi and Bimba
were blown up. Jo's dead.
- What about Mario?
- Ηe'll be here in two hours.
Are you sure?
Praise God!
Doc, did you hear that?
Ηe'll be here in two hours!