My name's Marlowe.
The general wanted to see me.
Yes, Mr. Marlowe.
Will you come in, please, sir?
- I'll tell the general that you're here.
- Thank you.
Morning.
You're not very tall, are you?
Well, I tried to be.
Not bad-looking...
...though you probably know it.
Thank you.
- What's your name?
- Reilly. Doghouse Reilly.
That's a funny kind of name.
You think so?
What are you? A prizefighter?
- No, I'm a shamus.
- What's that?
- A private detective.
- You're making fun of me.
You're cute.
The general will see you now, sir.
- Who's that?
- Miss Carmen Sternwood.
You ought to wean her.
She's old enough.
- This is Mr. Marlowe, general.
- How do you do, sir?
- Sit down, sir.
- Thank you.
Brandy, Norris.
- How do you like your brandy, sir?
- In a glass.
I used to like mine with champagne.
Champagne cold as Valley Forge...
...with about three ponies
of brandy under it.
Come, come, man!
Pour a decent one.
I like to see people drink.
That'll do, Norris.
You may take off your coat, sir.
Thank you.
Too hot in here for any man
with any blood in his veins.
You may smoke too.
I can still enjoy the smell of it.
Nice state of affairs when a man
has to indulge his vices by proxy.
You're looking, sir, at a very dull
survival of a very gaudy life.
Crippled, paralyzed in both legs.
Little I can eat, and
my sleep is so near waking...
...it's hardly worth the name.
I seem to exist largely on heat,
like a newborn spider.
The orchids are an excuse
for the heat.
- Do you like orchids?
- Not particularly.
Nasty things.
Their flesh is too much
like the flesh of men.
Their perfume has the rotten
sweetness of corruption.
Tell me about yourself.
There isn't much to tell.
I'm 38. I went to college.
I can still speak English
when my business demands it.
I worked for the
district attorney's office.
Inspector Bernie Ohls
said you wanted to see me.
You didn't like working
for the district attorney?
I was fired for insubordination.
I seem to rate pretty high on that.
I always did, myself.
What do you know about my family?
Well, you're a widower,
a millionaire.
You have two daughters.
One unmarried...
...and one married to a man
named Rutledge, but it didn't take.
- Both living with you and both...
- Go on, sir.
Both pretty and both pretty wild.
- Why'd you want to see me?
- I'm being blackmailed again.
Again?
About a year ago, I paid a man
named Joe Brody $5000...
...to let my younger daughter alone.
What does that mean?
It means, "Hm!"
It didn't go through the DA
or I'd have heard.
- Who handled it for you?
- Shawn Regan.
There must be some reason why
he isn't handling it this time.
Shawn has left me.
- I thought I hadn't seen him lately.
- A month ago, without a word.
I had no claim on him.
I was only his employer.
But I had hoped that he'd come
to regard me as something more.
And that at least
he'd have said goodbye.
That's what hurt.
You knew him too?
Yes, in the old days when he
used to run rum out of Mexico...
...and I was on the other side.
We swapped shots
between drinks...
...or drinks between shots.
My respects to you, sir.
Few men ever swapped more than
one shot with Shawn Regan.
He commanded a brigade
in the Irish Republican Army.
But you knew that.
No, I didn't.
I know he was a good man
at whatever he did.
No one was more pleased than I
when you took him on as your...
...whatever he was.
My friend.
My son, almost.
Many an hour he sat with me,
sweating like a pig...
...drinking brandy and telling
stories of the Irish Revolution.
Well, enough of that.
Here.
Read the other side.
These her signatures?
- Who's Arthur Geiger?
- I haven't any idea.
- Did you ask her?
- No, and I don't intend to.
If I did, she'd just suck
her thumb and look coy.
I met her in the hall
and she did that to me.
Then she tried to sit on my lap
while I was standing up.
Well?
Your other daughter, Mrs. Rutledge.
She mixed up in this?
They alike?
They're alike only in having
the same corrupt blood.
Vivian is spoiled, exacting...
...smart and ruthless.
Carmen is still a little child who
likes to pull the wings off flies.
I assume they have
all the usual vices...
...besides those they've
invented for themselves.
If I seem a bit sinister
as a parent, Mr. Marlowe...
...it's because my hold
on life is too slight...
...to include any
Victorian hypocrisy.
I need hardly add that any man
who has lived as I have...
...and who indulges, for the first
time, in parenthood at my age...
...deserves all he gets.
Well?
Pay him.
- Why?
- She signed these notes, didn't she?
Who's this Joe Brody
you paid the $5000 to?
I can't recall.
My butler, Norris, would know.
I think he called himself a gambler.
Geiger says these are gambling debts.
They may be.
Think they are?
You want me to take this Geiger
off your back, right?
Want to know anything?
I just want to get rid of him.
Might cost you a little.
Thanks for the drink.
I enjoyed your drink
as much as you did, sir.
- You'll hear from me.
- Good luck.
Mr. Marlowe, Mrs. Rutledge would like
to see you before you leave.
About the money, the general
has instructed me...
...to give you a check
for whatever you require.
Instructed you how?
I see, sir. I forget
that you're a detective.
By the way he rang his bell, sir.
- You write his checks?
- I have that privilege.
Good for you.
I don't need any money now...
...but when I do, I get
$ 25 a day and expenses.
- How did she know I was here?
- She saw you through the window.
I was obliged to tell her
who you were.
I don't know as I like that.
Are you attempting
to tell me my duties, sir?
Just having fun trying
to guess what they are.
This way, sir.
- Go right in. You're expected.
- Thanks.
You wanted to see me?
So you're a private detective?
I didn't know they existed,
except in books.
Or else they were greasy men
snooping around hotel corridors.
You're a mess, aren't you?
I'm not very tall either.
Next time I'll come on stilts, wear
a white tie and carry a tennis racket.
I doubt if even that would help.
Now, this business of Dad's,
think you can handle it for him?
It shouldn't be too tough.
I'd have thought
it took a little effort.
Not too much.
What will your first step be?
- The usual one.
- There's a usual one?
Sure there is.
It comes with diagrams...
...on page 47 of How to be a
Detective in Ten Easy Lessons...
...and your father
offered me a drink.
You must've read one
on comedy.
- Hear what I said about the drink?
- I'm serious. Father's...
- I said your father...
- Help yourself!
Now, look, Mr. Marlowe,
my father's not well.
I want this case handled with
the least worry to him.
That's the way
I was going to handle it.
I see. No professional secrets?
- I thought you wanted a drink.
- I changed my mind.
Then, what...
- How'd you like Dad?
- I liked him.
He liked Shawn. Shawn Regan.
I suppose you know who he is.
You don't have to play poker with me.
- Doesn't Dad want to find him?
- Do you?
Of course. It wasn't right
for him to go off like that.
Broke Dad's heart,
although he won't say much.
- Or did he?
- Why don't you ask him?
I don't see what there is
to be cagey about.
I don't like your manners!
I'm not crazy about yours.
I didn't ask to see you.
I don't mind if you don't
like my manners. I don't either.
I grieve over them evenings.
I don't mind your drinking
your lunch out of a bottle.
But don't waste your time
cross-examining me.
People don't talk to me like that!
Do you always think
you can handle people...
...like trained seals?
I usually get away with it too.
How nice for you.
Just what is it you're afraid of?
Dad didn't see you
about Shawn, did he?
Didn't he?
Could you find him
if Dad wanted you to?
Maybe. When did he go?
About a month back.
Drove off one afternoon
without saying a word.
They found his car parked
in some private garage.
They? Who's they?
Dad didn't tell you.
He told me about Regan, but that's
not what he wants to see me about.
That's what you wanted me to say.
I'm sure I don't care
what you say, Mr. Marlowe.
I'm wasting your time.
Goodbye, Mrs. Rutledge.
Oh, Norris.
You made a mistake. Mrs. Rutledge
didn't want to see me.
I'm sorry, sir.
I make many mistakes.
- Did you find what you wanted?
- Yes, thanks.
You don't look like a man who'd
be interested in first editions.
I collect blondes in bottles too.
Can I be of any assistance?
Would you happen
to have a Ben Hur, 1860?
- A what?
- Do you have a Ben Hur, 1860?
A first edition?
No, no, the third, the third!
The one with the erratum on page 116.
I'm afraid not.
How about a Chevalier Audubon,
1840, full set?
Not at the moment.
You do sell books?
What do those look like? Grapefruit?
They look like books.
Maybe I'd better see Mr. Geiger.
- He's not in just now.
- That's a pity because...
I said, Mr. Geiger is not in!
I heard you.
You needn't yell at me.
I'm late for my lecture on
Argentine ceramics, so I won't wait.
The word is "ceramics".
And they ain't Argentine,
they're Egyptian!
You did sell a book once, didn't you?
I'll run along to the library.
Or I could go to that bookstore
across the street, couldn't I?
Do so.
Thank you.
Is there something I can do for you?
- Would you do me a small favor?
- It depends on the favor.
- You know Geiger's bookstore?
- I think I may have passed it.
You know Geiger by sight?
What's he look like?
Wouldn't it be easier to go
and ask to see him?
I've already done that.
Know anything about rare books?
You could try me.
Do you have a Ben Hur,
1860, third edition...
...with a duplicated line
on page 116?
Or a Chevalier Audubon, 1840?
Nobody would. There isn't one.
The girl in Geiger's bookstore
didn't know that.
I see.
You begin to interest me, vaguely.
I'm a private dick on a case.
Perhaps I'm asking too much...
...although it doesn't seem
too much to me.
Geiger's in his early forties...
...medium height...
...fattish...
...soft all over,
Charlie Chan mustache...
...well-dressed...
...wears a black hat...
...affects a knowledge
of antiques and hasn't any...
...and I think his left eye is glass.
You'd make a good cop.
Thanks.
Gonna wait for him to come out?
They don't close
for another hour or so.
And it's raining pretty hard.
I got my car and...
That's right.
It is, isn't it?
It just happens I got a bottle
of pretty good rye in my pocket.
I'd rather get wet in here.
Well!
Looks like we're closed
for the rest of the afternoon.
- Tell me more about this business.
- There isn't much to tell.
What's the matter?
I'm just wondering if you have to...
Not necessarily.
Little things like that make an...
Hello!
I hate to tell you, but that's
Geiger's car driving up.
Who's the man getting out?
Geiger's shadow.
His name's Carol Lundgren.
Thanks.
- If you ever want to buy a book...
- A Ben Hur, 1860?
With duplications.
So long.
So long, pal.
You're cute.
And you're higher than a kite.
Come on, wake up.
I know you. Doghouse Reilly.
- You're cute.
- What do you know about this?
Mr. Geiger, here on the floor.
He's cute too.
You got a dead man at your feet.
How did it happen?
You talk a lot, Reilly.
Come on!
Lie down there and be quiet.
All right, Reilly.
Come on, we're going.
- Good evening.
- Is Mrs. Rutledge in?
- No, sir.
- The general?
- He's asleep.
- Good. I got something in the car.
She's all right.
Is the maid around?
Yes, I'll get Matilda.
Now wait a minute.
Not as I'm leaving.
I haven't been here.
You haven't seen me at all.
Kid hasn't been out of the house.
I understand.
May I get you a cab?
No, I'm all right.
Put her car away.
- Hello, Bernie. Come in.
- Hello, Phil.
Don't you ever go to bed?
What you been doing?
Just sitting around.
All evening?
What is it?
Does it have to be something?
You're a friend, but when
a man from Homicide...
...just drops in at 2 a.m.,
I kind of...
Working on cipher, huh?
Just fooling around.
You're working for the Sternwoods,
right?
Thanks to you.
Done anything for them yet?
I started today.
Then the rain came.
All right. They seem to be
a family that things happen to.
There's a Packard
belonging to them...
...washing around in the surf
off Lido Pier.
And there's a guy in it.
Couldn't be Regan, could it?
Shawn Regan.
That Irish ex-legger
old Sternwood hired...
...to do his drinking for him?
What would he be doing down there?
What would anybody
be doing down there?
That's what I'm going to Lido
to find out. Wanna come?
Yeah, I do.
- How's the weather?
- Clearing up.
- What time did that call come in?
- About 15 minutes ago.
- What kind of car you say it was?
- Packard.
- Hello, Bernie.
- Hi, Ed.
I see he's out.
Who is he?
Owen Taylor. Sternwood's chauffeur,
according to his license.
- What's the story?
- You can see it from here.
There's where he went
through the railing.
The rain stopped here about 9 p.m.
The broken rails are dry inside.
That would put it about 9:30.
Let's have it, doc.
His neck's broken and something
hit him across the temple.
What made the bruise?
Steering wheel?
Whatever it was, it was covered.
The wound had bled under
the skin while he was alive.
- Blackjack?
- Could be.
Bernie, funny thing.
The hand throttle is set
halfway down.
Thanks, Jim. So long, doc.
All right, boys. Take him away.
- Could be drunk or a suicide.
- Yeah, but it isn't.
You know anything about Owen Taylor?
Only that a few
Sternwood chauffeurs...
...lost their jobs because
of the younger daughter, Carmen.
Tell me what
you're working on, Phil.
They told me blackmail.
Who were they after? Carmen?
This doesn't look like
the way you'd handle it.
You know, I got a feeling that...
Me? I didn't do this.
What were you going to say, Phil?
Give me another day, Bernie.
I may have something for you.
Okay. Let's go home.
- I'm back again. Remember me?
- I'm afraid I...
Do you remember me now?
Now, see here!
That was only a stall
about those first editions.
I got something to sell.
Something Geiger wants. Is he in?
No, he isn't.
You might come back tomorrow...
Drop the veil.
I'm in the business myself.
Is he sick?
I could go to his house.
No, that wouldn't do.
If you'd come back tomorrow...
Say, Agnes, you...
Come on, Carol.
Hurry up, will you?
- Perhaps...
- His name's Lundgren, isn't it?
- What do you want?
- Who's the other guy?
You'd better come tomorrow.
In the morning? Early?
Because it looks like
you're moving today.
All right, driver. Let's go!
Around the corner, then take it easy.
- Where are we going?
- Follow a car. A tail job.
I'm your girl, bud.
It wouldn't be bad.
That station wagon coming out
of the alley. That's the one.
Here, sugar.
Buy yourself a cigar.
If you can use me again sometime,
call this number.
Day and night?
Night's better.
I work during the day.
- Good morning.
- You do get up.
I was thinking you worked in bed,
like Marcel Proust.
- Who's he?
- A French writer.
Come into my boudoir.
You don't put on a front.
Not much money in this work
if you're honest.
Are you honest?
- We're starting that again?
- I'm sorry. Also, about yesterday.
- Perhaps I was rude.
- We were both rude.
You want to see me about Taylor?
So you know about that.
- Poor Owen.
- The DA's man took me down to Lido.
He knew more about him than I did.
He knew Owen Taylor wanted
to marry your sister.
Perhaps it wouldn't
have been a bad idea.
You see, he was in love with her.
But I didn't come here about Owen.
You still can't tell me
what my father wants you to do?
Not without his permission.
You can't even tell me
if it was about Carmen?
You better look at this.
A messenger brought it today.
"Eight thirty-five".
That's right.
She takes a nice picture.
They want 5000 for
the negative and prints.
The demand came how?
A woman phoned me
after it was delivered.
- What else?
- There has to be something else?
This thing isn't
worth $5000 to anybody.
- They think it is.
- Why?
She said if they didn't
get the money today...
...I'd be talking to my sister
through a wire screen.
She said there was a police jam
connected with it.
What kind of a jam?
I don't know.
You know where
this picture was taken?
- I haven't the slightest idea.
- Or when?
Talk to Carmen about it?
She was asleep when I left.
She was sick last night.
- She go out at all?
- Servants say she didn't.
You?
I was out all evening.
Police already checked that.
Go ahead and scratch.
What was Owen doing
with your car last night?
Nobody knows.
He took it without permission.
- Why? You think...
- That he knew about this?
I don't rule him out.
Outside of what the woman said...
...you don't know why
they want $5000 for it?
That's why I came to you.
There's five fingers on any glove.
Why didn't you go to the police?
You were afraid they'd find
something I couldn't sit on.
Then where would the Sternwoods be?
May I use your phone, Mr. Marlowe?
Police headquarters, please.
Hello, this is Mrs...
Hello. What do you want, please?
What?
I called you?
Say, who is this?
Sergeant Reilly?
There isn't any Sergeant Reilly here.
Wait a minute.
You'd better talk to my mother.
Hello. Who's this?
The police?
This isn't a police station.
If you know it, why did...
Look, this is not a police station!
What was that you said?
My father should hear this.
Hello. Who is this?
Yeah, but she just told you that...
You're the police!
He's the police.
Well, that's different.
What can I do for you?
I can do what?
Where?
Oh, no! I wouldn't like that,
and neither would my daughter.
I hope the sergeant
never traces that call.
You like to play games, don't you?
Why did you stop me phoning?
Because I'm working for your father.
Or because I think I'm beginning to
like another one of the Sternwoods.
I prefer the second reason.
Well, let's get back to business.
Have you got $5000 in cash?
- Can you get it?
- I think so.
- Where from, your father?
- I'd rather not.
Where would you get it?
Well, from Eddie Mars.
The gambler?
That explains why you
haven't got $5000 in cash.
- I like gambling.
- So do I.
- How do you know he'll give it to you?
- I can get it.
I've been a good customer
of Eddie Mars'.
Another reason:
There's a bond between
Mr. Mars and the Sternwoods.
You see, Shawn Regan ran off
with Eddie's wife.
That doesn't interest you?
It might make it easier
for me to find him.
If I were looking for him.
Is Regan mixed up in this?
No. Shawn's not in any
cheap blackmailing scheme.
I'm glad you said that.
Do you want to tell me now?
- Tell you what?
- What you're trying to find out.
You know, it's a funny thing.
You're trying to find out
why I was hired.
And I'm trying to find out why you...
You could go on forever,
couldn't you?
It'll give us something
to talk about next time.
Among other things.
Oh, Mrs. Rutledge.
You wanted me to do something
about this, didn't you?
That call, how'd you leave it?
She's to call me at 6 p.m.
with instructions.
Phone me when you've heard from her.
Since you're going
to pay five grand for these...
...you'd better take this.
Goodbye, Mr. Marlowe.
Well, it wasn't intentional.
Try it sometime.
- What are you...
- Remember me? I'm Doghouse Reilly.
The man that didn't grow very tall.
What's the matter?
Couldn't you get in the house?
Come on. I've got a key.
- Where'd you leave your car?
- Around in back.
Looking for something?
How much do you remember
about last night?
Remember what?
I was sick last night. I was home.
Before you went home.
In that chair there.
You remember, all right.
Quit your stalling
and stop biting your thumb!
- Were you the one who was here?
- How much do you remember?
Are you the police?
No, I'm a friend of your father's.
Who killed Geiger?
Who else knows about it?
What, that he's dead?
I don't know.
Not the cops, or they'd be camping
here. Was it Joe Brody?
Joe Brody. Who's he?
I don't know how much trouble
you're used to...
...but I hope you've had plenty
of practice dodging it.
Did Brody kill him?
Kill who?
Yes, Joe did it.
He did?
Why?
I don't know.
But you're ready to tell
the police he did it?
That is, if we can get
the photograph.
You mean...?
It's gone. I looked for it.
Brody took it with him.
I've got to go home now.
I wouldn't say anything
to the police about Brody just yet.
about anything.
That you were ever here.
Not even to your sister.
Just leave it to Reilly.
Your name isn't Reilly...
Excuse the casual entrance.
The bell didn't answer.
Mr. Geiger around?
We don't know where he is.
We found the door open
and just stepped in.
- Friends of his?
- Business.
We dropped in for a book.
Any message if he comes back?
No, I don't think so.
We won't bother you.
Just a minute.
The girl can go.
- I'd like to talk to you.
- Suppose I don't want to talk?
I've got two boys out in the car.
It's like that, eh?
Run along, angel.
Your story doesn't sound right.
That's too bad.
Got a better one?
Maybe I can find one.
Blood.
Quite a lot of blood.
Is that so?
- Do you mind?
- No, I'm used to it.
I think we'll let
the police in on this.
- We'll have some law...
- Yeah. Why not?
Who are you, soldier?
Marlowe.
I'm a private detective.
- Who's the girl?
- A client.
Geiger tried to throw a loop on her.
We came to talk.
- Convenient, the door being open.
- Wasn't it? How'd you have a key?
- That your business?
- Could be.
I could make yours mine.
You wouldn't like it.
The pay's too small.
All right, I own this house.
Geiger's my tenant.
- Now what do you think?
- You know some nice people.
I take them as they come.
Got any good ideas?
One or two.
Somebody gunned Geiger.
Or somebody got gunned
by Geiger, who ran away.
Or he had meat for dinner
and likes to butcher in the parlor.
No, I don't like it either.
Maybe you'd better call downtown.
I don't get it.
I don't get your game.
Don't you, Mr. Mars?
Wondered why you didn't
ask me who I was.
You're telling me Geiger was
in a racket of some kind.
- What racket?
- I wouldn't know.
But I'll tell you
something you missed.
Somebody cleaned out
Geiger's store today.
You talk too much.
You really got those boys outside?
Open the door.
Open it yourself.
I already got a client.
It's all right.
Just proving something.
While you're here, look him over.
- Pardon me.
- Who is he?
Philip Marlowe, Hobart Arms,
Franklin Street.
Special license,
deputy badge and all.
All right, outside.
- A shamus.
- The man said, outside.
He said that.
That's what the man said.
He kills me.
Is he any good?
Who? Sidney?
He's company for Pete.
All right, talk.
Not to you.
I already got a client.
Who cleaned out Geiger's store?
Lots of weather we're having.
Did it rain at Las Olindas?
I might make it worth your while.
I might make it worth yours.
What do you care
who cleaned out Geiger's store?
- I could make you talk.
- It's been tried.
And?
Why don't you call the cops?
I think you'd better
get out of here.
By the way,
how's Mrs. Mars these days?
You take chances, Marlowe.
I get paid to.
Mrs. Rutledge. I've been
waiting to hear from you.
I'm sorry.
I have nothing to tell you.
- She didn't call?
- No, she didn't.
Did you get the money
in case she does?
I have the money. I'll get in touch
with you as soon as she calls.
All right, I'll stay
right here until you call.
Geiger?
- You said what?
- Arthur Geiger.
The guy with the blackmail racket.
- I don't know anybody by that name.
- You're Joe Brody?
- So what?
- So you're Joe Brody.
And you don't know Geiger.
That's very funny.
You've got a funny sense of humor.
Take it somewhere else.
Joe, you got Geiger's stuff.
I got his sucker list.
Don't you think we ought to talk?
Now!
All right. If you think
you got something.
You alone, Joe?
Except for this.
My, my, such a lot of guns
around town and so few brains.
You're the second guy
today that thinks...
...a gat in the hand
means the world by the tail.
Put it down, Joe.
The other guy was Eddie Mars.
You ever hear of him?
If he gets wise to where you were
last night, you'll hear of him.
What would I be to Eddie Mars?
I don't know if you don't.
Look, don't get me wrong.
I'm not a tough guy.
Just careful.
You're not careful enough.
That play with Geiger's stuff
was terrible.
Don't kid yourself I won't
use this if I have to.
What's your story?
Why don't you ask
your friend to come out?
She must get tired
of holding her breath.
Come on out, Agnes.
Hello, sugar.
I knew you were trouble.
I told Joe...
Ask Mrs. Rutledge to come out too.
What did you come for?
- Why'd you lie to me?
- I don't need you.
Keep out of it!
I don't want you here.
Will you get out?
But he won't let me.
He's curious, bothered and wondering.
You bet I'm wondering
and I'll find out.
- Sit down.
- Stop waving that gun.
I didn't do anything.
Can't you talk without that?
Don't argue with the man.
- You're ruining things.
- I'm not. If you'd...
Say, look!
What are you up here for?
To keep her from paying you off,
and to take the cops off your neck.
What cops?
The cops that want to know
where the lead in Geiger came from.
Look, Joe, you shot Geiger.
- I didn't know...
- The cops don't yet.
He wasn't alone
when you shot him.
Either you didn't notice that
or you got scared and ran away.
But you had nerve enough
to take the film.
And nerve enough
to come back and hide the body.
- You're crazy!
- Shut up!
So you could clean out the store...
...before the law knew
there was a murder.
You take chances. It's lucky
for you I didn't shoot Geiger.
But you can step off for it anyway.
You're made-to-order for the rap.
You think you've got me?
- Positive.
- How come?
I told you, there was a witness.
Now don't go simple on me.
You mean Carmen.
She'd say anything.
So you have got that picture.
I guess you think I'm dumb.
Just average, for a grafter.
You see, either you were
there last night...
...or you got the picture
from somebody who was.
You knew Carmen was there...
...because you had your girlfriend
threaten Mrs. Rutledge.
The only way you could have known
was by being there...
...and seeing what happened.
Or having the picture.
Make sense?
Who are you?
A guy who gets paid to do
people's laundry.
And all I'll get out
of it is that picture.
How about some dough?
I'm down to nickels.
Not from my client.
Get the picture, Joe.
Stay right there.
Here. Watch him.
- Take it easy.
- I want my picture.
- Now...
You shot Geiger.
Hold it!
Get up. You look like a Pekinese.
And since I'm collecting guns...
Sit down, sugar.
Now where were we?
Oh, yes, you were just about
to get something.
There better not be
any more prints.
There won't be.
Can I have my picture now?
Can I have my gun?
Later.
You're cute. I like you.
This is nothing. I got a Balinese
dancing girl tattooed on my chest.
You better take her home.
I suppose I should thank you.
No, just don't lie to me next time.
Come on, Carmen.
Hold it, Joe.
You got off easy, Joe.
What's the matter, sugar?
- He gives me a pain...
- Goes for me too.
You got the photos.
Get out.
- Where's the pain?
- In my...
Get out!
Not yet. We got a few things
to straighten out.
I told you to get out.
What difference does it make now?
Why'd you put the bee
on Mrs. Rutledge?
I tapped the old man six months ago.
I figured it might not work twice.
Why'd you think
Mrs. Rutledge wouldn't tell him?
- How well do you know her?
- We'll pass that.
I figured she might have a thing
or two she wouldn't want him to know.
That's a little weak,
but we'll pass that too.
Say, Joe, how'd you get that picture?
You got what you came for,
and you got it cheap.
I don't know anything about it.
Do I, Agnes?
- But you just gave it to me.
- A half-smart guy.
That's what I always draw.
Never once a man who's smart
all the way around the course.
Did I hurt you much?
You and every other man.
Where'd you get that picture?
It fell out of somebody's pocket.
- Got an alibi for last night?
- I was here with Agnes.
That's a great witness.
You can only die once,
even for a couple of murders.
A couple of murders?
I mean two murders. Where were you
about 7:30 last night?
Where were you?
All right, I was watching
Geiger's place.
Why?
- To get something on him.
- Look at me while you're talking.
It was raining hard
and I was in my car.
There was a car out front and another
down the hill. I was in back.
- Who else was back there?
- Nobody.
There was a big Packard near
where I was, so I took a look.
It was registered to the Sternwoods.
Nothing happened, so I got tired
of waiting and I went home.
Know where that Packard is now?
It's in the sheriff's garage.
It was fished out of 12 feet of water
off Lido Pier this morning.
There was a dead man in it.
It was pointed toward
the pier and the throttle pulled out.
- You can't pin that on me.
- I can try.
Sit down, Joe.
The dead man was Owen Taylor,
Sternwood's chauffeur.
He went up to Geiger's
because he was sweet on Carmen.
He didn't like the games
Geiger was playing.
He let himself in the back
with a jimmy and he had a gun.
The gun went off, as guns will,
and Geiger fell down dead.
Owen ran with the film.
You went after him and got it.
All right, you're right.
I heard the shots...
...and saw him run out and
enter the Packard and away.
I followed him.
He turned west on Sunset.
And beyond Beverly...
...he skidded off the road
and came to a stop.
So I came up and played copper.
He had a gun. He was rattled,
so I sapped him down.
I figured the film might be
worth something, so I took it.
That's the last I saw of him.
So you left an unconscious man
in a car way out near Beverly.
And you want me to believe
somebody came along...
...ran that car to the ocean,
pushed it off the pier...
...then hid Geiger's body?
- Well, I didn't...
- Somebody did.
You wanted time to take over.
You can't prove I did it.
I don't particularly want to.
All I want to do is find out
what Geiger had on the Sternwoods.
Maybe you and I can make
a little deal.
Go ahead.
Maybe she's back.
If she is, she hasn't got her gun.
You got a match, bud?
What'll it be, kid?
Me or the cops?
What do you want?
Sit in that car,
back of the wheel. You drive.
As soon as this police car goes by,
we're going to Geiger's house.
By the way, Carol,
you shot the wrong guy.
Brody didn't kill Geiger.
All right, let's go.
- You got a key. Let's go in.
- Who said I got a key?
All right, come on!
Maybe you need this.
- Hello.
- Hello, Bernie?
Is this who I think it is?
It's Marlowe.
How are you fixed for red points?
I haven't got any.
Who has?
I got some cold meat set out,
might interest you.
What are you talking about?
You find a gun on Owen Taylor
when they fished him out of the drink?
- That's police business.
- I know it's police business.
But if they did,
it had three empty shells in it.
You come up to
7244 Laverne Terrace...
...off Laurel Canyon.
I'll show you where the slugs went.
- I'll be right out.
- I'll be waiting for you.
What did you hide Geiger's body for?
- Do you admit shooting Brody?
- Take a jump, Jack.
He doesn't have to admit it.
Here's his gun.
Come on.
You too, Phil.
The DA is waiting for us.
On the way, you and I
can have a little talk.
The DA isn't going
to like this very much.
Yeah, I know.
Cronjager'll be there too.
That won't help.
Maybe I can needle him enough
to take the heat off you.
Appreciate it.
Thanks.
- Evening, Mr. Wilde.
- Hi, Marlowe.
Hi, Cronjager.
- You know Marlowe?
- I know him.
Sit down. Unless
you'd rather be on your feet.
You'd better start.
I guess the best way to begin is...
...to ask Cronjager what he's got
on the Randall Place killing.
Brody was the name.
We got Brody with two slugs in him,
two guns that hadn't been fired...
...a dame trying to start a car
that didn't belong to her.
Hers was next to it.
The same model.
She acted rattled.
We brought her in and she talked.
- She didn't see the killer...
- That's all you got?
- It only happened an hour ago.
- I know.
- You expect the movie of the killing?
- Not from you.
That'll do.
Go ahead, Bernie.
Your killer's down below, handcuffed.
Here's the gun he used.
- Marlowe got him for you.
- How...?
Oh, yeah, there are a couple
more deaths involved.
One of them in your territory.
Maybe you know about it.
- Marlowe uncovered them too.
- Keep going.
And the car that was lifted out
of the ocean with a dead guy in it.
What about it?
The guy was chauffeur to a rich family
that was being blackmailed.
Mr. Wilde recommended Marlowe
to the family through me.
He'd been playing it
close to the vest.
I love private dicks who do that.
And you don't have
to be so coy about it.
I don't have to be coy.
I don't often get to be coy with you.
I dig up stuff
your men don't see.
- My men don't...
- That's enough.
Sit down, captain.
And you, Bernie, go on with it.
Well, this chauffeur
killed a guy last night.
A guy named Geiger.
He ran a racket, back of
a bookstore on Hollywood Blvd.
In your territory.
But you hadn't heard about Geiger,
had you? Or the racket.
Marlowe, tell it to them.
- Well...
- I hadn't heard...
- You want to talk?
- Go ahead.
You'd better get this down.
Yesterday, General Sternwood
showed me a letter...
Brody stalled, but when Agnes
didn't back him up...
...he began to get cold feet.
While I was persuading Brody to talk,
the doorbell rang.
He opened it and somebody shot him.
Well, you know the rest.
Outside of Taylor, Lundgren and Brody,
nobody knew about Geiger.
His secretary.
She got it from Brody.
No one else was near the house?
So all you failed to do was report
a murder that happened last night?
You fooled around all day so he
could commit a second killing today.
That's all?
I was in a tough spot. I was wrong.
But I wanted to protect my client.
I didn't know he'd gun for Brody.
Just worked out that way.
That's police business.
You're still in a tough spot.
Have you told it complete?
I left out personal details and
intend to keep on leaving them out.
- Why?
- My client's entitled to protection.
You think.
I got another idea.
You could lose your license.
Your division's got two murders,
both solved, with both killers.
I don't see what you can gain
by starting trouble.
Besides, there are
other people in this.
What you bring out
wouldn't do any good.
If Marlowe wants to forget it,
your office can take the credit.
I hate to let him get away with it.
Besides, it won't do you any good
by watching this over in the papers.
- What do you want?
- I've got a prisoner to turn over.
So long, Wilde.
Eddie, you can go.
Just a minute.
Leave that notebook here.
You'll have to make another
statement for our files.
You think we can keep
the two killings separate...
...and keep Sternwood's
name out of it?
Yeah, I think so.
Know why I'm doing this
instead of tearing your ear off?
- I expected to lose both of them.
- You should have.
- What are you getting for all this?
- $ 25 a day and expenses.
- That's $50 and a little gasoline.
- About that.
For that, you're willing
to get in touch with the law...
...and lose your license?
I don't like it, but I'm on a case.
Just what did General Sternwood
really want you for?
To settle this business with Geiger.
Are you sure it didn't have anything
to do with that ex-bootlegger Regan?
What makes you say that?
I had an idea that he thought
Regan was mixed up in this.
And he really wanted you
to find out that Regan isn't.
Shawn's no blackmailer.
I know him.
You'd better find him and make sure.
Maybe I had.
- And buy Bernie a box of cigars.
- I'll do that.
- He's earned it.
- Someday, Cronjager'll blow up and bust.
- So long, Mr. Wilde.
- So long.
Thanks, Bernie.
Forget it.
Cronjager's always been my pigeon.
What happens now?
Looks like I'll get paid off.
That'll end it, huh?
I don't know, Bernie.
This began as a case of blackmail.
All at once, things started
to happen for no reason.
No reason at all.
- Now it's over...
- You think there's more.
Well, so do you.
What's your dope
on Regan's disappearance?
Missing Persons has all we've got.
It boils down to one thing:
Eddie Mars' blonde wife disappeared
the same time Regan did.
Mars ever ask you to find her?
Could be people want us
to think they ran off together.
Is that just a hunch?
Almost.
Why don't you play it?
That's what the DA said.
I think I will.
- Well!
- Good morning.
And how are you today?
Better than last night.
Come on in.
No answer on your telephone.
It was unplugged.
I wanted to get some sleep.
I was tired.
I was worried and wanted to know
what happened after I left.
Worried or curious?
Both.
Then I read the morning papers.
We were lucky. We managed to keep
the Sternwoods out of it.
My father and I were
both very pleased.
He hopes you didn't involve
yourself too deeply.
You tell him you were there?
Nothing would be gained
by telling him.
You're probably right. Anything
special you wanted to see me about?
Dad asked me to give you a check.
He considers the case closed.
It is, isn't it?
Well, as regards Geiger, yes.
Then it's completely closed.
I hope this is satisfactory.
Five hundred!
It's a lot more than I expected,
but welcome just the same.
Here you are.
Here's the three promissory notes
and Geiger's card.
As for the photographs, I'll destroy
them myself, if you don't mind.
We appreciate what you've done.
Someday, my father wants
to thank you himself.
Fine, I'll come and
drink more of his brandy.
Maybe he'd talk some more
about Shawn Regan.
My brandy's just as good.
If you can stop being
a detective long enough...
...to have a drink with me.
I'd like to. I like brandy.
I have lots of it.
"Completely closed".
- Long distance.
- Hello, long distance?
This is Philip Marlowe at Main 9-1494.
Hello? I have Mr. Mars for you.
Thanks. Put him on.
Hello, Mr. Mars?
Hello, Eddie.
This is Phil Marlowe.
- I called because I want to see you.
- Sure. When?
- I could drive up tonight.
- Okay, come ahead.
Good evening.
Mr. Mars around? I'm Marlowe.
He's expecting me.
Wait here and I'll find out.
He would spend it on the ponies
He would spend it on the girls
Buy his mother lovely roses
For her dear old hennaed curls
But when his wife said, "Sweetie...
... what did you get for me?"
He socked her in the choppers
Such a sweet, sweet guy was he
And her tears flowed like wine
She's a real sad tomato
She's a busted valentine
Knows her mama done told her
That a man is darned unkind
I'm a telling you, mister
She was a sob, sob sister
Lying on a pillow
Weeping like a willow
My, oh, my
How that baby could cry
And her tears flowed like wine
Yes, her tears flowed like wine
- Hello, boys.
- Stop it. He's waiting to see you.
Thanks.
Glad you came.
You never been here before?
First time.
I wouldn't be here now...
...if you hadn't told me
I could come up here if I needed help.
Drink?
I like the way you've
handled this whole thing.
It made me sore at first, but I see
now you knew what you were doing.
You and I could get along.
I like to pay my bills as I go.
- How much do I owe you?
- For what?
Still careful, huh?
All right, then.
I want some information...
...about Shawn Regan.
You got it from
the Bureau of Missing Persons.
- You get around.
- My boys do.
- Where is he?
- I haven't any idea.
You didn't bump him off, did you?
No. You think I did?
- That's what I came to ask.
- You're kidding.
All right, I'm kidding.
You didn't do it and your boys
aren't good enough to. I knew Regan.
You said you weren't looking for Regan.
I wasn't then.
Maybe I just got curious.
I finally got it
that the general was worried...
...Regan might be mixed up
in this blackmail business.
Sternwood can turn over now
and go back to sleep.
It was Geiger's own racket.
I did some inquiring myself today.
When Geiger and Brody got gunned,
it finished it.
- That, I'm sure of.
- It's finished, then.
The general thinks like you do.
He paid me off today.
I'm sorry to hear that.
I wish he'd hire you to keep
that daughter of his home.
- She's there now.
- I heard her.
She's not very popular here.
When she loses, she doubles and
I get a fistful of paper.
- If she wins, she takes my money.
- Don't you get it back?
- She spends it somewhere else.
- Oh, she goes on the cuff.
Keep her out of here, then.
- I took the trip for nothing.
- Sorry I can't help you.
You mind if I look
the place over?
Take that door,
it comes out behind the tables.
No, thanks. I'll go out
with the other suckers.
Maybe someday I can do
you a favor.
Maybe.
There's one thing that puzzles me.
You don't seem in a hurry
to find that wife of yours.
I hear she's not the kind of wife
a guy wants to lose.
Could it be you know where she is,
and maybe Regan too?
Stop being curious. What's between
me and my wife is between us.
Sorry.
Oh, Eddie, you don't have
anybody watching me, do you?
Tailing me in a gray Plymouth coupe?
No. Why should I?
I can't imagine, unless you're worried
about where I am all the time.
I don't like you that well.
So long, Eddie.
Mr. Marlowe?
- Mrs. Rut...
You better take it.
Mrs. Rutledge wants to
see you before you go.
She's at the center table.
Thank you both.
Mr. Marlowe. Mrs. Rutle...
Mrs. Rutledge wants to see me.
- How did you know?
- He told me.
She sure is picking them tonight.
Just won eight in a row.
- I didn't hear him tell you anything.
- He didn't.
What kind of game is this?
Go on. Spin the wheel.
I want another play.
I'm sorry. You have
more than $ 14,000 there.
The table cannot cover your bet.
Don't you want your money back?
I sent for Mr. Mars.
- Lady...
- Do you want to cover it?
The lady.
- Something the matter?
- I'd like one more play.
All this on the red.
Cover her bet in even thousands.
If no one objects to this turn of
the wheel being for the lady alone.
Wish me luck, Marlowe.
You wanted to see me.
The people I came with want to stay...
...so I thought maybe
you'd like to drive me home.
- Sure.
- Are you ready, lady?
- Yeah, I'm ready.
- So am I.
Number five, red!
You did all right.
I'll get my car while you collect,
and meet you outside.
Cash me in.
Good night.
This is a gun, lady.
I want that money.
Yell and I'll cut you in half.
Give me that bag!
Hello, pal. Easy!
Somebody's always giving me guns.
You can turn around now.
I don't like people who play games.
Tell your boss...
...when you wake up.
Nice work.
Are you my bodyguard now?
Looks like it.
You ready to go?
Why are you trembling?
Don't tell me you were scared.
I'm not used to being hijacked.
Give me time.
Hijacked? Is that what it was?
What else?
You're still shaking.
What's the matter?
You weren't worried about me?
Afraid I'd get hurt?
When did you begin
to feel that way about me?
Why are we stopping?
To settle something.
All right...
...let's begin with
what Mars has on you.
If he had, would it
be any of your business?
You've already been paid.
Yeah, by you.
- Are you after more money?
- I guess you've got a right to ask.
No, I've already been well-paid.
I've got another reason.
You like my father, don't you?
Why don't you stop?
Remember I said I was beginning
to like another Sternwood?
I wish you'd show it.
That should be awful easy.
I liked that.
I'd like more.
That's even better.
All right.
Now that's settled.
What's Eddie Mars got on you?
- So that's the way it is.
- That's the way it is.
Kissing you is all right.
I'd like to do more of it.
But I want to find out
what Mars has on you.
- If you say that again...
- I'll keep saying it till I find out.
I told Eddie Mars
I was coming up to see him.
When I arrived, you were there.
You two staged an act.
He let you win money...
...and then sent a man
to take it away...
...to prove there was
nothing between you.
You're shaking again.
- Take me home.
- Sure I will.
But first, open that bag.
If there's 28 grand in it,
I'll eat every word I've said.
Make a sap out of me,
or else stop playing me for one.
Take me home.
All right, but that's as far
as I'll carry you.
From now on, you can
take care of yourself.
Hello, Phil?
- Hello, Bernie. What's up?
- I want to see you right away.
I haven't had breakfast.
It's 2:00.
If you're not here in 30 minutes
you'll be eating on the county.
I'd rather buy my own.
I know that food the county puts out.
All right, I'll be there.
Don't you know better than to wake
a man at 2 p.m.?
- What's up?
- I got some orders for you.
You're to lay off the Sternwood case.
- Who says so?
- The DA.
The DA, huh?
He must have changed his mind.
- Who changed it for him?
- General Sternwood.
Personally?
All right. Between you and me,
he didn't talk to the general.
He talked to the daughter,
Mrs. Rutledge.
- Any reason given?
- Not that I know of.
There's no law says a man can't
work on a case without a client.
Keep his hand in.
I'm just supposed to
tell you to lay off.
I know, you just work here.
All right, you told me to lay off.
I'm getting breakfast.
Want a cup of coffee?
No, thanks.
- Sternwood residence.
- Hello, Norris? This is Marlowe.
Yes, Mr. Marlowe. I...
I'd like to come out
and see General Sternwood.
I don't think it
would be possible tonight.
- Why not?
- I've been trying to call you.
Mrs. Rutledge is very anxious
to talk to you.
If you'll wait just a minute,
I'll put her on.
Hey, sugar, you got a match?
Sure thing.
Hello, Marlowe?
Thanks.
Hello, Mrs. Rutledge.
I wanted to tell you
you can stop worrying...
... and call off your bloodhounds.
We found Shawn.
You found Shawn?
Yes. He's been in Mexico.
He hasn't been very well.
What happened?
An accident of some kind.
We didn't get all the details.
I'm leaving at once to meet him.
I see.
I suppose the general's quite pleased.
We haven't told him yet.
We thought it best to wait.
Thanks for telling me.
Have a nice trip.
I will. Goodbye.
Goodbye.
Say, mister...
...would you please...
This is just our way
of saying, "Lay off".
You the guy that's been tailing me?
Yeah. My name's Jones.
Harry Jones.
- I want to see you.
- Swell!
Did you want to see
those guys jump me?
I didn't care one way or the other.
You could've yelled for help.
A guy's playing a hand, I let him
play it. I'm no kibitzer.
You got brains.
Get my hat, will you?
Help me up to my office.
That working-over they gave you
was the best I've seen.
And I've been around too.
Used to run a little liquor.
Rode the scout car
with a Tommy gun in my lap.
- Tough racket.
- Terrible!
- Sit down. You make me nervous.
- Maybe you don't believe me.
What do you want?
That's better.
I'm selling something, cheap.
For a couple of C's.
Don't let me stop you.
- Don't you want to even know who I am?
- I already know.
You're not a cop.
You don't belong to Eddie Mars,
because I asked him.
So you must be one of Brody's friends.
So Agnes is loose again, huh?
How'd you know that?
She's a nice girl.
We're talking about getting married.
She's too big for you.
That's a dirty crack, brother.
I suppose you're right.
Maybe I've been running around
with the wrong people.
Cut the babble.
What is it?
Will you pay for something?
- If it what?
- Helps you find Regan.
This is getting funny.
I'm supposed to pay you two C's
for telling me I'm looking for Regan.
People are always
telling me that.
I don't even pass out cigars anymore.
Do you want to know what I've got?
I don't know.
200 buys a lot of
information in my circle.
Would you pay it to know
where Mars' wife is?
Would you pay $ 200 for that, shamus?
I think I might.
- Where?
- Agnes found her.
She'll tell you when she has
the dough in her hand.
- You might tell the cops for nothing.
- I ain't so brittle.
Agnes must have something
I didn't see.
I ain't tried to pull anything.
I came here with a proposition.
Take it or leave it.
One right guy to another.
You start waving cops at me.
You ought to be ashamed of yourself.
I am.
Okay, 200 it is.
- Have you got the money?
- Where's Agnes?
You know Puss Walgreen's office?
Fulwider Building?
428 in the back?
No, but I can find it.
Can you meet me there
in an hour?
- I guess so.
- You bring the dough.
I'll take you to Agnes.
Who are you?
What do you want?
I wanted to see you.
Who are you?
I work for Eddie Mars.
My name is Canino.
Canino?
Sure, I thought you would remember.
What do you want?
Why have you been following Marlowe?
- Who says I've been?
- I do.
That was a mistake, your mistake.
Eddie Mars don't like it.
Sit down and quit stalling!
Why are you tailing Marlowe?
All right, there's no harm telling.
It was for Joe Brody's girl.
She has to leave town.
That takes dough.
She tried to
get it through Marlowe.
Why would he pay?
You know about the night
the kid bumped Brody?
The young Sternwood girl was there.
But Marlowe didn't say that.
Agnes figured it was carfare
when she got hold of him.
- You get it?
- Sure, I get it.
- Where's this Agnes?
- What do you care?
What do you want with her?
What's she got...
What's the matter, Jones?
Ain't you ever seen a gun?
Where's the girl?
You want me to count three,
like a movie?
Where's Agnes?
You win.
She's in an apartment...
...at 28 Court Street.
Apartment 301.
I guess I'm yellow.
You just got good sense.
I ain't gonna hurt her.
Not if everything's like you say.
Nervous, ain't you?
- Maybe you need a drink.
- I don't think so...
You got a glass?
At the water cooler.
There you are, pal.
Drink her down.
Well, drink it!
What do you think it is, poison?
I bet that Agnes
wouldn't turn it down.
No, I'll bet she wouldn't.
What's funny?
Nothing's funny.
So long, Jonesy.
Information, give me the number
of apartment 301, 28 Court Street.
Thank you. One moment, please.
- Courtview Apartments.
- This is Police Identification Bureau.
You got a girl living there
named Agnes Lowzier?
Nobody by that name here.
Have you got a brunette with
green eyes...
...either alone or with a little guy,
weighs about 115 pounds...
...wears a gray hat and gray suit?
Sorry. Nothing like that.
Somebody just gave out
the wrong address.
Thanks.
You did all right, Jonesy.
But you left me high and dry.
Who is this?
- What did you say?
- I said, "Who is this?"
Hello, Agnes. This is Marlowe.
Marlowe, the man you want to see.
Is Harry there?
Yeah, he's here.
- Put him on, will you?
- He can't talk to you.
- Why?
- Because he's dead.
Your little man died to keep
you out of trouble.
I got your money for you.
Do you want it?
- Yeah, I want it.
- Have you got a car?
- Where can I meet you?
- Rampart and Oakwood.
I'll be there in half an hour.
What happened to Harry?
There's no use going into that.
You don't really care anyway.
Just put it down your little man
deserved something better.
Here's your 200.
Joe and I were riding on Foothill
Boulevard a couple of weeks ago.
We passed a brown coupe and
I saw the driver.
It was Eddie Mars' wife.
- There was a fellow with her. Canino.
- I know him.
Some people you don't forget,
even if you've only seen them once.
We got curious and Joe tailed them.
Do you know where Realito is?
About 10 miles east,
there's a side road.
Off the highway,
there's a garage and paint shop...
...run by a guy named Huck.
Hot-car drop, likely.
And a frame house right behind it.
That's where Mars' wife is.
- You sure of that?
- Why should I lie?
Art Huck's, 10 miles east of Realito.
Is that right?
So long, copper. Wish me luck.
I got a raw deal.
Your kind always does.
What do you want?
Open up.
I got a flat on the highway.
Sorry, mister, we're closed
for the night. Better try Realito.
All right.
Come on in.
You'd scare off
a lot of trade with that.
You can get yourself hurt
kicking on doors.
Cut it out, Art.
The guy's right.
You run a garage, don't you?
Go ahead. Give him a hand.
Thanks, mister.
I suppose you can fix flats?
Good as you can make them,
but I'm working on a spray job.
It's too damp
for a good spray job, Art.
You got time to fix his tire.
- But I don't...
- Get moving!
Sure.
Here's the key to the back.
Put the spare on.
That'll make it easier.
Yeah, I took a skid up at the corner.
A front tire went.
Lucky to find some help.
You live around here?
Just drove in from Reno
and Carson City.
Came the long way around, huh?
Business trip?
Partly.
Having your car painted?
Just a spray job.
Art's pretty slow.
He should've been finished by now.
All right, Art.
Take him in the house.
You'd be Mrs. Eddie Mars...
...the blonde that was
supposed to run off with Regan.
That's right.
Hello, angel.
Move that light, will you?
Or move me.
I thought I'd find you here.
I suppose we're in the house
back of the garage.
Maybe you'd better stop talking.
The boys don't take
any chances, do they?
Where are they?
Out digging a grave?
You had to go on
with this, didn't you?
Where are they?
They've gone down
the road to telephone.
Call up Eddie Mars,
find out what to do with me.
I could tell them that.
Why did you have to go on?
Too many people told me to stop.
Light me a cigarette,
will you, angel?
Why'd you make trouble?
Eddie never did you any harm.
I wasn't in love with Shawn.
We were friends.
If I hadn't hidden
when Shawn disappeared...
...the cops would've been sure
he killed him.
Maybe he did kill him.
Eddie's not that kind.
- You mean Eddie never kills anybody.
- No.
You really believe that, don't you?
How do you suppose
I found out you were here?
Little man named Jones told me.
Funny little guy. Harmless.
I liked him.
Came to sell me the information
because I was working for Sternwood.
How he came to know,
it's a long story.
Canino, your husband's man,
got to him first...
...while I stood around like a sap.
I was in the next room.
Now the little man is dead.
But Eddie didn't do that, did he?
He never kills anybody,
he just hires it done.
You're lying!
You think he's just
a gambler, don't you?
I think he's a blackmailer,
a hot-car broker...
...a killer by remote control.
Anything with money pinned to it,
anything rotten...
Ask him when you see him.
Well, we got rid of her.
She's all right.
I like her.
You like too many people.
- I wonder if you'd do that for a man.
- None that I've ever met.
Then there's nothing to do
but wait till Canino gets back.
He doesn't know
I was there.
You know what he'll do
when he finds out, don't you?
Beat my teeth out then kick me
in my stomach for mumbling.
- That'll be just the start...
- Stop talking that way!
You should have gone to Mexico.
- But then you couldn't, could you?
- Stop it.
Border patrol would have
checked you through alone.
People would have
seen you without Regan.
It was safer for you to come here,
especially for Eddie.
Will you stay out of this
if I let you go?
No.
Take this thing out of my mouth.
That's better.
Get a knife and cut these ropes.
Watch your fingers.
Don't cut toward your hand.
- Who's got a key to these handcuffs?
- Canino.
I don't suppose
there's a gun around?
None that I know of.
The boys made a fast trip.
What can you do?
Look, angel. I'm gonna
leave you in a tough spot.
That's all right.
- How do I get out of here?
- That door leads to a porch.
As soon as I've gone,
you count to 20.
- Then scream your head off.
- I will.
All right. Start counting.
Get going, Art.
You heard what I said!
There! Behind the wheel!
Over here, Canino!
Here.
That looks like the key.
We'll have to take his car.
How far is it from back there
to the nearest telephone?
About eight or 10 miles to Realito.
Why?
When Eddie's wife fixes my car
and he finds out what happened...
...there'll be trouble.
You'll be in it
just as much as I will.
I don't mind,
as long as you're around.
I didn't get a chance to thank you
for what you did.
You looked good. Awful good!
I didn't know they made them
like that anymore.
I guess I'm in love with you.
Will you go to the police with me?
I can't.
Why not?
What if I told you
I killed Shawn Regan?
Would you tell the police that?
I will if you take me there.
I'm not going to.
Look, angel, I'm tired.
My jaw hurts, my ribs ache,
I killed a man back there...
...and stood by while
a harmless guy was killed.
I can't say it all happened...
...because Geiger tried to throw
a loop over Carmen.
They'll swarm your house...
...so fast that every closet
in your family...
...will look like a police convention.
They'll all ask the same question...
..."Where's Shawn Regan?
Why did Mars hide his wife so
it looked like she ran off with Regan?"
Why did you hide out there?
You're playing with dynamite.
- If I...
- I won't ask any more questions.
I won't even ask you
how you got into this mess.
I'll ask Eddie,
if I can get there quickly.
Why are you doing that?
I guess I'm in love with you.
Hello. Let me talk to Mr. Mars.
Hello, Eddie.
This is Marlowe.
Yeah, Marlowe,
or what's left of him.
That Canino's a pretty good boy.
You'll have trouble getting
another as good.
What's the matter, Eddie?
Can't you talk?
I'm in Realito, the same
place Canino called from.
Only now it's me that's calling.
I want to see you.
Why don't you go to the police?
I just killed your best boy.
Do you want to see me
or don't you?
All right. Where?
Las Olindas is too far.
Not your apartment either.
Your house?
You mean the one
that Geiger lived in?
All right. When?
How long will it take me
to get there?
I'll be there just as quick as I can.
- It worked.
- You're taking an awful chance.
He'll be here in 10 minutes.
Go and make sure
that back door is locked...
...and then close these curtains.
I'll get rid of the car.
You're the one who's shaking now.
I'm scared, angel.
I'm sore too.
Mars has been ahead of me
all the way. Way ahead!
If I don't get the jump on him
this time, we're cooked.
Here they are.
Watch the back.
If you see anybody coming,
yell like you did before.
- What?
- The curtain! Stop it swinging.
I got here first.
Put those scissors down.
Put them down!
Turn around.
Over there.
Sit down.
There's two men out in back.
- Watch them.
- Hello, Mr. Mars.
- You double-crossing...
- I told you to sit down.
And leave her out of it.
She's all right.
She kept her deal.
She didn't tell me a thing...
...except that she killed Regan.
I didn't believe that.
Regan's dead,
but she didn't do it.
It was Carmen, wasn't it?
How'd it happen?
- She didn't tell...?
- I asked you how it happened.
- Carmen liked Regan.
- But he liked your wife.
He said no to Carmen.
She gets mad when anybody says that.
I've seen her that way.
She was high. When it was over,
she couldn't remember much about it.
I've seen her that way too.
- You hid the body.
- You can't prove it.
It's just as bad for you
if I prove it to myself.
Then you blackmailed
Mrs. Rutledge...
...by telling her
what Carmen had done.
How did you prove to her
that Carmen had done it?
Prove it to me.
You've seen her when she's that way.
Sure I have. Have you?
Why didn't you know her
when you walked in here?
You're pretty smart,
but I've been waiting for this one.
What are you gonna do?
I said you're smart.
You walked in without a gun.
You'd agree to everything,
just like you're doing now.
When I left,
things would be different.
That's what those boys
are doing out there.
But everything's changed now,
since I got here first.
Angel, get on the floor!
Don't get excited, Marlowe.
If anything happens, if there's
any shooting, you'll just...
What do you think will happen now?
What'll your boys think?
What'll they do to
the first one out that door?
Who's it gonna be, you or me?
- Now look...
- You look at this!
Haven't you ever seen a gun?
Want me to count,
like in the movies?
That's what Canino said to Jonesy.
- Don't go crazy!
- Jonesy took it better.
- That's one, Eddie.
- Don't! Don't!
That's two, Eddie!
Don't shoot! It's me, Mars!
Bernie?
This is Marlowe.
I've got some more red points for you.
- Who is it this time?
- Eddie Mars.
His boys got him.
There's more to it than that.
He killed Regan.
I'll tell you when I see you.
Where are you?
The same place, Laverne Terrace.
Come up and get me out of here.
And watch yourself.
They may still be outside.
Right away.
It won't take him long.
Wait a minute, let me do the talking.
I don't know what I'll tell him,
but it'll be pretty close to the truth.
You'll have to send Carmen away...
...from a lot of things.
They have places for that.
Maybe they can cure her.
It's been done before.
We'll have to tell your father
about Regan. I think he can take it.
You've forgotten one thing.
Me.
What's wrong with you?
Nothing you can't fix.