How you doing, Keaton?
I can't feel my legs...
Keyser.
Ready?
What time is it?
Twelve-thirty.
It all started back in New York
six weeks ago.
A truck of stripped guns parts
got jacked outside of Queens.
The driver didn't see anybody,
but he heard a voice.
Sometimes that's all you need.
- Mr. McManus.
- Don't you guys ever fucking sleep?
- We have a warrant for your arrest.
- Fuck you, pig.
Todd Hockney?
- Who wants to know?
- New York Police Department.
- Shit!
- Police! Hold it!
Sure you brought enough guys?
It's quite simple,
a restaurant that changes with taste
without losing the overall aesthetic.
On other words, the atmosphere
will not be painted on the walls.
Let me give you an example.
This I had to see for myself.
- I'm in a meeting.
- Time for another one.
Everyone, this is David Kujan.
Special Agent Kujan, U.S. Customs.
And the New York Police Dept.
You look good, Keaton.
- You have a problem, Mr. Keaton?
- A stolen truck loaded with guns.
Will you excuse us for a moment?
We have some questions.
It's going to be some time.
No, no, please sit down.
This is a small problem.
Enjoy the meal.
Talk to you later.
It didn't make sense I was there.
They were hard-core hijackers.
But there I was.
I wasn't scared. I hadn't done
anything they could do me for.
Besides, it was fun.
I got to make like I was notorious.
When your number is called,
step forward and repeat
the phrase you've been given.
Number 1, step forward.
Hand me the keys, you cocksucker.
Number 2, step forward.
Give me the fucking keys,
you cocksucker motherfucker!
Knock it off. Number 3.
- Hand me the keys, cocksucker.
- In English, please.
- Excuse me?
- In English.
Hand me the keys, cocksucker.
What the fuck?
Number 4, step forward.
The whole rap was a setup.
Hand me the keys, you cocksucker.
It was the cops'fault. You don't
put guys like that together.
Who knows what can happen?
Hand me the keys, you cocksucker.
This has got to be
embarrassing for you guys.
They drilled us all night.
The cops had nothing.
They hoped somebody'd slip up.
They knew we wouldn't fight it.
They knew how to lean on us.
Our rights went out the window,
it was disgraceful.
They went after McManus first.
Top-knotch entry man.
- What truck?
- The truck with the guns, fucko.
Fucko?
He was a good guy.
Crazy, though.
Want to know what Fenster said?
McManus told us another story.
Was that the one about
the hooker with dysentery?
Fenster always worked
with McManus.
When it came to the job
he was right on. A smart man.
- What are you saying?
- I said you're flip here.
- What?
- Flip here, flipping for real.
I'm shaking. Come on.
- Answer my question.
- Can you hear me at the back?
I want my lawyer.
I'll have your badge, cocksucker.
Todd Hockney.
Good with explosives.
The one guy who didn't
give a fuck about anybody.
- You don't have a leg to stand on.
- You think so, tough guy?
You were in Queens on the night
of the highjacking.
Really? I live in Queens.
Did you put that together, Einstein?
You got a team of monkeys?
You know what happens
if you do another turn in the joint?
Fuck your father in the shower.
You gonna charge me, dickhead?
I'll charge you when I'm ready.
- With what?
- You know damn well, dead man.
Keaton was the real prize
for them, for obvious reasons.
It was your mistake, not mine.
Did you ever stop to ask me?
I have the same face, the same name.
- I'm a businessman.
- The restaurant business?
From now on, you're in the
getting-fucked-by-us business.
- I'm going to make you famous.
- Like I said,
it was your mistake, not mine.
Charge me with this shit,
and I'll beat it.
Okay?
Let's get back to the truck, asshole.
I hold someone's shit
for five minutes.
So I did a little time.
Does that mean I get railed
every time a truck loses its way?
Fuck 'em!
Fenster, will you relax?
They don't have probable cause.
Fucking -A right. No P.C.
You do some time,
they never let you go.
They treat me like a criminal.
I'll end up a criminal.
You are a criminal.
What you got to do that?
I'm trying to make a point.
Why don't you make your point?
You're making me tired all over.
Fuck it, then.
I heard you were dead.
You heard right.
Word I got is you
hung up your spurs.
What's that all about?
What's this?
Rumor has it Keaton's gone straight.
I hear he's tapping Edie Finnerman.
Who's that?
A big uptown criminal lawyer.
I hear she's Keaton's meal ticket.
How about it? You a lawyer's wife?
What retainer are you giving her?
Fenster,
do your friend a favor.
Tell him to keep quiet.
Dean Keaton.
Gone clean, huh?
Say it ain't so.
- Or did you hit the truck?
- Mac, forget him.
Did you talk to your lawyer?
This was a shakedown.
- What makes you say that?
- You've been in a lineup.
It's always you
and four dummies.
The P.D. Pays homeless guys
ten bucks a head.
No way they'd line five felons
in a row. No way.
A voice lineup? A public defender
could get you out of that.
- So why was I strip-searched?
- It was the Feds.
A truckload of guns gets snagged,
Customs goes to NYPD,
they come up with us.
- They're clutching at straws.
- I had a guy's finger up my asshole.
Is it Friday already?
Yeah, lover boy.
You want a piece?
Who are the pigs
stole our fucking truck?
- What did you say?
- Who stole the fucking truck?
I don't want to know.
- Who asked you, working man?
- Fuck who did it. Who's the gimp?
- He's okay.
- Says you.
What about it, pretzel man?
- What's your story?
- His name is Verbal.
Verbal Kint.
Roger, really. People say
I talk too much.
I was going to tell you to shut up.
We met before once or twice.
I was in county for fraud.
In a lineup. What happened?
I walked.
- 90 days suspended.
- So you did it!
All right, look.
We've been put out by this.
I figure we owe it to ourselves
to salvage a little dignity.
Now...
Me and Fenster heard about a job.
Why don't you just calm down?
What do you care what he says?
I'm just talking here.
Mr. Hockney wants to hear,
and I know Fenster's down.
What about you, guy?
I'm interested, sure.
There. See?
So I'd like to exercise my
right to free assembly.
Why don't you just shut up?
You're missing the point.
No. You're missing the point.
I don't want to hear
anything from you.
I don't care about your job.
And...
I want nothing to do with
any of you. I beg your pardon,
but you can all go to hell.
Dean Keaton,
gone the high road.
What is the world coming to?
Fuck him.
And that was how it started.
The five of us on a trumped-up
charge to be leaned on by halfwits.
I can't talk about much here.
What the cops didn't figure out
and what I know now,
was these men would never break.
Never bend over for anybody.
Anybody.
- Who are you?
- Agent Jack Baer, F.B.I.
- How many dead?
- 15. They're still finding bodies.
- Any survivors?
- Yeah, there's two.
One's in hospital in a coma.
The D.A. Has the second,
a cripple from New York.
The chief wants this place
sealed off. Call him.
This is David Kujan. I'll be
in Los Angeles until Tuesday.
If you need to reach me, contact
Jeff Rabin, San Pedro P.D.,
on extension 112.
Have a nice day.
- Why can't I see him?
- Dave, I told you.
The D.A. Was ready to arraign
before they moved him to county.
Kint's lawyers comes and the D.A.
Comes out looking smacked around.
They take his statement
and cut him a deal.
- Did they charge him?
- Yeah, weapons. Misdemeanor 2.
What is that?
- I give the D.A. Credit for that.
- Excuse me, sir.
It's turned political. The Mayor
and Chief were here last night.
This morning, the Governor called.
This guy is protected from on high
by the Prince of Darkness.
- When does he post bail?
- Two hours, tops.
- I want to see him.
- No.
- I cannot do this for you.
- I came a long way for this.
Dave, please.
Even if I let you talk to him,
he won't talk to you.
He's paranoid. He knows the
interrogation rooms are wired.
I quit. It won't be an interrogation,
just a friendly chat.
He won't go in there.
- Then someplace else.
- Where?
Where is the dope?
If it was a hit, who called it in?
I'm sure you have wild theories
to answer all these questions.
- You know what I think.
- It doesn't even matter.
The guy's got total immunity.
His story checks out.
He doesn't know
what you want to know.
I don't think he does, exactly.
There's more to his story.
I want to know why 27 men
died on that pier...
for 91 million dollars of dope
that wasn't there.
Above all, I want to be sure
Dean Keaton's dead.
He's dead.
Come on, two hours.
Just till he makes bail.
They're all dead.
I don't care how tough Keaton was.
Nobody could've survived that boat.
Is he talking?
He regained consciousness,
he spoke, not English, and lapsed.
- Hungarian.
- I don't know, maybe.
Most of them were Hungarians.
- You've got to put this on.
- Burns victims catch infections.
And of course there's no smoking.
Keep your mask up.
Please don't touch him.
Is he going to die?
He's got burns on 60% of
his body and broken ribs.
- Get a man put on the door.
- Is he dangerous?
Yes.
Do it.
Do it now.
Yeah, Baer. Down at L.A. County.
The guy they pulled out of
the harbor is Arkosh Kovash.
Nah, he's all fucked up.
I can't hear you.
Shut up. I'm on the phone.
Send me
someone who can
speak Hungarian.
He's talking like a Thai hooker.
What?
Keyser Soze!
No shit.
Call Dan Metzheiser at Justice
and find Dave Kujan from Customs.
Verbal, this is Agent Kujan
from Customs.
- Nice to meet you.
- He want to ask some questions.
- What about?
- About Dean Keaton mostly.
I'd like to start with
the lineup back in New York.
- Can I get some coffee?
- In a while. What about the lineup?
I'm really thirsty. I used to
dehydrate as a kid.
Once my piss came out
like snot. I was all thick and...
- I'll get your fucking coffee.
- Get me one too.
That guy is tense.
Tension is a killer.
I used to be in a barbershop
quartet in Skokie, Illinois.
The baritone was this fat guy
named Kip Diskin.
- He got so stressed in the morning.
- We're trying to help you.
I appreciate that and I want to
help you, Agent Kujan.
I like cops.
I would've been a fed...
You're not telling everything.
I know you know something.
I told the D.A. Everything.
I know you like Keaton
and you think he's a good man.
- I know he was good.
- He was a corrupt cop.
Sure, fifteen years ago.
But he was a good thief.
Cops wouldn't let him go legit.
Dean Keaton was a piece of shit.
Are you trying to get a rise
out of me, Agent Kujan?
- I just want to hear your story.
- It's all there.
May I have a cigarette?
- According to your statement...
- I need a light.
According to your statement
you're a short con operator.
Run of the mill scams.
- That's suppressed, inadmissible.
- I know.
Sweet deal you have here.
Total immunity.
I do have the weapons charge.
I'm looking at 6 months hard time.
You know a dealer
named Ruby Deemer?
You know a religious guy
named John Paul?
- You know Ruby's in Attica?
- He didn't have my lawyer.
I know Ruby. He's big on respect.
He's a friend, he likes me.
I know your testimony's sealed,
but Ruby's got lots of
friends inside.
What would he say if he found out
you dropped his name to the D. A?
- There's nothing there about Ruby.
- I'll mention that to him.
First thing I learned on the job
was how to spot a murderer.
You arrest three guys for a killing
and put them in jail overnight.
Next morning, whoever is
sleeping is your man.
If you're guilty, you know you're
caught and let your guard down.
- You follow me?
- No.
Let me get right to the point.
I'm smarter than you.
And I'll find out what I want
whether you like it or not.
I'm not a rat.
Thank you.
When I picked beans in Guatemala,
we used to make fresh coffee.
Right off the trees.
That was good. This is shit,
- but I'm in a police station.
- Can we get started again?
What happened after the lineup?
The desk sergeant said
he couldn't release you.
You weren't even charged.
I want pictures of your face.
I'll take them to the D.A.
Forget about it.
I'll have this thing in front of
a Grand Jury by Monday.
I don't want to talk about it, okay?
What did Fortier and Renault say?
They asked for more time
to think about investing.
- They just want more time.
- More time for what, Edie?
No matter how you cover my tracks,
they'll still find out about me.
Give me some credit.
Let's go to the Grand Jury.
This isn't going to stop.
It's never going to stop, period.
By next week, every investor
will walk away from us.
It's finished. I'm finished.
Don't give up on me now, Dean.
It's never going to stop.
I love you.
They ruined me in there tonight.
Do you hear me?
What?
Let's just go to my place.
We'll worry about this tomorrow.
- All right.
- Let's go.
Fenster and McManus
had a cagey proposition,
a fast jump, high risk,
long money.
We knew it could be done,
but doing it wrong meant killing.
To do it right took five men.
Five men meant Keaton.
Keaton took convincing.
New York's Finest Taxi Service.
Bullshit.
They don't operate anymore.
McManus' friend in the 14th says
they're doing one job on Thursday.
Some emerald smuggler.
McManus has a fence.
- A fence? Who?
- A guy in California. Redfoot.
- I never heard of him.
- You have to come.
What's it to you if I do or not?
They don't know me, you do.
They won't take me unless you go.
I need this.
You don't?
Is this your place?
Looks like you got a good
scam going with this lawyer.
I'm sorry.
It's okay.
You say it's the real thing,
that's cool.
- You okay?
- I was out of line.
But they'll never stop with us.
They'll never let you go now.
We hit the cops where it hurts
and we get well in the meantime.
You sure you're okay?
I'll be all right.
Look...
- Sometimes I get...
- Forget it.
I'll probably shit blood tonight.
So...
How do they want to do it?
McManus wants to
go in shooting. I say no.
Fenster? Hockney?
They're pretty pissed off.
They'll do anything.
I got a way to do it without
killing anyone, but like I say,
they won't let me in without you.
Three million?
Maybe more.
No killing.
Not if we do it my way.
New York's Finest Taxi Service
was not your normal taxi service.
It was a ring of corrupt NYPD cops
that ran a high profit racket,
driving smugglers and
drug dealers all over the city.
For a few hundred dollars a mile,
you got your own police escort.
They even had business cards.
Someone started asking questions
and the taxi service shut down.
Ever since, Internal Affairs
has been waiting to catch them.
And that's where we came in.
- So how was the flight?
- Fuckin' great.
Will this get me to Staten Island?
This'll get you to Cape Cod.
McManus came to us with the job.
Fenster got the vans,
Hockney the hardware and I
figured how to get no one killed.
Keaton put on the finishing touch.
A little "fuck you"from
the five of us to the NYPD.
Careful! Careful!
Come on, asshole.
- Don't move, you fucker!
- Drop it!
- Don't point that at me!
- What do you guys want?
Asshole!
Want a buckshot shampoo, chubby?
Fuck!
Good afternoon, porkchops.
Now give me the shit.
- Give him the shit!
- Give it to him, man!
Hurry up!
- Now the money.
- There's no money.
Give me the fucking money.
There's no money.
- Give him the fucking money!
- There's no money.
Hurry up!
Do you know who I am?
You know who the fuck I am?
We do now, jerkoff.
What's that?
Shit!
Keaton made an anonymous
phone call.
The press was on the scene
before the police.
Strausz and Rizzi were indicted
and weeks later, 50 more cops.
Everybody got it in the ass
from the Chief on down.
It was beautiful.
I owe you two-fifty.
Doctor Keaton.
- There's more than I thought.
- When's the fence coming?
Redfoot doesn't come to me,
I always go to him.
In California?
Yes. Fenster and I...
Hold the fucking phone!
You and Fenster?
- You fucking kidding me?
- Okay, everyone's going.
We all go.
What's your fucking problem?
You and Fenster are off
honeymooning in California
and the rest of us
are holding our dicks.
The job is over.
Cool it.
L.A.'s a good place to lie low
for a while.
You want to dance?
Ladies.
I would like to propose a toast.
There you go.
To Mr. Verbal.
The man with the plan.
We're going to miss the flight.
Don't do this. Send her a note.
I said we'll make it.
We're going to miss the plane.
She'll understand.
That's heartwarming. Really.
I'm weepy.
Want to wait outside?
I'm telling you what happened
after the lineup.
Come on, Verbal, who do you
think you're talking to?
You expect me to believe
he retired? For a woman?
Bullshit. Keaton was using her.
- He loved her.
- Sure.
And hitting the Taxi Service
wasn't his idea either?
- It was all Fenster and McManus.
- Keaton was a cop for 4 years.
Who knew the Service better?
That job had his name on it.
Edie had him all turned round.
Let me tell you something.
I know Keaton. I've been
investigating him for 3 years.
He's a cold-blooded bastard.
I.A.D. Indicted him on 3 counts
of murder before he was kicked off.
Don't sell me the hooker
with the heart of gold.
You've got him all wrong.
Do I?
He was under indictment 7 times
while he was on the force.
In every case, the witnesses
either reversed their testimony...
or died before they could testify.
They finally nailed him for fraud
and he spent 5 years in Sing Sing.
He killed 3 prisoners inside.
Of course,
I can't prove this.
But I can't prove
the best part either.
Dean Keaton was dead.
Did you know that?
He died in a fire two years ago
during an investigation into
the murder of a witness who was
going to testify against him.
Two people saw him walk into
his warehouse before it blew up.
They said he went in to check
a leaking gas main.
It blew up and took all of
Dean Keaton with it.
Within three months
the two witnesses were dead.
One killed himself in his car,
the other fell down
an open elevator shaft.
Let's get this show on the road.
This is not what we discussed.
There are too many people.
We'll be out of here before
he blows his porch light.
- I have a noon meeting.
- Everyone calm down, all right?
I want you to ask this man about
the shoot-out in the harbor.
He says they were buying...
Dope. We know.
He doesn't know what they
were buying, but not dope. People.
What?
- He needs guarantees...
- What's he talking about?
He says his life's in danger.
He saw the devil,
looked him in the eye.
- I'm on my way.
- No, wait a minute.
Ask him to tell you
what he told me.
The devil. Who's the devil?
Keyser Soze.
He was in the harbor
killing many men.
He saw Keyser Soze?
He saw his face.
Tell him to tell her
what he looks like.
Describe him.
I get an anonymous phone call
telling me I can find Keaton
at Mondino's with his attorney,
and there he is.
Because he never profited
from his alleged death,
and we pinned the murder
on another, we had to let him go.
He was dead long enough
for the murder rap to blow over,
and then he had lunch.
- I don't know about that.
- I don't think you do.
But you say you saw Keaton die.
I think you're covering his ass
and he's still out there.
He's behind the whole circus
at the harbor.
He's using you because you're stupid
and you think he's your friend.
You tell me he's dead, so be it.
I want to be sure he's dead
before I go back to New York.
It was the lawyer behind it.
What lawyer?
What lawyer, Verbal?
When I was in that barbershop
quartet in Skokie, Illinois...
You held out on the D. A!
What did you leave out?
- I can phone Deemer in ten minutes.
- The D.A. Gave me immunity.
You get no immunity from me,
you piece of shit.
Every criminal I put in prison,
every cop that owes me a favor,
every creep and scumbag
will know the name Verbal Kint.
Talk, or that precious immunity
they see fit to grant you
won't be worth the paper of
the contract put out on you.
There was a lawyer.
Kobayashi.
- Did he kill Keaton?
- No. But I'm sure Keaton's dead.
Convince me.
And tell me every last detail.
In Los Angeles we met
McManus'fence, Redfoot.
He had a good reputation,
he seemed like a good guy.
We should have known better.
How you doing?
- Good. You?
- Not bad, can't complain.
How you doing, Fenster?
Want me to open it, Ray?
You must be Keaton.
Redfoot, Dean Keaton,
Todd Hockney and Verbal Kint.
Verbal, the man with the plan.
You guys interested in more work?
We're always looking for work.
We're on vacation.
Well, that's too bad.
I got a ton of work and no
good people. Not like you guys.
- What's the job?
- A Texas jeweler named Saul.
He rents a hotel suite downtown.
He does free appraisals.
Sometimes buys, sometimes doesn't.
He carries around a lot of cash.
I figure I get the merchandise,
you keep the green.
- What about security?
- Couple of bodyguards.
Nothing you couldn't handle.
Give me time to check it out?
I'd expect nothing less from you.
We'll call you.
Enjoy L. A... Get yourself laid.
Friend of mine in New York
says you knew Spook Hollis.
The way I hear it, you did time
with old Spook.
Good man. I used to
run dope for him.
- Too bad he got shivved.
- Yeah.
I shivved him.
Better you hear it from me now
than from somebody else.
I appreciate that.
Just out of curiosity,
was it business,
or personal?
A bit of both.
Like I said,
give me a call if you're interested.
Is there a problem?
One job. That was the deal.
One job?
That's a good one, Keaton.
Keaton fought as best he could,
but a man can't change what he is.
He can convince anyone he's
someone else, but never himself.
One day of McManus nagging
and we went back to work.
So my car is wrecked.
I look in the other car
and this woman is naked.
- I laugh so hard I can't breathe.
- Get in the car, Saul.
Freeze!
Here we go!
Right there.
The second one.
Give me the case.
Give me the fucking case!
For the last time,
give me the fucking case!
Come on!
Don't move.
Just hand over the case.
Hand over the fucking case.
Come on, let's go.
Bad day. Fuck it.
Go! Go!
Fuck.
Looks like a lot of
China to me. Shit!
Guys, come on!
- What are you doing?
- I'm gonna kill him.
- Now we'll do it my way.
- Are you gonna kill him?
I'm gonna deal with him.
- You better, or I'm going to.
- Shut up.
What do I do with that?
Feed it to the gimp.
- Ease his pain.
- You don't know what that is?
Some lawyer threw me this job.
Yeah, who?
I don't know. Some Limey.
He's a middle man for someone.
- He doesn't say. I don't ask.
- You're fucking full of shit!
- Fuck you.
Listen. We want to meet him.
That's funny.
He called me last night.
Says he wants to meet you guys.
Okay.
- We'll meet him.
- I'll call you.
- Good. Do that. No problem.
- I don't like it. Wait a minute.
One more thing, tough guy.
Any more surprises
and I'll kill you.
Such a tough guy, McManus.
Do me a favor, all right?
Get the fuck off my dick.
Put a leash on that puppy.
Shame about Saul getting whacked.
Cops are going to be looking for
the guys who did it.
Sooner or later they'll
come around asking me.
You have a sweet night, ladies.
Fuck you.
- So, this lawyer...
- Kobayashi.
- Came from Redfoot.
- Right.
Why leave this out when you
talked to the D. A?
Dave, someone to see you.
I've been looking all over for you.
Still after that coke that left that
bloodbath in the harbor yesterday?
You can stop looking.
There was no coke.
I talked to the guy they pulled out
of a drain pipe after the shootout.
He came to this morning.
He's part of a Hungarian mob
doing a deal with Argentineans.
He says it was definitely not
a dope deal.
But...
Our man says no way on the dope.
The whole bunch was pulling stumps
for Turkey the next day.
They had no time to negotiate
or move that kind of product.
- What's the money for?
- He didn't know.
No one knew except for key people.
They were very hush about it.
It was very sensitive.
I don't get it.
They tell me you got the cripple.
Did he mention Keyser Soze?
Who?
Just bear with me here.
- Who is Keyser Soze?
- Fuck!
We've been going over this
for an hour and a half.
We need to find Redfoot,
and get the hell out of here.
What we need to do
is think back.
Somebody with power,
capable of tracking us
from New York to Los Angeles.
- What the hell are we doing here?
- We're waiting.
- Sit down.
- No. It's hot and I'm bored.
Mr. Hockney, do stay.
Mr. Keaton.
Mr. Fenster and Mr. McManus
I recognize from mugshots.
I assume you are Mr. Kint,
the man who disposed of Saul Berg.
My employer sends his gratitude.
An unexpected benefit.
I am Mr. Kobayashi.
I've been asked by my employer
to bring a proposal.
- What do you want?
- Your services, gentlemen.
One job, one day's work.
Very dangerous.
He doesn't expect you all to live,
but those of you who do
will have 91 million dollars
to divide between you
- in any way you see fit.
- Who's your boss?
I work for Keyser Soze.
- Who's Keyser Soze?
- Judging by the change in mood,
I feel your associates can tell you.
I come with an offer from Mr. Soze.
- An order, actually.
- What do you mean "an order"?
In 1981, Mr. Keaton, you hijacked
a truck in Buffalo, New York.
The cargo was raw steel
which belonged to Mr. Soze
and was destined for Pakistan
to be used in a nuclear reactor.
A most profitable violation
of UN regulations.
You had no way of knowing this
because the man shipping the steel
was working for Mr. Soze
without his knowledge.
Earlier this year, Mr. Fenster
and Mr. McManus hijacked
a cargo flight out of Newark.
The plane carried gold and
platinum wiring, also for Pakistan.
Two months ago, Mr. Hockney
stole a truck carrying gun parts
through Queens.
They were set to be destroyed
by the State of New York.
They were to be lost
and re-routed to New York.
Again Mr. Soze using pawns
who had no knowledge.
Which brings us to Mr. Kint.
Nine months ago,
an unintelligent courier for Mr. Soze
was taken in a confidence scam
by a cripple.
He was relieved of $62,000.
It's taken us some time to find you.
We were to approach you after
your apprehension in New York.
- You set up the lineup.
- Yes,
I was to come and see you.
It seems Mr. Keaton's attorney,
Miss Finnerman,
was a little too effective
in expediting his release.
Holding the rest of you
became a moot point.
- What about Redfoot?
- Mr. Redfoot knew nothing.
Mr. Soze rarely works with
the same people for very long,
and they never know
who they're working for.
One cannot be betrayed
if one has no people.
So why are you telling us?
Because you've stolen from
Mr. Soze, all of you.
That you did not know it
is the reason you're still alive.
He feels you owe him.
You will repay your debt.
Fuck the debt and you. How do
we know you work for Soze?
I don't think that's relevant.
You're responsible for the murder
of Saul Berg and his bodyguards.
Redfoot can testify and we can
see to it that he will.
- What's your point?
- The offer is this, gentlemen.
Mr. Soze's primary interest
is narcotics.
He has been competing for years
with some Argentineans.
Competing with Mr. Soze
has taken its toll.
These Argentineans are
negotiating the sale of 91...
million dollars in cocaine in 3 days.
This purchase will revitalize
the diminishing strength
of their organization.
Mr. Soze would like you
to stop the deal.
You may wait until after the buy.
Any money is yours.
He would like you to get to
the boat and destroy the cocaine.
Then you will be free of your
obligations to Mr. Soze.
Give me one reason why
I shouldn't kill you right now.
A gift
from Mr. Soze.
Good day, gentlemen.
They've got my whole life,
everything I've done since I was 18.
They fuckin' know everything.
Everybody I've worked with
or did time with.
- No. This isn't right.
- I don't know.
Who was that guy who talked
about Soze in New York?
Bricks Marlin.
Yeah, he did jobs for him.
Indirect stuff.
Said he always made five times
more than the job was worth.
A pipe dream. Kobayashi's
using him as window dressing.
I don't know. This is bad.
It's bullshit. Guy could be LAPD.
It's a fucking setup.
The way I hear it,
Soze's some kind of butcher.
- A peerless psycho butcher.
- There is no Keyser Soze!
Who is Keyser Soze?
He's supposed to be Turkish.
Some say his father was German.
Nobody believed he was real
or saw anybody that
worked directly for him.
To hear Kobayashi, anyone
could have worked for Soze.
You never knew.
That was his power.
The greatest trick
the Devil ever pulled...
was convincing the world
he didn't exist.
A story they told me that I believe
is from his days in Turkey.
Some Hungarians
wanted their own mob.
They realized
that to be in power,
you didn't need guns or money
or even numbers.
You just needed the will to do
what the other guy wouldn't.
They come into power
and then they come after Soze.
He was just running dope then.
They come to his home
in the afternoon
looking for his business.
They find his wife and kids
and decide to wait for Soze.
He comes home to find his wife
raped and children screaming.
The Hungarians knew Soze was
tough, not to be trifled with.
So they let him know
they meant business.
They tell him they want
his territory, all his business.
Soze looks over the faces
of his family.
Then he showed these men of will
what will really was.
He tells them he would rather
see his family dead
than live another day after this.
He lets the last Hungarian go.
After his wife and kids are buried,
he goes after the rest of the mob.
He kills their kids,
he kills their wives,
parents and their parents' friends.
He burns down their houses
and the stores they work in.
He kills people that owe them money.
And like that...
he's gone.
Nobody's seen him since.
He becomes a myth, a spook story
criminals tell their kids at night.
"Rat on your Pop,
and Keyser Soze will get you. "
- And no on ever really believes.
- Do you believe in him, Verbal?
Keaton always said:
"I don't believe in God,
but I'm afraid of him".
Well I believe in God...
and the only thing that
scares me is Keyser Soze.
Do you give any weight to this?
Dan Metzheiser from Justice
has a file on Soze in D.C.
It's his hobby. Guys equate him
to that reporter on Incredible Hulk.
- You've heard of him?
- On the street, a few times.
Outside stuff.
Somebody working for a guy
who got money from Keyser Soze.
It could be an old badge,
a hex sign.
When a name meant something.
- But you're here.
- Well, shit yeah.
A burnt guy tries to walk out of
hospital because he's afraid of Soze.
I'll run it up the flagpole.
I told you like it happened.
So I left out how I got there?
D.A. Would have cut my amnesty.
You got what you wanted
out of me. So big fucking deal.
- That's why you never told the D. A?
- You tell me, Agent Kujan.
If I said the Loch Ness Monster
hired me, what would you say?
Turn state's evidence.
I've got immunity now.
What can you possibly offer me?
If there really is a Keyser Soze,
he's gonna come looking for you.
Where's your head, Agent Kujan?
Where do you think
the pressure's coming from?
Keyser Soze knows where
I am right now.
He's got you to let me go so
he can scoop me up 10 minutes later.
Immunity was to deal with you.
I got problems when I post bail.
Why play into his hands?
We can protect you.
Thanks, Dave.
Bang-up job so far:
Extortion, coercion.
Pardon me, but kiss my pucker.
The same fuckers that rounded
us up are now bailing me out?
Think you can catch Keyser Soze?
You think a guy like that gets
close to sticking his head out?
If he comes up, it'll be to get me.
And after that...
you'll never hear from him again.
What happened next?
We woke up and Fenster was gone.
He didn't like slumming for Soze.
He left a good luck note
and took a chunk of the money.
- Then what?
- McManus was furious.
He talked about tracking him
down and ripping his heart out.
That night we got the call.
What call?
Kobayashi told us where
we could find Fenster.
Let's get the fuck out of here.
We got to bury him.
- With what?
- With our hands.
This is nuts.
It's dry sand. When he rots,
surfers will smell him a mile away.
Dig, you fuck.
What are we gonna do?
This guy is gonna kill us.
I don't know about you, pegleg,
but I got no problem running.
Kobayashi doesn't seem to have
a problem with it either.
If you run, we'll be digging
a hole for you. You got that?
This ain't my boy we're burying.
I don't owe anybody.
- So fuck you.
- He was my partner for 5 years.
We did more jobs and saw more
money than you can count.
'Cause now it's payback!
It's not payback.
It's precaution. You want payback
or run away? I don't care.
I'm not doing this for Fenster.
I'm not doing it for you.
I'm doing this for me.
I'm gonna to finish this thing.
This Kobayashi bastard
is not gonna stand on me.
After they killed Fenster,
nobody would run?
- I wanted to.
- Why didn't you say anything?
I tried, but Keaton wouldn't have it.
It was too far-fetched for him.
Keaton was a grounded guy,
an ex cop.
To a cop, the explanation
is always simple.
There's no mystery to the street,
no arch-criminal behind it.
You got a dead body and you think
his brother did it, you're right.
Nobody argued with Keaton.
They set about whacking Kobayashi.
They're coming up.
You hear me? He's coming up.
He's on his way down.
Don't move.
Press 20. Do it now.
Move!
The answer is no.
Mr. Soze will be most...
There is no Soze. Mention his
name again and I'll kill you.
A strange threat. I assume you've
come here to kill me anyway.
We know that you
can get to us.
But now you know
we can get to you.
I'm giving you one last chance
to call this off.
My employer's made up his mind.
He does not change it.
Neither do we.
You got Fenster, but you won't
be able to get all of us.
Not before one of us gets you.
I believe you, I sincerely do.
You would not have been chosen
were you not so suitable.
But I cannot make this decision.
Whatever you threaten me with
is ludicrous in comparison to
what will be done to me if I do not
carry out my orders in full.
I'm the guy that's gonna get you.
I just wanted you to know that.
I'm so sorry, Mr. McManus.
I implore you, believe me.
Mr. Soze is very real.
- And very determined.
- We'll see.
Before you do me in,
Mr. McManus,
will you let me finish my
business with Miss Finneran?
What did you say?
Edie Finneran. She's upstairs,
in my office
for an extradition deposition.
I requested her personally.
She flew in yesterday.
No matter. Kill away, Mr. McManus.
You're lying.
Am I?
Her escort while she's here
in Los Angeles.
Never leaves her side.
She's in good hands.
Get some rest. The boat will be
ready for you on Friday.
If I see you or any of
your friends before then,
she will be the victim of
a gruesome violation before dying.
As indeed will your father,
Mr. Hockney,
and your Uncle Randall
in Arizona, Mr. Kint.
I might only castrate
Mr. McManus' nephew, David.
Do I make myself clear?
Take care of the bodies.
Add it the cost of Mr. Fenster.
If you'll excuse me, gentlemen.
It's a logistical nightmare.
Close quarters,
ten maybe twenty men.
No telling how many below deck.
- Can we stealth these guys?
- No.
With all that coke,
they're gonna be ready.
Now sunny point number two.
If one of us gets through and
jacks the boat, we still got nothing.
What if we wait for the money?
Ten more men at least.
In my opinion, it can't be done.
No one comes out alive.
I'm gonna wait for the money.
- Me too.
- Didn't you hear what he said?
- Lf I'm going in, I want a cut.
- Me too.
There's nothing that can't be done.
We're walking into certain death.
The news said it's raining
in New York.
- What language is that?
- I don't know.
Russian, I think.
Hungarian?
The package has arrived, gentlemen.
You kids ready?
I would be if I didn't have to
stop and answer you.
I'm ready. McManus...
you better be set up in 10 seconds.
I'm ready.
I want you to stay here.
I'm supposed to cover...
If I don't get out of this, I want
you to take the money and go.
Tell Edie what happened.
She knows people and what to do.
If I don't get Kobayashi,
she'll get him her way.
- What if I?
- Just do what I say.
Please.
Tell her that...
Tell her I tried.
McManus, he's on his way.
I'm there.
One, two, three, four...
five, six, seven.
Oswald was a fag.
Hi. How you doing?
Is there a problem?
Now.
Old MacDonald had a farm.
And on this farm he shot some guys.
Elvis has left the building.
Why didn't you run?
I froze up.
I thought about how Fenster
looked when we buried him.
And then about Keaton.
Looked like he might pull it off.
A boy found a body on the beach
shot twice in the head.
- The Bureau identified him.
- What else?
Arturo Marquez, a petty smuggler
from Argentina.
Arrested, New York, for trafficking.
He escapes to California.
Picked up on Long Beach, they set up
extradition, he escapes again.
Get this. Edie Finneran's brought in
to advise on the proceedings.
Kobayashi.
New York faxed a copy of
his testimony. He was a rat.
- Yeah, a big fucking rat.
- He opposed returning to prison.
So he named close to fifty people.
Guess who he named in the finale.
Keyser Soze.
There's more.
I'll tell you what I know.
Stop me when this sounds familiar.
There was no dope on that boat.
You, stay quiet.
He's here. I know he's here.
That's him. I'm telling you.
I know he's here.
- You can't understand. That's him!
- Shut up!
I tell you it's Keyser Soze!
- Where's Hockney?
- I don't know.
- There's no coke.
- What?
There's no coke. I've been up
and down this ship,
in every fucking room.
There is nothing!
Nothing!
Don't fuck with me.
There is no fucking coke!
I'm out of here.
I told them nothing.
I swear.
Please.
McManus.
What the fuck is going on?
The strangest thing.
It's in your statement: You saw
a man in a suit with a slim build.
- Wait a minute.
- I don't have a minute.
You saw Soze and told the DA
you didn't know who it was?
- There was dope on that boat.
- You know what I'm getting at.
- Get out of my face.
- You know.
I've got immunity.
I don't have to take that shit.
- You know what I'm getting at.
- I don't know.
The truth.
Try to tell me you saw
someone kill Keaton.
- I did.
- You are lying to me.
You've known this whole time.
I don't know what you're saying.
I did see Keaton get shot.
Then why didn't you help him?
You had a gun.
He was your friend.
Because I was of afraid.
Okay?
- Afraid.
- Afraid of what?
I knew it was Keyser Soze.
It was Keyser Soze,
the Devil himself.
How do you shoot the Devil
in the back?
What if you miss?
Let's get back to the pier.
- Ever hear of Arturo Marquez?
- What? No.
He was a stool pigeon for
the Justice Dept. He swore
to Federal Marshals that he
had seen and could identify
one Keyser Soze.
It says right here in the report.
He had knowledge of his business,
including drug trafficking
- and murder.
- I never heard of him.
His people were selling him
to a gang of Hungarians.
Most likely the ones that Soze
all but wiped out in Turkey.
The money wasn't for dope.
They were buying the one guy
that could incriminate Soze.
- I said I never heard of him.
- But Keaton did.
Edie Finneran was
Marquez's extradition advisor.
She knew who he was
and what he knew.
There were no drugs on that boat.
It was a hit...
a suicide mission to whack out
the guy that could finger Soze.
Soze sent men in that he could
march into certain death.
Soze sent us to kill someone?
I'm saying Keaton did.
He left you behind for a reason.
Just do what I tell you.
If you all knew that Soze
could find you anywhere,
why give you the money to run?
He could've used you on the boat.
He wanted me to live.
A dirty cop without loyalties
finds it in his heart to save
a worthless rat cripple?
No sir! Why?
Edie!
I don't buy that reformed story.
Even if I did, I don't believe
he'd send you to protect her.
So why?
- Because he was my friend.
- No, Verbal.
He wasn't your friend.
Keaton didn't have friends.
What are you doing here?
He saved you
because he wanted it that way.
It was his will.
Keaton was Keyser Soze!
The kind of man
who could wrangle
the wills of men like
Hockney and McManus,
and engineer a police lineup
through all his years
of contacts in NYPD.
The kind of man who
could've killed Edie Finnerman.
She was found yesterday in a hotel.
Shot twice in the head.
What do you think about Keaton now?
Edie?
He used all of you
to get him on the boat.
He couldn't get on alone.
He had to pull the trigger
to make sure he got the one man
who could identify him.
- This is all bullshit.
- You said you saw him die.
Or did you?
You had to hide when you
first heard the police cars.
You said you heard the shot
before the fire,
but you didn't see him die.
- He would never...
- He programmed you
to tell us what he wanted.
He knew we were close.
Why the political pressure?
Why were you protected?
It was Keaton.
- Immunity was your reward.
- But why me?
Why not Fenster or McManus
or Hockney?
I'm stupid. I'm a cripple.
Because you're a cripple.
Because you're stupid.
Because you're weaker than them.
If he's dead,
if what you say is true,
then it won't matter.
It was his idea to hit
the Taxi Service, wasn't it?
- Tell me the truth.
- It was all Keaton.
We followed him
from the beginning.
I didn't know.
I saw him die.
I believe he's dead. Christ!
You're not safe on your own.
You think he's?
Keyser Soze?
I don't know, Verbal.
Keyser Soze's a shield.
Or like you said, a spook story.
But I know Keaton, and someone
is pulling strings for you.
Stay here and let us protect you.
- I'm not bait. I post today.
- You posted 20 minutes ago.
Captain Leo wants you out,
unless you turn state's.
I'll take my chances.
If someone wants to,
they'll get you out there.
Testify. You might not see trial.
Maybe so.
But I'm not a rat, Agent Kujan.
Fucking cops.
Excuse me. Can I use your fax?
Sign for these, Mr. Kint.
One watch, gold.
One cigarette lighter, gold.
One pack of cigarettes. Thank you.
We still got nothing, Dave.
I know what I wanted about Keaton.
Which is nothing.
No matter. He must know
how close we came.
Keyser Soze or no Keyser Soze,
if Keaton is alive,
he's not coming up again.
I'll find him.
Waste of time.
A rumor is not a rumor
that doesn't die.
What?
Nothing.
Man, you're a slob.
Yes, but it all has a system, Dave.
To make sense of it,
you got to stand back.
Want to see a real horror show?
See my garage.
Convince me.
When I was in a barbershop
quartet in Skokie Illinois...
Where's your head, Agent Kujan?
What we need to do
is think back.
I'm sure you've heard tall tales.
This isn't right.
It's all there.
I'm telling it straight, I swear.
Some guy in California. Redfoot.
A gift from Mr. Soze.
Talk to me, Verbal.
What about Redfoot?
Mr. Redfoot knew nothing.
Baritone was a big fat guy.
...never seen again.
...picking beans in Guatemala.
- You thought he was a good man.
- I know he was good.
The strangest thing.
How do you shoot the Devil
in the back?
...protected from on high
by the Prince of...
What's your story, pretzel man?
- There was a lawyer.
- What lawyer, Verbal?
I am Mr. Kobayashi.
Convince me.
Every creep will know the name
of Verbal Kint.
The cripple, did you see him?
Which way did he go?
He went out that way.
I know you know something.
I'm smarter than you.
And I'll find out
what I want, whether you
like it or not.
You know what I'm getting at!
The truth!
Somebody with power,
capable of...
I'm talking about Keyser Soze!
You think a guy like that gets
close to sticking his head out?
Because you're stupid.
Because you're a cripple.
You've known the whole time!
I can't feel my legs, Keyser.
First thing I learned on the job
was how to spot a murderer.
You got the cripple from New York.
- Did he mention Keyser Soze?
- Who?
You'll never hear from him again.
The greatest trick
the Devil ever pulled...
was convincing the world
he didn't exist.
And like that...
he's gone.