Dream, little one
Dream
Dream, my little one
Though the hunter
In the night
Fills your childish heart
With fright
Fear is only
A dream
So dream, little one
Dream
Now, you remember, children,
how I told you last Sunday...
about the good Lord going up into he mountain
and talking to the people...
and how he said,
"Blessed are the pure in heart...
for they shall see God..."
and how he said that King Solomon
in all his glory...
was not as beautiful
as the lilies of the field?
And I know you won't forget,
"Judge not lest ye be judged..."
because I explained that to you.
And then the good Lord went on to say...
"Beware of false prophets...
"which come to you in sheep's clothing...
"but inwardly they are ravening wolves.
Ye shall know them by their fruits."
Five, 10, 15, 20, 25, 30,
35, 40, 45, 50, 55, 60...
65, 70, 75, 80, 85, 90, 95, 100!
Here I come, ready or not!
What's wrong?
Hey! Hey!
"A good tree cannot bring forth evil fruit.
"Neither can a corrupt tree
bring forth good fruit.
Wherefore, by their fruits
ye shall know them."
Well, now, what's it to be, Lord?
Another widow?
How many has it been? Six?
Twelve?
I disremember.
You say the word, Lord,
I'm on my way.
You always send me money
to go forth and preach your word.
A widow with a little wad of bills
hid away in a sugar bowl.
Lord, I am tired.
Sometimes I wonder
if you really understand.
Not that you mind the killings.
Your Book is full of killings.
But there are things you do hate, Lord.
Perfume-smellin' things...
lacy things, things with curly hair.
There are too many of them.
You can't kill a world.
You driving a touring car
with a Moundsville license?
Harry Powell, for the theft
of that touring car...
you will spend 30 days
in the Moundsville Penitentiary.
Uh, Preacher Harry Powell.
A car thief, picked up where you were-
a man of God?
Harry Powell.
Hold Miss Jenny still.
Stand still, Miss Jenny!
There. What's so hard about that?
Daddy!
- Where's your mom?
- Out shoppin'.
- You're bleedin', Dad.
- Listen to me, John.
This money here-
we gotta hide it before they get to me.
There's close to $10,000. Where?
Under a rock in the smokehouse?
No, no.
Under the bricks in the grape arbor?
No, no. They'd dig for it.
Sure. That's the place.
- That's him.
- He probably still has that gun.
Listen to me, Son.
You've gotta swear.
Swear means promise.
First, swear you'll take care of little Pearl.
Guard her with your life, boy.
Then swear you won't never tell
where the money's hid, not even your mom.
- Yes, Dad.
- You understand?
- Not even her?
- You got common sense. She ain't.
When you grow up,
that money will belong to you.
Now stand up straight and look me in the eye.
Raise your right hand.
Now swear-
"I'll guard Pearl with my life."
I will guard Pearl with my life.
- "And I won't never tell about the money."
- And I won't never tell about the money.
And you, Pearl- you swear too.
Ben Harper.
I'm goin' now, children. Good-bye.
Drop that gun, Harper.
We don't want the kids hurt.
Just mind what you swore, Son.
Mind, boy.
Don't.
Don't!
Dad.
Ben Harper, it is the sentence of this court...
that for the murder
of Ed Smiley and Corey South...
you be hanged by the neck
until you are dead.
And may God have mercy on your soul.
I got you all buffaloed.
Ain't none of you gonna get it outta me.
None of you.
Where, Ben? Where?
- Where?
- "And a little child shall lead them."
Now, come on, boy. Tell me.
Ben, I'm a man of God.
- Tryin' to make me talk about it in my sleep.
- No, Ben. No.
What'd I say?
What? What? What? What?
You was quotin' the Scripture, Ben.
You said, "And a little child shall lead them."
- You killed two men, Ben Harper.
- That's right, Preacher.
I robbed that bank
'cause I got tired of seein'...
children roamin' the woodlands
without food...
children roamin' the highways
in this here depression...
children sleepin' in old abandoned car bodies
and junk heaps.
And I promised myself I'd never see the day
when my young 'uns would want.
With that $10,000,
I could build a tabernacle...
make that Wheeling Island tabernacle
look like a chicken house.
Will you have free candy for the kids, Preacher?
Think of it, Ben-
with that cursed, bloodied gold.
How come you got that stick knife
hid up in your bed blankets, Preacher?
The Lord blinded mine enemies
when they brought me in this evil place.
I smuggled it in right
under the noses of them guards.
I come not with peace...
but with a sword.
You, Preacher?
This sword has served me through
many an evil time, Ben Harper.
What religion you profess, Preacher?
The religion the Almighty and me
worked out betwixt us.
I'll bet.
Salvation is a last-minute business, boy.
Keep talkin', Preacher.
If you was to let that money
serve the Lord's purpose...
he might feel kindly turned towards you.
Keep talkin', Preacher.
Now, don't you think the Lord
might change his mind if you was to-
Lord...
you sure knowed what you was doin'...
when you put me in this very cell
at this very time.
A man with $10,000 hid somewhere...
and a widow in the makin'.
- Any trouble?
- No.
He was a cool one, that Harper.
Never broke.
He carried on some, kicked.
They say he left a wife and two kids.
I never heard.
- He never told about the money?
- No.
What do you figure he done with it?
He took the secret with him
when I dropped him.
That you, Bart? Supper's waitin'.
Mother, sometimes I think it might be better
if I was to quit my job as guard.
You're always this way
when there's a hangin'.
You never have to be there.
Sometimes I wish
I was back in the mine.
And leave me a widow
after another blast like the one in '24?
Not on your life, old mister.
See what the hangman done
See the robber swing
And now my song is done
See what the hangman done
See the robber swing
Are you going to buy it, John?
So your mommy's keepin' you
out of school these days.
How is your poor, poor mother?
She's at Spoon's ice cream parlor.
Say, did they ever find out what your father done
with all that money he stole?
Pearl and me, we have to go.
- You better not sing that song.
- Why?
'Cause you're too little.
Can we get some candy?
No.
Willa Harper, there are certain
plain facts of life that adds up...
just like two plus two makes four,
and one of them is this-
No woman is able to raise
growin' youngsters alone.
The Lord meant that job for two.
Icey, I just don't want a husband.
Ain't a question of wantin' or not wantin'.
You're no spring chicken.
You're a grown woman
with two little young 'uns.
It's a man you need in the house,
Willa Harper.
Tell me a story, John.
Well, once upon a time...
there was a rich king...
who had himself a son and a daughter.
They all lived in a castle over in Africa.
Then one day this king
got taken away by some bad men.
And before he got took off...
he told his son to kill anyone
who tried to steal his gold.
And before long,
the bad men came back and-
Leaning
- Leaning
- Just a man.
Good night, Pearl. Sleep tight
and don't let the bedbugs bite.
Good night, Miss Jenny.
Don't let the bedbugs bite.
Leaning
Leaning on
The everlasting arms
She don't put in Cresap's Landin' no more,
but she still blows as she passes.
Come on in and have a cup of coffee, boy.
Ain't nobody stole Dad's skiff.
Ain't nobody gonna neither
as long as Uncle Birdie's around.
First day my joints is limber enough,
I'll haul her out and give her a good caulkin'.
Ain't seen ya in a coon's age, boy.
I've been mindin' Pearl.
Shucks. Ain't it a caution what a woman
will load onto a man's back...
when he ain't lookin'?
Excuse me, cap, while I-
while I sweeten my coffee.
Dead and gone these 25 year
and never takes her eyes off me.
Man of my years needs a little snort
in the mornin' to heat the boilers.
Yeah.
I was talkin' to this stranger
up at the boardinghouse.
- He knowed your dad.
- Where'd he know Dad?
I'll not hide it from you, boy.
He knowed him in the Moundsville Penitentiary.
I gotta go now, Uncle Birdie.
Well, you just got here, boy.
I told Mom I'd be back to Spoon's for Pearl.
"God works in a mysterious way,
his wonders to perform."
Yes, I was with brother Harper
right up to the end.
Now that I'm no longer employed
by the penitentiary...
it is my joy to bring this small comfort
to his loved ones.
It's a mighty good man
would go out of his way...
to bring a word of cheer
to a grievin' widow.
- So you ain't with the state no more?
- No, brother. I resigned only yesterday.
The heartrendin' spectacle of them poor men
was just too much for me.
Ah, little lad, you're starin' at my fingers.
Would you like me to tell you
the little story of right hand, left hand...
the story of good and evil?
H-A-T-E.
It was with this left hand
that old brother Cain...
struck the blow that laid his brother low.
L-O-V-E.
You see these fingers, dear hearts?
These fingers has veins
that run straight to the soul of man.
The right hand, friends-
the hand of love.
Now watch and I'll show you
the story of life.
These fingers, dear hearts, is always a-warrin'
and a-tuggin', one again' t'other.
Now watch 'em.
Old brother left hand.
Left hand hate's a-fightin'.
And it looks like love's a goner.
But wait a minute. Wait a minute.
Hot dog! Love's a-winnin'.
Yes, sirree!
It's love that won.
And old left hand hate
is down for the count.
I never heard it better told.
I wish every soul in this community
could get the benefit.
Oh, you've just got to stay
for our picnic Sunday.
No, I must wend my way downriver
on the Lord's business.
You ain't leaving' in no hurry
if we can help it.
John, mind your manners.
Take that look off your face. Act nice.
Why, he don't mean no impudence,
do you, boy?
Do ya, boy?
Ah, many's the time poor brother Ben
told me about these young 'uns.
What'd he tell ya?
Why, he told me what fine little lambs
you and your sister both was.
Is that all?
Why, no, boy.
He told me lots and lots of things.
- Nice things, boy.
- Thank you.
My, that fudge smells yummy.
It's for the picnic.
And you don't get a smidgen of my fudge
unless you stay for the picnic.
Bringing in the sheaves
We shall come rejoicing
bringing in the sheaves
Sowing in the morning
Sowing seeds of kindness
Sowing in the noontide
and the dewy eve
Waiting for the harvest
and the time of reaping
We shall come rejoicing
bringing in the sheaves
Bringing in the sheaves
We shall come rejoicing
bringing in the sheaves
Bringing in the sheaves
We shall come rejoicing
bringing in the sheaves
Don't he have the grandest singin' voice?
John! Pearl!
Run along and play, you two.
- Where?
- Down by the river! My goodness.
Bringing in the sheaves
That feller's just achin' to settle down
with some nice woman...
and make a home for himself.
Icey, it's awful soon after Ben's passing.
If ever I saw a sign from heaven.
- John don't like him much.
- Pearl dotes on him.
The boy worries me.
I know it's silly, but it's like
there's somethin' still between him and his dad.
What he needs is a dose of salts.
- No, there's somethin' else.
- What?
- The money.
- I declare, Willa Harper.
You'll let that money haunt you
to your grave.
Icey, I would love to be satisfied...
that Harry Powell don't think
I got that money hid somewhere.
You come right out
and ask that man of God.
Mr. Powell!
Clear that evil mud out of your soul.
John! Pearl!
Come along here and get some fudge.
- I don't want no fudge.
- You do what you're told!
- You go set down by the river.
- Oh, Icey, I'm a sight.
Get along with you.
You!
That young lady better look sharp...
or some smart sister between here and Captina
is gonna snap him up right from under her nose.
She's not the only fish in the river.
Now, you two stay put.
Shilly-shallying around.
A husband's one piece of store goods
you never know...
till you get it home and take the paper off.
Did Ben Harper ever tell you
what he done with the money he stole?
My dear child, don't you know?
She's moonin' about Ben Harper.
That wasn't love.
That was just flapdoodle.
Have some fudge, lambs.
When you've been married
to a man 40 years...
you know all that don't amount
to a hill of beans.
I've been married to my Walt that long...
and I swear, in all that time,
I just lie there thinkin' about my canning.
John!
A woman's a fool to marry for that.
That's somethin' for a man.
The good Lord never meant
for a decent woman to want that.
Not really want it.
It's all just a fake and a pipe dream.
John, Mr. Powell has something to tell you.
Well, John, the night before your father died...
he told me what he did with that money.
That money's at the bottom of the river...
wrapped around a 12-pound cobblestone.
Thank you, Harry.
I feel clean now.
My whole body's just a-quivering with cleanness.
John, come here.
Your tie is crooked.
'Twas down at Cresap's Landin'
Along the river shore
Birdie Steptoe was a pilot
In the good old days of yore
Now he sets in his old wharf boat
All the big boats heave a sigh
- When'll Dad's skiff be ready?
- Can't hear you, boy!
They blow for Uncle Birdie
And the times
That ere gone by
When'll the skiff be ready?
Have her ready inside a week.
Then we'll go fishing.
- How's your ma?
- Oh, she's all right.
- How's your sister, Pearl?
- Just fine.
- You leavin', boy?
- Yep. Gotta watch out for Pearl, Uncle Birdie.
Well, good night, boy.
Come again anytime.
And mind, boy...
I'll have your pa's skiff shipshape
inside a week.
Somebody there?
Anybody there?
Anybody here?
Good evenin', John.
I had a little talk
with your mother tonight, John...
and your mother decided it might be best for me
to let you know the news.
Your mother told me she wanted me
to be a daddy to you and your sister.
We're gonna get married, boy.
Did you hear what I said, boy?
Married.
We're goin' to Sisterville tomorrow,
and when we get back-
You ain't my dad.
You'll never be my dad.
When we get back,
we're all going to be friends...
and share our fortunes together, John.
You think you can make me tell!
But I won't! I won't! I won't!
- Tell me what, boy?
- Nothin'.
We're not keeping secrets from each other,
are we, little lad?
No, no.
Well, no matter.
We've got a long time together, boy.
Wave your hands. Great sakes.
Now, you wait here
while I get your night things.
Now can I tell?
When Mr. Powell's our daddy,
then can I tell him about-
- You swore, Pearl.
- John, don't.
You promised Dad you wouldn't tell.
I love Mr. Powell lots and lots, John.
Men.
Harry?
Fix that window shade.
- Harry?
- I was praying.
Oh, I'm sorry. I didn't know.
I- I thought-
You thought, Willa,
that the moment you walked in that door...
I'd start to pawin' you
in that abominable way...
that men are supposed to do
on their weddin' night.
- Ain't that right now?
- No, no, no.
I think it's time we made one thing
perfectly clear, Willa.
Marriage to me represents a blending
of two spirits in the sight of heaven.
Get up, Willa.
- Harry, what-
- Get up.
Now, go look at yourself
yonder in that mirror.
Do as I say.
Look at yourself.
What do you see, girl?
You see the body of a woman-
the temple of creation and motherhood.
You see the flesh of Eve
that man since Adam has profaned.
That body was meant for begettin' children.
It was not meant for the lust of men.
Do you want more children, Willa?
I-
No.
It's the business of this marriage
to mind those two you have now...
not to beget more.
Yes.
All right, you can get in bed now
and stop shiverin'.
Help me to get clean...
so I can be what Harry
wants me to be.
Meanest, orneriest, sneakingest critter
in the whole river, boy.
A gar.
- Here are your can of hooks, Uncle Birdie.
- Boy.
Ain't a hook in the land
strong enough to land Mr. Gar.
What a feller needs is mother wit
and a horsehair.
Golly. Won't it bust it, Uncle Birdie?
Nah, a horsehair will hold
a lumpin' whale.
- You mind my cussin', boy?
- No.
Well, the reason I ask,
your step-pa bein' a preacher and all-
Never was much of a one
for preachers my own self.
I don't know what's wrong
up at your house...
but always remember, cap...
if you're ever in trouble,
holler and come a-runnin'.
Uncle Birdie's your friend.
There! There, you slimy, snag-toothed,
bait-stealin' so-and-so!
- Amen! Amen!
- Amen!
Amen!
- You have all sinned.
- Yes! Yes!
Which one of you can say,
as I can say...
that you drove a good man to murder?
Because I kept a-houndin' him for perfume...
and clothes and face paint!
And he slew two human beings!
And he come to me, and he said...
"Take this money and buy yourself
the clothes and the paint!"
- Yes! Yes!
- But, brethren-
Brethren, that's where the Lord stepped in!
- That's where the Lord stepped in!
- Yes!
"Ye," said the Lord to that man...
"you take that money...
and you throw it in the river!"
- In the river!
Now, you're John, and you're Pearl.
Pearl? Pearl?
You'll get awful mad, John.
I done a sin.
- Pearl!
- I didn't tell no one.
Pearl, oh, Pearl.
It's all here.
- John.
- Yes?
- What are you doing, boy?
- Gettin' Pearl to bed.
- What's taking you so long about it?
- Nothing.
What's that you're playin' with?
Uh, Pearl's junk. Mom gets mad
when she plays out here and don't put it away.
Come on, children.
Off to bed with the both of you.
Come here, John.
Your mother tells me you tattled on me.
She said you told her
I asked where that money was hid.
That wasn't very nice, boy.
Have a heart.
Yeah.
Well, it doesn't matter.
It's your word against mine.
It's me your mother believes.
Were you impudent again
to Mr. Powell, John?
Mom, I didn't mean it.
What were you impudent about?
He asked me about the money again, Mom.
John, you always make up that lie.
There is no money.
Why can't you get that through your head?
The boy's as stubborn
and as mulish as a sheep.
- It's a shame.
- Good night, Icey.
- Good night, honey.
- Good night, Walt.
Good night, Willa.
Plan on a longer visit next time.
You hardly get settled
before you're frettin' to get home again.
I'm needed to keep peace
and harmony betwixt them.
It's my burden,
and I'm proud of it, Icey.
- Where's the money hid?
- I don't know.
She thinks that money's
at the bottom of the river.
But you and me, we know better,
don't we, little lad?
I don't know nothin'.
Well, never mind, boy.
The summer's young yet.
Pearl?
Come here.
John's a fella likes to keep secrets.
I'll tell you a secret.
Yes?
I knowed your daddy.
And you know what your daddy told me?
He said,
"You tell my little girl Pearl...
that there's to be no secrets
between her and you."
- Yes?
- All right. Now it's your turn.
What secret shall I tell?
Oh, uh, what's your name?
You're just fooling.
My name's Pearl.
Well, I reckon I'll have to try again.
Uh, where's the money hid?
Pearl, you swore you wouldn't tell!
You swore! You swore! You swore!
You hit Daddy with a hairbrush.
Now, you see?
We just can't have anything to do with John.
You and me are goin' down
to the parlor, Pearl.
John was just plumb bad
through and through.
- John's bad.
- Yes, John's bad.
Tell me another secret about my dad.
Oh, no. Your turn.
All right. What secret shall I tell?
Where's the money hid?
- John's bad.
- Where's the money hid?
You tell me, you little wretch,
or I'll tear your arm off!
- Icey, I'm worried about Willa.
- How do you mean?
Well, I'm figurin' how to say it
so as you won't get mad.
Say what, Walt Spoon?
- There's something wrong about it, Mother.
- About what?
- About Mr. Powell, all of it.
- Walt!
Now, Mother, a body's
got a right to their feelings.
May the Lord have mercy on you,
Walt Spoon.
Now, Mother, I was just-
Amen.
Are you through praying?
I'm through, Harry.
You were listening outside the parlor window.
- It ain't in the river, is it, Harry?
- Answer me.
Ben never told you he throwed it
in the river, did he?
The children know where it's hid.
John knows. Is that it, Harry?
Then it's still here amongst us...
tainting us.
You must have known about it
all along, Harry.
But that ain't the reason
why you married me.
I know that much.
Because the Lord just wouldn't let it be.
He made you marry me...
so you could show me
the way and the life...
and the salvation of my soul.
Ain't that so, Harry?
So you might say that it was the money
that brung us together.
The rest of it don't matter.
Walt! Come quick!
- What's wrong, Mother?
- He's in there.
- Who?
- Mr. Powell.
Willa has run away.
I'll be switched. Just went?
She took out some time in the night
in that old Model "T."
- Oh, is he hit pretty bad?
- All to pieces.
- There's a little peach brandy in here.
- Walt!
- A man of the cloth?
- Well, just a sip.
Walt Spoon, that's for sickness in the house!
- Well, what can we do, Mother?
- I thought if you went and talked to him- you know, another man.
- Oh, no, now, Mother, please. No, I'm no good at-
- Get in there.
- Mr. Powell?
- A strange woman is a narrow pit.
Amen. Amen.
She lieth in wait as for prey
and increaseth the transgressors among men.
Oh, my dear, dear friends,
whatever would I do without you?
Mr. Powell!
Well, if there's anything-
anything we can-
No, it's my shame. It's my crown of thorns.
I must wear it bravely.
What could have possessed that girl?
Satan.
Didn't you have no inklin'?
Yes, I did from the very first night.
- First night?
- Our honeymoon.
How's that?
She turned me out of the bed.
No.
- Well, what do you figure to do?
- Do?
Why, just stay right here
and take care of them kids.
Maybe it was never meant for a woman like Willa
to taint their young lives.
It's mighty brave of you, Preacher.
Oh, I reckon it was just ordained that way,
brother Spoon.
Didn't- Didn't she leave no word?
A scrawl on a notepaper on the bureau.
I burned it.
Tore it up and burned it.
It stank so strong of hellfire.
Amen.
The pitcher has went to the well
once too often, friends.
Oh, she'll come draggin' her tail back home.
She'll not be back.
I reckon I'm safe in promisin' you that.
- Maybe she's just run off on a spree.
- No, no.
- Well, there's no harm in hopin'.
- Ain't no sense in it neither.
I figured somethin' like that was brewin'
when she went to bed last night.
How?
Well, she tarried around in the kitchen
after I'd gone up...
and when I went downstairs
to see what was wrong-
What?
Well, she'd found this jar
of dandelion wine...
that the husband- this Harper-
had hid somewheres in the cellar.
She was drinkin'.
I tried to save her.
I know you did, Mr. Powell.
I know how hard you tried.
But the devil wins sometimes.
Can't nobody say
I didn't do my best to save her.
Leaning
Safe and secure from all alarms
Leaning on the everlasting arms
Children!
Children.
Pearl?
Careful. Here.
Why do we have to hide, John?
Children.
- Where's Mom?
- She's gone to Moundsville.
- To see Dad?
- Yes, I reckon that's it.
Now, listen to me, Pearl.
You and me is runnin' off tonight.
- Why?
- Children.
If we stay here,
something awful will happen to us.
- Won't Daddy Powell take care of us?
- No.
That's just it. No.
- Where are we going, John?
- Somewheres. I don't know yet.
I'm hungry, John.
- We'll steal somethin' to eat.
- It'll spoil our suppers.
Pearl.
I can hear you whisperin', children,
so I know you're down there.
I can feel myself gettin' awful mad.
I'm out of patience, children.
I'm coming to find you now.
Mr. Powell.
Well, well, Mrs. Spoon.
Where are the children?
They're down there in that cellar
playin' games...
and they won't mind me
when I call them.
I'm at my wit's end, Mrs. Spoon.
John? Pearl?
John! Pearl!
Shake a leg.
Well, well, well. What's that?
Just a little hot supper
I fixed for you and the children.
It seemed the Ieast we could do.
I won't have you worrying
poor Mr. Powell another minute.
Just look at you-
dust and filth from top to toe.
Want me to take 'em up
and wash 'em good?
No. No, thank you, dear Icey.
Thank you.
I'll tend to them. Thank you.
Don't be too hard on 'em, Preacher.
Poor motherless children.
Remember now, Mr. Powell,
don't be afraid to call on us.
Good-bye.
Good-bye, Miz Spoon, and thanks again.
Now, weren't you afraid, little lambs,
down there in all that dark?
They'll think it was me.
They'll say it was poor old Uncle Birdie.
If you could've seen it, Bess.
Down there in the deep place...
with her hair wavin' soft and lazy, like...
meadow grass under floodwater.
And that slit in her throat...
like she had an extra mouth.
You're the only human mortal
I can go to, Bess.
If I go to the law...
they'll hang it on me.
Sweet heaven, save poor old Uncle Birdie.
- I'm hungry.
- Sure.
And there's fried chicken, sweet potatoes,
corn bread and apple cobbler.
- Can I have my supper, please?
- Naturally.
Can I have milk too?
But first, we'll have a little talk-
about our secrets.
- No.
- And why not, pray tell?
'Cause John said I mustn't.
Never mind what John said!
John's a meddler.
Now stop that sniveling.
Look a-here.
You know what that is?
Wanna see something cute?
Now looky.
How about that?
This is what I use on meddlers.
John might be a meddler.
No, no.
No, no, little lamb. Don't touch it.
Don't touch my knife.
That makes me mad.
Makes me very, very mad.
Now, just tell me.
Where's the money hid?
But I swore.
I promised John I wouldn't tell.
John doesn't matter!
Can't I get that through your head,
you poor, silly, disgusting little wretch?
There now. You made me lose my temper.
I'm sorry. I am real sorry.
Now just tell me.
- Where's it hid, honey?
- I'll tell.
I thought I told you
to keep your mouth shut.
It ain't fair to make Pearl tell
when she swore she wouldn't.
I'll tell.
Well, I declare.
Sometimes I think poor old John
might make it to heaven yet.
All right, boy, where's the money?
In the cellar,
buried under a stone in the floor.
It'll go hard if I find you're lyin', boy.
I'm not lying. Go look for yourself.
All right.
Come along.
What?
Go ahead of me, the both of you.
Down those stairs.
You don't reckon I'd leave you,
do you, boy?
Well, don't you believe me?
Why, sure, boy. Sure.
All right. Where now?
Mind, no tricks now.
I can't abide a liar.
Yonder.
Oh, no, you don't.
- Now, where, boy? Where?
- Under the stone in the floor.
This is concrete.
John made a sin.
John told a lie.
The Lord's a-talkin' to me now.
He's a-sayin'...
"A liar is an abomination
before mine eyes."
Speak, boy. Where's it hid?
Speak.
Speak, or I'll cut your throat
and leave you to drip...
like a hog hung up in butcherin' time.
Pearl, shut up. Pearl, you swore.
You could save him, little bird.
It's in my doll! It's in my doll!
The doll.
Why, sure.
Last place anybody'd think to look.
Uncle Birdie Steptoe.
Open that door!
You spawn of the devil's own strumpet!
Uncle Birdie! Uncle Birdie!
- Uncle Birdie.
- Don't.
Hide us, Uncle Birdie.
He's a-comin' with his knife.
It's me- John Harper and Pearl.
You told me to come.
- Johnny?
- Uncle Birdie. Oh, please.
Please! Wake up!
I swear on- on the Book.
I never done it. I-
I never-
There's still the river.
The skiff is under the willow.
Children!
Once upon a time
There was a pretty fly
He had a pretty wife
This pretty fly
But one day she flew away
Flew away
She had two pretty children
But one night
These two pretty children
Flew away
Into the sky
Into the moon
"Dear Walt and Icey...
"I bet you been worried
and gave us up for lost.
"Took the kids down here with me
for a visit to my sister Elsie's farm.
"Thought a little change of scenery
would do us all a world of good...
"after so much trouble and heartache.
"At least the kids will get a-plenty
of good home cookin'.
Your devoted Harry Powell."
Now, ain't you relieved, Walt?
Sure. But you was worried too, Mother.
Takin' off with never a word of good-bye.
You know, I got to figurin' maybe them Gypsies
busted in and done off with all three of 'em.
You and your Gypsies.
They've been gone a week.
Sure. But not before one of 'em
knifed a farmer and stole his horse.
Never caught the Gypsy nor the horse.
Such times when young 'uns run the roads.
Go away, children.
Hungry, I suppose.
- Well, I can't spare you more than one potato apiece.
- Come on.
- Where're your folks?
- Ain't got none.
Oh, go away. Go away.
An ungrateful child
is an abomination before the eyes of God.
The world is fast goin' to damnation because of
impudent young 'uns a-flyin' in the face of age.
They make soup out of them...
but I wouldn't know
how to go about gettin' 'em open.
We're gonna spend the night on land.
Hush, little one
Hush
Hush, my little one
Morning soon
Shall light your pillow
Birds will sing
In yonder willow
Hush, my little one
Hush
- Are we going home now, John?
- Hush, little one
Hush
Rest, dearest one
Rest
Rest here on my breast
Little child
With heart so brave
Angel hosts
Will keep you safe
Rest, my little one
Rest
Rest, little one
Leaning
Safe and secure
From all alarms
Leaning
Leaning on the everlasting arms
What a fellowship
What a peace is mine
Leaning on the everlasting arms
Don't he never sleep?
What a blessedness
What a joy divine
Pearl! Wake up!
Come on! Pearl!
...on the everlasting arms
Leaning
Safe and secure
From all alarms
You two youngsters
get up here to me this instant.
Get on up to my house.
Mind me now.
I'll get me a switch.
- Don't you hurt her!
- Hurt her, nothing.
Wash her is more like it.
Ruby! Clary! Mary!
Yes, Miz Cooper!
Bring your baskets.
Nicely picked, Clary.
Mary, put the big ones on top.
Oh, Ruby. Most of them
ain't fit to go to market.
Well, put your baskets down.
Ruby, run to the house and fetch the tub
and put it by the pump.
Clary, uh, Mary, run up
and fetch a bar of laundry soap.
- Yes, Miz Cooper.
- And a scrub brush.
Come on up to the house, children.
Gracious! If you ain't a sight to beat all.
Where you from?
Where're your folks?
Come on, speak up now.
Gracious. So I've got
two more mouths to feed.
Howdy, Miz Cooper.
What happened to my milk supply?
Price of milk what it is,
not on your life.
Do better making butter with the cream,
sell it retail.
Make smearcase for the children,
feed what's left to my hogs.
- She talks to herself.
- All the time.
- Your ma's funny.
- She ain't our ma.
We just live at her house.
- Where are your folks?
- Someplace.
My daddy's in Detroit.
Mary!
Honey. Good morning, Miz Cooper.
Guess what.
I'm saving up to buy you a charm bracelet.
Never mind the gewgaws.
Don't forget your visit this Sunday,
and come to church with us.
See ya Sunday, love.
Take your baskets in, children.
Women is fools.
All of 'em.
Look a-there.
She'll be losing her mind
to a tricky mouth and a fool moon.
And like as not,
I'll be settled with the consequences.
Here's what you owe me.
One, two, three, four, five-
Where's the other basket?
- Where's Ruby?
- She went.
John, you go find Ruby.
Big Ruby's my bothersome girl.
She can't get eggs without bustin' them.
But she's got mother hands with the young 'uns,
so what are you to say?
How about tonight, Ruby?
- What gives?
- The old lady's around.
How about Thursday?
The old gal thinks she comes in
for sewing lessons on Thursday.
Miz Cooper wants you.
And will you show me
your dolly, little lady?
I see you got two more peeps in your brood.
Yeah, and ornerier than the rest.
How's your own boy, Miz Cooper?
Haven't heard from Ralph
since last Christmas.
Don't matter though.
I've got a new crop.
I'm a strong tree
with branches for many birds.
I'm good for somethin' in this old world,
and I know it too.
Now, old pharaoh,
he was king of Egypt land...
and he had a daughter.
And once upon a time...
she was walkin' along by the riverbank...
and she seen somethin' bumpin' and scrapin'
along on a sandbar down under the willows.
- And you know what it was, children?
- No.
Now, it was a skiff,
washed up on the bar.
And who do you reckon was in it?
Pearl and John.
Not this time.
There was only one young 'un-
a little boy babe.
- And you know who he was, children?
- No.
It was Moses- a king of men.
Moses, children.
Now off to bed with you.
John, get me an apple.
And get one for yourself too.
John, where are your folks?
- Dead.
- Dead?
Where are you from?
Upriver.
Well, I didn't figure you'd rowed that skiff
all the way up from Parkersburg.
Tell me that story again.
Story? What story, honey?
About them kings...
and the queen found down on the sandbar
that time on the skiff.
Kings? Why, there was only one king, honey.
I mind you said there was two.
Well, shoot now.
Maybe there was.
Yes, come to think of it,
there was two.
Must be Thursday.
Here comes Ruby.
Here I go.
Why, you're Ruby.
Ain't you, my child?
- Can I have this?
- Surely.
I'd like to talk to you, my dear.
- Will you buy me an ice cream?
- Of course.
- Watch out, Preacher.
- Why, Preacher.
Shut your dirty mouths.
Ain't I pretty?
Why, you're the prettiest thing
I ever seen in all my wanderin'.
Ain't nobody never toId you that, Ruby?
No. No one never did.
There's, uh, two new ones
out your place, ain't there?
- What's their names?
- Pearl and John.
Ah, yeah. Is there a doll?
Only they don't never
let me play with it.
Did you ever see such pretty eyes
in all your born days?
Don't let him get away, sugar.
He ain't like you all. Next time,
I won't even ask him to buy me an ice cream.
I've been bad.
Ruby, you didn't have money
to buy this.
- You'll whip me.
- When did I ever?
- This man at the drugstore, he gave me-
- The drugstore?
Miz Cooper, I never been to sewin' lessons
all them times.
What you been up to, Ruby?
I been out with men.
Child.
Oh, my God.
You were lookin' for love, Ruby,
in the only foolish way you knew how.
We all need love, Ruby.
I lost the love of my son.
I found it with you all.
You're gonna grow up
to be a strong, fine woman...
and I'm gonna see to it that you do.
This gentleman weren't like them.
He just give me a book
and buy me an ice cream.
- Now, who was this?
- He didn't ask me for nothin'.
What'd you talk about?
Pearl and John.
John and Pearl?
- Is he their pap?
- I don't know.
Wonder why he hasn't been to the house.
Oh, Miz Cooper! Miz Cooper!
- What?
- The man! The man!
Good mornin', ladies.
How do?
Why, you're Miz Cooper, I take it.
It's about that John and that Pearl?
Oh, them poor little lambs.
To think I never hoped
to see them again in this world.
Oh, dear madam, if you was to know
what a crown of thorns I've borne...
in my search for them stray chicks.
Ruby, go fetch them kids.
Oh, madam, I see you're lookin' at my hands.
Would you like me to tell you
the little story of left hand and right hand-
the tale of good and evil?
It was with this left hand that old brother Cain
struck the blow that laid his brother low-
Them kids is yours?
My own flesh and blood.
Where's your missus?
Uh, she run off with a drummer-
during prayer meetin'.
- Where's she at?
- Down the river somewheres.
Parkersburg maybe or Cincinnati-
one of them Sodoms on the Ohio River.
She took them kids with her?
Oh, heaven only knows
what unholy sights and sounds...
them innocent little babes has heard
in the dens of perdition where she dragged 'em.
Right funny, ain't it, how they rowed
all the way upriver in a 10-foot johnboat.
Are they well, Miz Cooper?
A sight better than they was.
Gracious, gracious.
You are a good woman, Miz Cooper.
How you figurin' to raise them two
without a woman?
The Lord will provide.
The Lord is merciful.
Oh, what a day this is.
And there's little John.
- What's wrong, John?
- Come to me, boy.
- Didn't you hear me, boy?
John, when your dad says come,
you should mind him.
He ain't my dad.
No. And he ain't no preacher neither.
Just march yourself yonder
to your horse, mister.
March, mister! I'm not foolin'!
All right, but you haven't heard
the last of Harry Powell yet.
The Lord God Jehovah
will guide my hand in vengeance.
You devils!
You Whores of Babylon!
I'll be back when it's dark!
Leaning
Safe and secure
From all alarms
Leaning
Leaning on the everlasting arms
What a fellowship
What a joy divine
Leaning on the everlasting arms
What a blessedness
What a peace is mine
Leaning on the everlasting arms
- Leaning on Jesus
- Leaning
Safe and secure
From all alarms
- Leaning on Jesus
- Leaning
Leaning on
The everlasting arms
Shame on you, Ruby...
mooning around the house
after that mad dog of a man.
Merciful heavens!
Ruby, go get the children out of bed
and bring them down here.
Women are such durn fools.
It's a hard world for little things.
Now, there was this sneakin',
no-account, ornery King Herod.
And when he heard tell
of little Jesus growin' up...
he figured, "Well, shoot,
there won't be no room for the both of us.
I'll just nip this in the bud."
But he wasn't sure which of all them
babies in the land was King Jesus.
So that cruel old King Herod figured
if he was to kill all the babies in the land...
he'd be sure and get little Jesus.
And when little King Jesus' ma and pa
heard about this plan...
what do you reckon they went and done?
- They hid in a broom closet.
- They hid under the porch.
No. They went a-runnin'.
Well, now, John, you're right.
That's just what they done.
And little King Jesus' ma and pa
saddled a mule...
and they rode all the way down
into Egypt land.
Yeah. And that's where the queen
found 'im in the "billy rushes."
Oh, no. That wasn't the same story at all.
That was little King Moses.
But just the same, it did seem
like it was a plague time for little ones...
them olden days, them hard, hard times.
Figured I was gone, huh?
Run! Hide in the staircase!
Run quick!
Ruby! Git!
- What do you want?
- I want them kids.
- What do you want them for?
- That's none of your business, madam.
I'm giving you to the count of three
to get out of here.
Then I'm comin' across the kitchen shooting.
Miz Booher? Rachel Cooper.
Get your state troopers out to my place.
I got somethin' trapped in my barn.
I'll go see to Pearl.
I'll make coffee.
She's all right.
John, you know, when you're little...
you have more endurance
than God is ever to grant you again?
Children are man at his strongest.
They abide.
Why didn't you call us before now?
Didn't want your dirty shoes
trackin' up my clean floors.
- Is that him, ma'am?
- Yes.
Mind where you shoot, boys.
There are children here.
Harry Powell, you're under arrest
for the murder of Willa Harper.
Drop that knife, Powell.
Don't.
Don't!
- Here! Here!
- John! John!
Take it back, Dad! Take it back!
I don't want it, Dad!
It's too much! Here!
Here!
Lynch him! Lynch him!
Bluebeard!
- Twenty-five wives!
- And he killed every last one of 'em!
- The people of Marshall County-
- Bluebeard!
Lynch him! Lynch him!
Will you identify the prisoner?
Please, little lad.
Won't you look yonder
and tell the court...
if that is the man
that killed your mother?
It's all right, Mrs. Cooper.
You can take the little fellow away.
Merry Christmas to you and yours, Mrs. Cooper.
And what's Santa Claus going
to bring you for Christmas, little man?
Bluebeard! Bluebeard! Bluebeard!
Bring out that bluebeard!
There's Pearl!
Get your coats.
Them's her orphans!
- Where's Ruby?
- She went.
Them poor little lambs!
Them is the ones he sinned against,
my friends!
Go out the back door.
Don't just stand around. Come on.
They're bringing him out.
Ain't we goin' to the bus depot?
Draggin' the name of the Lord
through the evil mud of his soul!
String that bluebeard up to a pole!
He's Satan hidin' behind the cross!
Come on!
I love him.
You think he's like them others.
You were so mad, you shot him.
- Hey, Bart.
- Yeah?
We're savin' this bird up for you.
This time, it'll be a privilege.
I'm glad they didn't send me nothin'.
Whenever they do, it's nothin' I want...
but just something to show me
how fancy and smart they come up in the world.
Can we give you your Christmas presents now?
Shoot. You don't mean to say
you got me a present?
Shoot now.
Ruby.
A potholder.
And it's much neater
than last year, Ruby.
Clary.
Another potholder.
Now, ain't that thoughtful?
I'm always burnin' my hands.
Oh, this doesn't look basted.
This looks made.
Oh, and you finished the edge
with a chain stitch.
Oh, that's just dandy, Clary.
Another potholder?
Oh, now, did you two make this together?
You helped us some.
That's the richest gift
a body could have.
And your presents are in the cupboard
under the china closet.
Ruby.
This is yours.
Oh, look what you've got!
Lord save little children.
You'd think the world would be ashamed
to name such a day as Christmas for one of them...
and then go on in the same old way.
My soul is humble when I see the way
little ones accept their lot.
Lord save little children.
The wind blows, and the rains are cold.
Yet they abide.
That watch sure is a fine loud ticker.
Be nice to have someone around the house
who can give me the right time of day.
This watch is the nicest watch I ever had.
Well, a fella just can't go round
with rundown, busted watches.
They abide, and they endure.