[door opens, shuts]
[shivers]
[jazz music]
[door opens, shuts]
- lt's getting cold.
- Thanks.
That is one fine frame.
One fine frame, that is.
[shivers]
How much...
...does a fine frame
like that cost, do you think?
l never told you,
but you sound a little like
Dr. Seuss when you're drunk.
Anna, l'm serious.
Serious, l am, Anna.
l'd say it cost
at least a couple hundred.
l'm gonna read it for you.
Do l really sound like Dr. Seuss?
"ln recognition of his
outstanding achievement
in the field of child psychology,
his dedication to his work
and his continuing efforts
to improve the quality of life..."
Will you concentrate?
"...his continuing efforts
to improve the quality of life
for countless children
and their families,
the city of Philadelphia
proudly bestows upon its son,
Dr. Malcolm Crowe..." That's you.
"...the Mayor's Citation
for Professional Excellence."
They called you their son.
Wow.
We should hang it in the bathroom.
This is an important night for us.
Finally, someone is recognizing
the sacrifices you've made.
That you have put everything
second, including me...
...for those families
that they're talking about.
They're also saying
that my husband has a gift.
You have a gift that teaches
children how to be strong
in situations where most adults
would piss on themselves.
l believe what they wrote is real.
Thank you.
[Malcolm] l would like
some wine in a glass.
l would not like it in a mug.
l would not like it in a jug.
[giggling]
[grunting]
Look.
[phone beeping]
[screams]
Anna, don't move.
Don't make a sound.
This is 47 Locust Street.
You've broken a window
and entered a private residence.
You don't know so many things.
There are no needles
or prescription drugs
of any kind in this house.
[gasps]
[sobbing]
Do you know why you're
afraid when you're alone?
l do. l do.
What do you want?
What he promised me!
- l want what he promised me.
- Oh, my God.
Do l know you?
Don't you know me, hero?
Don't you even remember
your own patients?
[sobbing continues]
D... downtown clinic.
S... single-parent family.
Possible mood disorder.
l was afraid!
You told me l was having trouble
coping with my parents' divorce.
You... you were wrong.
You were wrong.
[sobbing]
Now look at me!
l don't want to be afraid no more.
Please, just give me a minute to think.
l waited ten years for you!
l'm not giving you nothing!
Ben Friedkin?
Some people, they call me "freak."
Ronald Sumner?
l am. l am a freak. Look at...
Vincent.
Vincent Grey.
Don't. Don't.
l do remember you.
- No.
- Quiet, very smart.
Compassionate.
Unusually compassionate.
You forgot "cursed."
You failed me.
You failed me!
Vincent, l'm sorry if l
wasn't... if l didn't help you.
But if you just... let me try.
You just give me a chance...
- [groaning]
- [Anna screams]
[gunshot]
- Oh, God. Oh, God, honey.
- [groaning]
- Did Vincent...
- Now, don't talk. Shh.
[groaning]
[boy] De profundis clamo ad te, Domine.
De profundis clamo ad te, Domine.
lt's OK, Cole.
My name is Dr. Malcolm Crowe.
We were supposed to meet today,
but l missed our appointment.
l'm sorry.
You know,
in the olden days in Europe,
people used to hide out in churches.
They would claim sanctuary.
What were they hiding from?
Bad people, mostly.
People that wanted to put
them in jail... hurt them.
Noticed your eyeglasses. They
don't have any lenses in them.
They're my dad's.
The lenses hurt my eyes.
What were you talking
about with your soldiers
when l came in?
- De...
- De profundis clamo ad te, Domine.
lt's called "Latin."
All your soldiers speak Latin?
No.
Just one.
Are you a good doctor?
Well...
l used to be.
l won an award once
from the mayor.
Had an expensive frame.
l'm gonna see you again, right?
lf that's OK with you.
[door opens, shuts]
lt's me.
[bell tolling]
[helicopter blades whirring]
[radio] Pennsylvania Turnpike
westbound slow to Valley Forge 24.
On the Blue Ridge both directions,
generally slow between number three...
- [dog barks]
- Hey, good morning.
Cole?
Hey, your Cocoa Puffs
are getting soggy.
Let me see you.
Aw, honey, you got a spot.
OK, here it comes.
[screams]
Something you were looking for, baby?
Pop-Tarts?
They're right here.
Oh.
What are you thinking, Mama?
Lots of things.
Anything bad about me?
Hey, look at my face.
l was not thinking
something bad about you.
Got it?
Got it.
- Get up.
- [bell rings]
- Th... that's Tommy, Mom.
- OK, you tuck it in.
Hey, Cole? You want this?
Hey, freak, how'd you like that
arm-around-the-shoulder bit?
l just made that up. l went
with it as great actors do.
lt's called "improv."
[bell ringing]
Hey, baby.
How was your day?
Hmm?
You know, you can
tell me things if you need to.
Oh, you know what l did today?
l, uh... l won the Pennsylvania
Lottery in the morning.
l quit my jobs.
And l ate a big picnic in the park
with lots of chocolate mousse pie.
And then l swam
in the fountain all afternoon.
What'd you do?
l was picked first for
kickball teams at recess.
l hit a grand slam to win the game.
Everybody lifted me up
and carried me around, cheering.
ln that case, l am gonna
make you some triangle pancakes.
You got an hour.
Hi.
Want to sit?
Don't feel like talking today?
Wanna play a game?
lt's a mind-reading game.
Here's how it works:
l read your mind.
lf what l say is right, you
take one step towards the chair.
lf what l say is wrong,
you take one step back
towards the doorway.
lf you reach the chair,
you sit down.
lf you reach the door, you can go.
Wanna play?
OK.
[humming]
When your mother and father
were first divorced,
your mom went to see a doctor
like me, and he didn't help her,
so you think l'm not
going to be able to help you.
You're worried that
she said she told him things,
things she couldn't tell anyone else.
Secrets.
You have a secret,
but you don't want to tell me.
Your dad gave you
that watch as a present
just before he went away.
He forgot it in a drawer.
Doesn't work.
You keep pretty quiet
in school, but...
...you're a good student.
You've never really been
in any serious trouble.
We were supposed
to draw a picture.
Anything we wanted.
l drew a man...
...got hurt in the neck by
another man with a screwdriver.
You saw that on TV, Cole?
Everyone got upset.
They had a meeting.
Mom started crying.
l don't draw like that anymore.
How do you draw now?
Draw... people smiling...
...dogs running...
...rainbows.
They don't have
meetings about rainbows.
No.
l guess they don't.
What am l thinking now?
l don't know what you're thinking now.
l was thinking,
you're nice...
...but you can't help me.
[sighs]
l thought you meant
the other ltalian restaurant
l asked you to marry me in.
[sighs]
l'm so sorry, Anna.
l just can't seem to keep track of time.
And l didn't have
a very good session today. l...
[sighs]
They're both so similar.
Same mannerisms,
same expressions, same...
...things hanging over their head.
l think it might be some kind of abuse.
Cole has... scratches on his arm.
l think they might be fingernail cuts.
Defensive cuts, maybe.
l don't know, Anna.
[sighs]
Maybe a teacher or a neighbor.
l don't think it's the mother.
l've seen her with him, and...
...doesn't seem to fit.
Or l could just be wrong.
Maybe he's just a kid who
likes to climb trees a lot.
[sighs] Anna...
l know that l've been
a little distant. l...
l know that it makes
you mad. l just...
...feel like l'm being
given a second chance
and l don't want it to slip away.
Anna.
Happy anniversary.
[sighs]
[Cole] Stop looking at me.
l don't like when people
look at me like that.
OK.
l walk this way to school
with Tommy Tammisimo.
He your best buddy?
He hates me.
Do you hate him?
No.
Did your mom set that up?
Yes.
Did you ever talk to your mom
about how things are with Tommy?
- l don't tell her things.
- Why not?
She doesn't look at me like
everybody else. l don't want her to.
- l don't want her to know.
- Know what?
That l'm a freak.
Hey.
You are not a freak. OK?
Don't you believe anybody that
tries to convince you of that.
That's bullshit!
You don't have to go through
your life believing that.
OK?
Come on.
You said the "S" word.
Yeah, l know.
Sorry.
[music plays over headphones]
[Malcolm] Your Dad lives in Pittsburg
with a lady that works in a tollbooth?
[Cole] What if she has
to pee when she's working?
Think she just holds it?
l don't know. l was just
thinking about that myself.
You asked a lot of questions
about Dad today. How come?
Well... sometimes we do
things to draw attention,
to express our feelings
about certain issues, uh,
divorce, whatever.
For example, a person might
leave something on a desk
for someone else to find.
Do you know what
free-association writing is, Cole?
[Cole] No.
[Malcolm] Free-association writing is
when you take a pencil in your hand
and you put the pencil to a piece
of paper and you start writing.
You don't look at what you're writing
or think about what you're writing.
You just... keep your hand moving.
And after a while,
if you keep your hand moving
long enough, words and thoughts
start coming out that you
didn't even know you had in you.
Could be... something
you heard somewhere else, or...
...feelings you had
deep inside of you.
Have you ever done any
free-association writing, Cole?
Yes.
What did you write?
Upset words.
Did you ever write any upset
words before your father left?
l don't remember.
Can you do something for me?
l want you to
think about what you want
to get out of our time together,
what our goals should be.
Something l want?
lf you could change something
in your life, anything,
what would it be?
lnstead of something l want,
can it be something l don't want?
OK.
l don't want to be scared anymore.
[knocking]
[Malcolm] You gonna get that?
Are you gonna get that?
- [footsteps]
- [door opens]
- [Anna] Hey.
- [man] Hi.
[Anna] Don't you see
enough of me at the store?
[man] l'm on my way out to the flea
market in the Amish country. l thought
you'd wanna come along and show me
how to buy at one of these things.
[Anna] l don't know if l can
deal with the Amish today.
You can't curse or spit
or anything around them.
[man] l just figured maybe
you just wanted to get some air
because you'd seemed
kind of down lately.
[Anna] Um... l'm OK.
[man] All right. Do you think that
l should stop by on my way back
and show you what l got?
'Cause that wouldn't be a problem.
[Anna] No. l... You know,
l can see 'em on Monday.
[man] Sure. Yeah,
that's fine. Understood.
OK, so l guess
l'm gonna get going then,
- and l'll speak to you later.
- [Anna] OK.
- Don't step in horse manure.
- [man] Thank you very much.
[both chuckle]
[door shuts]
Keep moving, cheese-dick.
Can anybody guess what city
was capital
of the United States ofAmerica
from 1790 to 1800?
l'll give you a hint:
lt's the city you live in.
- [kids] Philadelphia.
- Right, right.
Philadelphia's one of the
oldest cities in this country.
A lot of generations have
lived here and died here.
Almost any place you go in this city
has a history and a story behind it.
Even this school
and the grounds it sits on.
Can anyone guess what
this building was used for
a hundred years ago,
before you went to school here,
before l went to this school, even?
[kids whispering]
Yes. Cole.
They used to hang people here.
[chalk screeches]
No. Uh, that...
Mm-mmm. That's not correct.
Uh, where'd you hear that?
They'd pull the people in,
crying and kissing their families bye.
People watching... spit at them.
U-Uh, Cole, this-this building
was a legal courthouse.
Laws were passed here,
some of the very first laws
of this country.
This whole building was
full of lawyers, lawmakers.
They were the ones
that hanged everybody.
[kids giggling]
Um...
l don't... l don't know which
one of these guys told you that,
but, um... they were
just trying to scare you.
l don't like people
looking at me like that.
Like what?
Stop it!
l, uh... l-l-l don't
know how else to look.
You're Stuttering Stanley!
Excuse me?
You talked funny when you went to school
here. You talked funny into high school.
- What?
- You shouldn't look at people.
lt makes them feel bad.
- How did you...
- Stop looking at me!
Who have you...
b-b-been speaking-ing to?
Stuttering Stanley!
- Stop it.
- Stuttering Stanley!
- S-S-Stop... Stop that!
- S-S-Stop it.
Stuttering Stanley!
Shut up, you f-f-f-freak!
Hey, big guy.
How's it going?
l don't wanna talk
about anything right now.
OK.
[children playing outside]
You like magic?
Hmm?
Observe: the magic penny.
Looks like an ordinary penny.
But l do my little magic shake, and...
...now it's in my right hand.
But that's not the end
of the magic trick.
l do another little shake, and...
...right there in the vest pocket.
But that's not the end
of the magic trick.
l do another little shake...
...and...
...right back in
the left hand where it started.
That isn't magic.
What are you talking about?
Of course it's magic.
You just kept the penny
in that hand the whole time.
Think so?
l didn't know you were funny.
[woman] Malcolm, sit your
cute butt down and listen up.
No doubt about it.
Anna is like my sister.
And you better make her happy.
And l'm not talking about no...
..."Mmm! This taste like
real butter" kind of happy.
l'm talking about...
What's up, girl?
"Julie Andrews,
mm-hmm, twirling around
like a mental patient on
a mountaintop" kind of happy.
Now, that's the kind
of happy l'm talking about.
Shh. Come here.
Shh. Don't tell her l told you,
but she said she knew she love you
from the first time
she met you on the street.
She'd do anything for you.
[sobbing] l love you guys.
[sniffling]
My nose is running. Turn it...
[water running]
[exhales]
[rock music]
And then you do the magic shake.
The penny has moved
from my pocket...
...all the way back
to the hand it started in.
That's stupid.
lt's supposed to be funny.
lt's stupid.
l want my penny back.
[Mrs. Sear] He doesn't
get invited places, so...
[woman] lt's our pleasure.
Last time was a Chuck E. Cheese
party a year ago.
He hid in one of those purple,
plastic tunnels and didn't come out.
- Chucky who?
- Cheese. lt's a kids place.
- [woman] Excuse me.
- [Mrs. Sear] Sorry.
[man] Sir.
Madam?
ls someone out there?
Open this door, please. Come on.
l can't breathe.
lf you can hear me, open this door.
l swear on my life l didn't
take the master's horse.
Open this door, or l'll break
through it and grab you!
The star of the commercial
always gets his own trailer.
For what?
He needs a place to think
about his character, alone.
You only had one line.
[Tommy] Darren, check it out.
Oh, yeah.
My dad made me invite him.
Happy birthday, Darren.
ls there something
you wanna see in there?
No.
We're gonna put on a pretend play.
Wanna be in it?
OK.
lt's called Locked in the Dungeon.
Yeah, Cole, and... you get to be
the one locked in the dungeon.
Don't! Don't! Don't! Don't!
No! Don't!
- [pounding]
- Let me out! No! No! No! No! No! No!
- [pounding stops]
- [shuffling]
[screams]
[hard rock music]
[distant screaming]
[pounding, screaming]
[Cole] Help! Help! Help!
- Cole?
- Oh, no!
- Help! Help!
- [pounding continues]
- [screaming continues]
- Cole!
- Oh, God. ls there a key for this door?
- Help me!
Cole? Honey, honey, can you hear me?
- Open the door!
- God!
- No!
- [Mrs. Sear screams]
- Oh, my God, Cole!
- Oh, my God! Help me!
- [pounding]
- Help! Help!
[latches clicking]
[silence]
[heavy breathing]
[man] The tests would indicate
he did not have a seizure.
He's doing fine.
After some rest,
he can go home tonight.
[chuckles]
There's some cuts
and bruises on your son
- that are concerning me.
- Oh, man.
Yeah, those are from sports.
You think l hurt my child?
You think l'm a bad mother?
Mrs. Sloan over there,
she's a social worker with the hospital,
and she's gonna ask you
a couple procedural questions.
What happened to my child today?
Something was happening to him,
physically happening.
Something was very wrong!
Hey.
Did your father used to
tell you bedtime stories?
Once upon a time,
there was this young prince,
and he decided that
he wanted to go for a drive.
And he got his driver,
and they started driving.
Driving, driving.
Driving a lot, and, uh... um...
...they drove so much
that he fell asleep.
And...
Then he woke up, and he realized
they were still driving.
- This was a very long trip.
- Dr. Crowe?
You haven't told
bedtime stories before.
Uh, not too many, no.
Well, you have to add
some twists and stuff.
OK. Some twists.
Like what kind of twists?
Give me an example.
Maybe they run out of gas.
They run out of gas?
That's good
'cause they're driving, right? OK...
Tell me the story
about why you're sad.
You think l'm sad?
What makes you think that?
Your eyes told me.
l'm not supposed to talk
about stuff like that.
[exhales]
Once upon a time, there was
this person named Malcolm.
He worked with children.
He loved it.
He loved it more than anything else.
And then one night,
he found out that he made a...
...mistake with one of them.
He couldn't help that one.
And he can't stop thinking
about it. He... can't forget.
Ever since then,
things have been different.
He's not the same person
that he used to be.
And his wife... doesn't like
the person that he's become.
They barely speak anymore.
They're like strangers.
And then one day, Malcolm
meets this wonderful little boy.
A really cool little boy.
Reminds him a lot of the other one.
And Malcolm decides
to try and help this new boy...
...'cause he feels that
if he can help this new boy,
be like... helping that other one too.
How does the story end?
l don't know.
l want to tell you my secret now.
OK.
l see dead people.
ln your dreams?
While you're awake?
Dead people, like,
in graves and coffins?
Walking around like regular people.
They don't see each other.
They only see what they want to see.
They don't know they're dead.
How often do you see them?
All the time.
They're everywhere.
You won't tell anyone my secret, right?
No. l promise.
Will you stay here until l fall asleep?
Of course.
[click]
[Malcolm] Cole... has pathologies
more severe than initially assessed.
He's suffering
from visual hallucinations,
- paranoia...
- [tires screeching]
...some kind of...
school-age schizophrenia.
Medication, hospitalization
may be required.
[sighs] And l'm not helping him.
[sighs]
[clears throat]
Hi. This is Lynn Sear, Cole's mom.
Yeah. Uh, yeah, l-l'd like
to talk to you about your boy
and his friends keeping
their goddamn hands off my son.
[shuffling]
Mama?
No.
Dinner is not ready!
What are you gonna do?
Y-You can't hurt me anymore!
Lenny, you're
a terrible husband, Lenny!
Look what you made me do! Lenny!
[Cole sobbing]
[panting] l'm OK. OK. OK.
[Tommy] Once there was a boy,
very different from all the other boys.
He lived in the jungle...
...and he could speak
to the animals.
- [piano music]
- [camcorders whirring]
[kids making animal noises]
[applause]
[Cole] Did you think
the play sucked big time?
Heh. What?
Tommy Tammisimo acted
in a cough syrup commercial.
He said everyone was
self-conscious and unrealistic.
He said the play sucked big time.
This Tommy kid sounds like a real punk.
l thought the play was
excellent. Better than Cats.
- Cats?
- Never mind.
Cole, l was really interested
in what you told me at the hospital.
l'd like to hear more about it.
Cole?
What?
Something up there?
Cole?
l don't see anything.
Be real still.
Sometimes you feel it inside,
like you're falling down real fast,
but you're really just standing still.
Do you ever feel the prickly
things on the back of your neck?
Yes.
And the tiny hairs on your arm,
you know, when they stand up?
Yes.
That's them.
When they get mad...
...it gets cold.
l don't see anything.
Are you sure they're there?
Cole?
Please make them leave.
l'm workin' on it.
Come on.
Aah! [laughing]
Mommy, Daddy?
[coughing]
My throat hurts.
Run! Run!
[announcer]
Pedia Ease cough suppressant.
Gentle, fast, eff...
Cole.
Oh, l don't care what they say.
This thing is broken.
Take 'em off.
l don't want them on my table.
l saw what was in your bureau
drawer when l was cleaning.
Got something you want to confess?
Hmm?
The bumblebee pendant?
Why do you keep taking it?
lt was Grandma's.
You know, what if it broke?
You know how sad l'd be.
You'd cry 'cause you
miss Grandma so much.
That's right.
Sometimes people think
they lose things...
...and they really didn't
lose them, it just gets moved.
So did you move
the bumblebee pendant?
Don't get mad.
So who moved it this time?
Maybe someone came in our house,
took the bumblebee pendant
out of my closet and placed
it nicely in your drawer.
- Maybe.
- God, l am so tired, Cole.
l'm tired in my body,
l'm tired in my mind,
l'm... tired in my heart.
l need some help. You know,
l don't know if you noticed,
but our little family
isn't doing so good.
l mean, l've been praying,
but l must not be praying right.
Looks like we're just gonna have
to answer each other's prayers.
lf we can't talk to each other,
we're not gonna make it.
Now, tell me, baby.
l-l... l won't get mad, honey.
Did you take the bumblebee pendant?
- No.
- [silverware clatters]
You've had enough roast beef.
You need to leave the table.
Go!
[barking, whimpering]
[gasps]
Hey, come on.
l'll show you where
my dad keeps his gun. Come on.
[dog whimpering]
[sobbing] Sebastian, come on.
Mama?
lf you're not very mad,
can l sleep in your bed tonight?
Look at my face.
l'm not very mad.
Baby, why are you shaking?
Cole, what's wrong?
Oh, God, please tell me!
Oh, please.
Oh.
[Anna] lt's Edwardian,
beautifully worked
with mine-cut diamonds
and an actual color Burmese sapphire.
lt's timeless.
Oh.
You, uh... [clears throat]
...got anything a little plainer?
Plainer?
You want a plain ring to go with
your plain fianc‚? ls that how it is?
No! Baby, don't... don't get in a tizzy.
Uh...
You're so beautiful.
Y-You're like a Burmese
sapphire all by yourself.
- You don't need all that.
- Uh-huh.
Why don't you try it on and see
how you both feel about it?
There. How does that feel?
l think this piece, um,
communicates a longing.
l imagine that the woman who owned it
loved a man that she couldn't be with.
Did he have wavy hair and chestnut eyes?
- What?
- Um, l-l don't know, but...
...a lot of the pieces
in this store communicate,
and l think you should choose
a piece that speaks to you.
l think maybe when people own
things and then they pass away,
a part of themselves gets
printed on those things,
like... like fingerprints.
l'll just wrap it up.
You don't need a guy with a master's.
You need a wrestler with
a neck larger than his head.
[chuckles] No, l need
a wrestler with a master's.
- What's this?
- Happy birthday.
- From you?
- Mm-hmm.
lt's a...
...first edition.
- Wow.
- [giggles]
Oh, this is too much.
No. Took it out
of your Christmas bonus.
lt's perfect, Anna.
Thanks.
[chuckles]
[Cole] What do you want
more than anything?
[Malcolm] l don't know.
[Cole] l told you what l want.
- [bang, glass breaking]
- [gasps]
[Malcolm] l know what l want.
l want to be able
to talk to my wife again...
...the way we used
to talk to each other...
...like there was no one
else in the world except us.
[Cole] How are you gonna do that?
[sighs]
l can't be
your doctor anymore.
l haven't paid enough
attention to my family.
Bad things happen
when you do that.
Do you understand?
l'm going to transfer you.
l know two psychol...
Don't fail me.
Don't give up. You're the only
one who can help me. l know it.
l can't help you.
You...
Someone else can help you.
You believe me, right?
Dr. Crowe, you believe my secret, right?
l don't know how
to answer that, Cole.
How can you help me...
...if you don't believe me?
Some magic's real.
[Vincent] Do you know why
you're afraid when you're alone?
l do. l do.
[click, tape hissing]
[Malcolm] l'm sorry about that, Vincent.
l hope l didn't leave
you alone too long.
- Whew. lt's cold in here.
- [Vincent sobbing]
Vincent, why are you crying?
[Vincent sniffles]
You won't believe.
- [click]
- l'm sorry about that, Vincent.
l hope l didn't leave
you alone too long.
- Whew. lt's cold in here.
- [sobbing]
- Vincent...
- [click, whirring]
- [click]
- Whew. lt's cold in here.
[sobbing]
- [click]
- [Malcolm] No, you know what?
l never liked 'em either.
When l was a kid,
l had this blood test done,
and l threw up chili cheese
fries all over this male nurse.
- [Vincent giggles]
- [knocking, door opens]
[woman] Excuse me.
Dr. Reed is on line two.
Vincent, will you excuse me?
l have to take this.
- Just give me a minute, OK?
- OK.
[door shuts]
[soft whine]
[Vincent panting]
[faint voice, indistinct]
[tape hissing loudly]
[Vincent breathing heavily]
[faint voice continues]
[man speaking Spanish]
No entiendes.
Yo no quiero morir.
Yo no quiero morir...
[continues in Spanish]
Yo no quiero morir.
- Oh, my God.
- Yo no quiero morir!
You been running around?
Make you feel better?
l like to run around.
lt's good exercise.
Do you wanna ask me questions now?
Wanna be a lance corporal in Company M,
Third Battalion, Seventh Marines?
We're being dispatched
into the Quang Nam province.
Maybe later.
Something happened, didn't it?
You wiggin' out?
Yes.
l think l am.
[Malcolm] Do you know what
"yo no quiero morir" means?
lt's Spanish. lt means
"l don't want to die."
What do you think these ghosts
want when they talk to you?
l want you to think about it, Cole.
l want you to think
about it really carefully.
What do you think they want?
Just help.
That's right. That's what l think too.
They just want help,
even the scary ones.
And l think l might know
a way to make them go away.
How?
Listen to them.
What if they don't want help?
What if they're just angry and
they just want to hurt somebody?
l don't think that's the way it works.
How do you know for sure?
l don't.
Hey.
Hey! Hey!
[Lynn sobbing]
What's happening?
What's... what's happening?
Cole!
What's...
[panting]
What's happening to you?
ls someone hurting you?
l'll... l will kick their ass.
Cole, if they're hurting you...
[groaning]
[sighs]
Mama, you sleep now.
[panting]
[snapping]
Aah!
[sobbing, panting]
[retching]
[spits]
[sobbing]
l'm feeling much better now.
D-Do you want to tell me something?
[engine running]
[brakes squeaking]
[gasps]
She came a long way
to visit me, didn't she?
l guess she did.
[woman sobbing]
Can you get some water?
That's her sister.
[sobbing]
[woman 1] ...you know, and l went
through this with my father's cancer...
l just can't imagine a child
being in bed for two years.
[woman 2] How many...
how many doctors?
- l think it was six.
- Six different doctors?
- l think so, yes.
- Oh.
l just heard the, uh...
the little one is falling ill now.
God help them.
Don't go home, OK?
l definitely won't.
Aah!
[panting]
Mister?
Excuse me, mister.
Are you Kyra's daddy?
lt's for you.
Sh-She wanted to tell you something.
[Kyra] Oh, no! Here he comes!
Look, he's coming my way. Psst.
Would you like to dance?
Um, well, actually,
l just came with my friends.
Oh. Well, how about this?
We can dance for a little bit,
and if you don't like the way l dance,
y-you can kick me.
Oh. OK then.
[splash]
lt's time for lunch, Kyra.
- l'm feeling much better now.
- That's so great, honey.
lt's time for your food.
Can l go outside if l eat this?
l don't know. You know how
you get sick in the afternoons.
We'llsee.
Don't say that it tastes funny.
You know l don't like to hear that.
Sammie's mom called.
You were keeping her sick.
You liked it, she said.
She looked out for you.
ls Kyra coming back?
Not anymore.
- [Cole] All right.
- [woman] l think that's enough.
- That's enough makeup.
- OK.
They're calling for the stable boy.
Oh, we have to hurry!
Who, uh... who were you talking to?
Just practicing my lines.
[Cole] Thanks for giving me
this part, Mr. Cunningham.
When l went to school here, there
was a terrible fire in the theater.
They rebuilt the whole thing.
Yeah, l know.
[audience] Aw.
Only he who is pure of heart
can take the sword from the stone.
Let the boy try.
[scattered applause]
But he is a stable boy.
He cleans up after the horses.
Silence, village idiot.
Let the boy step forward.
[all gasp]
[all] Hail King Arthur!
[applause]
[kids] Yea!
- Hoorah!
- [applause]
[kids shouting]
[audience laughing]
[applause resumes]
[kids chattering]
l thought you were really
great in the play, Cole.
- Really?
- Yeah.
- You know what else?
- What?
l thought Tommy Tammisimo
sucked big-time.
Ha-ha-ha.
[chuckles]
l got an idea how you
can talk to your wife.
Wait till she's asleep.
Then she'll listen to you
and she won't even know it.
l'm not gonna see you anymore, am l?
l think we said
everything we needed to say.
Maybe it's time to say things
to someone closer to you.
Maybe we can pretend like we're
gonna see each other tomorrow.
Just for pretend.
OK.
l'm gonna go now.
l'll see you tomorrow, Cole.
[siren wailing]
[chatter on police radio]
l-l'm OK, officer. l-l'm OK.
l don't know what happened.
[Lynn] Hmm.
Jeez, l hope nobody got hurt.
You're very quiet.
You're mad l missed
the play, aren't you?
l have two jobs, baby.
You know how important
they are for us.
[sighs]
l'd give anything to have been there.
l'm ready to communicate with you now.
Communicate?
Tell you my secrets.
What is it?
You know the accident up there?
Yeah?
Someone got hurt.
They did?
A lady.
She died.
Oh, my God. What, you can see her?
Yes.
Where is she?
Standing next to my window.
Cole, you're scaring me.
They scare me too sometimes.
They?
Ghosts.
You see ghosts, Cole?
They want me to do things for them.
They... they talk to you?
They tell you to do things?
They're the ones that used to hurt me.
What are you thinking, Mama?
You think l'm a freak?
Look at my face.
l would never think
that about you. Ever.
- Got it?
- Got it.
Just let me think for a minute.
Grandma says hi.
She says she's sorry for
taking the bumblebee pendant.
She just likes it a lot.
What?
Grandma comes to visit me sometimes.
Cole, that's very wrong.
- Grandma's gone, you know that.
- l know.
- She wanted me to tell you...
- Cole, please stop.
She wanted me to tell you
she saw you dance.
She said... when you were little,
you and her had a fight
right before your dance recital.
You thought she didn't
come to see you dance.
She did.
She hid in the back
so you wouldn't see.
She said you were like an angel.
She said...
...you came to the place
where they buried her...
...asked her a question.
She said the answer is...
..."Every day."
What did you ask?
Do...
Do l make her proud?
Mama.
[people laughing on TV]
[man] Hi, everybody.
As most of you know,
l'm not used to doing this,
and, uh, l promised Anna that
l'd try not to embarrass her.
l'll leave that to her mother.
[chuckling]
But we do want to thank
all of you for coming
and for sharing this
wonderful day with us.
lt's, uh... bittersweet,
almost, for me,
because l hate giving her up...
Anna?
l miss you.
l miss you too.
Why, Malcolm?
What?
- What is it? What?
- Why did you leave me?
l didn't leave you.
[clattering]
[Cole] lsee people.
They don't know they're dead.
[Malcolm] How often do you see them?
All the time.
They're everywhere.
They only see what they want to see.
[Malcolm] OK, Mikey.
Come on. Give me a minute.
- [gunshot]
- [groaning]
[Anna screams]
[sobbing]
- Oh, God. Oh, God, honey.
- [groaning]
- Did Vincent...
- Let me see.
lt doesn't even hurt.
- Let me see. Take your hand...
- [groaning]
Oh, God.
OK. OK.
[Anna sobbing]
- [gasps]
- [groaning]
Anna, l think l'm OK.
Really, l think it just went...
...went in and out. l...
lt doesn't even hurt anymore.
[long exhale]
l think l can go now.
Just needed to do a couple things.
l needed to help someone.
l think l did.
And l needed to tell you something.
You were never second.
Ever.
l love you.
You sleep now.
Everything will be
different in the morning.
Good night, Malcolm.
Good night, sweetheart.
Yo no quiero morir.