Tokyo Story
Screenplay by
Kogo Noda and Yasujiro Ozu
Produced by Takeshi Yamamoto
Cinematography by Yushun Atsuta
Production design
by Tatsuo Hamada
Music by Kojun Saito
Cast:
Chishu Ryu
as Shukichi Hirayama
Chieko Higashiyama
as Tomi
Setsuko Hara
as Noriko
Haruko Sugimura as Shige Kaneko,
So Yamamura as Koichi Hirayama
Kuniko Miyake as Fumiko,
Kyoko Kagawa as Kyoko
Eijiro Tono as Sanpei Numata,
Nobuo Nakamura as Kurazo Kaneko
Shiro Osaka as Keizo Hirayama,
Hisao Toake as Osamu Hattori
Directed by Yasujiro Ozu
The train gets in to Osaka at 6:00
Is that right? Keizo should have
finished work by then
If he got our telegram,
he should be at the station
- Here's your lunchbox, Mother
- Thank you
l’m leaving now
You don't need to see us off
if you're busy at school
It’s fine, I have plenty of time
- Are you sure?
- l’ll see you at the station
- l’ve put tea in your thermos, Mother
- Thank you
- Right, l’ll see you later
- See you
See you later
Bye!
Have you got the air cushion?
Didn't I give it to you?
It’s not here
- l’m sure I gave it to you
- Did you?
Good morning!
Morning
- Off to Tokyo today?
- Yes, the train's this afternoon
- I see...
- We're going to see all our children
They must be looking forward
to your visit
You'll keep an eye on the house
for us, won't you?
Of course. You enjoy yourselves
You're lucky you've got such
fine sons and daughters
Well, we'll see how we fare
- And it's a lovely day, too
- We're very lucky
- Well, I wish you both a safe trip
- Thank you
- I still can't find that air cushion
- It must be there. Have another look
- Oh, here it is
- Found it?
Got it
Doctor Hirayama
Paediatrician
Don't make the place untidy, Isamu
l’m back!
Welcome home!
Hi. Have grandpa and grandma
arrived?
They'll be here very soon
Mum!
- What is it?
- Why have you moved my desk?
To make room
for grandpa and grandma
You don't have to move my desk,
do you?
They need the space to sleep in
Where am I supposed to study
for my exams?
You can study wherever you like
But Mum... where do I do my homework?
- Where, Mum?
- Just pipe down
- You never usually want to study
- Yes, I do!
You do not!
So I don't have to do
any homework, then?
- Well, that suits me just fine!
- Quiet, Minoru!
They're here
Welcome home, dear
Come on in
- Welcome
- Come in
Come in
There you go
You must be tired, Mother.
Did you sleep on the train?
Yes, very well
Come and sit here
Welcome to you both
It’s been a while
since we last saw you
Many thanks for having us to stay
- It’s been ages, Mother
- It has indeed
It’s lovely to see you
- Is our sister Kyoko well?
- Very well, thank you
- She's looking after the house?
- Yes
Oh, wait, Fumiko
I brought you a little something
Just some rice crackers.
They're quite tasty
- Thank you so much
- Mother's fond of them
Shall I serve them?
Any bowl will do
- How about this?
- Perfect, perfect
Did Noriko go to the station?
No, she didn't.
I told her when they were arriving
- I wonder what happened?
- Serve these, will you?
Minoru? Isamu?
What are you up to?
Come with me
Grandpa, grandma...
You've both grown
- Minoru's at primary school now
- I see
- And how old are you, Isamu?
- How old are you?
How old?
The bath's ready for you
whenever you like
- Would you like a bath, Father?
- All right...
- Would you like to change, Mother?
- l’ll get you a light kimono...
l’m fine, Fumiko
l’ll get in the bath
l’ll take that
This way
Did Keizo meet you at Osaka?
Yes, I sent him a telegram
and he met us
- Is he well?
- Yes
He sent a present for you
It’s all right, Mother, give it to me later
- Have you got a towel, Father?
- Yes, yes
Take your time
- What shall we feed them?
- I don't know...
- Hey, brother?
- What?
Meat's all right for supper, isn't it?
Sukiyaki?
Yeah, fine
And maybe some sashimi?
The meat'll be enough
There's plenty to go round
- Hello?
- Here's Noriko. Come in!
- Welcome
- I was too late!
- Did you go to Tokyo Station?
- By the time I got there, they'd gone
- For you
- Oh, thank you
- Oh, come in
- Welcome
- Sorry l’m so late
- They're upstairs
All right, l’ll go and say hello
Welcome to you both
- It’s been a while, Noriko
- It’s lovely to see you
Were you very busy?
Not really, but by the time I'd finished,
it was too late
Oh, you needn't have rushed round here.
We could've met tomorrow
Still working for the same company?
- It must be hard, supporting yourself
- Not at all
- Your bath's ready, Father!
- Coming!
- l’ll do that for you, Mother
- l’m fine
Being in Tokyo is like a dream
I always thought Tokyo
was so far away...
...but it was only yesterday we were
in Onomichi, and now we're with you
l’m glad l’m alive to see
so many changes
But the two of you
haven't changed at all
Of course we have,
we're a couple of old folks now
Mother?
What are you two talking about?
Let's go downstairs
Mother, l’m sure you're getting taller
How could I have grown?
It’s true, you have.
And you've put on weight
When I was a child,
she was so big...
...I used to feel ashamed
in front of my classmates
- Once, she broke a school chair
- Don't tell lies!
That chair was already broken
- You still believe that?
- Of course!
Never mind. Let's go down
- Shall I take this through, Sister?
- Yes, do
- And this?
- Just leave it out
It’s a little cooler now
- It must be hot in Onomichi
- It is indeed
Mother, how is O-Ko?
She must've been born
under an unlucky star
When she was widowed,
she married again last spring...
...and took her child with her
to Kurashiki
But I hear the poor woman's
not very happy
Really?
What was the name of that fellow
on the council staff?
Oh, Mihashi, you mean?
He passed away
- Quite some time ago, wasn't it?
- That's right
Do you remember Hattori?
In the military section?
I remember him
- He's living in Tokyo now
- Is that right?
- I intend to go round and visit him
- Where is he?
Somewhere in the Daito district.
I have his address
Right...
Have you tidied everything up?
Thanks so much
Noriko, here's your present
from Keizo
Oh, thank you
Thank you
- Oh, sorry, Grandma...
- Not at all, Fumiko, not at all
You're going out tomorrow, aren't you?
It’s Sunday,
so I can show them around
- Right. Shall we be off then, Noriko?
- Let's leave together
- Thank you
- Thank you for coming
- Thanks for dinner, Brother
- Sorry it's so late
- l’ll see you soon, Father
- Thanks
We'll be fine, Fumiko
- Thanks for having us so late
- Thank you for supper
Thank you for coming
You must be tired, Father
Do you want to go to bed, Mother?
Shall we retire, then?
- Night, then
- Goodnight
- Night
l’ll bring you some water
- You must be tired
- Not really
l’m glad they're all well
We're here at last
What part of Tokyo is this?
- The suburbs
- I guess so
It was a long ride from the station
I thought they'd live
somewhere more central
- Than here?
- Yes
Koichi did want to move more centrally
But it's not easy
Urara Beauty Salon
How long are your mother
and father staying?
Four or five days. Pass me that
- Shouldn't I call round to see them?
- Don't bother. They'll come here
I should take them to a show
or something
You needn't bother
worrying about them
They're delicious, these beans
What are their plans for today?
Don't eat all those beans
My brother's taking them sightseeing
So I needn't bother, then
Kiyo, come and get some food
Behave yourselves today
when you're with grandpa and grandma
- You hear me?
- Yes
Sit down
- How much longer?
- They'll be ready soon
Go upstairs and
ask if they're ready to go
- Are you ready?
- Ready
- Sorry to keep you waiting
- Let's go, then
They're coming
What about lunch?
We'll go to a restaurant
in a department store
- The children will like that
- Fine
- Isamu loves those kiddy lunches
- All right
Excuse me...
- How is he?
- No better
- Any appetite?
- He'll only take a cold drink
- Has his temperature fallen?
- His temperature is still 102
I see. I'd better see him
Thank you, l’m sorry to spoil your day
Are the hypodermics sterilised?
I must visit a patient
Really?
Father, l’m afraid
I have to visit a patient
- I see
- Sorry
- Never mind
- It could take a while
That's all right
- l’ll see you later
- Take care
- Still not ready?
- No...
- I may be late
- What about your mother and father?
Shall I take them?
You can't leave the house unoccupied.
We'll go next Sunday
Very well. See you later
- Where's dad going?
- To see a patient
l’m awfully sorry
Never mind.
A busy doctor's a good doctor
He's very dedicated
Aren't we going, Mum? It’s not fair!
It can't be helped. A patient needs him
Not fair!
- You can go another time
- Not fair!
Behave yourself, Minoru!
- You lied!
- Make yourself scarce!
- Come here
- No way!
- They're so naughty
- It’s good for boys to be spirited
Now just behave yourselves
It’s not fair!
You can go another time
It’s always "another time".
We never go!
It can't be helped
that dad had to go out
- As usual!
- Now don't be so difficult
- It’s not fair!
- Not fair!
- What? You're being horrible
- Behave, or l’ll tell your father
- Go and tell him!
- You just remember those words!
- See if I care!
- What's the matter?
- Oh, nothing...
Come along, Isamu,
come for a walk with granny
- Won't you come, too, Minoru?
- Minoru...
- Come on, then
- That'll be nice with granny, Isamu
Let's go
Sure you don't want to come, Minoru?
Thank you
Minoru, go with them
- Shan't!
- Suit yourself then
See you later
Here you are
Thank you
- What's up with Minoru?
- He's just so stubborn
His father was the same
Koichi always had to have his own way
It’s just a shame he had to go out
when you're here
Oh, we're fine
We'll go next Sunday
Thank you
After a few days here,
we're thinking of visiting Shige
There they are
What do you want to be
when you grow up, Isamu?
Do you want to be a doctor
like your daddy?
By the time you're a doctor,
I wonder where l’ll be?
Welcome back
Hello
- There was a call for you
- Who from?
- Enomoto phoned about that business
- That's all wrapped up
- What are your folks up to?
- They're upstairs
I bought some sweets for them
from a place in Asakusa
Try one, they're delicious
These are expensive.
They don't expect such things
Tasty, eh?
Yes, but such things
are wasted on them
Rice crackers would've done
But they had rice crackers yesterday
Yes, but they really like them
Will you take them out somewhere
tomorrow?
Tomorrow? l’m afraid I can't
- I have to collect some accounts
- Really?
I was hoping my brother
would do something with them
- How about taking them to a film?
- What's on?
- There's plenty on in the evenings
- Do that with them, then
They've seen nothing of Tokyo yet
It'd be a shame for them
not to get out
I know, but who has the time
to take them?
- You look busy
- Oh, you're back
- Here
- Oh, thank you
- What a job you've been asked to do!
- Not at all
- Where's father?
- Putting clothes out to dry
I see. Let's go to the bathhouse
Father? Father!
Let's go to the bathhouse
Welcome home
- And we can buy ice-cream afterwards
- Oh, thank you
Right, let's go
- We're off to the bathhouse
- All right
- See you later
- Bye
See you later
Mother, you can use my old sandals
Really? Thanks
Here
Hello? Is that Yoneyama & Co?
May I speak to Noriko Hirayama?
Thank you
Ah, Noriko? It’s me
Don't mention it
Listen, I need a favour
Can you spare any time tomorrow?
Father and mother haven't
been sightseeing yet in Tokyo
I was wondering if you could
take them out somewhere tomorrow
I know. I ought to take them really,
but l’m too busy at the shop
I know, l’m sorry
Eh? Really?
- Thank you
- Not at all
Wait a moment, l’ll have to see
- l’m sorry it's such short notice...
- What is it?
- May I have tomorrow off?
- All right
- Thank you
- What about the aluminium contract?
l’ll get it finished today
Hello? Sorry to keep you waiting
l’ll call for them at 9:00
tomorrow morning
Not at all
Give my best regards
to your mother and father
Till tomorrow, then
Ladies and gentlemen,
welcome to Tokyo
Let's trace the illustrious history
of this great city
On your right, the Imperial Palace,
formerly Chiyoda Castle
Built 500 years ago
by Lord Dokan Ota...
...its tranquil setting amid
green pine trees and a large moat...
...contrasts strongly
with the bustle of modern Tokyo
- Koichi's house is in that direction
- I see...
- And Shige's house?
- Her house is that way, I think
- And yours?
- My house is in that direction
- It’s over that way
- I see
I hope you'll come home with me later
Who is it?
- Only me
- You're home early today
- Is Miko sleeping?
- She's just settled down
- You don't have any sake, do you?
- Sake?
- My in-laws are here
- I think I might have some
- This is all l’ve got. Is this enough?
- Fine. Thanks
Where did he have this photo taken?
In Kamakura. A friend took it
- I see
- When was that?
- The year before he was conscripted
- Really...
That's his typical look
Head on one side
He always stood like that
- What is it?
- May I borrow a flask?
Oh, right
There you go. Do you want these, too?
They're delicious
Thank you
Sorry to bother you
Noriko, please don't go to any trouble
It’s fine, it's no trouble
Thank you so much for today
Not at all.
You both must be exhausted
No, we've seen so many places,
thanks to you
l’m sorry you had to put up with us
all day
Of course not
- You must be busy at work, though
- Not really
We're only a small company and
not that busy, so I can take time off
Well, that's lucky for us
Please...
All right...
And on an empty stomach, too...
This is good stuff
Do you like a drop of sake, Father?
Oh, yes,
very much so in the old days
If we ever ran out at home...
...he'd rush out for more,
any time of the night
Every time we had a son...
...I'd pray he wouldn't
become a drinker
Did Shoji drink?
- He did indeed
- Is that so?
Often, when he went out drinking
after work...
...he'd bring friends home because
they'd missed their last trains
- Really?
- So you had the sort of trouble I had
Yes... but now
it's a very dear memory
How true
Poor Shoji,
he lived so far away...
...I feel he's still alive somewhere
Father often tells me
not to be so foolish
He must be dead. It’s been
eight years since the end of the war
I know, but all the same...
He was so wilful as a boy
l’m sure he gave you
plenty of trouble, too
Not really...
Then he had to die. Poor Noriko
Yes?
- Sorry to keep you waiting
- Thank you
It’s not much, but...
- There you are, Mother
- Thanks
- Help yourself
- Very well. Thank you so much
- They're late
- They'll be back soon
How long are they planning
to stay in Tokyo?
- They said nothing to you?
- No...
Listen, Brother...
...I was thinking, are you willing
to put up 3,000 yen?
- What for?
- I will if you will
2,000 yen should suffice
- No, we'll need 3,000 yen
- What for?
I was thinking we could send them
to a hot springs
You and I are too busy
to shepherd them around
And we can't keep asking Noriko
- What do you think?
- Not a bad idea...
I know a nice hotel in Atami,
not expensive at all
- Sounds good. Let's send them there
- l’m sure they'll be pleased
Good...
I was worrying about the cost of taking
them around. But 3,000 yen's fine
Of course, sending them to Atami
will be much cheaper for us
Dear?
What is it?
We're making plans
to send the old folks to Atami spa
That's a great idea
I wish I could show them around,
but l’m just so busy
- So you agree?
- Absolutely. It’s a great idea
Let's do it, then
- We can do nothing for them here
- Yeah, you're right
Atami is a good idea
Rather than tramping around Tokyo...
...they can bathe in the hot springs
and relax
- The old folks will love it, won't they?
- You're right
They are late, though
- Perhaps they're at Noriko's place
- Oh, maybe
l’ve never been to a hot springs before
We've put them to additional expense
Isn't this nice, though?
Let's get up early tomorrow
and take a walk along the beach
Let's do that
The scenery around here
is supposed to be lovely
- That's what the maid told me
- Really?
The sea is so calm
- Sorry to keep you waiting
- The noodles have arrived
- What's the bet?
- You had that?
- That hurts me
- Not bad, not bad
- There you are
- l’ll take, l’ll take
- Ready!
- Ready?
- You discarded this?
- Yeah, I did
l’m out
How do you like that, you idiot?
That makes 1632
He thrashed us!
It’s so noisy
I wonder how late it is
Evening!
What's the matter?
You didn't sleep well last night,
did you?
But you slept well
No, I didn't sleep a wink
You say that,
but you were sound asleep
Really?
This place is for the younger generation
You're right
Hey, what about those newlyweds?
They made so much noise!
Do you think they're really
honeymooners?
He was up this morning,
but she was lolling in bed
He's a fool
I heard him tell her, "You're all mine!
Ears, eyes, mouth, all mine!"
A woman like her!
I wonder how Kyoko's getting on
by herself
Shall we head home?
Are you feeling homesick already?
You're the one that's homesick,
aren't you?
We've seen Tokyo,
we've seen Atami
- Shall we go home?
- Very well, let's go home
What's the matter?
I just felt slightly dizzy.
l’m fine now
You didn't sleep very well, that's why.
Let's go
How about sweeping it back?
That would suit you
You think so?
You have a lovely neckline
Keep the left side flat
and put a wave in the right side
- l’ll try it next time
- It will enhance your personality
Kiyo, pass me another magazine.
And some matches
- Welcome
- We're back
What? Back so soon?
- Afternoon
- Why didn't you stay longer?
- What happened?
- Well...
Afternoon
- Who's that?
- Just some friends from the country
Kiyo, take over this for me
What happened?
You're back so soon
- How was Atami?
- Yes, we liked the hot baths
And our room had a lovely view
I know. That hotel's only just
been built. Was it crowded?
Hmm... a little crowded
- And what about the food?
- Sashimi, savoury egg custard...
Their sashimi is tasty.
It’s on the coast, that's why
And they served huge omelettes, too
How come you came back?
We wanted you to relax
We thought you'd have
two or three days' rest
We thought it was time
we got back home
So soon?
You're not that often in Tokyo
Still, we'd better be going
Kyoko must be feeling lonely at home
She'll be fine, Mother.
She's not a baby anymore
Next time, I plan to take you
to the Kabuki theatre
I don't want to put you
to so much expense
I just want you to relax
Still, my colleagues are holding
a meeting here tonight from 7:00
Oh? Will there be many of them?
Yes. It’s my turn to be host
We've come back
at the wrong moment
I should have told you. That's why
I wanted you to stay at Atami
- The dye's ready
- All right. Excuse me
What shall we do?
I don't know
We can't go to Koichi's
and bother them again
You're right.
Shall we get Noriko to put us up?
She hasn't got room for both of us.
You go there
What about you?
l’ll visit the Hattori family
and stay there if I can
Anyway, let's get going
Well, we've become homeless at last
- Noriko ought to be home by now
- You think so?
Perhaps it's still a bit early
If you're going to the Hattori family,
you'd better start now
Yes, we'd better go
That's just like you
Isn't Tokyo vast?
Isn't it just?
If we were to get lost,
we might find never each other again
Hattori - Professional Scribe
Is that how long it's been?
It must be 17 or 18 years
Really?
Still, you've sent me a card
every New Year's
Don't mention it
I suppose Onomichi
has changed a lot
Well, fortunately, it wasn't bombed
The area you used to live in
hasn't changed at all
Is that right?
It was such a nice place
We used to enjoy the view
from the Senko temple
The price of sea bream used to drop
after the cherry blossom season
We haven't eaten it
since we moved to Tokyo
That's so true
Listen, dear...
Hmm, later
Tell my friends
l’ll be playing pin-ball round there
- See you later
- Thank you
We rent the upstairs room to him.
He likes going out at night
He's a law student,
but he never does any studying
Really?
He's always gambling at pin-ball
and mah-jong. I feel sorry for his father
Go on, dear...
How's about going for a drink
for old times' sake?
l’m sure my cooking isn't
good enough for you
Forgive me for turning up
out of the blue
- Remember our old police chief?
- Numata?
- He lives nearby
- Does he? How is he?
He's fine. His son's an executive
in a printing company
- Well, good for him
- Shall we pay him a visit?
That would be wonderful
Fancy that?
- Drink up
- l’ve had plenty
Drink up, for old times' sake!
I haven't touched a drink in years
Remember how you drank
when the Governor visited us?
You mean at the Takemura?
You got absolutely legless!
Remember that young geisha
who served us?
- Umeko?
- You really took a fancy to her
So did the Governor,
if you remember?
And you, as well
Ah, youth! I always disgraced myself
whenever I got drunk
Not at all!
Drink is good for your health
You're lucky, your children
are all well settled
l’m not so sure about that
I often wish at least
one of my sons were alive
Both were killed in the war
Didn't you lose one?
Yes, my second son
l’ve had enough of war
It’s hard to lose one's children
However, living with them
isn't always easy, either
A real dilemma
Let's drink
Let's change the subject
- And cheer up!
- Yes!
If I had an extra bedroom for you,
we could drink till morning
Miss, more sake!
Come on, Miss,
bring us some sake...
Anyway, l’m really glad you came
I never dreamed
I'd see you here in Tokyo
Okaya Noodles
Here's some warm sake
Pour one for me, would you?
You're so drunk
Hirayama, she looks like
someone, don't you think?
- Here we go again!
- Don't you think so?
Well, like who?
- Yes, she does
- Like who?
- That geisha Umeko?
- Oh, no! She was much fatter
- She looks like my wife
- You're right
See, especially here...
Isn't it time you went home?
You've had enough
- And both of them are bad-tempered!
- You're being a nuisance
That's what my wife says, too
Hey, come here and pour for me
Have some more
No, thanks
I think you're the luckiest one of all
How come?
With good sons and daughters
to be proud of
You can be proud of yours, too
No, my son's no good
He's henpecked
and treats me like l’m in the way
He's nothing!
But being head of department
is a good position
Head of nothing, more like!
He's only an assistant section chief
I get so depressed that I lie to people
about his position
He's a failure
I don't think so
He's my only son,
so I spared the rod and spoiled him
You brought your son up properly
He has a degree and everything!
All doctors have to have degrees
l’m afraid we expect
too much of our children
They lack spirit
And they lack ambition
l’ve told my son that
He said that there are
too many people in Tokyo...
...that it's hard to get ahead
What do you think?
Young people today have no backbone
Where is their spirit?
That's not how I raised him!
But Numata...
You don't agree with me?
- You're satisfied?
- Of course not, but...
You see?
Even you aren't satisfied
It makes me feel so sad
No more to drink
However, Numata,
until I came up to Tokyo...
...I was under the impression
that my son was doing better
But l’ve found that he's only
a small neighbourhood doctor
I know how you feel
l’m as dissatisfied as you are
But we can't expect too much
from our children, Numata
Times have changed.
We have to face it
- That's what I think
- Is it?
- Yes
- I see. You, too
My son has really changed,
but there's nothing I can do about it
After all, there are
too many people in Tokyo
You think so?
I suppose I should be happy
Maybe you're right
Nowadays, some young men
kill their parents without a thought
At least mine wouldn't do that
Look, it's gone midnight
So what?
It’s time you went home
You get more and more like my wife.
I like you, you know?
Do something with him, will you?
Leave him alone
Let's drink up tonight, right?
A wonderful night, eh?
Wonderful, wonderful
Wonderful night
Thank you. That's enough for me
It’s been a long day today
First we get back from Atami...
...then to Shige's house...
...then over to Ueno Park
You must be tired
Not so much
And here I am, troubling you
- l’m so sorry
- Not at all
But I really appreciate your coming.
l’m so happy
l’m a burden to everyone
- You've done more than enough
- Really?
Thank you so much
You must go to bed now.
You have your work tomorrow morning
You need to go to bed, too.
Let's both get some sleep
- Very well. I think I will
- Please do
What a treat,
to sleep in Shoji's bed
Noriko...
- Forgive me if l’m being rude...
- What is it?
Well, it's been eight years
since my son's death...
...yet you still keep
his photo up there like that
I feel sorry for you
Why?
Because you're young and...
l’m not that young anymore
Yes, you are
I feel we're doing you wrong
l’ve often talked to Father about this
If you ever meet someone else...
...you must feel free
to get remarried any time
I mean it
It pains us to think
that you won't remarry
All right, if I meet the right man...
You certainly will
Why wouldn't you?
You think so?
You had more hard times
than happiness after marrying him
I know we should have done
something for you
Please, Mother.
l’m quite happy as I am
But you should have had
a better life
Not at all. I like it this way
You may be happy
while you're still young...
...but as you get older,
you'll find it lonely
I won't get that old,
so don't worry
You're such a good person
Goodnight, then
Goodnight
Good evening!
Hello? Hello?
Mrs Kaneko?
Yes? Who is it?
Who could it be?
- Who is it?
- The police. Officer Takahashi
Oh, all right...
Sorry for calling so late.
l’ve brought your friends round
They're quite drunk
Why, Father!
- l’m terribly sorry
- Goodnight
Who's he, Father?
Father, what's all this?
Father!
Hey, what's happened?
- He's brought some stranger with him
- Who is it?
- I don't know
- Stop all the noise!
What's all this, Father?
Father!
- Father! What's all this?
- Well...
Hopeless!
You've started drinking again!
Hello? Hello?
Hey, you! Hey, you!
Father? Father!
You're hopeless!
What happened?
Where's he been drinking?
Where? How should I know?
He used to drink all the time
Used to come home blind drunk,
upsetting Mother
We hated it
But he stopped drinking
after Kyoko was born
He was like a new man,
I thought it was great
Now he's started again
Hey, what shall we do?
I didn't expect him back here tonight,
let alone with company!
- We can't leave them there like that
- It can't be helped
Let's bring Kiyo down
and we'll put them upstairs
They're too drunk to make it upstairs
What shall we do?
What a mess!
You sleep upstairs.
l’ll put them here
What a bother!
Why didn't he tell me
he was coming back?
So late and so drunk!
I hate drunkards
And with a stranger, too
Oh, I can't bear it!
- Thank you for letting me stay
- Not at all
l’m sorry the place is such a mess
Won't you be late for work?
Will you be all right?
Yes, l’ll be fine
- Mother?
- What is it?
I want you to have this
- Spending money for you
- What do you mean?
- It’s not much, though
You don't have to do this!
Please take it, Mother!
- I couldn't possibly
- Please, Mother!
- I couldn't...
- Please
l’m the one who should be
giving you something
Please accept it, Mother
Please
Must I?
Then thank you very much, my dear
Please
You must need money for yourself,
but still you do this for me
I don't know what to say...
...but thank you so much
Thank you
Let's get going, Mother
Yes...
If you come up to Tokyo again,
Mother, please visit me
But I don't know
whether l’ll be able to...
I know you're busy, but you should
try to come to Onomichi
I'd really like to,
if only it were a bit nearer
You're right. It’s so far away
Mother, you forgot these
Oh, again! l’ve got so forgetful lately
Let's go, then
Next Tokaido line departure
on Platform 14
21:00 express to Hiroshima
It’s packed, isn't it?
But we're in a good position
to get seats here
The train should arrive in Nagoya
or Gifu by morning
- When does it arrive in Onomichi?
- 01:35 tomorrow afternoon
Did you send Kyoko a telegram?
Yes, I did
Keizo will meet you at Osaka, too
Mother, I hope you have
a good sleep on the train
She can sleep soundly anywhere!
Even if I don't,
l’ll be home tomorrow afternoon
And Father, don't drink too much
Well, last night's reunion
was an exception
Has the headache gone?
It’s fine
Let this be a warning
l’m sure it was a good lesson
You've been very kind to us, all of you.
We enjoyed our trip
Thanks for looking after us
when you have such busy lives
Now that we've seen you all,
you needn't come down...
...even if anything should happen
to either one of us
Don't talk like that, Mother
This isn't a farewell
I mean it. We live so far away
Sorry for keeping you waiting.
The 21:00 departure is now ready...
- Morning
- Morning. Sorry about yesterday
- I heard your parents came
- Yes. What a palaver
They weren't supposed to get off
the train, but my mother became ill
- What was the trouble?
- She didn't feel well here
- Was it her heart?
- Travel sickness, I reckon
She hadn't been on a train
for a long time
What a drama
I had to borrow blankets
and send for the doctor twice
- And how is she now?
- She's feeling fine this morning
How old is she?
Let me see...
She's way over 60
67 or 68, maybe
Fairly old, then
Take good care of her
"Honour your parents
while they are still alive"
That's right
And they say, "One cannot serve
one's parents beyond the grave"
It must've been
because the train was so crowded
You're probably right
- Feeling better?
- I feel fine now
I should be able
to leave for home tonight
Well, let's stay here one more night
and tomorrow take a less crowded train
Kyoko must be worried about us
But at least we're here in Osaka
and able to see Keizo
In the past ten days
we've managed to see all our children
And our grown-up grandchildren, too
Some grandparents seem to prefer their
grandchildren more than their children
What do you think?
What about you?
I prefer my own children
I agree with you
But it surprises me
how children change
Shige used to be
a much nicer person before
She did, didn't she?
When a daughter marries,
she becomes a stranger
Koichi has changed, too.
He used to be such a nice boy
Children never live up
to their parents' expectations
Let's just be happy that
they're better than most
They're certainly
better than average
We're fortunate
I think so, too
We should consider ourselves lucky
Yes, we are very lucky
My folks had to get off the train
at Osaka
Oh, really?
Mother became sick on the train
They got home on the 10th
Is she all right now?
I think so.
They wrote to say thanks
She must've been tired
The trip was too much for her
- Was she satisfied?
- Why wouldn't she be?
She got to see lots of places
and went to Atami, too
I suppose so
She'll talk about Tokyo
for a long time to come
Hello?
Speaking...
A telegram?
Not yet. Where from?
From Onomichi
It came today, but it's very odd
It says mother's critically ill
Eh? That's right
That's strange
I just got a letter from father
It says they got off at Osaka
because mother felt sick
They arrived home in Onomichi
on the 10th
That's right
Telegram!
Hold on
Thank you
- It’s from Onomichi
- Read it
"Mother critically ill - Kyoko"
Hello? Hello?
The telegram just arrived
You just got one too?
Right, l’ll come over
- See you later
- l’ll be waiting
How did it happen so suddenly?
I wonder if it's serious
Should I let Noriko know?
Yes, do that for me
Yes? Yoneyama Trading Company
Hold the line, please
Miss Hirayama, telephone!
For me?
Hello?
Oh, hello
Mother is?
Is that so?
Thank you
What can it mean?
I can understand Father falling ill
But Mother's got so much vitality
Think it's serious?
It’s not good.
They said "critically ill"
I suppose we'll have to go then
I sensed something wasn't right
at the station
She said,
"If anything should happen..."
She must've had a bad feeling,
somehow or other
- Anyway, we should go and see her
- I guess so, since she's critically ill
If we're going, we better hurry.
We should take the express
l’ll have to make all kinds
of arrangements before I leave
So will I
In the middle of this busy time, too
Come in
Hey, can you bring a bandage?
A bandage
Let's leave tonight, then
Might as well, if we have to go.
See you later
Brother?
What is it?
What about mourning clothes?
Shall we take them?
Maybe we should
All right, let's take them
Let's just hope
we don't need to use them
- Right
- l’ll meet you at Tokyo Station
l’ll go and meet them, Father
That's very good of you
l’ll be back soon
What's the matter?
Are you too hot?
The children are coming from Tokyo
to see you
Kyoko's just gone to meet them
They'll be here any moment
You'll get better
You will...
Her blood pressure's dropped,
but she's still in a coma
I see
Her reactions are weak
- Thank you, anyway
- l’ll drop by again
Thank you for coming
Take care
I wonder where Keizo is.
He's so late
- Did he answer the telegram?
- No, not a word
But he lives in Osaka,
the closest of all of us
Father, come with me
You as well
Listen, Father,
I don't like her condition
I see...
What do you mean?
I mean it's dangerous
The fact that she's still in a coma
isn't a good sign
I see...
Did the trip to Tokyo exhaust her
and bring this on?
I don't think so. She was so lively
in Tokyo. Wasn't she?
- It might've caused it
- So what is it, then?
She may not live till tomorrow morning
Tomorrow morning?
It'll probably happen around dawn
I see...
She's not going to live
Mother's 68, isn't she?
So... she's not going to live
That's what I think
I see...
So this is the end?
That's all
Then Keizo won't be in time, will he?
Life's too short, isn't it?
She was so lively, too
She must've had a feeling
this would happen
Perhaps
Still, l’m glad she came to Tokyo
We were able to see her alive
And we talked about many things
Noriko, did you bring
any mourning clothes?
- No
- You should've brought some
Do you have any, Kyoko?
No, I don't
You'll have to borrow some, then
And get some for Noriko, too
At least mother died peacefully
and without suffering at all
I wonder if that's Keizo
How is she?
So... I wasn't in time
I was afraid of that
Good day
Unfortunately,
I was out of town on business
l’m sorry l’m late
- The telegram came while I was away
- Really?
How awful...
When was it?
This morning... at 3:15
I see...
If I'd taken the 8:40 train from
Kagoshima, I would've been in time
Keizo, look at her.
See how peaceful she is
Forgive my delay
Where's father?
I wonder
Father...
- Keizo has just arrived
- Has he?
It was such a beautiful dawn
It’s going to be another hot day today
What's the matter?
I can't stand that sound
Why?
As I hear it, I feel as if my mother
were becoming smaller, bit by bit
I wasn't a very good son
It’s time to offer incense
I can't lose her now
"One cannot serve one's parents
beyond the grave"
We used to watch fireworks
from this room, didn't we, Father?
Oh, did we?
On the night of the town festival
- Remember, Keizo?
- No, I don't
You were so excited,
but after sunset you fell asleep
With your head on mother's lap
I really don't remember
What were you doing
in those days, Father?
I was head of the city's
board of education, I believe
Were you?
A long time ago, wasn't it?
Once we all went to Omishima
during the spring holidays
Oh, that I do remember
- Mother got seasick
- Yes, I remember that
She was so full of life then
How old was she then? Forty...?
Forty-two or forty-three, I think
You have to take good care
of yourself now, Father...
...and enjoy a long life
Thank you
Some more?
More, sis?
It may sound heartless to say so...
...but I rather wish father had died first
If Kyoko gets married,
he'll be left all alone
Maybe
We could've looked
after mother in Tokyo
Kyoko, did mother still have
that grey summer sash?
- Yes
- I'd like it as a memento
- Is that all right, Brother?
- Why not?
And also...
...that linen kimono
she used to wear in summer?
- It’s here
- I want that, too
You know where it is?
Get it out for me
It’s all over now
Thank you all for coming so far
and giving up your precious time
Thank you
She would've been pleased
to know Koichi looked after her
I didn't really do anything
I remember when we went
to Atami from Tokyo...
...she had a dizzy spell
- Oh?
- It didn't seem that serious
Really? Why didn't you tell us, Father?
You should've told Koichi at least
I guess I should have
But that wasn't the cause
Mother was overweight,
so the illness came on suddenly
I see...
It’s just like a dream
- When are you leaving, Brother?
- I can't stay long
Me neither.
Shall we take the express tonight?
- What about you, Keizo?
- I can stay
- Let's leave tonight, then
- Right
Noriko, you'll stay with father
a bit longer, won't you?
- Yes
- No, you're busy. l’ll be fine
I might as well go, then.
I have to make a report.
And there's that baseball match, too
Well, thanks for coming
when you're so busy
You'll be lonely now, Father
l’ll get used to it
Kyoko, pass me some more rice
Get the train tickets for us,
will you, Keizo?
Yes. Rice for me, too
I hope the train's empty
Father, you mustn't drink too much
l’ll be all right
So, you're all going home?
- Here's your lunch
- Thank you so much
Thanks for letting me stay
Come and see me in Tokyo
in your summer holidays
- Do you have to go home today?
- Yes, I must
Really?
- Sorry I can't see you off
- That's all right
Do come and see me
in the summer holidays
l’m so glad you stayed
I think my brothers and sister
should have stayed a bit longer
But they're very busy
They're just selfish
Demanding things
and then leaving just like that
That can't be helped.
They have work to get back to
But you have yours too
- They think only of themselves
- But Kyoko...
Asking for mementos of mother
right after her death!
I felt so sorry for poor mother
Even strangers would have been
more considerate
But look, Kyoko,
I thought so too when I was your age
But, as children get older,
they drift away from their parents
A woman has her own life,
apart from her parents...
...when she becomes Shige's age
So she meant no harm, l’m sure
They have their own lives to look after
I wonder...
But I won't ever be like that
Otherwise what's the point
of being part of a family?
You're right
But all children become like that
eventually
You, too?
I may become like that,
in spite of myself
Isn't life disappointing?
Yes, nothing but disappointment
- Well, I should get going
- Goodbye, then
Father, l’m leaving now
- Take care of yourself
- Thank you. You, too
Come and see me
in the summer holidays
Goodbye, then
- Goodbye
- See you soon
Has Kyoko left?
Father, l’m leaving
on the afternoon train
Oh? You're going home?
Thank you for everything
Please, I didn't do anything
- You've been a great help
- Not at all
My wife told me
how kind you were to her...
...when she stayed
at your place in Tokyo
Not at all.
I didn't have much to offer
Well, she really meant it
She told me that evening with you
was her happiest time in Tokyo
- I want to thank you, too
- Not at all
She was so worried
about your future
You mustn't go on like this
Don't worry about me
You should get remarried
if you meet the right man
Just forget about Shoji
It pains me to see you
living like this
No, it's not like that
She said she'd never met
a nicer woman than you
l’m sure she was overestimating me
She certainly wasn't
l’m not the nice woman
she thought I was
It embarrasses me that
you should think of me like that
Well, it shouldn't
Really, I can be quite selfish
l’m not always thinking of your late son,
though you may think I am
You should just forget him
Often, there are days
when I don't think of him at all
Sometimes I feel
I can't go on like this forever
Often I lay awake at night wondering
what will become of me if I remain alone
Days pass and nothing happens,
and I feel so alone
In my heart,
I seem to be waiting for something
- l’m just being selfish
- No, you're not
Yes, I am
But I couldn't say this to mother
That's all right
You truly are a good woman.
An honest woman
Not at all
This watch belonged to her
It’s rather old-fashioned...
...but she used it
since she was your age
Please take it as a memento
- But I...
- Please take it
l’m sure she'd be very happy
if you used it
Please take it
Thank you
Please believe me when I say
that I want you to be happy
I mean it sincerely
It’s strange...
We have children of our own...
...yet you've done the most for us,
and you're not even a blood relative
Thank you
You must be feeling lonely
with them all gone
It was so sudden, wasn't it?
Well, she was a headstrong woman...
...but if I'd known things
would come to this...
...I'd have been kinder to her
while she was alive
Living alone,
I think the days will seem very long
Absolutely
You'll feel lonely
The End