Subtitles downloaded from Podnapisi.NET
Special Forces Unit
base 27-33.
Our mission is to seek and destroy.
Our enemies are not.
Lethal weapons are ours.
They have knowledge of
soft targets in the
basement and that makes
them difficult to destroy.
We are allowed to shoot our goal.
There will be no mercy for any of us.
Dude, is it?
Do not talk back Friend, quiet!
I am Eric's friend Max!
Eric?
Yes, Eric!
It's great to see you!
A taste, man!
I thought you were going to kill me!
She is Jenna and she Evie.
We all grew up with Max.
What a great view, good is to return.
Buy some drinks!
Come on baby.
Well, Jenna!
It is time for some shots!
Here we go.
Health!
Health.
How were things?
I heard there were problems.
He met a sexy doctor.
Really? And I can not or Cosmetelogía.
Travel the world and returns
with the girl, incredible.
She must be good and intelligent Dr.
Do not be jealous, come.
'Hello!
'Hi, Eric!
How are you?
'I'm glad you're back 'Me too.
Evie!
Oh my god!
...I missed you so much!
Is it .. Dr.?
Evie, Jenna, she's my girlfriend Look.
Hello
...Our boy won the prize.
'I'm Eric
...Look
I have a memory to show.
It looks sexy, no?
You look good for women
...Hey, I'm a real man, real man!
Have fun!
Perfect I do not like these places.
Will be an adventure.
Well, do it fast.
Sorry, big guy.
What the hell's the matter?
Reviewing my dog??,
What are you doing, man?
Fuck you!
Want some cowboy?
You are nothing.
Stay away, bitch.
Come for a little bitch.
Go!
I will cut like a fish.
Stand down, soldier
I'm.
Saved by the Bell, bitch.
Storm, bitches.
Come on, come on!
At the door, fast!
Quick, hurry!
They were.
They shot the door, Billy.
What the hell?
What the hell are you doing?
Oh shit.
Shot?
Yes, there are thugs out.
They have weapons
...What? Open the door!
Shut up 'You shut up.
What did you say?
Do not you hear me?
Hey, hey.
Depart.
You do not know you, but relax.
All relax
I can not, I'm claustrophobic.
And why did you come?
...Do not be stupid.
Come.
Help, Help!
...Closed doors!
Guys, the music stopped, the
party ended, No one comes to us.
How we get out?
It is made of concrete... and metal
shit.
It is an industrial cave.
Typical underground U.S. military.
All these places are the same.
Have drivers, radiators,
a second exhaust port
and those fans used to escape.
If I get a radiator,
I can recharge my cell.
How are you going to have
an underground service?
Well, where is the second exit, genius?
There's something wrong with this place.
'This way there should be a door
'Sorry, I will not go more.
The exit is over there.
It is the only path to an exit.
Preserve light, with cell phones and
the glosticks when necessary.
We must leave here.
Idiot!
Do not make jokes, Storm.
Storm, come here
Eric, turns on the light.
Shit...
...What is it?
Here are gas lamps,
used it in an emergency.
Pull this 'All right, boss.
Oh god, I could kiss!
Do not get excited, do not
know how much gas has.
You're right, let's use this light,
let's go.
Come on, move!
Left.
What the hell was that?
Oh my god.
Hurry
...I will not go over there.
Can be stopped?
They think they have a GPS?
That is the wrong way.
Let's face.
Relax, this place is easy to confuse.
No big deal, is what is happening now.
The second output should
be opposite to the first.
We are still at the first exit,
come on, think a little.
Come, come.
Why did I come?
It's your fault!
Shut up!
We are going to die!
They shut up and walk.
My God... This leads to
another level, the only way out.
We will divide into 2 groups
takes the girls with you, Billy
I'll be behind you, quiet
I do not know how safe they are,
we should not use together.
It's just down ..
Everything all right?
Let us find the damn exit.
That is disgusting.
Great, no output.
Check this out.
What is it?
One type of tunnel
I will review
I saw something, I swear to God
I saw eyes.
You say that there is something there?
Yes.
What could have down here?
...Hey!
What do you do with scare?
...I just saw your eyes, man.
Lie, go see it again.
Yes, nothing.
It must be reflective, I was wrong
I saw that there is a way, maybe if we,
we reach the second level
I will not go there
...We also.
Look for a door.
There.
If someone wants to do it, do it now
'That will be me.
Meanwhile, go over there
I have very thirsty Yes, I also.
What, what was that?
Only the tubes.
Is glass?
For what?
Give me the pole.
Sounds like a old aquarium
I can not see anything.
And they are in a contest to urinate?
Why is taking so long?
We.
Hey, you can take water
from the urinary.
You are sick.
Have fun.
What the fuck!
My God, my God!
What the hell happened?
We do not know, do not know!
Jenna!
Just steer clear, okay?
Is breathing.
You'll be fine.
There's nothing there Click, right?
Jenna, Evie!
Where were they?
I do not know, but we must leave here.
Not far from us We are going to die.
It's going to survive?
Yes, still breathing.
And if we find a way out...
We can not take it, we will stop,
need speed
I think it'll be fine.
You'll be fine.
Both must be calm.
Yes, listen to Dr. He did not even
know what it was that attacked him.
These gang... did
They?
You think they were?
Eric, not.
Come a time.
We have to think a strategy now.
'We have to be quiet
How are we to do?
- Because we're going to die!
- Shut up, shut up!
Shut all.
We need help now or
will bleed to death.
We have to divide us.
Someone must stay with him
I'll go with you.
'All right, all right According
God is vomiting blood!
Where are we going?
What the hell was that?
Let's go.
We're gonna die! We're gonna die!
See that? It was not human!
'I do not know!
Who did you think human?
I have seen so many bodies in Iraq.
By bombs, but no hands!
Pick it up, do it.
You can do
...No, I can!
Okay, okay.
We're not alone 'I know.
No, look at that.
What do they do?
Without departing from the group.
What the hell is that?
Definitely not human.
We do not know how much
gas is in the generators.
We have to keep moving.
The more we know what it is,
better to fight them.
He's dead, whatever it is,
That is not breathing.
This is not something
you've seen before.
You can not break the glass, go, go!
What the hell is it?
...No time to find out! Come on!
We can still way out hajar.
It is clear.
'It's a good place to hide
'Come, come.
Come on!
Look what is necessary for
use as weapons, whatever.
They must do whatever
is necessary to defend.
Whatever you have to do, they will.
Water, food, whatever they are.
Are we ready?
Go!
The generators ran out of gas,
Eric catches that
I can not see anything.
The light works?
Are upon us.
Quick!
Shit!
I'm coming!
Calm down.
It is not.
Silence.
You should not have come for me.
We are one, remember?
You out of here.
Let's see if it works.
What we are fighting are not human,
are much more lethal than we.
You can shoot and destroy the enemy.
The military were here.
They can not stop.
They tried but failed.
We.
Take this
I do not know why they did,
but must have a reason.
It makes no sense.
It will not return, is dead.
We do not know that.
Do not leave.
What is it?
It is clear.
- How bad is it? We will stop?
- No, not, give me a hand Eric
1, 2, 3
It is not so serious, will
be fine in a few minutes.
We can not fight these
things if we are dragging.
Sorry, it's tough, but
not die for that.
Shut up... How often will tell
you that we will not stop anyone?
Friend.
Yes?
Will not let you 'You saw what
he did to Evie? The split in two.
These things... are not animals.
What you say?
I saw a recording of the soldiers,
Special Forces Unit came to destroy
these things killed the unit.
They were organized in piles,
clothes, necklaces, bones, weapons.
They have more intelligence
than an animal.
How to kill them?
If you are alive, may die
Eric, come, we belong together.
Think I do not know where we are?
They are everywhere.
When no noise, do not come.
We kill one by one.
We have to cross this.
Come.
What place is this?
Panels are.
In what is floating?
The temperature changes.
How deep is it?
Hard to say.
Not cross it, those damn in the water.
We have no choice.
'I do not listen? No it will cross
These stay.
Dies
...Jenna, please.
Hurry 'OK, go, go
Eric, come, do not stay.
Water
...Eric!
What?... These waters are toxic,
these creatures are amphibians.
'Be careful He's right.
Were carried Eric.
There was nothing you could do.
What happened in your chest?
Max told me, tell.
We came from the mission ..
We were at the base
Iraqi police was behind us
and we all jumped up and shot them
and saw two approaching
Matt told me not to shoot, but
I did not hear
shot
and fired
and children were
sent children behind us
and killed.
We threw grenades
Matty took me to a safe place.
He took the shot.
It's my guardian angel.
We must focus.
Come on, we have to concentrate.
We got company!
Looking for a generator.
Okay, soldier.
Look at this
I created a creature face
that can replace soldiers
these creatures are made for
the French Navy and American
American prototypes.
Soldiers
...Using a radical form of genetic
animal and human
with a high mortality rate, we created
these creatures of human mothers.
Women have obtained.
Feeding with blood, I
got that creatures
survive in the womb of
their human mothers
to create a new species.
Our older generations
were more primitive
but the following may be transmitted.
You can call them as they
want but I call them Frogs.
They think like soldiers.
That's why you kept alive.
To use you as an incubator.
Yes?
The army teaches us to kill and create
these things for the same purpose.
Now they want to kill?
Someone left this plan.
Do you mean?... That whatever it is,
we can not tell anyone that went down.
That's right, the military
will not let us tell.
If we talk, we will disappear.
If we fall, we die
and if we, we die also.
No, when we leave,
we will stay silent.
If you are part animal, what they fear
Most animals?
Fire? 'Exactly, if we adecuandos
chemicals, we can overcome
I agree, better to try.
Doctor.
Bingo.
Check this out.
If you could ignite the whole place.
If we unite, we can overcome.
Do not want to fight in groups.
Shit.
Come back, come!
Jenna!
You should be here.
Please, please help.
Help us out.
Once you enter, do not go.
Mat!
I'm here!
I'm down here!
To make my creatures, deadly
I found the best way to create.
My drugs make them better
but makes a bit angry.
What say?
My drug test No, do not wanna die.
No, no, no others!
I can save.
Yes, I know.
- What is your name?
- Jenna.
Thank you, thank you very much.
Come, come, come.
Your eyes are beautiful.
Come, come here.
Let me take.
Are you okay?
Stay close.
Shit!
Are you okay?
Just a scratch.
Where is Jenna?
I do not know brother.
Should not enter.
Believe me, no return.
Neither your friend Jenna.
Fuck you, man!
Typical American.
You're a damned fool,
left you here alone like a rat.
No, I'm left here with my
project, to create more
for thewar I will save
many lives and the glory.
At what price?
Collateral Damage.
Come on, come on!
I think we lost.
We're going down that
road and then down.
A taste.
Shit.
Mat?
Mat!
Look at me!
I!
Sorry.
Look up.
Come on, damn!
It is dead quiet, dead!
We.
Storm!
Hello.
Well, team.
Put your arm around my neck,
will carry you.
No, come on, man...
Look.
We have seen men like that, not
even that bad, and did not make it.
They broke my stomach,
I'm not going anywhere.
They have to fight.
Well done.
Very well.
This is what I deserve for
killing those children
I feel so bad about it
...Not.
Do not do that.
Listen to me, okay? You out of
here and take you to a hospital
I'm not going to be OK, Matty
I can load on your neck.
Those things will kill you,
I will only waste your time
I can not leave.
Will not live long.
You heard what he said?
He said he will not live long.
Clava something in my chest now
you hear me?
Now, Matty.
Do not leave me this way
I love you, brother
I really do.
Look, this fucking cares for me
Do you agree?
Well, that's a thank
I can not believe you got back.
Semper Fi.
Do it now, damn.
Curse.
Time to go.
It's time to go home.
The missing girl's name
is Evie, her parents
say who went to a rave
at the military base
would be good to go there and check
I have fear.
Hey.
We leave here.
No way out, we.
What the hell happened?
They are alone?
Where is Evie?
Sheriff, Sheriff, now!
No!
We did.
How can we continue?
Do not know
I guess we have to.
And learn to put it in the past.
Try
I feel so guilty
I will miss him
I love you And I love you.
What is it?
I can not get out of my head.
Okay, it's just a nightmare.
You're safe, right?
You're safe.
Okay.
Mat.
Who was it?
Mat?
Get away from me!