Like a fragrance floating in the breeze
A fragrance that is unspeaking
You live with it
I'm aware of it
Out in the open for the world to see
What is this unknown mystery?
Laila?
You'll forgot something?
I hate regrets.
Then you shouldn't have any.
Bye.
Flying away in the open sky...
Are the birds of my dreams
Flying away...
To the land of my heart
are the birds of my dreams
Don't know where they'll go nest
Wings have taken flight and
now says my sight you've flnally awoken
What was on your mind is left behind
You've moved far ahead in time
Life is floating on a breeze
Life is telling you and me
Now whatever will be will be
A touch from someone
and I've been wandering without a thought
Somewhere new words were spoken
and since then I've been lost
Something made the heart melt
In a blink, I was someone else
Now whatever will be will be
A light shone down
Now there's a beauty being showered on the streets
Happiness came down
Now there's a zest being showered upon me
Now I flnally know who I was meant to be
Do you remember that moment yesterday
The one with the magic force?
It transformed us into something new
I wonder which moment it was?
The heart says just blindly go to
Any place that desire takes you
Now whatever will be will be
What do you mean,
you've quit your job?
Meaning?
We're getting married in two months.
So? You can resume after the wedding.
How?
First, we'll go on the honeymoon...
then I want to redo the house.
That will take about a year.
And if you're going
to Singapore for your new project...
I'll be coming with you.
But...
that hotel is your dream project, Natasha.
Dreams change baby.
Then, I didn't know I'd be getting married.
Married?
What does marriage have to do with it?
What do you mean?
Obviously, priorities change.
After the wedding, even you wouldn't
want to go on this kind of boys holiday
- When is her flight?
- At 6 p.m.
Don't worry man, we'll make it.
Yeah.
Very funny!
All okay, babe?
Yeah.
Can I drive?
Can you drive?
Babe, the speed limit is 120.
You can go faster.
Yes, we may just miss that flight.
I'm not going to drive rashly.
Watch out!
Please keep your eyes on the road, please!
Then tell him not to talk to me.
Don't talk to her.
I love this song.
Rock chick in a hard rock world...
I'm a rock chick in a hard rock world...
Nothing rocks better than a rock chick girl...
I had fun.
Listen...
I'm sorry.
Me too.
Bye Bagwati.
Tell me...
what do you think about them?
- Kabir is not himself when Natasha is around.
- That's what I thought.
Correct.
I sense some tension.
Did you speak with him?
Why should I?
If a friend doesn't address
a personal problem, then who will?
Forget it man!
They'll sort their problem
and we'll get screwed in the middle.
Chee, man!
You are seriously shameless.
What?
Look... he is our friend.
When he is back,
let's talk to him.
Okay?
Okay.
God!
Now what has he done?
He's buried inside his diary again.
He's too boring.
What do you write in it?
It's private.
Rascal...
you've always been secretive.
- But there's nothing to tell.
- No, no, no!
You're obviously struggling
with an emotional problem.
What? Me?
Arjun...
I truly believe that...
if a friend doesn't address
a personal problem, then who will?
- Continue.
- Yes, absolutely.
To figure out the problem
we have to do a test.
- I'll say a word.
- Okay.
And you have to say the first thing
that comes to your mind.
Without deliberating.
- Alright?
- Okay.
- Ready, doctor.
- Fine.
Car.
Road.
Arjun.
Brother.
Diary.
Poetry.
Heart.
Love.
Mumbai.
Traffic.
Father.
- Father?
- Mother.
According to my test...
your father is the root of
your emotional problem.
And you're keeping this from the world.
And, in my opinion,
Dr. Sigmund Fraud...
it's time to shred your degree.
Please stop practicing, please!
You hurt my feelings, man.
My bwoys!
If you want a view,
look that way.
We should talk to him.
Natasha is really sweet.
It was really nice to meet her.
Yeah... even she was glad
to have met you.
Kabir...
- are you happy?
- Yes.
Why... are you asking like this?
I don't know man. Listen...
it's possible I may be wrong.
But, we are friends.
And I just...
I just have to ask you.
Are you happy with Natasha?
Dude, you just met her.
And the poor girl was a bit tense.
She thought there was something
between Laila and me.
Yeah.
But, now there's no problem.
Thanks to you, my bwoys!
Okay?
She's sweet.
Imran, you've met her.
You spent time with her.
Tell him.
Yes, she is very sweet.
Well that's good, man.
I'm happy for you.
Hey... here's an extra pillow!
Good night, bwoys.
Good night.
Guys, do you mind
if we take a detour?
Why?
There is an artist, Salman Habib.
He lives around here.
The lady at the gallery told me.
That he sells his paintings from home.
Really?
Sounds good.
Anyway, I'm a bit bored
hanging with just the two of you.
The map says we should take
the next right for Grazalema.
- Salman Habib.
- You'll find Indians in
every corner of the world.
- Really, man. We're everywhere!
Grazalema. Turn right over here.
- Dude, I said right.
- Forget it.
Don't feel like it.
Let's go to Seville.
- Are you sure?
- Yeah.
We can go on the way back.
It's okay.
Okay!
It's time to see
what I've planned for us.
Check it out, bwoys!
Look at that guys!
- Arjun, my pal. You rock!
- Look at that dude!
- Wow!
- You b******!
You're purposely doing this.
You know I'm scared of heights.
Don't be silly.
I want to do this.
It's my dream.
- Yeah right!
- Just imagine...
jumping from 15,000 feet
and flying towards the earth.
That's not flying, that's falling.
It will be fun.
Relax.
Remember he eventually enjoyed diving.
- Correct.
- Big deal.
With a beautiful instructor
like Laila, who wouldn't!
You never know,
you also might get lucky.
You people ready to
jump out of a plane?
- Oh yeah!
Are you ready to enter the air?
Yeah!
Head up. Eyes to the horizon.
Legs at 45 degrees.
Arch! Arch!
- Did I say relax?
- No.
I said arch.
I didn't say relax.
These are total malfunctions.
In case of a total malfunction
what you have to do is this.
Cut away your main and
deploy your reserve.
What is that?
You have a malfunction.
Cut away my main and
deploy my reserve.
What are you doing?
- It's a broken line.
- Are you sure it's a broken line?
Scissor kick... scissor kick...
Cut! Deploy!
Perfect!
What's this?
Waiver form.
Waiver form?
If something happens to us... like death,
these guys aren't responsible.
We are responsible for it.
What?
I'll see you outside.
- I'm feeling sick.
- What?
I'm going to throw up.
I'm scared too.
But that's why we are here.
Everybody get ready.
Okay!
Alright, guys. This is it!
Bye!
Dude!
I'm next.
Adios amigo!
See you downstairs!
Let go, lmran.
Just let it all go!
Push me!
Come on, lmran!
Lmran!
Who are you?
Where have you been?
I've moved the heaven and the earth
but I couldn't flnd you
But you arrive today,
so suddenly
And you give meaning to
my whole life with your love
I don't understand
I don't know
What you've said to me, Señorita
Even then, I have no idea why
I like what I heard, Señorita
Don't look away
Stay close to me
Take me in your arms
Hope you've understood Señorita
Even a few moments of love
Are never too less
Come let's lose ourselves in them
And forget we ever knew sadness
Señorita, listen to us
Señorita, d'you hear what we're saying
I will never understand
The meaning of the words
you dedicate to me
But the warmth of your gaze
Makes me feel like
the most beautiful Señorita
Our eyes looked at each other
And recounted tales of desire Señorita
That for affection and for love
There is only one language
in the world Señorita
Don't look away from me now
Come closer to me
Take me in your arms
Hope you've understood Señorita
Even a few moments of love
Are never too less
Come let's lose ourselves in them
And forget we ever knew sadness
Señorita, listen to us
Señorita, d'you hear what we're saying
With every moment that has passed
Oh Señorita
You've managed to win my heart
And that's all there is to it
Don't look away
Stay close to me
Take me in your arms
Hope you've understood Señorita
Even a few moments of love
Are never too less
Come let's lose ourselves in them
And forget we ever knew sadness
Remember before cable TV
we only had one national channel?
And every Sunday
they showed a Hindi film.
Get to the point.
The point is...
before the film there was this animation.
A white circle went round and round
and formed the channel logo.
Do you remember the tune?
Brilliant!
That tune never failed to depress me.
Depressed.
I'm feeling the same right now.
Weekend's over and school begins.
- And you wanted to cancel this trip!
- I know, man!
Can you imagine?
You know what that means?
It means...
that everything is predestined.
Everything!
This holiday was in our destiny.
You know!
You, me and asshole.
- Cheers asshole.
- Where's asshole?
Cheers!
Laila too.
I was meant to meet her.
You are in louw, my bwoy.
No, man!
You are in louw...
- You are in louw...
- Kabir, man!
Everything is written.
Listen to me.
It's all predestined.
You know what I'm saying?
This moment... us right now...
it's predestined.
Predestined.
Please stop saying, 'predestined... '!
I beg of you!
This too is predestined.
It's all written.
Alright, we get it.
Listen, we get it, zip!
Come on, man!
It's true.
It's predestined...
Guys...
Hola...
Guys, watch out!
What the hell, guys?
Yes?
- Our man is back.
- Their mobiles are switched off.
- What?
- Yup.
Even Nuria's?
Yes, I'm shocked.
When she knew we'd land up in jail,
she should've kept the phone switched on
If our bail isn't posted...
we'll be stuck here for days.
Arjun...
tell them I want to make a call.
To whom?
Salman Habib.
The artist?
Yeah.
Why will he come to post our bail?
Are you alright?
Just because we can't reach anyone,
he's losing it.
He's my father.
What?
I am his son.
Just let it go lmran.
Just let it go.
- Hello...
Hello, may I...
speak with Mr. Salman Habib, please?
- Yes?
Sir, I am lmran.
I am Rahila's son.
When did you find out?
Afew days after Abu died.
In his stuff, I found a letter
that Ammi had written to him.
The letter stated that...
Ammi was grateful that Abu had
accepted her and her unborn child.
Why didn't you tell us?
I was a bit shaken up.
What would I tell you?
Abu is not my father.
He loved you a lot.
He really loved you.
And us.
I mean, think about it.
Be it sports day or
parent-teacher meetings...
our fathers seldom came,
but Abu was always there.
Well, my father was dead.
So, if he showed up for sports day
it would've been a bit strange.
- You've got bail.
They're here.
Hi.
Imran.
Imran...
I'm Salman.
My friends, Arjun and Kabir.
- Hello.
- Thank you.
Hi... thank you.
You three look pretty hungover.
You're welcome to come over to
my place and freshen up.
Our bags and car are at the hotel.
I'll drive you there.
Come.
- Wow, this is beautiful.
It's really nice.
Are you always so polite?
It's absolute rubbish.
Anyone can do that.
This gentleman, my neighbour...
was obsessed with having his wife
immortalised in a potrait.
So, I applied my brush
and fulfilled his desire.
And with his money, paid my bills.
So, what are you guys doing in Seville?
Skydiving.
- Really?
- Yeah.
So, you jumped out of a plane
and landed in jail?
You could say that.
That apart, what do you do?
Well, I'm a financial broker.
In London.
Money man.
And you?
My family is in the construction business.
Well, never mind.
Everyone makes mistakes.
That's funny.
You're a Xerox copy of him.
And, what about you?
I write.
What?
I'm a copywriter in advertising.
Writing copy for ads is like
a buffet for the masses.
For instance, this painting is
for someone else.
Do you write anything
to feed your own soul?
I do.
Sir?
Salman.
Right. We'll be outside.
Your hands are very similar to mine.
Sit.
Do you live alone?
No.
I have a wife.
But she is away... in Paris.
Sit.
And any...
children?
Do you ever come to India?
Yes.
I was there four years ago
when my mother passed away.
- Sorry.
- I have a brother there...
but...
we don't meet.
I've often thought about you.
I mean...
that someday, somewhere we might meet.
But I never figured...
what I would say to you.
Just say the truth.
The truth... what is the truth?
Everyone has their own version.
Look... I was...
25 then.
Rahila was a few years younger.
When you're young
the future doesn't matter.
We were just kids.
One day...
Rahila told me that she's...
expecting a baby.
I wasrt ready for
the responsibility then.
And nor am I now.
So... you just abandoned her?
I guess, you could say that.
Rahila wanted a family,
she wanted to be a mother.
I had other dreams.
I wanted to be an artist.
I wanted to paint...
travel the world.
I loved her but...
she made her choice
and I made mine.
That's all.
I found out about you
only last year.
But...
you've always known about me.
Did you never want to see me?
I thought it was better this way.
You asked for the truth.
Well, this is it.
I... am sorry, lmran.
No, you're not.
Is there something
I can do for you?
Apologise only when it comes from here.
When clouds of pain loom in the sky
When a shadow of sadness flickers by
When a tear flnds it's way to the eye
When fear keeps the loneliness alive
I try and console my heart
Why is it that you cry? I ask
This is only what life imparts
These deep silences within
Have been handed out to all by time
Everyone's story has a little sorrow
Everyone's share has a little Sunshine
No need for water in your eyes
Every moment can be a new life
Why do you let them pass you by
Oh heart, why is it that you cry?
Morning...
Did you sleep or not?
No.
I think, we should get going.
Let's go.
Arjun...
I'm really sorry.
I'll see you at the car.
Yeah.
What do you mean,
'you slept in the car'?
Long story, babe.
Tell me, what happened?
Well, lmran just...
I'll tell you later, okay.
Why? Tell me now,
what happened?
I can't tell you right now.
I'll tell you when I'm back.
Why are you getting irritated?
Why are you going on about it?
Okay, forget it.
See.
It's our wedding card.
Can you see it?
Isn't it gorgeous?
I'm just so happy with it.
Oh... I've emailed a few options
for your suit.
Please select one. Okay?
Don't forget.
Okay.
You are so far away.
You love me, right?
Yeah.
Then stop fighting with me.
Everything was fine before you
went on this holiday.
Kabir, just come home.
To me, your family, your friends.
My friends are with me.
Yeah, I know.
But you know what I mean.
Happy birthday to you...
Happy birthday dear Anjali...
Oh my God!
It's beautiful!
- Nice, right?
- Yes!
Tanya?
What are you doing, baby?
I'm sorry, I'm so happy.
Kabir just proposed to Natasha.
- What??
Oh my God!
You could've waited until
your mother had cut the cake.
Kabir, this is the best birthday gift, ever!
I love you, son.
- The shy guy!
- It's a double celebration.
I'm so happy.
Now you have to call me 'mummy'.
- Get some champagne!
Come here.
Very good decision.
I'm so happy.
Babe, what just happened in there?
- What do you mean?
- I mean...
This ring...
I got it for my mom.
It's her birthday gift.
This is for your mom?
Look at it sweety...
it's a mummy ring.
What?
Why didn't you say something?
I tried.
But you were excited and screaming.
And Tanya made an announcement.
So you don't want to marry me?
It's not about you.
I haven't even thought about marriage.
What do I tell my father?
We'll say that
we gave it some more thought and...
we need more time.
That's all.
This is so embarrassing.
I'm so sorry, sweety.
You don't ever want to marry me?
It's not like that.
If it is, you better tell me right now!
I really love you, Kabir.
And I don't...
No, no... no sweety.
Don't cry.
Not now.
Kabir...
are you even serious
about this relationship or not?
You know what...
Will you marry me?
Who is it?
Room service.
Laila?
Hi!
Oh my God!
You're here... how... I mean...
Imran called and
he begged me to come.
- So I came.
- Imran?
I knew it.
He is my best friend.
I am... so glad you're here.
I'm glad you are glad.
Hello... my the two the love the birds!
Hello!
Surprised, Arjun?
Thank you.
It's good to see you.
- And you.
- Hey gorgeous.
- I love you too.
- Nice to have you back.
You got a tan!
Get dressed, soon!
- We had to leave at seven.
- Correct.
- Two minutes?
- You missed me?
I always miss you, darling.
Where are we going?
It's a surprise.
Can't tell you in front of him.
What's going on?
What do you mean?
It's San Fermin.
Running with the bulls.
- Really?
- Didrt you know?
Just follow me...
Holy shit!
Are these guys mad?
What are they doing?
Suicide.
Isn't that why you are here?
I felt this should be the
last experience of our trip.
This could be the
last experience of our life!
Stop it, Arjun.
Let's grab a bite.
Come on.
- Excuse me.
- Dude are you...
- I'm starving!
This is not an adventure sport.
I object, Judge sahab!
I agree it's not as safe as regular sports.
And is illegal in some countries.
But according to the
Spanish tradition and culture...
it is allowed.
And technically,
according to our deal...
we can choose any sport, remember?
Lmran, it's really dangerous, you know.
Yes, those bulls could kill us, alright?
We'll be dangling on their horns
like tandoori chicken on skewers!
Precisely the point.
You want to get rid of
the fear within you?
Well then, here's
our deepest fear. Death.
Let's face it.
Because beyond this fear...
lies victory!
Please spare us the tag lines!
Dude, think about it!
No training, no instructors.
Just us, my amigos!
And some bulls running after us.
If you want to live... just run!
Laila, do you know
any psychiatrist around here?
Because our amigo has
completely lost it!
I'll be at the starting line
at seven tomorrow morning.
With or without you.
I have something for you, lmran.
It's from Nuria.
It's in Spanish.
Love has no language.
So true.
I think you should
buy her something.
You're absolutely right.
Guys... next stop - shopping.
Count me out,
I'm going back to the hotel.
Are you alright?
I'm fine.
That we'll only know after a test.
Test?
What do you say, Dr. Fraud?
Are you game?
Bring it on.
You have to say the first thing...
I know the drill. Ask!
Black.
Night.
Sea.
Salty.
Work.
Money.
Sex.
I like!
Friend.
You.
Marriage.
Family.
What?
Is that all?
It was enough.
Smartass...
You're using my trick on me?
Just say what you want to.
Okay.
You hesitated on 'marriage'.
So?
I'm just saying...
you hesitated... on marriage.
Look...
I don't have the time for this crap.
See you later.
- Okay.
- I'm sorry, I'm going to...
Kabir.
Go!
Kabir!
Kabir... man, just stop!
What?
Talk to us man.
What's going on?
It's nothing, really.
Kabir...
Look, I'm sorry I lost my cool.
Because I said you have
a problem with marriage?
I guess, I'm freaking out.
I don't know what's happening.
It's normal to be nervous.
It's not like you're having
an arranged marriage.
Yeah, but she isn't
the same person I met.
She's changed,
she's become possessive.
The girl I knew was a
talented, independent interior designer.
She enjoyed her work.
But now...
she's bid adieu to her passion and...
taken over my life.
Of course, I want a partner but...
I want my own life too!
The whole two bodies, one soul thing
I won't be able to handle it.
- May I ask you something?
- Yes.
Don't you think
you proposed to her too soon?
Actually, I didn't even propose.
- What?
I'd bought a ring for my mom
as a birthday gift.
Before giving it, I happened to show
it to Natasha and she thought...
it was meant for her.
- Are you crazy?
- What are you doing?
- What's wrong with him?
No wonder this vacation was
so important for you.
Meaning?
Basically, you wanted to hear from someone else
that you shouldn't get married
And besides us,
who would've told you this.
Have you totally lost it?
The invites are printed.
This isn't the time to overreact!
Kabir.
We know Natasha is a great girl.
And we know you like her.
And of course,
you don't want to hurt her.
But ask yourself...
Do you really want to marry her?
And if not, be honest.
To yourself and to her.
Of course, she'll be hurt.
But in the long run its best for both of you.
He is absolutely right, Kabir.
But I've made a commitment.
Okay, you screwed up.
No one's going to send you to prison.
It's not that simple.
Our parents are involved.
Parents?
Dude, it's your life.
You won't get it.
Just...
Just let it be, okay?
I'm sorry.
Kabir...
What a guy!
Laila?
Why're you shouting?
Why are you so far?
Better?
Best.
Ammi?
How are you?
I met Salman.
I now know why you and Abu
kept this from me.
I'm sorry, Ammi.
- I love you.
I love you too, my boy.
It took a while but
I've now learnt to live
Without the consolation of tears
There is someone who brought to mind
How I had gotten left behind
Life is like a caravan
Why are you lonely, my man
Just know that we are all here
The first rocket indicates that
the pen gates have been opened.
Second rocket indicates that
the bulls are coming towards us.
We run at the second rocket.
Second rocket.
Oh San Fermin, please protect us.
If I die...
my spirit will come back to haunt you.
Why are you thinking about death?
Think about what you'll do
if you survive.
Listen...
a new pact.
An if-l-get out-alive pact.
If I get out alive,
I'll let you read my poetry.
Why just you? I'll just...
get it published.
You write poetry?
Yes.
Okay.
If I get out alive...
Okay!
I'll go to Morocco with Laila.
Yeah!
That's what I'll do.
What's the worst that could happen?
I'll get fired.
- Right?
- Yeah.
Who cares man?
I'll be with her and I will live.
Well done, my bro!
Come on, Kabir.
Okay.
If I get out alive...
Shit guys!
The gates are open!
Kabir just say it.
It's okay, just say it.
If I get out alive,
I'll go to London...
and tell Natasha that...
Say what?
Just say it!
Come on, Kabir!
- Come on, Kabir!
- Come on!
I'm sorry but I can't marry you.
- Congratulations!
- Look out!
If you're carrying
your restlessness in your heart
You are alive
If you're carrying
the lightning of dreams in your eyes
You are alive
Like a gust of wind,
learn to live free
Learn to flow like
the waves that make a sea
Let your arms be wide open,
to every moment you meet
May every moment gift you
a new sight to greet
If you're carrying
your wonder in your eyes
You are alive
If you're carrying
your restlessness in your heart
You are alive
In the arms of the sun now life will be
With the rays in our breath
And a shine when we speak
In the arms of the sun now life will be
With the rays in our breath
And a shine when we speak
In the arms of the sun now life will be
With the rays in our breath
And a shine when we speak
Just when the heart
started moving to another beat
Out of nowhere
a new thought found its feet
That life gives you just one shot
So why not love it with all you've got
Who knows what we're waiting for
'Cause life is here and life is now
What was only a desire till yesterday
Is esactly what we've found today
Hand in hand let's always be
As we wander through our destiny
And all day and all night
Happiness rains down on
everything in sight
In the arms of the sun now life will be
With the rays in our breath
And a shine when we speak
In the arms of the sun now life will be
With the rays in our breath
And a shine when we speak
If it can knit a new dream everyday
Then you can call it a life
If it can lead you down a brand new way
If it can flirt and fly,
If it can spin and jive
Then you can call it a life